<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>INTERPRETATION--GETTING THE POINT book on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/interpretation--getting-the-point-book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in INTERPRETATION--GETTING THE POINT book on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/interpretation--getting-the-point-book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>8. Hindrances to interpretation 	             Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/8-hindrances-to-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/8-hindrances-to-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several situations foster misinterpretation:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) adverse consequences would come from taking a certain position (persecution, being ostracized from a fellowship, loss of a ministry or a job)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(2) competition situations (debates)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(3) hurried circumstances (deadlines)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(4) emotional situations (anger, depression, fear)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(5) the believe that the Spirit is providing the interpretation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(6) partial information (starting to work on answers before assembling&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;all the information it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. Pride (attitude)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**John 8:37&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B. Interchange of Nature, State, and Action Terms                Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/b-interchange-of-nature-state-and-action-terms-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/b-interchange-of-nature-state-and-action-terms-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As to words, people shift categories without shifting them as to concepts, because the categories are interconnected in actual experience. Being, action, and relationship are equally present in any real event, but with the mind we can differentiate between them. So language, which reflects the subjective activity of sensory perception and mental conception, differentiates between the aspects of an event even though they are objectively interrelated. If we do not distinguish language and reality, we take a point stated about one aspect and slide it onto another. Furthermore, language itself may use a nature term to refer to an action or to state reality. If readers do not keep in mind the nature of the issue, they can make all kinds of false inferences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B. Misidentifying the genre	                 Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/b-misidentifying-the-genre-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/b-misidentifying-the-genre-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The genre issue comes into the reading of Genesis 1-11, the Book of Job, the Book of Jonah, and apocalyptic works like Revelation, Ezekiel, and Daniel. History is more replete with names, places, sequences of time; but myth, saga, novelle, and the like, may have these elements as well. Especially in myth, the place where an event happens may not be of prime importance because myth uses story form to teach timeless, universal ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>b. Presuppositions (accompanying misinformation)         Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/b-presuppositions-accompanying-misinformation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/b-presuppositions-accompanying-misinformation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Different kinds of presuppositions include (1) preliminary ideas from which further ideas derive. Presuppositions, or pre-understanding, lie ahead of the present matter. They color what we read and hear on this matter. An example of presupposition would be the idea that what works is good (pragmatism).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presuppositions can be (2) larger constructs that qualify statements about matters within them. One big issue in contemporary hermeneutics is the question about implicit cultural limitation. Revelation critiques culture and stands in prophetic relationship to it. Nevertheless, some have entertained the idea that Paul and others sought to show they were not cultural subversives. On the basis of the way they deal with slavery, table fellowship (eating with someone), salutation (speaking to someone), dress code (veil-wearing, hair length), this thinking pattern has been applied to (a) egalitarian vs. hierarchical structure of marriage and (b) homosexual behavior between consenting partners. One issue is whether such behaviors mean the same thing in our setting as they did then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIBLICAL FIGURES OF SPEECH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/biblical-figures-of-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/biblical-figures-of-speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BIBLICAL FIGURES OF SPEECH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;( ) = observations not expressly made by scripture itself&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boldface headings represent clusters of images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;means the concordance has been used to create the list&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note distinction between figures of speech and figures of thought.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note also the distinction between schemes (figures of thought) and tropes (= figures of words).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Figures of thought are represented by parables, allegories, Christ-Adam parallel, Hagar-Sarah, and so on. The words are literal, but their referent is substituted for the reality you mean. Hugh Blair, Lectures on Rhetoric and Belles Littres (Vol. 1). Carbondale, IL: SIU Press, 1965. 275 pp.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C. Confusing example and precedent 	            Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/c-confusing-example-and-precedent-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/c-confusing-example-and-precedent-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interpretation deals with what scripture teaches about doctrinal matters to be believed. It deals with what scripture teaches about practices to be done. Within “praxis” lies a further distinction between example and precedent—between what was done and what was meant to be done by other people thereafter. Establishing precedent has two steps: (1) showing that such and such was, in fact, a New Testament pattern; and (2) showing that the pattern was meant to apply universally and permanently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C. Consequent nature of appropriating scripture (illumination)      Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/c-consequent-nature-of-appropriating-scripture-illumination-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/c-consequent-nature-of-appropriating-scripture-illumination-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The meaning of “interpret”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpretation involves (1) discovering the referent, (2) connecting the referent by consistency with the rest of the big picture (integration), and (3) making application to issues the author does not address, including the modern needs of believers. The first two aspects belong to “what it meant”; the last is “what it means.” We “interpret” (exegesis) to discover “meaning” (integration) so we can “understand” and have “wisdom” (application). Until we reach a level of understanding that enables us to use what we know, we do not “understand” in a “useful” way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>c. Irrationalism (improper thinking patterns)	             Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/c-irrationalism-improper-thinking-patterns-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/c-irrationalism-improper-thinking-patterns-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(1) Irrationalism occurs when feelings become the final frame of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;reference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Viewpoints based on feelings can come from confusing feelings with the work of the Spirit. People do not consider changing beliefs because they feel that the viewpoint they have must be right. There is danger in supposing that the sense (feeling) of certainty is a reason for certainty—that the Spirit places it directly in the mind. There is no more reason to assume that happens in regard to a feeling than a thought. In either case, if people cannot differentiate between something planted by the Spirit and their own thoughts and feelings, they should not consider it divine in origin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON “FULFILL”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-fulfill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-fulfill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON “FULFILL”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We may wonder what definition to put on “fulfill” if it covers such a wide range of ideas as (1) a prediction’s coming to pass, (2) an event that illustrates a generalized principle (Acts 1:20?), (3) the accomplishment of something that was also the purpose of something else (the gospel’s fulfilling the Mosaic law: Matthew 5:17; cp. Romans 3:31?), (4) an obedience that accomplished what was commanded (Romans 13:8-10), (5) a necessary inference from another passage, (6) a meeting of the requirements for something (“This course fulfills the requirement”), and (7) a mere formal similarity (? Matthew 2:18, 23; perhaps 2:15).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONCEPT INVENTORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/concept-inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/concept-inventory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CONCEPT INVENTORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For interpreters to do their work properly, they must be able to bring to the text an awareness of as many linguistic and conceptual features as appear and are presupposed in the materials they are trying to understand. Jesus’ hearers in John 7:34-36 wondered whether he would go among the Gentiles or Diasporic Jews when he said, “You cannot go where I am going.” They could not understand him because in their minds they did not have the possibility of Messiah’s ascension to heaven. The same thing happened with the Sadducees when they presented Jesus with the problem about a woman married to seven brothers in succession. They did not understand the power of God to generate new possibilities beyond what they could already conceive of on the basis of past experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D.	Adopting an inappropriate model (cp. allegorizing comparisons and nature of the</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/d-adopting-an-inappropriate-model-cp-allegorizing-comparisons-and-nature-of-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/d-adopting-an-inappropriate-model-cp-allegorizing-comparisons-and-nature-of-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;D.&#x9;Adopting an inappropriate model (cp. allegorizing comparisons and nature of the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;case)&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;                     Virgil Warre, PhD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adopting an inappropriate model appears in cases that deal with analogical reasoning. It is a confusion that comes into discussions when people try to use illustrations. When the model is off, inferences made from it can be foreign to the topic at hand because the model has elements in it that are not in the thing it is called on to explain..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E. Misidentifying the Intended Reference (frame of reference)      Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/e-misidentifying-the-intended-reference-frame-of-reference-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/e-misidentifying-the-intended-reference-frame-of-reference-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A word, phrase, or general presentation does not mean whatever the expressions could mean; it means what fits the immediate flow of thought, the distant context, and the nature of the case. Readers need to look for the relevant contrast over against which the writer is speaking. They need to properly identify the topic an author is speaking about. They must transcend their existential situation and personality bent lest they put biblical statements in a foreign framework; otherwise, the dogmatic and practical principles get ahead of the exegetical one (see entries above). Readers have to read the biblical writer “on his own terms”; they have to “get inside the writer’s mind.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F. Confusing language and reality	                Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/f-confusing-language-and-reality-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/f-confusing-language-and-reality-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since language is based on perception, it expresses a person’s subjective viewpoint. Consequently, (a) statements can be made from the way things look more than from the way they really are (phenomenological language). In a related matter, (b) language does not reproduce the whole of the reality it refers to, but only enough to let the hearer know what the speaker is talking about. From previous experience or explanation, a hearer fills in the rest of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G.	Reading restrictive for nonrestrictive (or positive)	               Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/g-reading-restrictive-for-nonrestrictive-or-positive-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/g-reading-restrictive-for-nonrestrictive-or-positive-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Restrictive means limited to some portion less than all: “They are good people” (their relatives are not good). Nonrestrictive means all the group—at least generally—is characterized that way: “They are good people (I am not talking about anybody else here, and, yes, I am aware of the rotter that abandoned his family years ago).” Both statements indicate what the speaker means, not what is true or what else he knows about other people or about any exceptions to his point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GETTING THE POINT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/getting-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/getting-the-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GETTING THE POINT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION: The Nature of Language Communication&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. An allegory: parallels between working a puzzle and interpreting the Bible&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not everything is all there together; we have to put it together. The Bible has a historical organization and a practical application to specific situations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are tempted to start putting pieces together before we get all the pieces turned over and sorted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We begin by turning the pieces over and sorting them by color and perhaps shape, a procedure comparable to getting the data together before beginning to work on a conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H. Technicalizing terminology		 Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/h-technicalizing-terminology-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/h-technicalizing-terminology-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Assuming technical usage in the scripture is a way of trying to get something more specific out of a text than the author meant. Technicalizing is a kind of restrictive reading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technical contrasts with positive, general, or descriptive usage. Technicalizing shows up in taking words as appellative names rather than as descriptive ones: church of Christ, church of God, disciples become Church of Christ, Church of God, Disciples. Technicalizing leads to expectancy for uniform usage. It specifies a smaller group within those who could be described by the word picture. In church offices, elder means more than “older”; it ‎means a(n older) man who oversees a group of believers as when qualifications are listed and a process of selection takes place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HERMENEUTICS: GETTING THE POINT:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-getting-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-getting-the-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HERMENEUTICS: GETTING THE POINT:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AN OUTLINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION: Nature of Language Communication&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Parallels between working a puzzle and interpreting the Bible&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Nature of language&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Language is always from the subjective viewpoint.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;Literal language can occur even though language comes from the subjective side.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.&#x9;Figurative language is a possibility because language comes from the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;subjective side.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c.&#x9;Phenomenological language arises from the fact that language comes from the subjective side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I. Setting the conclusion and then working toward it	             Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/i-setting-the-conclusion-and-then-working-toward-it-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/i-setting-the-conclusion-and-then-working-toward-it-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ways of referring to the problem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. It is a “foregone conclusion.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b. Prooftexting&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c. Getting the dogmatic principle ahead of the exegetical one&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d. Getting the practical problem ahead of the exegetical one&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e. Not reading the Bible “on its own terms”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pattern of the procedure (the reason it has apparent validity)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People may “work backwards” from what works or what they have experienced to what they believe. At each step in the process, they choose what hooks up with other points that lead toward the desired conclusion. Setting the conclusion and working to it, yields firm interpretations in ambiguous cases, and twists statements in the direction of the foregone conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>II. 	SELECTED LINGUISTIC PHENOMENA (Note Dr. Warren’s Ph.D. dissertation The Implication of Divine Self-Consistency for the Doctrine of Natural Depravity, pp. 152-70.)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ii-selected-linguistic-phenomena-note-dr-warrens-phd-dissertation-the-implication-of-divine-self-consistency-for-the-doctrine-of-natural-depravity-pp-152-70/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ii-selected-linguistic-phenomena-note-dr-warrens-phd-dissertation-the-implication-of-divine-self-consistency-for-the-doctrine-of-natural-depravity-pp-152-70/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;II. &#x9;SELECTED LINGUISTIC PHENOMENA (Note Dr. Warren’s Ph.D. dissertation The Implication of Divine Self-Consistency for the Doctrine of Natural Depravity, pp. 152-70.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Streamlining Causal Distinctions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Streamlining causal distinctions is a shorthand way of speaking about causal relationships. It occurs especially when the exact manner of connection is unimportant for present purposes. It can create ambiguity because the (1) mode of causality and (2) the directness of causation get blurred. All languages streamline causality and interchange modality, but Hebrew does so more than English and other modern languages do in cultures impacted by scientific precision. Much of the “God talk” in scripture comes to mean something different when English speakers use it; they bring the verbiage into their language without adjusting its import. By allowing variation within the mode, Semitic thought tends to be general and holistic in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>III. GENERAL MECHANICS BEHIND INTERPRETATION         Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/iii-general-mechanics-behind-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/iii-general-mechanics-behind-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The “big three” in interpretation are (1) the law of harmony, (2) the law of contrast, and (3) the nature of the case. All three amount to one thing—the law of harmony, but we sort them out to stress the peculiar contribution each aspect makes to the whole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Law of harmony (analogy)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two things or two ideas can have varying degrees and kinds of relationship. From one extreme to the other is (1) what is positively determined by something else,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPRETATION, HERMENEUTICS, THEOLOGICAL METHOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpretation-hermeneutics-theological-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpretation-hermeneutics-theological-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPRETATION, HERMENEUTICS, THEOLOGICAL METHOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In dealing with controversial passages, interpreters make their choice by their understanding of the big picture, the general understanding, the conceptual context. They follow this procedure even with passages that at first glance would call for a more likely-sounding interpretation. The readers may choose a less likely sounding meaning because of the general understanding they bring to the text. In such cases, where more than one reading is possible, the text doesn’t prove either idea that the readers are bringing to it; that text rises no higher than confirmatory evidence in contrast to primary proof. The passage falls out of the process of arriving at the general understanding. That general understanding must come from someplace else or from other places taken together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTRODUCTORY CONSIDERATIONS ON JONAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/introductory-considerations-on-jonah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/introductory-considerations-on-jonah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTORY CONSIDERATIONS ON JONAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Observations against Jonah as history&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Overabundance of extreme miracle (12 miracles in 48 verses)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. The storm that arose (1:4)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b. The lot that fell on Jonah (1:7)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c. The stilling of the storm (1:15)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d. The preparation of a “great fish” (1:17)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e. The fish’s swallowing Jonah (1:17)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;f. The fish’s vomiting him on dry land (2:10)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;g. Jonah’s living through the experience (2:1-9)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IV. INTERPRETING VARIOUS CLASSES OF LITERATURE      Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/iv-interpreting-various-classes-of-literature-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/iv-interpreting-various-classes-of-literature-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Examples of biblical literary genres: apocalyptic, benedictions, covenant, diatribe, didactic, drama, epistles, fable, history, lament, law, myth, parables, poetry, prophecy (predictive), proverbs, psalms, riddles, speeches (sermons, prayer, dialog), wisdom literature&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Prime concerns&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The degree of figurativeness expected in various genres&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Figurativeness and literalness are matters of degree. The degree of figurativeness depends on the purpose of communication. If the purpose is to inform, the writing less figurative; if it is to motivate, it may be more figurative. Poetry and prophecy foster figurative expression; history and law have less figurativeness. Didactic material lies between the extremes. High levels of figurativeness do not occur so often in passages that seek to inform, because figurativeness works against clarity. Figurative language is used more for confirming truths already understood, exhortation, and impression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. Confusing advice and commandment	                Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/j-confusing-advice-and-commandment-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/j-confusing-advice-and-commandment-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Commandment means something that excludes alternative behaviors. It applies to (a) moral law, which goes back to first principles for determining right action. Moral law comes from divine purpose and the nature of the case. It distinguishes between natural and unnatural. Since moral commandments reflect purpose and the nature of things based on purpose, people obey moral commandments to bring about a more satisfying life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commandment applies to (b) positive commandment. Although other possibilities exist, this one is specified—perhaps for “good order.” Positive commandment rests more on authority because it addresses appropriate and more appropriate. (The purpose of positive commandment is nicely put by C. S. Lewis in Perelandra, p. 118.) It is a commandment obeyed out of love and deference more than from necessity, fear, or duty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JEWISH EXPECTATIONS OF THE KINGDOM OF GOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/jewish-expectations-of-the-kingdom-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/jewish-expectations-of-the-kingdom-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JEWISH EXPECTATIONS OF THE KINGDOM OF GOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AND SOME IMPLICATIONS FOR NEW TESTAMENT INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines for biblical interpretation include the “big three”: (1) the principle of harmony, (2) the principle of contrast, and (3) the nature of the case. The first derives from the nature of scripture, which as a matter of principle we accept as true throughout and therefore harmonious. The second principle derives from the nature of language, which conveys ideas relative to a framework of thought. The last principle derives from experience, a prime resource for knowing the way things are. All three principles interrelate and impact the interpretation of human language in general and scripture in particular.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NEW TESTAMENT INTERPRETATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/new-testament-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/new-testament-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NEW TESTAMENT INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF OLD TESTAMENT TEXTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several hermeneutical questions arise about the New Testament writers’ use of Old Testament texts. In cases like Matthew’s use of Hosea 11:1, we may broaden the definitions of prophecy and fulfillment as a way of legitimizing his use of the prophet’s comment. Making this move reflects a prior commitment to the principle that inspiration makes New Testament authors “forever correct.” People’s prior commitment to “inerrancy” causes them to take a positive view on a text that they might not otherwise have chosen or would otherwise consider a matter of opinion. That does not weaken its validity; it merely demonstrates consistency. We cannot with finality settle some questions directly. We take views on derivative issues that harmonize with primary views. On the other hand, the possibility of other imaginable reasons for a writer’s use of an earlier text does not invalidate one affirmed because of assumed inerrancy. We are involved here in the distinction between a presuppositional and phenomenological approach to the view of scripture. Without the assumption that divine inspiration kept writers from error, we would have less justification for using insights from one writer to clarify ambiguous words of another writer, for harmonizing two authors who could otherwise mean incompatible things, for interpreting biblical statements so as not to conflict with information we learn from science, for choosing this interpretation from among two or more otherwise equally plausible views, given only the text itself, or even for taking a less likely sounding interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMPLICATION OF DIVINE SELF-CONSISTENCY FOR THE DOCTRINE OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-implication-of-divine-self-consistency-for-the-doctrine-of-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-implication-of-divine-self-consistency-for-the-doctrine-of-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMPLICATION OF DIVINE SELF-CONSISTENCY FOR THE DOCTRINE OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A BIBLICAL-SYSTEMATIC APPROACH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EXEGETICAL IMPASSE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A standoff has persisted in exegesis between Calvinistic and non-Calvinistic thought on the nature of human kind largely because no necessary resolution can come at the level of individual passages that have implications for anthropology. A few examples illustrate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) Psalm 51:10 says, “Create in me a clean heart, O God; and renew a right spirit within me” (cp. 36:26); Ezekiel 18:31 shows another emphasis: “Make for yourselves a new heart and a new spirit.” The difficulty is whether Psalm 51:10 interprets Ezekiel 18:31 or vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V. PITFALLS IN INTERPRETATION  	               Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/v-pitfalls-in-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/v-pitfalls-in-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Allegorizing the comparison&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The allegorizing problem applies to all expressions that make comparisons: similes, metaphors, parables, illustrations (vs. examples). Comparison does not mean likeness in every respect, but in the respects the speaker indicates. All comparisons relate figure and fact as overlapping circles. Some things about the figure do not apply to the fact. When hearers press the comparison to aspects outside the purpose of the illustration,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;they abandon the speaker’s authority for claiming those likeness. They commit the equivalent of what in logic is called “the fallacy of four terms”; that is, the middle term does not refer to the same thing in both statements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VI. TESTING OTHER PEOPLE’S INTERPRETATION                   Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/vi-testing-other-peoples-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/vi-testing-other-peoples-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interpretation is a community effort. In practice, Christians do not just individually interact with the scripture; they interact with each other as well. For biblical interpretation purposes, we need to understand how language works both in studying scripture and in teaching and hearing the way of the Lord more perfectly. Theology as a community effort includes studying the history of Christian thought; it provides another resource for biblical understanding. It identifies the appropriate role of tradition as teacher rather than authority. Christians are church theologians, never professional theologians; they do something with what they learn (education for use), and they do it in community with other people inside and outside the body of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VII. HERMENEUTICS AND LIFE 	                Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/vii-hermeneutics-and-life-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/vii-hermeneutics-and-life-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A. The process of hermeneutics and life [understanding the biblical message]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Goal: to find out what the scripture means by experiencing what it says; do it to understand it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Passages take on a liveliness and relevance because of experiences we face. Meaning is not just objective significance, but subjective impact. The two correspond as to content, but the impact comes from the doing. Understanding through interpretation (validity) leads to belief (truth) and obedience (commitment), which turns around and clarifies the understanding. As reciprocation occurs between parts and whole in biblical-systematic interpretation, so also reciprocation occurs between text and experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WISDOM AND LAW: DIVORCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/wisdom-and-law-divorce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/wisdom-and-law-divorce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WISDOM AND LAW: DIVORCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The difference between law and wisdom as well as the relationship between them showed up in an article on the adult offspring of divorce by Irene Sege published in the Boston Globe (see The Manhattan Mercury for Friday, December 20, 1995, D1). Generalizations about these young people show that their parents’ divorce measurably affects a sizable portion of their children when they grow up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a matter of wisdom, then, not to enter marriage without the most earnest intentions of maintaining the future marriage for the children’s sake—among other things. And, it is likewise a matter of wisdom to go together into marriage with a set of values that increases the likelihood of the marriage’s permanence. This kind of observation is built on reality as based on human nature (vs. purpose or relationship) and has the pattern of tendency (vs. uniformity).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
