<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BASIC CHRISTINAITY STUDY GUIDES on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/basic-christinaity-study-guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BASIC CHRISTINAITY STUDY GUIDES on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/basic-christinaity-study-guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1.  STUDY GUIDE ON LOVE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-study-guide-on-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-study-guide-on-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON LOVE&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. From the groups of passages given below may be derived a significant process involving love. The first four groups correspond to individual parts of the process, although a certain amount of overlapping cannot be eliminated. The fifth group involves passages that cover varying amounts of the whole process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 3:16; Romans 5:8; 8:31-39; Galatians 2:20; Ephesians 2:4-5; 5:2, 25; 2 Thessalonians 2:16; 1 John 4:9-10; Revelation 1:5-6.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE FOR DIVINE GUIDANCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-for-divine-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-for-divine-guidance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE FOR DIVINE GUIDANCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Passages on divine calling and direction that are helpful in understanding the manner of God’s specially leading people are (1) Genesis 6:13ff.; (2) Genesis 12:1ff.; 13:14ff.; (3) Exodus 3; (4) Judges 6:11-25ff.; (5) Judges 13:2ff.; (6) 1 Samuel 3;           (7)  Amos 7:14ff.; (8) Jonah 1:1-2; 3:1-2; (9) Isaiah 6; (10) Jeremiah 1:1-2:1; (11) Ezekiel 2:1-7; 3:16ff., 22ff.; 6:1ff.; etc.; (12) Haggai 2:10ff.; 20; (13) Zechariah 1:1-3ff.; (14) Luke 1:5-25, 39-80; 3:1-20 (Matthew 3; Mark 1:11); John 1:6-36; (15) Matthew 10:1-4ff.; (Mark 3:13-19; Luke 6:12-16); Acts 1:1-11; (16) Acts 8:26-40; (17) Acts 9:10-19; (18) Acts 9:1-18; 22:3-21; 26:2-23; Galatians 1:11-2:10; Acts 16:9-10; 22:17-21 (cp. 9:26-30).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE ON ASSURANCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-assurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-assurance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON ASSURANCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. A study of assurance requires an understanding of the relationship between four sets of variables:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1)&#x9;Objective-subjective evidence. Objective refers to the real basis upon which our assurance rests; subjective refers to whether we feel assured of salvation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(2)&#x9;Primary-confirmatory evidence. Primary evidence fits only with one conclusion; confirmatory evidence fits with the correct conclusion, but it might fit with other possibilities as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(3)&#x9;Absolute-relative. Absolute certainty means there is no possibility of doubt; relative certainty is the kind that is sufficient for practical purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE ON CHRISTIAN FREEDOM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-christian-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-christian-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON CHRISTIAN FREEDOM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elements essential to an understanding of Christian freedom are diagrammed here in three sets of logical relationships: (1) subjective refers to our feelings about the matter; objective refers to what is there regardless of our feelings about it. (2) Plus (+) and minus (-) mean the presence or absence of the category at the left for those who are in Christ. (3) Jurisdiction of law is divine regulation of human behavior. Penalty of broken law is the guilt consequence we have for breaking God’s law. Reality means the barriers, boundaries, limitations—personal and external—in the reality where we live and what we are a part of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE ON PRAYER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON PRAYER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayer raises three issues. Think about them; study the surrounding verses and other scripture portions by cross reference or a concordance.  Write down answers to the accompanying questions, giving scriptural support wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Problem 1: Matthew 6:8: “Your Father knows what you need before you ask him.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As respects the knowledge of God then,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is prayer not for?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Explain why this or any other verse is no justification for not praying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE ON PSYCHOLOGICAL STRENGTH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-psychological-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-psychological-strength/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON PSYCHOLOGICAL STRENGTH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christianity is not a philosophy we believe, but a religion we live. It should have something to say, then, to the whole person and be able to help us psychologically cope with life. The following clusters of texts contain implications for psychological strength. Decide what the implication is and why it is true.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 6:33&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 4:16-5:10; cp. Matthew 6:19-21; Hebrews 12:18-29 as well as Galatians 6:8; Colossians 3:1ff.; James 1:15&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE ON SUFFERING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-suffering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-suffering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON SUFFERING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Major portions of scripture deal with suffering-pain-calamity-death: the Book of Job, 1 Corinthians, and 1 Peter. From these books cross references identify other shorter sections on this difficult subject.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. What basic facts about suffering do we observe in or inferred from the following groups of passages?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Genesis 3; Romans 5:12-14;1 Peter 1:6-7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. Genesis 18:31?; the thesis of the Book of Job; John 9:1-3ff., 34; Acts 28:1-6&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE ON THE SANCTIFICATION PROCESS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-the-sanctification-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-the-sanctification-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON THE SANCTIFICATION PROCESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following analysis of a Christian’s growth process produces a schematic based on the inner-outer differential. By inner we mean the understanding, emotions, and motives we have; outer means the actions we do. Each group of scriptures given below affirms something about the inner, the outer, or their relationship. Determine what that fact is and why it is important. Then synthesize all the parts into a working model of the growth process with observations on its implications for witnessing and applications to Christian education and defense of the faith.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE ON WEAKER BROTHER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-weaker-brother/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-weaker-brother/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON WEAKER BROTHER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relating to our brothers and sisters in Christ would be easier if we were all at the same stage of growth in understanding and virtue and if we all viewed things the same way. As a matter of fact, we are not all equally strong and do not see things alike. We must learn to make allowance for differences i to keep the unity of the faith in the bond of peace and to avoid stumbling and discouragement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
