<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Titus on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/titus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Titus on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/titus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Titus 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/titus/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/titus/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;titus-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Titus Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul, servant of God and apostle of Jesus ChristMessiah for the faith God&amp;rsquo;s chosen people have, and for the knowledge of the truth that leads to godliness and 2hope for eternal life. God our Savior, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t lie, promised that life before times eternal. 3Then at an appropriate time, he made the message available by the preaching he entrusted to me according to the commandment of our Savior God. 4To Titus, my loyal son in the faith we share. Grace and peace from God the Father and Christ Jesus our Savior.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titus 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/titus/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/titus/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;titus-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Titus Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; But you, encourage the kind of living that is appropriate to sound doctrine. 2Older men should be serious-minded, respectable, sensible; sound in faith, love, and endurance. 3The same thing applies to older women. They should be reverent in behavior, not prone to gossip or addicted to wine, but teaching what&amp;rsquo;s good. 4Then they can teach young women to love their husbands and children. 5They should be sensible, pure, devoted to their families, kind, and deferring to their husbands so people won&amp;rsquo;t slander God&amp;rsquo;s message.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titus 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/titus/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/titus/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;titus-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Titus Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Remind people to submit to rulers and authorities, to be obedient and ready to do everything that&amp;rsquo;s good. 2Remind them not to insult or get pushy, but to be considerate and gentle toward everybody. 3At one time we were foolish too, disobedient, deceived, addicted to various lusts and pleasures. We spent our lives in evil and envy, hated and hating one another. 4But, &amp;ldquo;the kindness of God our Savior appeared along with love for other people. 5We didn&amp;rsquo;t save ourselves by doing good. In mercy he saved us by the washing that regenerates and by the renewal the Holy Spirit gives. 6God poured out his Spirit on us richly through Jesus Christ our Savior. 7In grace he justified us so we could inherit the hope for eternal life.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
