<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MA THESIS on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/ma-thesis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MA THESIS on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/ma-thesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER I</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chapter-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chapter-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NON-DENOMINATIONAL UNITY IN PERSPECTIVE AND PREVIEW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;General Framework in Diagram&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The framework of thought for this entire presentation is previewed in the following diagram. The diagram delineates four aspects of Christian unity as it relates to salvation, and shows their general correspondence to proposed divisions of the whole topic of unity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fig. 1.  Four Aspects of Christian Unity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soteriological Context:  Being&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Salvation and Unity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Individual unity with Christ” refers to the interpersonal relationship with Christ made possible by his moral perfection. Individual salvation both precedes and pervades the subsequent horizontal group aspects of Christian unity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chapter-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chapter-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PRELIMINARY CONCEPTS IN ORGANIZATIONAL THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Influence and Authority&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Definitions of Influence and Authority&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physical force, legal authority, and personal influence are three means of controlling persons. The distinctness, compatibility, and relationship of the latter two are especially important in a study of church organization. Authority is the legal right to compel the behavior only of status inferiors. Influence is the personal ability to impel the behavior even of status superiors. A study of organizational structure concerns itself with the pattern of authority flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER III</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chapter-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chapter-iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE NEW TESTAMENT STRUCTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basic Structure&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter sketches the original organization of the universal church according to the evidence of the New Testament taken alone. As respects authority the approach will be to determine what positions have authority and to consider the rest as functions. This procedure is possible not only because an either-or matter is under consideration, but more particularly because authority includes function. One cannot suppose that a function is seen as such only because the evidence recorded happens to be insufficient to show that it was really an office. That approach becomes an argument from silence and shifts the burden of proof onto the negative. The negative burden of proof in this instance would be impossible since the only available evidence would pertain to function, which is part of the larger concept of office.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER IV</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chapter-iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chapter-iv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE NORMATIVENESS OF THE NEW TESTAMENT STRUCTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Divine Origination&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prescriptive Divine Origin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The normativeness of the first-century pattern may be conveniently discussed under three headings progressively arranged: divine origin, intended permanence, and inherent exclusive-ness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Formal application&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christ’s lordship. Jesus Christ is an appointed King of a granted kingdom (Luke 19:12). The givenness of that entity includes its form—“kingdom”—as well as the principles of kingdom government–formal authority prescriptively applied. The organization of the church did not result from a natural process of crystallization among the disciples of Jesus, for Jesus was not a teacher like Socrates, who wrote nothing, founded nothing, and died, only to leave behind a group of followers that evolved a tradition of thought and practice. As to essential nature the church is kingdom as well as brotherhood. As regards government, the church may be called a Christocratic monarchy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The church is saved people serving in divine pattern. The body of Christ possesses essential oneness by virtue of individual unity with Christ and collective unity through Christ. This invisible oneness is manifest by a dynamic structure-function called the church. Functional unity in Christ combines with organizational unity under Christ to form this non-denominational entity that has a fivefold oneness of attitude, doctrine, fellowship, name, and organization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a first major concern the historical argument for non-denominationalism focused particularly on the last of these elements: the organizational pattern of the church established under direct apostolic administration. Although the first four elements have probably never been fully present in the visible church, it was anticipated that sufficient evidence was available to show that formal oneness did exist in the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Title&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This thesis examines the historical argument for organizational church unity. The New Testament Basis for the Non-Denominational Church: The Historical Argument is used as the title for two reasons especially: (1) clarity–a concept is most definite in the context of contrast; (2) relevance–denominationalism is a feature of contemporary Christendom that stands in contrast to what will be presented as the nature of the church’s unity according to the New Testament.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NEW TESTAMENT BASIS FOR THE NON-DENOMINATIONAL CHURCH:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-basis-for-the-non-denominational-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-basis-for-the-non-denominational-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEW TESTAMENT BASIS FOR THE NON-DENOMINATIONAL CHURCH:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE HISTORICAL ARGUMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VIRGIL WARREN, PhD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NEW TESTAMENT BASIS FOR THE NON-DENOMINATIONAL CHURCH: THE HISTORICAL ARGUMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-basis-for-the-non-denominational-church-the-historical-argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-basis-for-the-non-denominational-church-the-historical-argument/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEW TESTAMENT BASIS FOR THE NON-DENOMINATIONAL CHURCH: THE HISTORICAL ARGUMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The church is saved people serving in divine pattern. The body of Christ possesses essential oneness by virtue of individual unity with Christ and collective unity through Christ. This invisible oneness is manifest by a dynamic structure-function called the church. Functional unity in Christ combines with organizational unity under Christ to form this non-denominational entity that has a fivefold oneness of attitude, doctrine, fellowship, name, and organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
