<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>THE NATURE of MAN  (Book) on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/the-nature-of-man--book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in THE NATURE of MAN  (Book) on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/the-nature-of-man--book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ETHICAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE AS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ethical-observations-on-the-image-as/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ethical-observations-on-the-image-as/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETHICAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE AS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ethical Use of Imago dei&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) The image as interpersonal capacity connects the natural and the ethical usages of the expression image of God. One pervasive concern of biblical content is wholeness, the big picture, the synthetic emphasis in contrast to a dichotomistic, analytical, reductionist approach. That concern carries over into the terminology. The penchant for integration accounts for the rather facile shifting back and forth between natural, behavioral, and relational usages of terms like image, life, sin, flesh, create, knowledge, and wisdom associated with the creation narrative. Integration accounts for places where such expressions may combine these rather different, though related, concepts when dealing with subjects in broad scope.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMAGE AND LIKENESS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/image-and-likeness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/image-and-likeness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IMAGE AND LIKENESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have not made a distinction between “image” and “likeness,” even though Genesis 1:26 uses two words to compare mankind and God. (a) Nothing in the context distinguishes them. Furthermore, (b) in most other passages only one term occurs, image in Genesis 9:6-7; 1 Corinthians 11:7; James 3:9 and likeness in Genesis 5:2 in an otherwise word-for-word parallel to 1:26. Like in Genesis 3:5, 22 translates a different item than in 1:26.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATURAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/natural-observations-on-the-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/natural-observations-on-the-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NATURAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter we offered restrictive guidelines for identifying the image of God—boundaries within which the understanding of image must fall. The image must be a creatable likeness that applies to the whole individual even after the Fall. Then we offered two sets of positive evidence for the image as interpersonal capacity to build the view “from zero.” There were two deductive arguments: (1) the interpersonal purposes of mankind predict interpersonal nature of man as the image; (2) being in the image of an interpersonal God implies that mankind is interpersonal. Finally, we made inductive observations: human peculiarities observed in connection with image terminology end up being aspects of interpersonal capacity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIMARY EVIDENCE FOR THE IMAGE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/primary-evidence-for-the-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/primary-evidence-for-the-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRIMARY EVIDENCE FOR THE IMAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From evidence presented in the next three chapters, we conclude that having the image of God means having interpersonal capacity. At the outset we want to make explicit three notable ideas in the designation “interpersonal capacity.” (a) Interpersonal means that the image of God has to do with persons instead of things, forces, animals, or ideas. (b) Interpersonal relates the image to the social setting. The image involves more than the individual because it pertains to marriage, community, church, society, humankind as well as God’s purposes for persons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGE AND ETHICS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-image-and-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-image-and-ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGE AND ETHICS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theory of meaning, the basis for self-image, and the theory of ethics all three reference the same factors: being, action, and relationship. The previous chapter discussed meaning and self-image as the objective and subjective sides of the same thing. This chapter notes that ethics belongs to action in the interpersonal sphere. Since we have identified the image of God with the interpersonal capacity, it remains for us to explicate the principles for ethical theory that grow out of the construct established by God’s creating us in his (a) interpersonal image for (b) fellowship and (c) purpose. Action connects the first item with each of the last two. Image defines human nature/being, which behavior ties to relationship and purpose. Relationship and purpose are relational since action relates persons to others in fellowship and relates them to the results of their deeds. Action connects being to relations (ethics) even as action connected objective and subjective in the previous chapter (meaning).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGE AND THE BODY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-image-and-the-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-image-and-the-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGE AND THE BODY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Including the Body in the Image&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter we address more deliberately the issue noted before. A long-standing debate about the image concerns whether to include the body in it. There are three ways to relate the image and the body. The body might be (a) part of the image, (b) involved with the image, or (c) analogous to the image. Several considerations go into deciding whether the body is in, with, or like the image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NATURE OF MANKIND</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-mankind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NATURE OF MANKIND&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preface&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The present volume was a project during a year’s sabbatical at Manhattan Christian College in Manhattan, Kansas. I am grateful to fellow faculty members, administration, and trustees for approving the sabbatical proposal. To my colleagues—especially Steve Isom, Dr. Franklin Karns, and Dr. Scott Caulley—I owe a debt of thanks for shouldering increased teaching loads so the necessary courses for the l989-1990 academic year could be maintained. Students and family have been encouragements as well during the completion of this and other commitments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRADITIONAL REASONS FOR GOD’S CREATING US</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/traditional-reasons-for-gods-creating-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/traditional-reasons-for-gods-creating-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRADITIONAL REASONS FOR GOD’S CREATING US&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Issues can be relatively simple in themselves; and so the question seems about God’s reason for creating us. Issues get complicated when we try to distinguish our own understanding from other ones and when we have to give reasons against such alternatives, especially if they overlap our own.1 As in our positive presentation so also in evaluating other positions, interpersonalism serves as the criterion for what is foreign and contradictory to what scripture says about the nature and purpose of God and man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
