<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 Thessalonians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-thessalonians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 Thessalonians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-thessalonians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2 Thessalonians 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-thessalonians-chapter-1&#34;&gt;2 Thessalonians Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul and Silvanus and Timothy to the church of-[the] Thessalonians in God (the) Father of-us and (the) Lord Jesus Christ.  2Grace to-you and peace from God (the) Father [of-us]ms and (the) Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; We-are-obliged to-give-thanks to-[the] God always about you, brothers, even-as is appropriate, because the faith of-you is-greatly-growing, and the love of-each one of-you all for one-another is-increasing, 4so-as-(a)-result we ourselves boast in you among the churches of-[the] God for the patience of-you and faith amidst all the persecutions of-you and the afflictions that you-are-enduring, 5evidence of-the righteous judgment of-[the] God unto your [the] being-considered-worthy of-the kingdom of-[the] God, for which also you-are-suffering, 6since (it is) just from God to-repay affliction to-the-ones afflicting you 7and (to repay) relief to-you the-ones troubled with us, at the revelation of-the Lord Jesus from heaven with (the) angels of-the power of-him 8in (a) fire of-flame, giving revenge to-the-ones not knowing God and the-ones not obeying the gospel of-the Lord of-us Jesus, 9who will-undergo eternal destruction from (the) face of-the Lord and from the glory of-the strength of-him, 10when he-comes to be glorified on that [the] day in the saints of-him and to-be-marveled-at in all the believing-ones, because the witness of-us to you was-believed.  11Unto that we┘also└pray for you always in-order-that the God of-us will-make┘you└worthy of-the calling and may-fulfill every intention of-goodness and work of-faith with power, 12in-order-that the name of-the Lord of-us Jesus may-be-glorified in you, and you in him according-to the grace of-the God of-us and Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Thessalonians 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-thessalonians-chapter-2&#34;&gt;2 Thessalonians Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now we-ask you, brothers, about the coming of-the Lord of-us Jesus Christ and (the) gathering of-us to him 2for [the] your not to-being-unsettled swiftly from the mind or being disturbed either by (a) spirit or by (a) message or by (a) letter as-if by us, as that the day of-the Lord has come.  3Let┘not anybody according-to any way└deceive you because unless2 the/a falling-away first comes and the man of-[the] lawlessness is-revealed, the son of-[the] perdition, 4the-one opposing and exalting-himself above everything called God or (an) object–of-worship so-that him to-be-sitting in the temple of-(the) God presenting himself that he-is God.  5Do-your┘not└emember that, yet being with you, I-was-telling you these-things?  6And you-know the restraining-thing now unto his [the] being-revealed in [the] his-own time.  7For the mystery of-[the] lawlessness is┘already└at-work; only the-one restraining now (will restrain) until he-becomes out-of (the) midst.  8And then the lawless-one will-be-revealed, whom the Lord [Jesus]ms will-kill with-the breath of-the mouth of-him and will-destroy by-the appearance of-the coming of-him, 9whose [the] coming is according-to (the) working of-[the] Satan in all power and signs and lying wonders 10and in every deception of-wrapping for-the-ones perishing against whom they-did┘not└receive the love of-the truth unto [the] their being-saved.  11And on-account-of this [the] God sends to-them (a) working of-deception unto [the] their believing [the] lie, 12in-order-that all the-ones not having-believed, but having-taken-delight in-[the] wrong-doing may-be-judging by-the truth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Thessalonians 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-thessalonians-chapter-3&#34;&gt;2 Thessalonians Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Finally2, brothers, pray for us in-order-that the word of-the Lord may-make-progress and be-glorified even-as also (it was) with you, 2and in-order-that we-may-be-delivered from harmful and evil men, for [the] faith (is) not of-all.  3But the Lord is faithful who will-strengthen you and keep (you) from the evil-(one).  4And we-are-confident in (the) Lord over you, that what-things we-command you-are┘both└doing and will-do.  5And may┘the Lord└direct the hearts of-you into the love of-[the] God and into the endurance of-[the] Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
