<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ezekiel on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ezekiel on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The fifth day, fourth month, thirtieth year, I was by the Chebar River with the exiles. The sky opened up, and I saw a vision of God. (2The fifth month, fifth year of Jehoiachin&amp;rsquo;s exile, 3God&amp;rsquo;s message came to Ezekiel, and God&amp;rsquo;s hand came on him.) 4A strong north wind was blowing, and a large cloud with a bright glow around it flashed constantly with lightning. In the cloud was something like glowing metal 5and four figures like living beings with human forms. 6Each one had four faces and four wings. 7They had straight legs, and their feet resembled calf hooves that shined like polished bronze. 8There were hands under their wings, 9and the wings of all four touched each other. Their faces didn&amp;rsquo;t turn as they moved straight forward. 10Each one had the faces of a man, an eagle, a lion on the right, and a bull on the left. 11Their wings spread out above them, two wings touching the wings of the next living beings and two covering their bodies. 12They went straight forward wherever the spirit went, without turning as they went. 13Among the beings were what looked like burning coals, like torches moving back and forth. The fire burned bright, and lightning kept flashing out of it. 14The living beings darted back forth like bolts of lightning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Son of man, stand up so I can talk to you!&amp;quot; 2When the Spirit stood me up, 3he said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sending you to the Israelites, a rebellious people. They and their ancestors have been sinning against me to this day. 4Tell those impudent, stubborn children, &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh says.&amp;rsquo; 5Whether they listen or not, they&amp;rsquo;ll know a prophet&amp;rsquo;s been there. 6Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of them or intimidated by what they say, though you&amp;rsquo;re surrounded by briars and thorns and sitting on scorpions. 7Tell them what I&amp;rsquo;ve said whether they listen or not. 8&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t be like that rebellious house. Eat what I&amp;rsquo;m giving you.&amp;rdquo; 9A hand held out a scroll to me. 10When he unrolled it for me, I could see writing on both sides—lamentations, mourning, and misfortune.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Eat this scroll and go speak to Israel.&amp;quot; 2So I opened my mouth, and he fed it to me. 3It tasted sweet like honey.&#x9;   Ezek 2:8-3:3 [4] 5-6&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;m not sending you to people that speak a hard foreign language you can&amp;rsquo;t understand. I&amp;rsquo;m sending you to people that should listen; 7but they won&amp;rsquo;t listen to you, because they won&amp;rsquo;t listen to me. The whole house is stubborn. 8I&amp;rsquo;ve made your face and forehead as hard as theirs, 9like corundum, harder than flint. So don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of them or be intimidated by them though they&amp;rsquo;re rebellious people. 10Listen closely and take everything to heart that I tell you. 11Go to your people in exile and tell them, &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh says,&amp;rsquo; whether they listen or not.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now, son of man, take a tablet and etch Jerusalem on it. 2Lay a siege against it with a siege wall and ramp, pitch camps, and position battering rams all around it. 3Then set up an iron plate as a wall between you and the city. Face it and press the siege against it. It&amp;rsquo;s an omen for Israel. 4&amp;quot;Lie down on your left side, and I&amp;rsquo;ll lay Israel&amp;rsquo;s punishment on you. You&amp;rsquo;ll bear their punishment for the number of days you lie on it. 5Lie like that one day for each of the 390 years they&amp;rsquo;ve sinned. 6When you&amp;rsquo;ve finished, lie down on your right side, and bear Judah&amp;rsquo;s sin. I&amp;rsquo;ve assigned you 40 days, one for each year. 7Then you&amp;rsquo;ll face the siege of Jerusalem with your arm bared, and prophesy against it. 8I&amp;rsquo;ve tied you up with ropes so you can&amp;rsquo;t turn from one side to the other till you&amp;rsquo;ve finished the days of your siege. 9&amp;quot;Take wheat, barley, beans, lentils, millet, and spelt; put them in one container and bake bread. Eat it for the 390 days you&amp;rsquo;re lying on your side. 10Once a day eat 8 oz 20 shekels of food 11and drink a quart ⅙ hin of water. 12Eat it like a barley cake after you&amp;rsquo;ve baked it in front of them over human feces. 13That&amp;rsquo;s how the Israelites will eat their bread unclean among the nations where I&amp;rsquo;ll banish them.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Son of man, take a sharp sword and shave off your hair and beard. Divide up the hair on a scales. 2Burn a third of it in the center of the city when the siege is over. Strike a third of it with a sword all around the city. Scatter another third of it in the wind, because I&amp;rsquo;m going to chase my people with a drawn sword. 3Attach a few to the hem of your robe. 4Throw a few in the fire. They&amp;rsquo;ll spread from the fire to the whole House of Israel.  5I&amp;rsquo;ve set Jerusalem in the center of the nations. 6It rebelled against my ordinances and statutes more than those other nations did.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, face Israel&amp;rsquo;s mountains and prophesy, 3&amp;rsquo;Listen to the Lord Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s message to the mountains and hills, ravines and valleys: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to bring a sword against you and destroy your high places. 4Your altars will be demolished and your incense altars smashed. You&amp;rsquo;ll fall slain in front of your idols, 5and I&amp;rsquo;ll scatter your bones around your altars. 6Everywhere you live, towns will be waste, high places desolate, idols broken, incense altars cut down, and the religious objects you&amp;rsquo;ve made, destroyed. 7You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh. 8&amp;quot;But I&amp;rsquo;ll leave a few of you. Some will escape the sword in the nations where you scatter. 9You&amp;rsquo;ll think back to me where they take you captive—how you&amp;rsquo;ve hurt me with your adulterous hearts and with eyes that carried on prostitution with idols. You&amp;rsquo;ll abhor yourselves for those detestable deeds. 10You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh, that I meant it when I said I&amp;rsquo;d inflict you with this disaster.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; 11&amp;quot;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;Clap your hands, stomp your feet, say, &amp;ldquo;This has happened because of Israel&amp;rsquo;s abominations. It will fall by sword, famine, and disease! 12The one that&amp;rsquo;s far off will die by the disease. The one that&amp;rsquo;s nearby will fall by the sword. The one that&amp;rsquo;s left and besieged will starve to death.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;ll vent my fury on you. 13Your slain will lie among your idols, around your altars, on every tall hill and mountaintop, under every green tree and leafy terebinth tree—where you offered a soothing aroma to your idols. 14The land will be more desolate than the desert toward Diblah. That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; The End Has Come&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, the Lord Yahveh says to Israel, &amp;lsquo;The end is coming on the four corners of your land. 3I&amp;rsquo;ll judge you by your ways, direct my anger at you, and bring your detestable things against you. 4I won&amp;rsquo;t pity or spare when I bring on you the consequences of your deeds with the detestable things you&amp;rsquo;ve used.&amp;rsquo;  5A disaster—a unique disaster—is coming! 6The end is here! It has awakened against you! 7You&amp;rsquo;re doomed, resident in the land—confusion instead of happy shouting on the mountains. [8] 9You&amp;rsquo;ll know that I Yahveh am striking you. 10&amp;quot;The rod has budded, arrogance has blossomed, 11violence has grown into a rod of sinfulness. Nothing will remain of their multitude, their wealth, or anything outstanding that they have. 12The buyer shouldn&amp;rsquo;t celebrate, the seller shouldn&amp;rsquo;t mourn, because anger is aimed at their abundance. 13The seller won&amp;rsquo;t regain what he sold as long as they&amp;rsquo;re both alive, because the vision about their affluence won&amp;rsquo;t fade away. Because of his sin, neither will live. 14&amp;quot;They&amp;rsquo;ve blown the bugle and everything&amp;rsquo;s ready, but nobody is going to battle because I&amp;rsquo;m angry with this whole population. 15The sword&amp;rsquo;s outside; famine and disease are inside. The ones out in the country will die by the sword; famine and disease will kill the ones in the city. 16Even when survivors escape, they&amp;rsquo;ll be on the mountains like pigeons from the valley, mourning over his sinfulness. 17Hands will hang limp; knees will be like water. 18They&amp;rsquo;ll put on burlap and shudder. Their faces will blush; their heads will be bald. 19They&amp;rsquo;ll toss their silver into the streets and abhor their gold. Their silver and gold won&amp;rsquo;t be able to deliver them from Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s anger. They won&amp;rsquo;t satisfy their hunger with it because that&amp;rsquo;s what made them stumble. 20The beautiful jewels they were so proud of, they used for making detestable idols; so I&amp;rsquo;ll turn their wealth into something detestable to them. 21I&amp;rsquo;ll give them to foreigners as plunder, to the sinful as spoil; and they&amp;rsquo;ll defile them. 22I&amp;rsquo;ll look the other way while invaders profane my precious land. Robbers will go in and defile it 23and make it desolate.    &#x9;Ezek 7:14-23a &amp;ldquo;The land&amp;rsquo;s filled with bloody crimes; the city&amp;rsquo;s full of violence. 24So I&amp;rsquo;ll bring the worst of the nations to take over their houses. I&amp;rsquo;ll put an end to their proud strength and profane their holy places. 25When anguish comes, they&amp;rsquo;ll look for peace, but there won&amp;rsquo;t be any, 26just disaster on top of disaster, rumor on top of rumor. They&amp;rsquo;ll find no vision from a prophet; the law will be lost from the priest and counsel from the elders. 27The king will mourn; the prince will put on rags; the people&amp;rsquo;s hands will tremble. I&amp;rsquo;ll deal with them by the way they&amp;rsquo;ve acted, judge them by their own judgments. They&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; Idolatry in the Temple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The fifth day, sixth month, sixth year, I was sitting in my house with Judah&amp;rsquo;s elders sitting in front of me, and the hand of the Lord Yahveh came down on me. 2I saw what looked like a man. From the waist down, he looked like fire; from the waist up, he looked like bright glowing metal. 3He reached out and took hold of my hair. The Spirit lifted me up between earth and sky, and took me in a vision to Jerusalem, to the entrance of the north gate of the inner court, to the seat of the idol that provokes jealousy. 4The glory of Israel&amp;rsquo;s God was there—like what I&amp;rsquo;d seen in the plain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He shouted, &amp;ldquo;Executioners, come here with your weapons.&amp;rdquo; 2Six men holding a shattering weapon, came from the direction of the upper gate, which faces north. One of them was wearing linen with a scribe&amp;rsquo;s inkhorn on his hip. They went in and stood beside the bronze altar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; The glory of God rose up from the cherub it rested on and went to the threshold of the Temple. He called out to the man with the inkhorn, 4&amp;quot;Go all over the city and mark the foreheads of people who sigh and groan over the detestable things going on here.&amp;quot; 5-6He told the others, &amp;ldquo;Follow him and kill old men, young men, girls, little children, and women. Don&amp;rsquo;t pity or spare, but don&amp;rsquo;t touch anybody with the mark. Start at my sanctuary.&amp;rdquo; So they started with the elders that were in front of the Temple. 7He told them, &amp;ldquo;Defile the Temple and fill the courts with the slain. Go!&amp;rdquo; So they went out and struck down the people in the city. 8While they were striking them down and I was by myself, I fell on my face and shouted, &amp;ldquo;Lord Yahveh! Are you going to destroy the whole remnant of Israel by pouring out your anger on Jerusalem?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then in the expanse above the cherubs, I saw something like a sapphire stone shaped like a throne. 2He spoke to the man dressed in linen, &amp;ldquo;Go between the turning wheels under the cherubs and fill your hands with coals. Scatter them over the city.&amp;rdquo; I watched him go in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; The cherubs were standing on the right side of the Temple when he went in, and a cloud filled the inner court. 4The glory of Yahveh rose up from the cherubs to the threshold of the Temple. The cloud filled the Temple, and the bright glory of Yahveh filled the court. 5The cherubs&amp;rsquo; wings could be heard all the way to the outer court—like God Almighty when he speaks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Spirit lifted me up and took me to the east gate of theY Temple. There were 25 men at the entrance of the gate, including Jaazaniah Ben-Azzur and Pelatiah Ben-Benaiah, leaders of the people. 2He told me, &amp;ldquo;Those men devise sin and give bad advice in this city. 3They say, &amp;lsquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t it time to build houses? This city is the pot and we&amp;rsquo;re the meat.&amp;rsquo; 4So prophesy against them, son of man, prophesy!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, you&amp;rsquo;re living with a rebellious people. They have eyes but don&amp;rsquo;t see, and ears but don&amp;rsquo;t hear. 3So get together baggage for exile and go into exile in the daytime so they can watch; go from one place to another. Maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll understand, though they&amp;rsquo;re a rebellious house. 4Bring your baggage out in the daytime. Then go out in the evening as if you&amp;rsquo;re going into exile. 5Make a hole in the wall so they can watch you go out through it. 6&amp;quot;Put the baggage on your shoulder and carry it out in the dark. Cover your face so you can&amp;rsquo;t see where you&amp;rsquo;re going. I&amp;rsquo;m using you as an object lesson for Israel.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, prophesy against Israel&amp;rsquo;s prophets who prophesy their own ideas, 3&amp;rsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;Misfortune awaits foolish prophets that follow their own imagination and haven&amp;rsquo;t seen anything. 4Israel, your prophets have been like foxes among ruins. 5You haven&amp;rsquo;t gone up into the breaches or built the wall around the House of Israel to stand in the battle in the day of Yahveh. 6They see falsehood and lying fortunetelling who say, &amp;lsquo;Yahveh says,&amp;rsquo; when heY hasn&amp;rsquo;t sent them. They&amp;rsquo;re just hoping their message will be what happens. 7Didn&amp;rsquo;t you see a false vision and say a lying fortunetelling when you said, &amp;lsquo;Yahveh says&amp;rsquo;? I&amp;rsquo;m not the one that spoke.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; 8&amp;quot;So because you&amp;rsquo;ve lied, 9I&amp;rsquo;m against the prophets that see false visions and say lying fortunetelling. You won&amp;rsquo;t be in the council of my people, be recorded in the registry of Israel, or go to the land of Israel. You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m the Lord Yahveh. 10That&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;ve misled my people by saying, &amp;lsquo;Peace!&amp;rsquo; when there isn&amp;rsquo;t any. When somebody builds a wall, he daubs it with whitewash. 11Tell him it will fall. A downpour will come, hailstones will fall, violent wind will blow. 12When it falls, won&amp;rsquo;t they ask you where the plaster is you daubed on it?&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then some elders of Israel came and sat down in front of me. 2A message from Yahveh came to me: 3&amp;quot;Son of man, these people have set up idols in their hearts, and put their sins in front of them to trip over. Should they consult me? 4So tell them, &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;If any Israelites or immigrants in Israel set up idols in their heart, put their sin in front of him to trip over, and then come to a prophet to inquire from me, I&amp;rsquo;ll answer them myself because of their many idols. 5I&amp;rsquo;ll do it to lay hold of the hearts in Israel that are alienated from me by their idols.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; 6&amp;rsquo;So repent and turn away from your detestable idols. [7] 8I&amp;rsquo;ll oppose you and make an example out of you and a proverb. I&amp;rsquo;ll cut you off from my people. So you&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh. 9But if the prophet is tempted to speak a message, I&amp;rsquo;m the one that tempted him, and I&amp;rsquo;ll destroy him from my people. 10The inquirer and the prophet will get the same punishment for their iniquity. 11That&amp;rsquo;s so Israel won&amp;rsquo;t stray from me anymore and defile themselves with their sins.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; Jerusalem Not Spared&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, how does the wood in a grapevine compare to the wood in a tree limb? 3Can you make anything out of grapevine wood, say, a peg to hang a bucket on? 4If it&amp;rsquo;s been put in the fire for fuel, is burned on both ends and charred in the middle, can you make anything out of it? 5If it&amp;rsquo;s intact and you can&amp;rsquo;t make it into anything, how much less when fire has burned and charred it.&amp;quot; 6So the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;Like grapevine wood that I&amp;rsquo;ve put in the fire for fuel, I&amp;rsquo;ve given up the people in Jerusalem. 7Though they&amp;rsquo;ve come out of the fire, it&amp;rsquo;s charred them. You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh when I set myself against them. 8I&amp;rsquo;ll make the country desolate because they&amp;rsquo;ve been unfaithful.&amp;rdquo; Jerusalem, an Unfaithful Wife&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, confront Jerusalem about her detestable things. 3Say, &amp;lsquo;Your birth was from the Canaanites—an Amorite father and a Hittite mother. 4When you were born, your umbilical cord wasn&amp;rsquo;t cut off, you weren&amp;rsquo;t washed, or rubbed with salt, or even wrapped in cloth. 5Nobody took pity on you to do any of those things for you. You were tossed out in an open field because you were repulsive. 6&amp;quot;When I went by and saw you squirming in your blood, I said to you, &amp;lsquo;Live!&amp;rsquo; 7I made you as numerous as plants in a field. You grew up tall and filled out. Your breasts formed and your hair grew, but you were naked and bare. 8Then I went by and saw you were at the age to be sexually active; so I spread my cloak over you and covered your nakedness. I gave you my word and made a covenant with you so you&amp;rsquo;d be mine. 9I gave you a bath, washed off your blood, and anointed you with oil. 10I dressed you with embroidered cloth, put porpoise-skin sandals on you, wrapped you in fine linen, and covered you with silk. 11I adorned you with bracelets, a necklace, 12a ring in your nostril, earrings, and a beautiful crown. 13You wore gold and silver, fine linen, silk, and embroidered cloth. You ate fine flour, honey, and oil. You were especially beautiful, and advanced to royalty. 14You became famous in every country because of your beauty. It was perfect because of the splendor I put on you. 15&amp;quot;But you trusted in your beauty and played the prostitute because you were famous. You poured out your prostitutions on every passer-by that was willing. 16You took some of your clothes and made high places of various colors, and played the prostitute on them. That shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have happened. 17You took the beautiful gold and silver jewels I gave you, and made male images so you could carry on prostitution with them. 18You took your embroidered cloth and covered them, and offered my oil and incense to them. 19The bread I gave you, the fine flour, oil, and honey I fed you, you offered in front of them for a soothing aroma. 20You took the sons and daughters you bore to me and sacrificed them to idols. Were your prostitutions a small thing? 21You slaughtered my children and offered them up to idols by making them pass through fire. 22Besides your abominations and prostitutions, you forgot your youth when you were naked, squirming in your blood. 23&amp;quot;Then after all your sinfulness (The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;Misfortune awaits you!&amp;rsquo;), 24you built a shrine and made a high place in every square. 25You built a high place at the head of every street and made your beauty detestable. You spread your legs to every passer-by to multiply your prostitution. 26You carried on prostitution with the Egyptians, your lustful neighbors, to make me angry. 27I reached out against you, diminished your rations, and delivered you to those who hate you, the young women of the Philistines, who are embarrassed by your lewd behavior. 28You carried on prostitution with the Assyrians 29and multiplied it with the merchants of Babylon. You still weren&amp;rsquo;t satisfied.&amp;quot;&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; 30&amp;quot;How lovesick your heart is,&amp;quot; the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;while you do all this brazen prostitution. 31When you built your shrine at the beginning of every street and made your high place in every square, in disdaining money, you weren&amp;rsquo;t like a prostitute—32you adulteress wife that takes strangers instead of your husband! 33Men pay prostitutes but you pay your lovers to get them to come to you. 34Nobody carries on prostitution like you do. You do the paying!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-17&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, tell Israel this parable. 3&amp;rsquo;A large eagle with big wings, long pinions, and full plumage of many colors flew to Lebanon and plucked off 4the top of a cedar tree. He took it to a land filled with merchants and planted it in a city full of tradesmen. 5He also took a seedling from the land and planted it in fertile soil, like a willow beside a stream. 6It took root and became a low, spreading vine with branches turned upward toward the eagle and roots growing down into the soil. It put out shoots and grew branches. 7&amp;rsquo;But then another large eagle came along with big wings and full plumage. Now the vine bent its roots and branches toward him so he would water it. 8It was already planted in good soil beside plenty of water so it could grow branches, bear fruit, and become a splendid vine.&amp;rsquo; 9Say, &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh asks, &amp;ldquo;Will it thrive? I&amp;rsquo;ll pull it up by the roots, cut off its fruit, and let its leaves wither. I won&amp;rsquo;t need great strength or a big army to uproot it. 10If it&amp;rsquo;s transplanted, will it thrive? It will completely wither when the east wind blows on it in the soil where it had grown so well before.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-18&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;What do you mean by the proverb about Israel, &amp;lsquo;The parents ate sour grapes, and the children&amp;rsquo;s mouths puckered&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; As I live, you&amp;rsquo;re not going to use that proverb in Israel anymore. 4Every soul belongs to me, the parent&amp;rsquo;s as well as the children&amp;rsquo;s. The soul that sins is the one that dies. 5&amp;quot;If a man practices goodness,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-19&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Sing this funeral song for Israel&amp;rsquo;s officials: 2&amp;rsquo;What was your mother? A lioness among lions! She lay down among young lions; she raised her cubs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; When she brought up one of her cubs, he became a young lion, learned to catch prey, and devoured people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Then nations heard about him. They captured him in their pit, and brought him with hooks to Egypt.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; As time went on, she saw that her hope was lost, and took another of her cubs and made him a young lion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-20&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The tenth day, fifth month, seventh year, some of Israel&amp;rsquo;s elders came to inquire from Yahveh and sat in front of me. 2A message from him came to me: 3&amp;quot;Son of man, tell Israel&amp;rsquo;s elders the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;Are you coming to inquire from me? As I live, I won&amp;rsquo;t let you.&amp;rsquo; 4&amp;quot;Are you willing to judge them, son of man? Then remind them about their ancestors&amp;rsquo; detestable deeds. 5Tell them that when I chose Israel, swore to Jacob&amp;rsquo;s descendants, and made myself known to them in Egypt,6I swore I&amp;rsquo;d take them out of Egypt to a land I&amp;rsquo;d chosen, a land flowing with milk and honey, the most beautiful of all the lands. 7I told them to throw away the detestable things their eyes feasted on and not defile themselves with Egypt&amp;rsquo;s idols. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh their God. 8But they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t discard them. &#x9; Ezek 20:1-8a &amp;ldquo;So I resolved to pour out my wrath on them in Egypt. 9I did it to keep my name from being profaned in the nations that I revealed myself to by bringing Israel out of Egypt. 10So I took them into the desert, 11and gave them my statutes and ordinances that would give people life if they kept them. 12I gave them my Sabbaths as a sign between us so they&amp;rsquo;d know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh who sanctifies them. 13But Israel rebelled. So I resolved to pour out my anger on them in the desert and wipe them out. [14] 15I swore to them there that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t bring them to the land I&amp;rsquo;d given them. [16] 17Yet I didn&amp;rsquo;t wipe them out in the desert. &#x9;Ezek 20:8b-17 18&amp;quot;I told their children in the desert, &amp;lsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t follow the statutes of your fathers, keep their ordinances, or defile yourselves with their idols. 19I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God; follow my statutes and keep my ordinances, 20sanctify my Sabbaths as a sign between us so you can know that I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh their God.&amp;rsquo; 21But the children wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do it. 22I withdrew my hand to keep my name from being profaned in the nations that saw me bring them out of Egypt. 23I swore to them in the desert that I&amp;rsquo;d scatter them among the nations 24for their rebellion. 25I let them keep statutes that weren&amp;rsquo;t good and ordinances that couldn&amp;rsquo;t give life. 26I pronounced them unclean for making their firstborn pass through fire so I could make them desolate. Judgment and Restoration 27&amp;quot;So, son of man, tell Israel the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;Your ancestors blasphemed me by acting deceitfully against me. 28When I did bring them to the land I swore to give them, they looked at every tall hill and leafy tree, and offered their sacrifices there and presented their provoking offerings. They made their soothing aroma and poured out their liquid offerings. 29Then I said to them, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;lsquo;high place&amp;rsquo; that you go to?&amp;rdquo; Its name is still Bamah.&amp;rsquo; 30So say to Israel the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;Will you defile yourselves like your ancestors did, and carry on prostitution with their detestable things? 31When you offer your gifts—making your sons pass through fire—you&amp;rsquo;re still defiling yourselves with your idols. Will you inquire from me, House of Israel? As I live, I won&amp;rsquo;t let you. 32&amp;quot;What you imagine won&amp;rsquo;t happen—as when you say you&amp;rsquo;ll be like the nations and tribes in the lands and serve wood and stone.&amp;rsquo; 33&amp;quot;As I live, I&amp;rsquo;ll rule you with a strong hand, outstretched arm, and anger poured out. 34From the lands where you&amp;rsquo;re scattered, 35I&amp;rsquo;ll take you to the wilderness of the nations and judge you directly 36like I judged your ancestors in the desert in Egypt. 37I&amp;rsquo;ll make you pass evaluation and bring you into the covenant. 38I&amp;rsquo;ll purge from you the rebels that sin against me. I&amp;rsquo;ll bring you out of the land where you&amp;rsquo;re living temporarily, but you won&amp;rsquo;t enter Israel. So you&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh. 39&amp;quot;Go on and serve your idols, Israel; later you&amp;rsquo;ll listen. You won&amp;rsquo;t profane my holy name anymore with your idols and offerings. 40-41&amp;quot;On my holy hill, Israel&amp;rsquo;s high mountain, the whole House of Israel will serve me. Like a soothing aroma, I&amp;rsquo;ll accept you there and seek your contributions and choice gifts with your holy things. I&amp;rsquo;ll prove myself holy among you for the nations to see 42when I bring you to the land I swore to give your ancestors. 43You&amp;rsquo;ll think back there to the ways you defiled yourselves, and you&amp;rsquo;ll despise yourselves for the sins you&amp;rsquo;ve committed. 44You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh when I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with you to maintain my reputation more than to punish your sins.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; Judgment Against the Negev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-21&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, face Jerusalem. Speak against its sanctuaries and prophesy against Israel, 3&amp;rsquo;Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll draw my sword and slay the good and the bad in you, 4everybody from south to north. 5Everyone will know I&amp;rsquo;ve drawn it, and it won&amp;rsquo;t go back into its sheath.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; 6&amp;quot;Son of man, moan with breaking heart and bitter grief. 7When they ask why you&amp;rsquo;re moaning, say, &amp;lsquo;Over the news that&amp;rsquo;s coming. Hearts will melt, hands will go limp, spirits will faint, knees will be as weak as water.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-22&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, are you willing to judge the bloody city? Then tell it about its abominations. 3Say, &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;A city that sheds blood in it, a city whose time will come, a city that makes idols to defile itself! 4-5You&amp;rsquo;ve become guilty by shedding blood and defiled by making idols. You&amp;rsquo;ve brought your appointed time near, you infamous one full of turmoil; I&amp;rsquo;ve made you a disgrace to nations near and far, something to ridicule. 6&amp;quot;Every ruler in Israel is intent on shedding blood, each according to his power. 7They treat parents with contempt, oppress foreigners, wrong the fatherless and widows. 8They despise my holy things and profane my Sabbaths. 9Slanderous men accuse falsely to get the death penalty, eat at the mountain shrine, commit lewd acts. 10They uncover their father&amp;rsquo;s nakedness and rape women that are in their period. 11One commit detestable acts with his neighbor&amp;rsquo;s wife, another defiles his daughter-in-law, another rapes his sister. 12You do murder for hire, charge interest, oppress other people for gain, and forget me.&amp;rdquo; 13&amp;quot;I slap my hand at your bloodshed and crooked gain. 14Will you have the courage and strength to deal with me when I do what I&amp;rsquo;ve said? 15I&amp;rsquo;ll scatter you across the nations and burn off your uncleanness. 16You&amp;rsquo;ll profane yourself in the sight of the nations. You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;quot;&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-23&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 23&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, there were two women, daughters of the same mother. 3They carried on prostitution in Egypt when they were young. Their breasts were pressed there and their virgin bosom was handled. 4Their names were Oholah the older and Oholibah her sister. They became mine and had children. Samaria is Oholah; Jerusalem is Oholibah. 5&amp;quot;Oholah played the prostitute while she belonged to me, and doted on her lovers, the Assyrians, her neighbors, 6who dressed in purple, governors and officials, all of them desirable young men, horsemen riding on their horses. 7She bestowed her prostitution on them, choice men of Assyria. She defiled herself with their idols. 8She didn&amp;rsquo;t abandon her prostitution from the time she was in Egypt. When she was young, men had lain with her, and handled her virgin bosom and poured out their lust on her. 9So I gave her to her lovers, the Assyrians. 10They uncovered her nakedness; they took her children but killed her with a sword. So she became a byword among women, and they carried out judgments on her. 11&amp;quot;Her sister Oholibah saw that and became even more corrupt in doting on her lovers. Her prostitution was worse than her sister&amp;rsquo;s. 12She doted on the Assyrians, nearby governors and officials, magnificently attired, horsemen riding horses, all desirable young men. 13I saw that she&amp;rsquo;d defiled herself; they both had followed the same path. 14So she increased her prostitution. She saw men painted on the wall, images of Babylonians painted with vermilion, 15wearing waistbands, with flowing turbans on their heads, all looking like officers, like Babylonians in Babylonia, the land where they were born. 16When she saw them, she doted on them and sent messengers to them in Babylonia. 17The Babylonians came to her bed of lust and defiled her with their prostitution. When they&amp;rsquo;d defiled her, she became disgusted with them. 18She uncovered her prostitution and her nakedness. Then I became disgusted with her like I had with her sister. 19She still increased her prostitution and remembered her youth when she carried on prostitution in Egypt. 20She doted on her paramours, whose members are like donkeys&amp;rsquo; and whose issue is like horses&amp;rsquo;. 21So she longed for the lewdness of her youth when the Egyptians handled her young breasts. God&amp;rsquo;s Judgment on Oholibah 22&amp;quot;So, Oholibah, the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll arouse your lovers against you—the ones you&amp;rsquo;re alienated from&amp;ndash;and bring them against you from every direction: 23the Babylonians and all the Chaldeans; Pekod, Shoa, Koa, and the Assyrians, desirable young men, governors and officials all, officers and soldiers every one, riding horses. 24They&amp;rsquo;ll attack you with weapons, chariots, and wagons, and an army of soldiers arrayed against you on every side with buckler, shield, and helmet. I&amp;rsquo;ll let them judge you by their customs, 25and direct my jealousy against you in anger. They&amp;rsquo;ll cut off your nose and ears, and any survivors will fall by the sword. They&amp;rsquo;ll capture your children and burn your survivors. 26They&amp;rsquo;ll strip off your clothes and take your beautiful jewels. 27That&amp;rsquo;s how I&amp;rsquo;ll stop your lewdness and prostitution with Egypt so you won&amp;rsquo;t look up to it or remember it anymore. 28I&amp;rsquo;ll turn you over to the ones you despise, people you&amp;rsquo;re alienated from. 29They&amp;rsquo;ll deal with you in hate, take your property, and leave you naked. 30Your lewdness and prostitution will be exposed. 31You&amp;rsquo;ve followed your sister&amp;rsquo;s ways; so I&amp;rsquo;ll give you her cup to drink.&amp;rsquo; 32&amp;quot;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll drink your sister&amp;rsquo;s cup, which is deep and wide. You&amp;rsquo;ll be laughed at and ridiculed, because it holds a lot.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-24&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 24&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The tenth day, tenth month, ninth year, a message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, write down the date. The king of Babylon laid siege to Jerusalem today. 3Tell the rebellious people a parable, &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;Put a pot on and pour water in it;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; put good pieces in it, thigh and shoulder; fill it with choice bones.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Take the best of the flock, and put wood under the pot. Boil it hard; seethe its bones with the meat.&amp;rdquo; 6&amp;rsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;Misfortune awaits the bloody city; it awaits the rusty pot! Take out piece after piece without choosing which ones.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-25&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 25&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Face the Ammonites and prophesy against them, 3&amp;rsquo;Because you said, &amp;ldquo;Ha!&amp;rdquo; at my sanctuary when it was profaned, and at Israel when it became a wasteland, and at Judah when they went into exile, 4I&amp;rsquo;m going to turn you over to the people from the east. They&amp;rsquo;ll set up their camps among you and live there, eat your fruit and drink your milk. 5I&amp;rsquo;ll make Rabbah into a pasture for camels and the Ammonites a resting place for flocks. 6Because you clapped your hands and stamped your feet and celebrated with scorn at Israel, 7I&amp;rsquo;ll give you to the nations for spoil, cut you off from the peoples, and make you perish from the land so you&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;rsquo; A Message for Moab 8&amp;quot;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;Because Moab and Seir consider Judah like any other nation, 9I&amp;rsquo;m going to take away from Moab its frontier towns, the pride of its land: Beth-jeshimoth, Baal-meon, and Kiriathaim. 10I&amp;rsquo;ll give it and the Ammonites to the people from the east and the Ammonites will pass from memory. 11I&amp;rsquo;ll carry out judgments on Moab. They&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; 12&amp;quot;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;Edom has taken revenge on Judah and incurred grievous guilt, 13so I&amp;rsquo;ll slay its people and animals and lay it waste. They&amp;rsquo;ll fall by the sword from Teman to Dedan. 14I&amp;rsquo;ll take revenge on Edom by my people Israel. They&amp;rsquo;ll act in Edom according to my anger; so they&amp;rsquo;ll know my payback.&amp;rsquo; 15&amp;quot;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;The Philistines have acted in scornful revenge to destroy with everlasting enmity. 16So I&amp;rsquo;ll slay the Cherethites and destroy the remnant along the coast. 17I&amp;rsquo;ll carry out severe vengeance with angry rebukes. They&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; A Message for Tyre&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-26&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 26&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The first day of the month, eleventh year, a message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, Tyre has said about Jerusalem, &amp;lsquo;Ha! its gate&amp;rsquo;s broken; it has swung open to me. I&amp;rsquo;ll be filled now that it&amp;rsquo;s laid waste.&amp;rsquo; 3But the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll bring nations against you, Tyre, like waves in the sea. 4They&amp;rsquo;ll destroy your walls and tear down your towers. I&amp;rsquo;ll scrape away the rubble and make you a bare rock, 5a place for spreading nets by the sea. I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken: you&amp;rsquo;ll become spoil for the nations, 6and your inhabitants on the mainland will die by the sword. You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; 7&amp;quot;From the north I&amp;rsquo;ll bring Nebuchadnezzar, king of Babylon, king of kings, with horses, chariots, cavalry, and an enormous army. 8He&amp;rsquo;ll slay your inhabitants on the mainland with the sword, build siege walls, put up a mound and a roof of shields against you. 9He&amp;rsquo;ll aim his battering rams at your walls and tear down your towers with his axes. 10The huge number of his horses will cover you with dust; your walls will shake from his cavalry, wagons, and chariots when they pour through your gates like men overwhelming a breached city. 11He&amp;rsquo;ll trample your streets with his horses and slay your people with the sword. He&amp;rsquo;ll tear down your strong pillars, 12make spoil out of your wealth, and plunder out of your merchandise. He&amp;rsquo;ll tear down your walls, destroy your pleasant houses, and throw your stones, timber, and rubble into the sea. 13So I&amp;rsquo;ll silence your songs and harps. 14You&amp;rsquo;ll be a bare rock, a place to spread nets. You won&amp;rsquo;t rebuild; I&amp;rsquo;ve said so.&amp;quot; 15&amp;quot;The Lord Yahveh says to Tyre, &amp;lsquo;Won&amp;rsquo;t the whole coastline quake at the sound of your fall when the wounded groan and the slaughter is taking place in you? 16Then the rulers of the sea will step down from their thrones, remove their robes, strip off their embroidered clothes, and dress themselves with trembling. They&amp;rsquo;ll sit on the ground, shaking every moment, appalled at you. 17They&amp;rsquo;ll take up a lamentation over you, &amp;ldquo;How you&amp;rsquo;ve disappeared from the seas, renowned city. You and your residents were powerful seafarers. You imposed fear on people everywhere!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 27</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-27&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 27&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, take up a lamentation over Tyre 3that sits at the port to the sea, the nations&amp;rsquo; merchant to many ports, The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;Tyre, you&amp;rsquo;ve said &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m perfectly beautiful.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Your borders extend into the heart of the sea; your builders have perfected your beauty.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; They&amp;rsquo;ve made your planks out of fir trees from Seir; they&amp;rsquo;ve taken a cedar from Lebanon to make a mast for you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 28</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-28&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 28&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me again: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, tell the leader of Tyre; &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re arrogant; you&amp;rsquo;ve said, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a god; I sit in God&amp;rsquo;s seat in the heart of the sea.&amp;rsquo; But you&amp;rsquo;re a mortal, not God, though you exalt yourself as if you were God. (3You think you&amp;rsquo;re wiser than Daniel, that no secret is a match for you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 29</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-29&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 29&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The twelfth day, tenth month, tenth year, a message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, turn toward Pharaoh, Egypt&amp;rsquo;s king, and prophesy against him and Egypt. 3&amp;rsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m against you, Pharaoh Egypt&amp;rsquo;s king, the big crocodile that lies in your streams, that has said, &amp;lsquo;My Nile belongs to me; I made it.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ll put hooks in your jaws, and make the fish in your streams stick to your scales. I&amp;rsquo;ll drag you out on your shore with fish clinging to your scales.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 30</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-30&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 30&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me again: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, prophesy, &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;Wail, &amp;lsquo;Oh for the day!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; The day of Yahveh is near, a cloudy day of doom for the nations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; A sword will come at Egypt; there&amp;rsquo;ll be anguish in Nubia when the slain fall in Egypt. They&amp;rsquo;ll carry away its wealth and tear up its foundations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Nubia, Put, Lud, Arabia, Libya, and the people of any land allied with them will fall by the sword with them. 6&amp;rsquo;Yahveh says: &amp;ldquo;Those who support Egypt will fall; its proud power will collapse. From Migdol to Syene they&amp;rsquo;ll fall by the sword.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 31</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-31&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 31&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The first day, third month, eleventh year, a message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, tell Pharaoh and his large host, &amp;lsquo;Who is as great as you?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Assyria was a cedar in Lebanon with beautiful branches and forest shade and its top in the clouds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; The water made it grow, the underground water made it tall; rivers continually flowed where it was planted; it sent out its channels to all the trees.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 32</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-32&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 32&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The first day, twelfth month, twelfth year, a message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, raise a lamentation over Pharaoh, Egypt&amp;rsquo;s king. Tell him, &amp;lsquo;You consider yourself a young lion among the nations, but you&amp;rsquo;re like a sea monster in the ocean. You splash around in your rivers, stir up the water with your feet, and muddy the rivers.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll cast my net over you along with a host of nations; they&amp;rsquo;ll haul you up from the water.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 33</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-33&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 33&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Tell your people, &amp;lsquo;If I bring the sword on a country, and the people&amp;rsquo;s watchman 3blows the ram&amp;rsquo;s horn to warn them—4then those who don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention are responsible for their own death. 5If they&amp;rsquo;d taken warning, they would&amp;rsquo;ve saved their life. 6If the watchman sees the sword coming and doesn&amp;rsquo;t warn the people, if the sword takes some people, they&amp;rsquo;ll be taken away in their sin, but I&amp;rsquo;ll hold the watchman responsible for it.&amp;rsquo; 7&amp;quot;Son of man, I&amp;rsquo;ve made you a watchman for Israel so you&amp;rsquo;ll hear a message from me to warn them. 8When I tell sinful people they&amp;rsquo;re going to die, but you don&amp;rsquo;t warn them, they&amp;rsquo;ll die in their sin, but I&amp;rsquo;ll hold you responsible for it.  9But if you warn them and they don&amp;rsquo;t turn from your way, they&amp;rsquo;ll die in their sin, but you&amp;rsquo;ve saved your life. 10&amp;quot;Now, son of man, tell Israel, &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve said, &amp;ldquo;Our sins are on us and we&amp;rsquo;re rotting away in them. How can we survive?&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; 11Tell them, &amp;lsquo;As I live,&amp;rsquo; the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t get any satisfaction out of seeing sinful people die. I want them to turn from their way and live. Turn back from your sinful way! Why die, Israel?&amp;rsquo; 12Son of man, tell your fellow citizens, &amp;lsquo;People&amp;rsquo;s goodness won&amp;rsquo;t deliver them when they sin. People&amp;rsquo;s sinfulness won&amp;rsquo;t prevent them from living when they quit doing it. Good people can&amp;rsquo;t have life from goodness when they practice sin. 13When I say to a good man he&amp;rsquo;ll surely live and he presumes on his goodness and starts sinning, I won&amp;rsquo;t consider his good deeds; he&amp;rsquo;ll die in that sin. 14But when I say to a sinful man, &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll surely die,&amp;rsquo; and he quits sinning—15if he returns a pledge, repays what he stole, follows the statutes that give life and doesn&amp;rsquo;t sin—he&amp;rsquo;ll surely live. 16I won&amp;rsquo;t hold his past sins against him. He is doing good; he&amp;rsquo;ll live. 17&amp;quot;Yet your people say, &amp;lsquo;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s way is not right,&amp;rsquo; when it&amp;rsquo;s their own way that&amp;rsquo;s not right. 18When a good man turns from his goodness, he&amp;rsquo;ll die because he practices sin. 19When a wicked man turns from his wickedness, he&amp;rsquo;ll live because he&amp;rsquo;s practicing goodness. 20Yet you say, &amp;lsquo;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s way is not right.&amp;rsquo; House of Israel, I&amp;rsquo;ll judge each of you by your own ways.&amp;quot; Israel&amp;rsquo;s Fall Explained&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 34</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-34&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 34&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, prophesy against Israel&amp;rsquo;s shepherds. &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;Misfortune awaits you, shepherds that feed yourselves! Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t shepherds feed the flock? 3You eat the healthy and dress with their wool. You slaughter the healthy sheep without feeding the flock. 4You don&amp;rsquo;t strengthen the sickly, heal the diseased, bandage up the crippled, bring back the scattered, or look for the lost. With force and severity, you bully them. 5They&amp;rsquo;re scattered all over the world because they didn&amp;rsquo;t have a shepherd; they became prey for wild animals. 6My flock wandered around in the mountains and tall hills; nobody looked for them. 7&amp;rsquo;So, shepherds, listen to Yahveh, [8-9] 10&amp;quot;Give me my sheep. You&amp;rsquo;re fired. I&amp;rsquo;ll protect my flock so you can&amp;rsquo;t eat them anymore.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 35</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-35&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 35&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from the Lord came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, face Mount Seir and prophesy against it, 3&amp;rsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m against you, Mount Seir; I&amp;rsquo;ll make you a wasteland.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ll lay your towns waste, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be desolate. You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; In your endless enmity, you delivered Israel to the sword at the time of its catastrophe, its final punishment. 6So as I live, I&amp;rsquo;ll deliver you to bloodshed. Since you haven&amp;rsquo;t despised bloodshed, it&amp;rsquo;ll pursue you. 7I&amp;rsquo;ll make Mount Seir a waste and slay everyone that tries to escape or return there. 8I&amp;rsquo;ll fill its mountains with the dead. They&amp;rsquo;ll fall in its hills, valleys, and ravines. 9I&amp;rsquo;ll make it a permanent wasteland and its towns uninhabited. It will know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh. 10&amp;quot;Mount Seir has said, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to take over those two lands and make them mine&amp;rsquo;—though Yahveh was there. 11So as I live,&amp;rdquo; the Lord Yahveh says. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll deal with you in proportion to the anger, envy, and hate you&amp;rsquo;ve shown them. I&amp;rsquo;ll make myself known among them when I condemn you. 12You&amp;rsquo;ll know that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard your contempt for the mountain in Israel, &amp;lsquo;They&amp;rsquo;re desolate; they&amp;rsquo;ve been given to us to devour.&amp;rsquo; 13I&amp;rsquo;ve heard you speak arrogantly against me over and over. 14While the whole world celebrates, I&amp;rsquo;ll make you desolate. 15As you celebrated Israel&amp;rsquo;s desolation, you&amp;rsquo;ll be desolate, Mount Seir and all Edom. You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; Prophecy to the Mountains of Israel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 36</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-36&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 36&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Son of man, prophesy to the mountains of Israel, &amp;lsquo;Listen to 2what the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;Your enemy has ridiculed you, &amp;lsquo;Ha!&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;The everlasting mountains are ours now!&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; 3So prophesy, &amp;lsquo;For good reason other nations made you desolate and crushed you from every direction, took possession of you, and mocked and whispered.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; 4&amp;rsquo;So, mountains of Israel, listen to the message from the Lord Yahveh to the mountains and hills, ravines and valleys, desolate wastes and abandoned towns that have become prey and objects of derision. 5&amp;quot;In my burning jealousy, I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken against those nations, particularly Edom that took over my land with wholehearted joy and scornful attitude. I&amp;rsquo;ve sworn to drive it out to become prey. 6So prophesy to Israel&amp;rsquo;s mountains and hills, ravines and valleys, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken in my anger because you&amp;rsquo;ve had to endure insults from other nations. 7I swear they will endure insults.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; 8&amp;quot;But you, mountains of Israel, will grow branches and bear fruit for my people, because they&amp;rsquo;ll be coming back soon. 9I&amp;rsquo;ll return to you, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be cultivated and planted. 10People will multiple in Israel to live in the towns and rebuild the places in ruins. 11People and animals will reproduce in you. I&amp;rsquo;ll make you lived-in like before and treat you better than at first. So you&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh. 12My people will carry on their lives in you and own you. You&amp;rsquo;ll become their inheritance and never again bereave them of children.&amp;quot; 13The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;Other nations tell you, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve devoured your people and bereaved them of children,&amp;rdquo; 14but you won&amp;rsquo;t do that anymore. 15I won&amp;rsquo;t let you listen to their insults anymore. You won&amp;rsquo;t make your nation stumble anymore.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 37</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-37/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-37&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 37&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s hand was on me. He took me out in spirit and put me down in a valley full of dry bones, 2and had me walk around among them. 3&amp;quot;Son of man, can these bones come alive?&amp;quot; &amp;ldquo;Lord Yahveh, you know.&amp;rdquo; 4&amp;quot;Prophesy over them, &amp;lsquo;Dry bones, listen to Yahveh. 5I&amp;rsquo;ll put breath in you so you can come to life. 6I&amp;rsquo;ll put sinews on you, make flesh grow back, and cover you with skin. You&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 38</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-38/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-38&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 38&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A message from Yahveh came to me: 2&amp;quot;Son of man, face Gog of the land of Magog, the prince that rules Meshech and Tubal, and prophesy against him, 3&amp;rsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m against you, Gog. 4I&amp;rsquo;ll turn you around, put hooks in your jaws, and take you out—you, your army, horses and horsemen, all splendidly attired, a large army with buckler and shield, wielding swords; 5Persia, Nubia, and Put with them, all with shield and helmet; 6Gomer with all its troops; Beth-togarmah from the remote parts of the north with all its troops—many nations with you. 7&amp;quot;Be prepared, you and the armies allied with you as their commander. 8After a long time you&amp;rsquo;ll be drawn to a land restored from the sword, whose residents live safely. They will have gathered from many nations to the mountains in Israel, which had been a continual waste. 9You and your troops will come down on them like a storm, like a cloud over the land.&amp;rdquo; 10&amp;rsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;At that time, you&amp;rsquo;ll start plotting, 11&amp;rsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to go up against a land with unwalled villages, against people at rest, that live safely, that don&amp;rsquo;t have walls, bars, and gates. 12I&amp;rsquo;ll capture spoil, seize plunder, and attack waste places that are lived in now and people that gathered from the nations, who have acquired livestock and goods, and think the world revolves around them.&amp;rsquo; 13But Sheba, Dedan, the merchants of Tarshish and its surrounding villages, will ask you, &amp;lsquo;Do you think the army you&amp;rsquo;ve gathered can capture lots of spoil, seize plunder and goods, carry off silver and gold, and drive away livestock?&amp;rsquo; 14&amp;quot;So, son of man, prophesy against Gog that the Lord Yahveh says, &amp;lsquo;When my people are living securely, you&amp;rsquo;ll know it, won&amp;rsquo;t you? 15You&amp;rsquo;ll come from the far north, riding horses, a great army 16swooping down like a cloud over the land. In the last days, Gog, I&amp;rsquo;ll bring you against my land so the nations can see my holiness displayed by what happens to you.&amp;rsquo; 17&amp;rsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;Aren&amp;rsquo;t you the one I spoke about in former times through my prophets in Israel? They predicted for many years that I&amp;rsquo;d bring you against them. 18&amp;rsquo;When Gog comes against Israel, my fury will flare.&amp;rsquo; 19In my zeal and blazing anger, there will be a violent earthquake in Israel. 20Fish in the sea, buzzards in the sky, scavengers in the open country, things crawling on the ground, and everybody in the world will shudder at my presence. Mountains will crumble, cliffs will collapse, walls will crash to the ground. 21I&amp;rsquo;ll call for a sword against Gog on all my mountains. His swordsmen will turn against each other. 22With disease and blood I&amp;rsquo;ll render judgment on him: rain on him, his troops, and many allies, a torrential rain with hailstones, fire, and sulfur. 23I&amp;rsquo;ll show my greatness, sanctify myself, make myself known where many nations can see me. They&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 39</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-39/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-39&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 39&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Son of man, prophesy against Gog, &amp;lsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m against you, ruler of Meshech, and Tubal. 2I&amp;rsquo;ll turn you around, drive you on, take you up from the most remote parts in the north, and bring you against Israel. 3I&amp;rsquo;ll knock the bow out of your left hand, and the arrows out of your right hand. 4-5You and your troops will fall on the mountains in Israel. I&amp;rsquo;ll feed you to every vulture and wild animal in the open country. I&amp;rsquo;ve said so.  6I&amp;rsquo;ll rain down fire on Magog and those who live securely in distant lands. They&amp;rsquo;ll know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;rsquo; 7&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;ll make my holy name known among my people; I won&amp;rsquo;t let it be profaned anymore. The nations will know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh, the Holy One in Israel. 8The day I&amp;rsquo;m talking about is coming; it will happen.&amp;rsquo; 9&amp;quot;For seven years, the people in the towns of Israel will go out and build fires with the weapons, shields and bucklers, bows and arrows, war clubs and spears. 10They won&amp;rsquo;t get wood from the pasture or gather firewood from the woods; they&amp;rsquo;ll build fires out of weapons and plunder the ones that plundered them,&amp;rdquo; &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;the Lord Yahveh says. 11&amp;quot;When I give Gog a burial ground in Israel—in the valley east of the Dead Sea, it will block travelers. They&amp;rsquo;ll bury Gog with all his army there and call it the Valley of Hamon-Gog. 12It will take Israel seven months of burying to clean up the land. 13The common people will do the burying to their renown when I glory myself,&amp;quot; the Lord Yahveh says. 14&amp;quot;They&amp;rsquo;ll appoint men to go through the land and bury the ones left on the ground. 15When they see a human bone, they&amp;rsquo;ll put a marker by it till those who do the burying put it in the Valley of Hamon-Gog. 16The city&amp;rsquo;s name will be Hamonah [Horde]. So they&amp;rsquo;ll clean up the land.&amp;quot; 17&amp;quot;Son of man, tell every bird and wild animal, &amp;lsquo;Gather to the great sacrifice I&amp;rsquo;m going to make for you on the mountains in Israel so you can eat flesh and drink blood. 18You&amp;rsquo;ll eat the flesh of powerful men and drink the blood of princes as if they were rams, lambs, goats, and bulls—grain-fed animals from Bashan. 19You&amp;rsquo;ll eat till you&amp;rsquo;re gorged, and drink blood till you&amp;rsquo;re drunk from the sacrifice I&amp;rsquo;ll make for you. 20At my table you&amp;rsquo;ll gorge on horses, charioteers, and mighty warriors,&amp;quot; &#x9;the Lord Yahveh says. 21&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;ll establish my honor among the nations. They&amp;rsquo;ll see the judgment I&amp;rsquo;ve carried out on them. 22Israel will know I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh their God from then on. 23The nations will know Israel went into exile for their sin, and I hid from them. I abandoned them to their enemies, and they fell by the sword. [24]&amp;quot;&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 40</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-40/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-40&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 40&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At the beginning of the twenty-fifth year of our exile, the tenth month, fourteenth year after the city fell, Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s hand weighed heavy on me. 2In visions he took me to Israel and set me on a tall mountain. On it to the south was a structure like a city. 3He took me over there. Standing in the gate was a bronze-looking man with a flax line and a measuring rod in his hand. 4He told me, &amp;ldquo;Son of man, look, listen, pay attention to everything I show you. That&amp;rsquo;s why Yahveh brought you here. Tell Israel everything you see.&amp;rdquo; The East Gate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 41</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-41/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-41&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 41&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then he took me to the nave and measured the side pillars. Each pillar was 10&amp;rsquo; 4&amp;quot; 6 cubits square. 2The entrance was 17&amp;rsquo; 3&amp;quot; 10 cubits wide; the sides of the entrance were 8&amp;rsquo; 7&amp;quot; 3 cubits on each side. He measured the length and width of the nave at 69&amp;rsquo; x 34&amp;rsquo; 6&amp;quot; 40 x 20 cubits. 3He went inside and measured each side pillar of the doorway at 3&amp;rsquo; 5&amp;quot; 2 cubits, and the doorway at 6&amp;rsquo; 10&amp;quot; high and 12&amp;rsquo; 1&amp;quot; wide 6h x 7w cubits. 4He measured the front of the nave at 34&amp;rsquo; 6&amp;quot; 20 cubits square He told me, &amp;ldquo;This is the Holy Place.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 42</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-42/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-42&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 42&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then he took me north to the outer court, to the rooms across from the Temple yard and the north building. 2The length of the building on the north side was 172&amp;rsquo; 5&amp;quot; x 86&amp;rsquo; 3&amp;quot; 50 x 100 cubits. 3Beside the 34&amp;rsquo; 6&amp;quot; 20 cubits that belonged to the inner court and facing the pavement of the outer court, there was a three-story gallery. 4In front of its rooms was an inner walkway 17&amp;rsquo; 3&amp;quot; wide x 172&amp;rsquo; 5&amp;quot; long 10 x 100lcubits with doorways on the north. 5The upper rooms were narrower, because the galleries took more space away from them than from the lower and middle floors of the building. 6The rooms had three stories and didn&amp;rsquo;t have any pillars like the pillars in the courts. So the upper rooms were set back more than the lower two levels. 7The outer wall beside the rooms toward the court was 86&amp;rsquo; 3&amp;quot; 50 cubits long. 8The rooms in the outer court were 86&amp;rsquo; 3&amp;quot; 50 cubits long. The rooms facing the Temple were 172&amp;rsquo; 5&amp;quot; 100 cubits long. 9Below those rooms, was the east entrance as you enter them from the outer court, where the outside wall begins.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 43</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-43/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-43&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 43&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then he led me to the east gate, 2and the glory of Israel&amp;rsquo;s God was shining through it. His voice sounded like crashing water, and the earth radiated with his glory. 3The vision I saw was like the one when he came to destroy the city, like the one by the Chebar River. I fell on my face. 4The glory of Yahveh came into the Temple through the east gate. 5The Spirit lifted me up and took me to the inner court, and the glory of Yahveh filled the Temple.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 44</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-44&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 44&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then he brought me back through the outer gate of the sanctuary, which faces east; it was shut. 2Yahveh told me, &amp;ldquo;Keep this gate shut. Nobody is to go in through it because I&amp;rsquo;veY gone in through it. 3The prince will sit in it to eat bread in myY presence. He&amp;rsquo;ll go in by the vestibule of the gate and go out the same way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Then he brought me through the north gate to the front of the Temple. I looked and watched the glory of Yahveh fill the Temple; I fell on my face. 5Yahveh said, &amp;ldquo;Son of man, mark well, see with your eyes and hear with your ears everything I tell you about the statutes and laws of Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s Temple. Mark well the ones who can and can&amp;rsquo;t be admitted to the sanctuary. 6Tell the rebellious people in Israel, &amp;lsquo;Enough of your abominations! 7Enough bringing foreigners—uncircumcised in heart and flesh—into my sanctuary to profane my Temple, when you offered me my food, the fat and blood. You made my covenant void—besides all your abominations. 8You&amp;rsquo;ve not taken care of my holy things yourselves; you&amp;rsquo;ve set foreigners to take care of my sanctuary.&amp;rdquo; 9&amp;quot;No foreigner living among the Israelites—uncircumcised in heart and flesh—can enter my sanctuary. 10The Levites that left me when Israel went astray after their idols will be punished. 11Yet they will minister in my sanctuary and oversee the gates to the Temple: they&amp;rsquo;ll slaughter the burnt offering and the sacrifice for the people, and minister to them. 12Because they ministered to them in front of their idols and Israel stumbled over them, I&amp;rsquo;ve sworn that they&amp;rsquo;ll be punished: 13they won&amp;rsquo;t come near to serve as priests to me or approach any of my things most holy; they&amp;rsquo;ll bear their disgrace and the abominations they&amp;rsquo;ve committed. 14Yet I&amp;rsquo;ll give them responsibility for the Temple, its service, and everything done in it. 15&amp;quot;But the Levitical priests, the descendants of Zadok, who kept charge of my sanctuary when Israel left me, will come near to minister to me. They&amp;rsquo;ll serve me to offer the fat and blood. 16They&amp;rsquo;ll go into my sanctuary; they&amp;rsquo;ll come near to my table to minister to me and keep my charge. 17When they go in at the gates of the inner court, they&amp;rsquo;ll wear linen vestments, not wool, while they&amp;rsquo;re ministering at the gates of the inner court and in the Temple. 18They&amp;rsquo;ll wear linen turbans and underclothes around their waist, nothing that will make them sweat. 19When they go to the people in the outer court, they&amp;rsquo;ll take off those vestments, lay them in the holy rooms, and put on other clothes so they won&amp;rsquo;t transmit holiness to the people. 20They&amp;rsquo;re not to shave their heads or let their hair grow long; they&amp;rsquo;ll trim it. 21They are not to drink wine when they go into the inner court.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 45</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-45/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-45&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 45&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When you divide the land by lot for inheritance, allot to Yahveh, a holy district 8.2 x 3¼ miles 25,000 x 10,000 cubits; it will be holy throughout. 2Inside it will be a holy place 861&amp;rsquo; 500 cubits square with 86&amp;rsquo; 3&amp;quot; 50 cubits open all the way around it. 3Inside the district, set aside a section 8.2 x 3¼ miles 25,000 x 10,000 cubits for the sanctuary, the most holy place, 4the holy portion of the land. It will be for the priests, the ministers of the sanctuary who come near to minister to Yahveh, a place for their houses and a holy place for the sanctuary. 5Another section 8.2 x 3¼ miles 25,000 x 10,000 cubits will be for the Levites, the ministers of the Temple, and as their possession for towns to live in. 6Alongside the section designated as the holy district, assign for the possession of the city an area 1.63 x 8.2 miles 5,000 x 25,000 cubits. It will be for the whole House of Israel. 7&amp;quot;The prince will have land on both sides, alongside the holy district and the property for the city, on the west side and on the east side. Its length will correspond to one of the tribal portions and extend from the east to the west boundary of the land. 8He&amp;rsquo;ll own it so my officials won&amp;rsquo;t any longer oppress my people, but they&amp;rsquo;ll give the rest of the land to the tribes of Israel. Warnings for the Princes 9&amp;quot;Stop it, officials of Israel! Stop evicting my people!  Stop violence and destruction. Practice justice and goodness. 10&amp;quot;Use accurate balances, ephahs, and baths. 11An ephah and a bath will be the same amount: .1 homer (4½ pecks/1.1 bushels). 12A shekel will equal 20 gerahs; 60 shekels will equal 1 mina. Offerings and Festivals 13&amp;quot;This is the offering you&amp;rsquo;re to provide: .18 bushel ⅙ ephah from 11 bushels 1 homer of wheat, .18 bushel ⅙ ephah from 11 bushels 1 homer of barley; 14and the prescribed portion of oil (that is, bath  of oil), .9 gallon  .1 bath from each 90 gallons 1 cor (which is 10 baths, or a homer, because 10 baths equal 1 homer); 15and one sheep from each flock of 200 from the watering places of Israel—for a grain offering, a burnt offering, and a peace offering, to make atonement for them,&amp;quot; the Lord Yahveh says. 16&amp;quot;All the general populace will give this offering for the prince. 17He will provide the burnt offerings, grain offerings, and liquid offerings for the festivals, new moons, and Sabbaths—at the stated festivals. He&amp;rsquo;ll provide the sin offering, grain offering, burnt offering, and peace offering, to atone for Israel. 18&amp;quot;On the first day of the first month. take a young bull without blemish and purify the sanctuary. 19The priests will take blood from the sin offering and put it on the door posts of the Temple, on the four corners of the ledge of the altar, and on the posts of the gate of the inner court. 20He&amp;rsquo;s to do that on the seventh of the month for everybody that goes astray or sins in ignorance to make atonement for the Temple. 21&amp;quot;On the fourteenth day of the first month, observe the Passover festival for a week; eat bread without yeast. 22On that day the prince will provide a bull for a sin offering for himself and the people. 23Each day of the festival he&amp;rsquo;ll provide a burnt offering to Yahveh: 7 bulls and 7 rams without blemish, and 1 male goat for a sin offering. 24He&amp;rsquo;ll provide a grain offering: 4½ pecks 1 ephah with each bull and ram, and 1½ gallons 1 hin of oil with each 4½ pecks l ephah. 25On the fifteenth day, seventh month, for the week of the festival, he&amp;rsquo;ll provide sin offerings, burnt offerings, grain offerings, and oil.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 46</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-46/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-46&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 46&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;The gate in the inner court that faces east will be shut the six working days, but open on Sabbaths and new moons. 2The prince will go in through the porch of the gate from outside and stand by the gate post. The priests will provide his burnt offering and peace offerings. He&amp;rsquo;ll worship at the threshold of the gate and then leave, but the gate won&amp;rsquo;t be shut till that evening. 3The people will also worship at the doorway of that gate before Yahveh on Sabbaths and new moons. 4The prince&amp;rsquo;s burnt offering on the Sabbath will be 6 lambs and 1 ram without blemish. 5The grain offering will be 4½ pecks 1 ephah with the ram, and a grain offering with the lambs as much as he can give, and 1½ gallons 1 hin of oil with each 4½ pecks 1 ephah.  6On the new moon, he&amp;rsquo;ll offer 1 young bull, 6 lambs, and 1 ram, all without blemish. 7He&amp;rsquo;ll provide a grain offering 4½ pecks 1 ephah with the bull and the ram, and as much as he can give with the lambs, and 1½ gallons 1 hin of olive oil for each 4½ pecks bushels 1 ephah. 8The prince will enter through the porch of the gate and leave the same way. 9&amp;quot;When the people present themselves to Yahveh at the stated festivals, the one that goes in through the north gate to worship will leave through the south gate. The one that goes in through the south gate will leave through the north gate. Nobody will leave through the same gate they entered. 10When they go in, the prince will go in with them; when they go out, he&amp;rsquo;ll go out. 11At the feasts and stated festivals, the grain offering will be 4½ pecks 1 ephah with each bull and ram, and with the lambs as much as a person can give, together with 1½ gallons   1 hin of oil with each 4½ pecks 1 ephah. 12When the prince provides a freewill offering, burnt offering, or peace offering, the gate facing east will be opened for him. He&amp;rsquo;ll provide his burnt offering and his peace offerings as he does on the Sabbath day. Then he&amp;rsquo;ll go out, and the gate will be shut behind him. 13&amp;quot;Each morning, provide a year-old lamb without blemish for a burnt offering to Yahveh. 14Provide a grain offering with it, .18 bushel ⅙ ephah and ½ gallon ⅓ hin of oil to moisten the fine flour, a grain offering to Yahveh continually by ongoing ordinance. 15So a lamb and a grain offering with the olive oil will be provided every morning. 16&amp;rsquo;The Lord Yahveh says, &amp;ldquo;If the prince gives a son a gift out of his inheritance, it will be a permanent possession. 17But if he gives a servant a gift from his inheritance, it will go back to the prince at the Year of Jubilee. His inheritance will belong only to his sons. 18The prince won&amp;rsquo;t confiscate people&amp;rsquo;s inheritance or chase them off their land. He&amp;rsquo;ll give his sons an inheritance from his own possessions so my people won&amp;rsquo;t be separated from their possessions.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 47</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-47/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-47&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 47&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then he took me back to the Temple door. Water was running east from under the threshold of the Temple, which faced east. It was running down from under the right side of the Temple, from south of the altar. 2He brought me out through the north gate and led me around the outside of the outer gate by way of the gate that faces east. Water was trickling from the south side.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezekiel 48</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezekiel/chapter-48/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezekiel-chapter-48&#34;&gt;Ezekiel Chapter 48&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; These are the names of the tribes. Beginning on the northern boundary, from the sea by way of Hethlon to Lebo-hamath, as far as Hazar-enon (on the northern boundary of Damascus beside Hamath) running from the east side to the west: one portion each for Dan, 2Asher, 3Naphtali, 4Manasseh, 5Ephraim, 6Reuben, 7and Judah. 8&amp;quot;Adjoining Judah from east to west will be the allotment set aside from east to west 8.2 miles 25,000 cubits wide and equal to one of the portions. The sanctuary will be in the middle of it. 9-10The allotment set aside to Yahveh will be 8.2 x 3¼ miles 25,000 x 10,000 cubits, running east and west. The allotment will be for the priests 11that are sanctified from the descendants of Zadok, who kept my charge and didn&amp;rsquo;t go astray when Israel went astray—like the Levites did. 12It will be an allotment to them from the land, a most holy place beside the Levites&amp;rsquo; portion. 13Alongside the boundary of the priests, the Levites will have a portion 8.2 x 3¼ miles 25,000 x 10,000 cubits. 14They won&amp;rsquo;t sell or temporarily exchange any of it or pass the first part of its harvest to anyone else, because it&amp;rsquo;s holy to Yahveh. 15&amp;quot;The remainder, 1.63 x 8.2 miles 5,000 x 25,000 cubits, will be for common use by the city, for houses and open spaces. The city will lie in the middle of it. 16It will be square, measuring 1.47 miles on a side. 17The city will have an open space 430&amp;rsquo; 7&amp;quot; 250 cubits wide all the way around it. 18The rest of the length alongside the holy allotment will be 3¼ miles 10,000 cubits wide running east and west. Its crops and produce will feed the workmen in the city. 19The workmen in the city—from all the tribes—will cultivate it. 20The whole allotment will be 8.2 miles 25,000 cubits square. Set it aside with the city&amp;rsquo;s property. 21&amp;quot;What&amp;rsquo;s left on both sides of the holy portion and the property of the city will belong to the prince, extending from east to west 8.2 miles 25,000 cubits parallel to the holy portion. The holy portion with the Temple in the middle, 22the property of the Levites, and the property of the city will be inside the prince&amp;rsquo;s portion, which will lie between Judah and Benjamin. 23&amp;quot;For the rest of the tribes from east to west: Benjamin, one portion; 24then Simeon, one portion; 25then Issachar, one portion; 26then Zebulun, one portion; 27then Gad, one portion. 28Joining Gad at the south side, the boundary will be from Tamar to the water at Meribath-kadesh to the River of Egypt to the Mediterranean Sea. 29That&amp;rsquo;s the land you&amp;rsquo;ll divide by lot to the tribes of Israel,&amp;quot; the Lord Yahveh says. The Gates of the City 30&amp;quot;The city, which is 1¼ mile on a side, 31will have gates that bear the names of the tribes: three gates on the north side: Reuben, Judah, and Levi;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
