<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CREATION (AND EVOLUTION) on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/creation-and-evolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CREATION (AND EVOLUTION) on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/creation-and-evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ABBREVIATED TIME</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/abbreviated-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/abbreviated-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABBREVIATED TIME&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture does not readily adapt itself to the eons of time projected for accomplishing what evolutionary theory postulates, particularly in the biosphere. With varying degrees of likelihood, certain possibilities might push the date A.M. beyond the 4000 + B.C. minimum reading of scripture as in fiat creationism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;Possibilities for Elongation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;Time prior to Genesis 1:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Proposed relationships between Genesis 1:1 and 1:2ff&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. &#x9;Genesis 1:1 as a caption for the subsequent creation account&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BASIC CONCEPTS IN CREATIONIST-EVOLUTIONARY THOUGHT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/basic-concepts-in-creationist-evolutionary-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/basic-concepts-in-creationist-evolutionary-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BASIC CONCEPTS IN CREATIONIST-EVOLUTIONARY THOUGHT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Can we put in sequence the origin of reciprocating parts that are necessary for the viability of the organism and the parts themselves? If we can put their origin in sequence, they are not reciprocal. But the parts of plants and animals are in fact reciprocally interdependent unto viability. All parts have to be present and functional at all times. Disorganization destroys functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reciprocation is related to the concept of irreducible minimums, but it adds to it the origin of complexity and change between levels of complexity; hence, the mechanisms of change plus hoistic harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMPARING THEISM AND NATURALISM IN ORIGINS THEORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/comparing-theism-and-naturalism-in-origins-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/comparing-theism-and-naturalism-in-origins-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMPARING THEISM AND NATURALISM IN ORIGINS THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A formal similarity could be seen between “emergent evolution” and progressive creationism. The “emergent points” of emergent evolution might appear to correlate with the “intervention points” of progressive revelation. From a scientist’s viewpoint, we could consider the possibility that a connector in a progression is a natural one rather than a supernatural one, as previously supposed. We may not already know that a natural “force” exists for accomplishing this complexification. There is a difference, however, between keeping the natural category potential for explanation in such cases and making it the necessary category for explanation by disallowing the supernatural category in principle. The latter is what methodological naturalism does by assuming that its method, good in itself, somehow becomes the only legitimate method. Creationists, however, want to keep the supernatural category open after the initial creation of mass-energy. The formal similarity is limited because of the internal-external variable in the respective formats at their correlating junction points.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTELLIGENTLY DISCUSSING CREATION AND EVOLUTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/intelligently-discussing-creation-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/intelligently-discussing-creation-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTELLIGENTLY DISCUSSING CREATION AND EVOLUTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presentation here is not for solving the creation-evolution problem, but for clarifying the issue and correcting inappropriate thinking patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Identifying the Issue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creationism as such vs. the Christian formulations of it. There is a difference between creation as a concept and the Judaeo-Christian—or even Islamic—formulation of it. The Christian formulation gets into additional matters, which vary according to the manner interpreters handle the relevant biblical materials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RECIPROCAL CAUSATIONʹ, THE BIOSPHERE,</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/reciprocal-causation%CA%B9-the-biosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/reciprocal-causation%CA%B9-the-biosphere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RECIPROCAL CAUSATIONʹ, THE BIOSPHERE,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AND THEISTIC PROOF&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following observations evaluate the possibility of general evolution in the organic realm, particularly in the animal kingdom. They address features of living reality that highlight reciprocal causation, its necessary accompanying features, and its implications in contrast to all forms of straight-line causal series.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Question #1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Can nature unaided put in sequence the origin of reciprocating parts that each together produce all the effects that are necessary for the viability of the whole and of each other? [system level per kind]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NOACHIAN FLOOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-noachian-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-noachian-flood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NOACHIAN FLOOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Views of the Flood&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Local flood theory: anthropologically universal, but not global&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Tranquil flood theory: perhaps universal, but not catastrophic with geological&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;upheavals, volcanic activity, or cosmic disturbances&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Catastrophic universal flood theory designed to account for the fossil-bearing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;geological column&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. The Universality of the Flood&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;The purpose of the flood for destroying “every living thing that I have made”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 7:4)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/untitled/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
