<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CHRISTIAN DOCTRINE 1 on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/categories/christian-doctrine-1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CHRISTIAN DOCTRINE 1 on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/categories/christian-doctrine-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE NATURE OF THEOLOGY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NATURE OF THEOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The Nature of Theology vs. Exegesis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the most part, the epistles of the New Testament are problem-solution writings; they were written to deal with difficulties in particular times and places. In the process of answering the problems, the apostles drew upon information on many topics that relate to the need. Not everything about any one topic is in any one place; so readers have to assemble the partial treatments and combine them to form the whole picture. In exegesis, readers follow along the present line of presentation. Theology requires an added step beyond following the line of thought: the readers topically arrange the data into a harmonious whole so they can understand the message itself instead of just one presentation that contains parts of that whole. Exegesis deals with the text; theology deals with the topic. Exegesis operates verse by verse; theology operates with the truth itself as information gathered from the several contexts that address it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THEOLOGY AND LIBERAL ARTS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/theology-and-liberal-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/theology-and-liberal-arts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THEOLOGY AND LIBERAL ARTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Theology establishes the context for liberal arts. It is the discipline of the whole, the discipline of the ultimate. It addresses what is original, eternal, central, basic, ultimate, and all-inclusive. As such, theology affirms first that reality is cohesive rather than chaotic—that the parts have a whole to be part of. Theology calls for “centeredness” and centers reality in the Creator rather than the creation and in the Teacher rather than the student. By implication, theology contextualizes all other disciplines as sub-disciplines, integrates them into one whole, relates them to each another, limits their province, and critiques their methods and findings in at least a restrictive sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY OF CONVICTIONS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-of-convictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-of-convictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY OF CONVICTIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Christian worldview is interpersonal. The interpersonal “category” is the ultimate frame of reference that qualifies and limits the impersonal realities that are also part of full picture. Some major aspects of Christianity are summarized below in ways that correlate with this understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture: Special revelation is interpersonal communication from God to mankind, available to us in written form. Although God could have chosen to relate to us in some other fashion, he spoke to most people through representatives whose messages are preserved in the Old and New Testament writings. We speak of those writings as inerrant relative to the (a) intended (b) content of (c) scripture as such.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SURVEY OF CHRISTIAN DOCTRINE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/survey-of-christian-doctrine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/survey-of-christian-doctrine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SURVEY OF CHRISTIAN DOCTRINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BIBLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture is the complete word of God written and sufficiently accurate in origin and preservation to accomplish what God sent it to accomplish (Isaiah 55:11). He sent it through chosen representatives endowed with the messages he revealed to them and with the ability to correctly express it to the ones he wanted to hear it. Consequently, non-canonical writings have the status, at best, of devotional writings (Apocrypha and tradition).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE BIG PICTURE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-big-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-big-picture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE BIG PICTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest plagues in Bible study is a failure to see the “big picture.” We tend to read a verse, think about it, and discuss it. As a result, that statement gets lifted from its setting and put in the context of our interests or problems even when it may not belong there. Foreign ideas come into the picture because we do not keep context in mind. Bible study needs to cover large portions to keep in sight the flow of thought. In addition, the purpose and character of Christian understanding must provide the framework for individual doctrines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHAT CHRISTIANS IDEALLY BELIEVE AND PRACTICE:</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/what-christians-ideally-believe-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/what-christians-ideally-believe-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHAT CHRISTIANS IDEALLY BELIEVE AND PRACTICE:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A SUMMARY DESCRIPTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian churches began as an effort to foster Christian unity by returning to scripture alone for the operation of the body of Christ and by setting aside items that have crept into Christendom from outside the New Testament. The conviction has been that division arose in part from such extras. But creating unity requires more than getting rid of what causes division; it also requires what Christ’s people must stand for. Below are characteristic beliefs and practices associated with these churches generally, though certainly not with them only.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON JOHN CALVIN’S PENAL SUBSTITUTION THEORY OF THE ATONEMENT</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comments-on-john-calvins-penal-substitution-theory-of-the-atonement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comments-on-john-calvins-penal-substitution-theory-of-the-atonement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON JOHN CALVIN’S PENAL SUBSTITUTION THEORY OF THE ATONEMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the Reformation, a common understanding of Christ’s atonement work considers his righteousness as a substitute for ours and his death as a substitute for our death as punishment for our sin. The comments below shoulder a negative burden of proof to show that John Calvin’s penal substitution understanding is foreign to atonement theory unless we adopt the rest of his legal theological method, where penal substitution would make sense. The thesis here is that substitutionary atonement theory does not belong in non-Calvinistic theology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REASONS FOR THE INCARNATION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/reasons-for-the-incarnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/reasons-for-the-incarnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;REASONS FOR THE INCARNATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing what heaven was like, why did Jesus ever leave it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing what earth was like, why did he ever come here?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing what Golgatha was going to be like, why did Jesus ever become a man?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Communication: Hebrews 1:1-2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Means of communication: “son” vs. angels/prophets&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. Manner of communication: demonstration and description&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;holistic      vs.   in many parts/progressive&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“son-wise”         in many ways&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;personal            verbal&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SACRIFICE AND SALVATION: ANCIENT NEAR EASTERN</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/sacrifice-and-salvation-ancient-near-eastern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/sacrifice-and-salvation-ancient-near-eastern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SACRIFICE AND SALVATION: ANCIENT NEAR EASTERN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ANTECEDENTS TO REDEMPTION THROUGH CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Sacrifice is as old as religion, and religion is as old as man.” The antiquity of sacrifice relates to its universality. Virtually every ancient culture offered sacrifices to supernatural entities; some cultures still do. In the Bible, sacrifice begins in the second generation (Genesis 4:2-8) and appears throughout the patriarchal and Mosaic periods, culminating in Christ’s “sacrifice.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite the abundance of biblical material on sacrifice, the origin of sacrifice is ambiguous. Did it arise from people’s natural religious instincts or from unrecorded divine appointment?1 The same uncertainty applies to the rationale for sacrifice; it is not explicitly stated anywhere in the Old Testament.2 After summarizing some particulars about sacrifice and noting some relevant archaeological remains, the following presentation offers a rationale for sacrifice that connects it with salvation as related to the life and death of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIX NOTATIONS ON IDENTIFICATION ATONEMENT THEORY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/six-notations-on-identification-atonement-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/six-notations-on-identification-atonement-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SIX NOTATIONS ON IDENTIFICATION ATONEMENT THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Identification as the Whole Basis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In identification atonement theory, “identification” means more than identifying with Christ from our own side so God will count Christ’s atoning death as a substitute for our own death. That leaves substitution—or whatever—as the operative mechanism. Identification likewise is not just God’s viewing us from his side as connected with Christ. Identification in these senses fits with any theory of the atonement. Identification would merely connect the sinner with Christ—in the sinner’s mind and God’s mind—in anticipation of whatever mechanism then removed the penalty: ransom, substitute, or conquest. Identification would not replace or obviate some additional operation after the subjective and objective connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STRICTURES ON CALVIN’S PENAL SUBSTITUTIONARY ATONEMENT  THEORY:</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/strictures-on-calvins-penal-substitutionary-atonement-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/strictures-on-calvins-penal-substitutionary-atonement-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STRICTURES ON CALVIN’S PENAL SUBSTITUTIONARY ATONEMENT  THEORY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IDENTIFICATION AS AN ALTERNATIVE PROPOSAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Salvation through Jesus Christ is the most distinctive feature of Christianity. Herein lies its primary difference from previous divine economies, other religions, and human agendas. In Christ, God is concerned with more than letting us know about him, about his moral standards, and about our responsibilities within his purposes. Salvation is not from ignorance, as by revelation; it is not deliverance from material existence as in Gnosticism and eastern dualism; it is not deliverance from individuality as in Hinduism. It is deliverance from alienation and all the negatives that grow out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE MEANING OF “IDENTIFICATION WITH CHRIST”</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-meaning-of-identification-with-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-meaning-of-identification-with-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MEANING OF “IDENTIFICATION WITH CHRIST”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Identification with Christ” refers to a complex of factors within the reality of personal relationship, which we are calling interpersonalism. Interpersonalism is a worldview that considers persons in relationship as the highest frame of reference. That reality includes aspects like the following.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Faith in Christ as the object of identification in place of all others. We not only understand and believe intellectually, but trust actively that Christ is an “extension of,” and the human “manifestation of,” the other side of the divine-human relationship. We believe that identification with him leads to identification with the Father because that is the Father’s condition for identification with himself. We believe what Christ believes; we accept what he teaches about all things whereof he speaks. We put our trust in him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE RATIONALE FOR ATONEMENT THROUGH CHRIST</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-rationale-for-atonement-through-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-rationale-for-atonement-through-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE RATIONALE FOR ATONEMENT THROUGH CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary statement: “Christ alone has achieved perfect goodness as a man in the flesh by obeying the Father in everything even to the point of yielding to an agonizing death. When we commit ourselves to Christ as Lord together with the values and purposes he shares with the Father, God considers us righteous like him, forgiving our sin, reckoning aspiration for achievement, reconciling us to himself.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A POSITION STATEMENT</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-position-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-position-statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A POSITION STATEMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ON THE MEANING OF CHRISTIAN BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of our standard response to the gospel, God appointed baptism for expressing personal identification with Jesus Christ, which involves commitment to his lordship, values, and purposes. In consequence of our identity with him, God forgives our sin, grants fellowship with his Spirit, and numbers us among his children.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this description, (1) “standard response” means that special cases and impossible circumstances are not in view, circumstances where baptism cannot be performed or cannot be performed without endangering life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A SKETCH ON BAPTISM FROM ACTS 2:38</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-sketch-on-baptism-from-acts-238/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-sketch-on-baptism-from-acts-238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A SKETCH ON BAPTISM FROM ACTS 2:38&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Repent         be baptized  into    the name of Jesus Messiah   &#x9;remission of sins&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the Holy Spirit as a gift&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;membership in Christ’s body&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Identity with Jesus the Messiah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;means commitment to him:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;total (every aspect)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;permanent (all life long)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;exclusive (vs. all other&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;parallel possibilities)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The remission is based on identity with the One who is what we are called to be and aspire to be. God is willing to consider us righteous on the basis of identity with the One who is righteous. The remission is not based on the act of baptism per se, but on the One we commit to in doing it. [identity with Messiah]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABSTRACT OF DISTINCTIONS ABOUT THE NECESSITY OF BAPTISM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/abstract-of-distinctions-about-the-necessity-of-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/abstract-of-distinctions-about-the-necessity-of-baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT OF DISTINCTIONS ABOUT THE NECESSITY OF BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A distinction needs to be made between standard situations and special cases. Denying the necessity of baptism applies only to special cases. Special cases include those in which&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) a person would be risking health or life in being baptized,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(b) people honestly misunderstand that baptism is immersion or should have been a personal adult response of their own,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(c) someone is “killed on the way to the baptistry.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BAPTISM AS IDENTIFICATION WITH CHRIST</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/baptism-as-identification-with-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/baptism-as-identification-with-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BAPTISM AS IDENTIFICATION WITH CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seeing baptism as identification with Christ provides a framework for working through several abnormal situations that arise and helps make sense even of normal situations that may be overlooked in the theory and practice of the ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Addressing first the normal situation, we observe clear cases of baptism that do not move lost people into a saved condition: righteous Jews called to John’s baptism for remission of sins, saved disciples of John called to Christian baptism, and the baptism of Jesus himself by John. Such examples show that Christian—and even Johannine—baptism has a bigger frame of reference than salvation from lostness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QUESTIONS ABOUT CHRISTIAN BAPTISM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/questions-about-christian-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/questions-about-christian-baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;QUESTIONS ABOUT CHRISTIAN BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Doctrinal Questions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is baptism for (meaning)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, in Christian baptism we identify with Jesus Christ. The New Testament means identification when it speaks of (a) being baptized “into Christ,” “into the name of Christ,” and similar expressions (Matthew 28:19; Acts 2:38; 8:16; 10:48; 19:5; Galatians 3:27). We identify with the Messiah instead of with Moses (1 Corinthians 10:1-2) or John the Baptist (Acts l9:1-7) or the apostle Paul (1 Corinthians 1:13-15). As a result, we belong to Christ (1 Corinthians 3:22-23; 1:12). Paul means identification when he says that by baptism we are (b) “united with Christ” (1 Corinthians 6:5). Baptism is a pledge of allegiance to him in which we commit ourselves to his purposes, values, and motivations. We make that commitment to the extent of the death that baptism pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REBAPTISM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/rebaptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/rebaptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;REBAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wise policy is to let candidates make their own decision about rebaptism; after all, baptism is their obedience to God, not ours. Nevertheless, people usually take their cue from those they have come to trust on religious matters. For these reasons we will not always be able to leave the issue in the hands of candidates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The predominate opinion has been that rebaptism is not necessary even for those who understood their previous baptism as a testimony to other believers or as the way of entering the visible body of Christ on earth. That opinion seems wise for reasons like the following.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RETHINKING THE DESCRIPTION OF BAPTISM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/rethinking-the-description-of-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/rethinking-the-description-of-baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RETHINKING THE DESCRIPTION OF BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following presentation gives the author’s understanding of Christian baptism even though it attempts to represent fairly a wider movement. What I am saying here may at first sound different to brethren from my background. That difference comes in part from the attention given to framework of thought and structure of presentation. We have tried to achieve wholeness, cohesiveness, and clarity by giving overt expression to our presuppositions. The difference comes also from the fact that there is some diversity in the movement, which is natural enough in a free-church heritage the size of this one. Unity through restoration assumes the desire to adjust toward a more New Testament understanding. Hopefully, this treatment will synthesize ideas and sharpen and improve what we believe and practice in regard to Christian baptism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIGHTLY DIVIDING THE WORD OF TRUTH IN ACTS 2:38</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/rightly-dividing-the-word-of-truth-in-acts-238/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/rightly-dividing-the-word-of-truth-in-acts-238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RIGHTLY DIVIDING THE WORD OF TRUTH IN ACTS 2:38&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian baptism is a self-expression of personal identification with Jesus Christ, and God gives consequences on the basis of that identity more than on the basis of the act itself: forgiveness of sin, gift of the Spirit, and fellowship in the body of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 2:38 connects with the thesis above by making the full threefold affirmation: baptism, in the name of Christ, and forgiveness of sins. It does not say, “(Let each one of you) repent and be baptized for the remission of sins,” as sometimes misquoted. Strictly speaking, scripture nowhere uses the phraseology “baptism for remission of sins.” The point, of course, is not to disconnect baptism from forgiveness in every way, but to conceptualize the connection exactly. Ananias does tell Saul to be baptized and wash away his sins (Acts 22:16). Peter feels free even to say that baptism saves us (1 Peter 3:21), salvation being reconciliation from alienation caused by sin. Evidently in referring to baptism, Titus 3:5 declares that God “saved us through the washing of regeneration.”1 Even John’s baptism was a baptism of repentance unto/for remission of sins (Matthew 3:2; Mark 1:4; Luke 3:3; Acts 13:24; 19:4). Baptism texts include the forgiveness consequence, especially when sin figures prominently in the circumstance; hence, the deliberative question on Pentecost, “What are we going to do?” (Acts 2:37) and Ananias’ directive to “the chief of sinners,” distraught over having so severely persecuted Jesus’ disciples (Acts 22:16).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PURPOSE OF CHRISTIAN BAPTISM: A SYNOPSIS*</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-purpose-of-christian-baptism-a-synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-purpose-of-christian-baptism-a-synopsis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PURPOSE OF CHRISTIAN BAPTISM: A SYNOPSIS*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIANITY AS AN INTERPERSONAL “SYSTEM”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian baptism is an interpersonal act in which a repentant believer identifies with Jesus Christ. On the basis of identity with Christ, God promises to forgive our sins, grant us the presence of his Spirit, and add us to Christ&amp;rsquo;s body, the church.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TWO BASIC POINTS ABOUT BAPTISM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/two-basic-points-about-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/two-basic-points-about-baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TWO BASIC POINTS ABOUT BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two points should be highlighted in presentations about baptism. First, baptism should not be too closely identified with outer response. That lends itself to distinguishing inner and outer, identifying faith with inner and baptism with outer, and then affirming that it is the inner dimension that justifies rather than the outer expressive act as well, thus trying to avoid baptism as a work and bringing it into conformity with the Pauline formula “salvation by faith” vs. works. But “faith” in Romans/Galatians does not mean inner action; that is the usage in James. Paul means action in the context of personal relationship (faith) vs. action in the context of legal process (works). We do well to unite inner and outer response in salvation and to consider baptism itself as comprised of both dimensions inseparably. That unity of aspects applies to all acts of obedience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TYPES OF SYSTEMS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/types-of-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/types-of-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TYPES OF SYSTEMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not all systems are alike. They often operate in respect to different kinds of matters, but the main contrast lies in the kinds of connectors in them that bind actions to results. Below are three types of systems that illustrate this diversity. We outline them here in order to clarify what causes people to differ so intensely about the role of Christian baptism in the salvation process. Basically what happens is that at various points in their total understanding of baptism they are shifting baptism back and forth between different systems without realizing it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNDERSTANDING CHRISTIAN ORDINANCES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/understanding-christian-ordinances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/understanding-christian-ordinances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UNDERSTANDING CHRISTIAN ORDINANCES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following presentation is, strictly speaking, the author’s understanding of Christian ordinances even though it attempts to represent fairly the view taken by a larger movement as well. There is some diversity in that movement, which is natural enough in a free-church heritage the size of ours; but that diversity makes it more difficult to state “our position.” Nevertheless, unity through restoration accomplishes one thing for us and for everyone here today: it assures the desire to continue adjusting toward a more biblical understanding. Hopefully, this treatment will synthesize our ideas and thereby sharpen and improve what we all believe and practice about Christian ordinances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHAT THE VERY EXISTENCE OF BAPTISM SHOWS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/what-the-very-existence-of-baptism-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/what-the-very-existence-of-baptism-shows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHAT THE VERY EXISTENCE OF BAPTISM SHOWS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The very fact that baptism exists shows that salvation is not by works of law, works in a legal sense, works in a legal context, acts that have some legal value. Furthermore, the very existence of baptism shows that salvation is not by human effort relative even to an interpersonal standard of behavior, which, as in law, is also a perfection standard. To make this claim convincing, we must show that baptism is not primarily for bringing about entrance into the institutional church or for communicating to other people that we have decided to follow Jesus. For present purposes, that point is sufficiently shown by the biblical expression “baptism into Christ,” not “baptism into the church” or some wording that indicates testimony to other people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE CHRIST</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Pre-Existence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Pre-existence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 1:1-4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 6:33, 38, 51&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 8:56-58&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 17:5, 24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philippians 2:5-7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Colossians 1:13-17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Hebrews 1:1-4&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. &#x9;Eternal pre-existence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The eternal pre-existence of Christ is difficult to prove. It is an inference from having first shown that he is personal deity. It is difficult to disprove the idea that the Father, Son, and Spirit were originally one person, but that for a time the Son and then the Spirit became a second and third person somehow set off from the original one. The nature of personhood would seem to exclude the separating idea; but it is possible that we make that inference because our personal nature is like that. The following information, however, relates to the eternal pre-existence of the Son.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADDED NOTATIONS ON APOSTLES TODAY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/added-notations-on-apostles-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/added-notations-on-apostles-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADDED NOTATIONS ON APOSTLES TODAY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We may question whether Judas should be counted among the men called apostles in the primary sense. Although he originally had that role, he left it (cp. Acts 1:15-22).. In addition, he did not see the resurrected Christ receive the commission and enablements distinctive to apostles in the primary sense. With Judas omitted, that leaves thirteen apostles with Matthias replacing Judas and Paul joining the class later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ARE THERE MODERN-DAY APOSTLES?</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/are-there-modern-day-apostles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/are-there-modern-day-apostles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ARE THERE MODERN-DAY APOSTLES?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two Word Meanings&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christians sometimes ask whether there are apostles in the church today. To answer the question, we must clarify what it means because the New Testament uses apostle in more than one way. Its general sense refers to someone who is “sent,” which makes it a synonym for missionary. In its technical usage, apostle refers to a group of men, fourteen in number, who had additional specialized qualifications: they were direct witnesses of the resurrected Christ (except for Judas Iscariot), directly chosen and commissioned by Christ, directly endowed with their message, directly guided in their work, and directly empowered by the Spirit. (See “Paul as Primary Apostle.”). “You tried the ones that call themselves apostles and aren’t” (Revelation 2:2) implies that some apostles were distinguishable from other apostles. If all apostles were simply traveling evangelists or insightful men differing only in degree, they could be called apostles. Denying the claim would be like denying that someone was a missionary. They were in fact traveling, they were in fact insightful if they were, and they were in fact sent from somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMPARING LISTINGS OF APOSTLES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comparing-listings-of-apostles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comparing-listings-of-apostles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMPARING LISTINGS OF APOSTLES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 10:2-4&#x9;Mk. 3:16-19&#x9;Lk. 6:14-16&#x9;&#x9;Acts 1:13&#x9;&#x9;John’s Gospel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simon Peter&#x9;Simon Peter&#x9;Simon Peter  &#x9;&#x9;Peter&#x9;&#x9;Simon Peter/Cephas8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bar-Jonah7&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;   Simon son of John7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andrew&#x9;James&#x9;Andrew&#x9;&#x9;John&#x9;&#x9;The disciple Jesus &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;     &#x9;    &#x9;      &#x9;   loved 9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;James&#x9;John&#x9;James&#x9;&#x9;James&#x9;&#x9;James  (21:2)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John&#x9;Andrew&#x9;John&#x9;&#x9;Andrew&#x9;&#x9;Andrew&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philip&#x9;Philip&#x9;Philip&#x9;&#x9;Philip&#x9;&#x9;Philip3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bartholomew&#x9;Bartholomew&#x9;Bartholomew&#x9;&#x9;Thomas&#x9;&#x9;Thomas2 Didymus6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thomas&#x9;Matthew11Levi&#x9;Matthew&#x9;&#x9;Bartholomew&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew&#x9;Thomas&#x9;Thomas&#x9;&#x9;Matthew&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Nathanael]5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;James of Alphaeus  James of Alphaeus &#x9;James of Alphaeus&#x9;James of Alphaeus&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HUSBAND OF ONE WIFE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/husband-of-one-wife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/husband-of-one-wife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HUSBAND OF ONE WIFE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul gives “husband of one wife” as a characteristic of elders and deacons in 1 Timothy 3:2, 12 and Titus 1:6. The following diagram traces the pattern of thought for determining what he meant by this phrase.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;STEP I. We must distinguish between what to do because it is best under the circumstances (“expediency”) and what a passage requires (“exegesis”). For instance, in the case of married versus not married, it is one thing to say that there are advantages to having a married eldership; it is another thing to say that Paul is requiring a married eldership. This treatment of the problem addresses primarily what the passage means as to whether elders and deacons must be married.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KINGDOM OF HEAVEN/KINGDOM OF GOD/CHURCH</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/kingdom-of-heavenkingdom-of-godchurch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/kingdom-of-heavenkingdom-of-godchurch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KINGDOM OF HEAVEN/KINGDOM OF GOD/CHURCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew                 &#x9;Mark                   &#x9;Luke                   &#x9;John&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3:5&#x9;&#x9;   &#x9;  &#x9;1:14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:17&#x9;  &#x9;1:15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:43&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5:3&#x9;&#x9;  &#x9;6:20&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5:10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5:19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5:20&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6:33 (K of G)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;7:21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11:11&#x9;&#x9;  &#x9;7:28&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11:12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;8:1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12:28 (K of G)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13:11&#x9;  &#x9;4:11&#x9;8:10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13:24&#x9;  &#x9;4:26&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13:31&#x9;  &#x9;4:30&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13:44&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13:45&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13:47&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13:52&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9:60&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9:62&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10:7&#x9;&#x9;  &#x9;9:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9:11&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:18 (church)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[16:28 (his kingdom)&#x9;9:1  &#x9;9:27]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18:1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18:4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9:47&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18:172 (church)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18:23&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10:9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew&#x9; Mark&#x9; Luke&#x9;John&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PAUL AS PRIMARY APOSTLE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/paul-as-primary-apostle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/paul-as-primary-apostle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PAUL AS PRIMARY APOSTLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some have questioned whether Paul belonged to the primary group of Jesus’ followers called “apostles.” During the early years of the Christian era, the Judaizing element in the church attempted (1) on doctrinal grounds to put him in secondary position. They tried to create the impression that he stood at odds with the primary apostles, those centering around Peter in Jerusalem. Judaizers believed that Gentile converts should become Jews in the process of becoming Christians. Paul opposed their call for circumcising Gentiles and thereby identifying them with national Israel and obligating them to keep the Mosaic Law. He understood in the first case, relative to the church, that Christianity does not have a political component. He observed in the second case, relative to salvation, that putting Gentiles under Jewish Law would in theory bring them under a perfection requirement for continued relationship to God—initial salvation by grace and continued salvation by works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REGARDING THE DISTINCTION BETWEEN</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/regarding-the-distinction-between/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/regarding-the-distinction-between/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;REGARDING THE DISTINCTION BETWEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EVANGELIST AND ELDER IN THE LOCAL CHURCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In theory, two positions operating in relationship may differ from one another in authority in at least six ways:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a)&#x9;as to its being resident in one vs. passing through the other from the first;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(b)&#x9;as to the area of work to be done where authority is exercised;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(c)&#x9;as to the level at which it is exercised, the first being higher than the second;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE ON DEACONS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-deacons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-deacons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON DEACONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“to serve”:  διακονέω (diakoneō)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Non-&#x9;Other&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reference&#x9;Text&#x9;Eccl.&#x9;General&#x9;Positions&#x9;Tech.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 4:11&#x9;Angels came and ministered to him&#x9;X&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;8:15&#x9;She got up and ministered to them.&#x9;X&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20:28&#x9;[I] did not come to be be ministered to, &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Lord&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;but to minister, and give his life . . . &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Lord&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;25:44&#x9;in prison, and did not minister to you?&#x9;X&#x9;X&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;27:45&#x9;from Galilee, ministering to him.&#x9;X&#x9;X&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY GUIDE ON ELDERSHIP</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-eldership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/study-guide-on-eldership/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY GUIDE ON ELDERSHIP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Passage&#x9;Term&#x9;#&#x9;&#x9;Reference&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;               Scope&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S  Pl&#x9;Old/&#x9;Men of&#x9;Jewish &#x9;24 in&#x9;Church&#x9;City/ House&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Older  Old  &#x9;Elders&#x9;  Rev&#x9;Office &#x9;Area&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 15:2&#x9;πρεσβύτερος&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;  x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 16:21&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 21:23&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 26:3&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 26:47&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 26:57&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 26:59&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 27:1&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 27:3&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 27:12&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt. 27:20&#x9;         &amp;quot;&#x9;&#x9;pl&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;    x&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY OF OFFICES IN THE CHURCH</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-of-offices-in-the-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-of-offices-in-the-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY OF OFFICES IN THE CHURCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;general&#x9;supernatural&#x9;  authoritative&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;vs.&#x9;         &#x9;   &#x9;vs.                               vs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Office&#x9;  local&#x9;    natural  &#x9;non-authoritative&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lord =&#x9;general&#x9;super&#x9;&#x9;author&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christ&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Messiah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;apostle1&#x9;general&#x9;super&#x9;&#x9;author&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;the disciples&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;the twelve&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;prophet1&#x9;general&#x9;super&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;non-a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;prophet2&#x9;general&#x9;&#x9;natural&#x9;&#x9;non-a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;evangelist =&#x9;general&#x9;&#x9;natural&#x9;&#x9;non-a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;apostle2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;elder (= presbyter)&#x9;&#x9;local&#x9;&#x9;natural&#x9;author&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;bishop (= overseer)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(= episcopos)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pastor (= shepherd)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;teacher&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ruler&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;deacon&#x9;&#x9;local&#x9;&#x9;natural&#x9;&#x9;non-a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The conclusion seems too restrictive that elders handled spiritual matters while deacons handled material ones. The idea comes from the account of the seven appointed in Acts 6:1-6 to “serve tables.” The account does not call them “deacons,” and later we find Philip and Stephen involved in spiritual matters and operating beyond the local situation. Their work evidently progressed beyond the earlier or primary responsibility. So, the case is ambiguous for defining the role deacons fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NEW TESTAMENT STRUCTURE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEW TESTAMENT STRUCTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basic Structure&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter sketches the original organization of the church in the New Testament. It determines what positions exercised authority and which were functions, all being places of service. The procedure works because it addresses an either-or matter and because authority includes function. We cannot suppose that a function seemed to be such only because the records happen to be insufficient to show that it was really an office. That would argue from silence and shift the burden of proof onto the negative. The negative burden would be impossible since the only available evidence would pertain to function, which is part of the larger concept: office.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A RATIONALE FOR THE STRUCTURE OF GENESIS 1:1-2:3</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-rationale-for-the-structure-of-genesis-11-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-rationale-for-the-structure-of-genesis-11-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A RATIONALE FOR THE STRUCTURE OF GENESIS 1:1-2:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Précis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author of Genesis 1:1-2:3 presents a picture of creating earth and sky from the time viewpoint of Israel’s founding. Specific creative acts appear in a set analogous to the intended six-day-week-plus-Sabbath that God established at the same time for his special people. The presentation is topical without concern for exact sequence, duration, parallel entry, completeness, and necessary divisions. The sequence of creation itself can differ from the sequence of the presentation about creation in a sensible order. Analogy describes the connection between the creation of National Israel and the presentation about the creation of the universe (Isaiah 43:1ff). Inspiration guides and protects the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIG LESSONS IN GENESIS 1-3</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/big-lessons-in-genesis-1-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/big-lessons-in-genesis-1-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BIG LESSONS IN GENESIS 1-3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;The God-universe distinction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II.&#x9;The people-animal distinction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;III.&#x9;The man-woman distinction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IV.&#x9;The origin of the cosmos (vs. eternal matter)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;V.&#x9;The good-evil distinction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VI.&#x9;The goodness of the material universe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VII.&#x9;People as responsible beings&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VIII.&#x9;The origin of evil: If all that is not God has been created, then evil can begin outside&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;of God in secondary agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IX.&#x9;The origin of suffering&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPRETING THE CREATION NARRATIVE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/interpreting-the-creation-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/interpreting-the-creation-narrative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPRETING THE CREATION NARRATIVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An Interpretative Approach&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1 uses the week as a literary device for organizing a topical presentation of God’s prominent creative activities. It is without strict concern for sequence and duration. While Genesis 1 uses the week as a literary device, Genesis 2-3 uses parable to organize important truths around historical persons. It is not necessarily that the events of Genesis 3 led to new effects after sin occurred; these characteristics of mankind and nature were put in place by God from the start. God knew beforehand that people would sin, and built factors into their situation that would limit the extent to which they could rebel and factors that would force them to recognize their dependent situation. This approach derives from Genesis several fundamental beliefs about God, people, nature, sin, and God’s connection to these aspects of the human circumstance. It stresses meaning (theological perspectives) over time (historical account).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MANAGING THE CREATION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/managing-the-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/managing-the-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANAGING THE CREATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God maintains contact with his creation and control over it. Especially in contrast to deism, God did not create the universe and leave it to operate entirely according to built-in laws for self-perpetuation. God is actively involved with what he made. There is built-in NATURAL LAW such as gravity that apparently operates “on its own” now that God has set it up to work in a particular way. But in addition, there is SUPERNATURAL INTERVENTION, where God enters the natural process and brings about results that would not have occurred had he not intervened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OVERVIEW OF CREATION AND EVOLUTION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/overview-of-creation-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/overview-of-creation-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OVERVIEW OF CREATION AND EVOLUTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Preliminary Definitions and Concepts&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;God: label for ultimate reality&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;God’s relationship to the universe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natural imminence: God is not distinct in kind from the universe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*2.&#x9;Natural transcendence: God is distinct from the universe. Overlapping in immanence has to do with availability; overlapping in kind has to do with personal creation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Change&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Modification: change without increasing the number of factors.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*2.&#x9;Complexification: change with increasing the number of actors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROPOSED RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN GENESIS 1:1 AND 1:2-2:3</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/proposed-relationship-between-genesis-11-and-12-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/proposed-relationship-between-genesis-11-and-12-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROPOSED RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN GENESIS 1:1 AND 1:2-2:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.   &#x9;Genesis 1:1, Caption for the Creation Account (Hebrew construct form)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this view, Genesis 1:1 does not necessarily provide a statement of absolute origin in the “book of beginnings.” (Day 4 may cover the origin of the heavens.) This view leaves open the possibility of eternal matter and, when in combination with a parabolic understanding of Genesis 1-11, poses no difficulties for a theistic evolutionary system. Observations against this view, however, include the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROVIDENCE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/providence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/providence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROVIDENCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God controls his universe and directs its functioning by the operations diagramed below. (1) Reality combines freedom and determinism with freedom occurring inside the determinism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we add advancing time, providence takes on the form of a “broad arrow,” which can represent the idea that (2) history is going somewhere rather than moving in a circle, that is, just moving back and forth among the old options. History is going somewhere intentionally rather than merely eventuating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DOCTRINE OF CREATION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-doctrine-of-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-doctrine-of-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DOCTRINE OF CREATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The doctrine of creation is unique to the Judaeo-Christian and Islamic heritages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Biblical Materials&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Genesis 1:1; 2:4; Isaiah 45:18; note other statements about “made” heaven and&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;earth (Acts 4:24; 14:15; 17:24-25; Exodus 20:11; Psalm 146:6; Hebrews 1:2;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revelation 14:7; 1 Peter 3:5)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;John 1:1-3: “All things were made through him, and without him nothing was&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;made that was made.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Colossians 1:15-17: “In [the Firstborn] all things were created in the heavens&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE MOSES-TIME VIEWPOINT OF GENESIS-DEUTERONOMY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-moses-time-viewpoint-of-genesis-deuteronomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-moses-time-viewpoint-of-genesis-deuteronomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MOSES-TIME VIEWPOINT OF GENESIS-DEUTERONOMY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presentation in Genesis is from Moses’ viewpoint in time and place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The narrowing scope from Genesis 1:1 till Moses’ time in history. See herein “The Structure of Genesis-Deuteronomy.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comment about the Sabbath. 2:1-3 comes from a day when Sabbath observance had been enacted as a memorial of the exodus (Deuteronomy 5:12-15). The purpose of the Sabbath was to serve as a memorial of the exodus, when God “created” Israel (Isaiah 43:15, “I am Yahveh, your Holy One, the Creator of Israel . . .”); the manner of observance correlated with God’s creative work: as a rest, weekly, at the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DISPENSATIONS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/dispensations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/dispensations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DISPENSATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Human history may be organized according to the ways God has operated with mankind. The accompanying diagram pictures that history in three periods, or “dispensations”: the patriarchal, Mosaic, and Christian. The patriarchal period is so called because during that era God operated through the heads of families, or “patriarchs.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God dispensed his grace through family heads all the way from the beginning up to the time when the Israelites left Egypt. The Mosaic period is so called because during that time God operated through the Law he gave through “Moses.” He called a nation to serve as a light to the other nations—the Gentiles. God worked in this fashion from Moses to Messiah, nearly 1500 years. Since the coming of Messiah, God has been dispensing his grace to individuals through “Christ.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EXEGESIS AND THE GOSPELS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/exegesis-and-the-gospels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/exegesis-and-the-gospels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EXEGESIS AND THE GOSPELS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Change of covenants deals only with what people do. That is why (a) there is no change regarding the nature of things (ontological matters) or matters of history (events, including prophecy). (b) Civil and ceremonial observances fall out because national Israel (Moses) and the Old Testament priesthood (Aaron) have been replaced by the interpersonal church with its ministry and message. (c) There are few new ceremonial matters—baptism and the Lord’s Supper—that have come in with Christ. (d) Some modifications in the moral code come in with progressive revelation. Marriage expectancy shifts from polygamy and divorce-remarriage possibilities to permanent monogamy standard. (See the broad arrow diagram in “Old Testament Backgrounds and the Messianic Covenant.”)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISRAEL’S CORE COMMANDMENTS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/israels-core-commandments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/israels-core-commandments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ISRAEL’S CORE COMMANDMENTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The List of Commandments&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Do not serve any God but the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not make graven images or bow down to them&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Do not use the LORD as a byword.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Remember to set aside the Sabbath day for resting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Honor your father and mother.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Do not commit murder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Do not commit adultery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not steal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not lie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not covet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Structure and Content of the Laws&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OLD TESTAMENT BACKGROUNDS AND THE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/old-testament-backgrounds-and-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/old-testament-backgrounds-and-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OLD TESTAMENT BACKGROUNDS AND THE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MESSIANIC COVENANT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God is the Great Teacher. Readiness is an educational principle he observed in working to achieve his purpose of a new united mankind (Ephesians 2:15). Over the centuries he has increased people’s readiness for spiritual growth by (1) giving progressive revelation, (2) instituting present forms for later realities, and even (3) adopting human forms to serve as shadows of later substances. Establishing covenants illustrates this third use of readiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PAUL VS. THE LAW OR THE TRADITION OF THE ELDERS?</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/paul-vs-the-law-or-the-tradition-of-the-elders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/paul-vs-the-law-or-the-tradition-of-the-elders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PAUL VS. THE LAW OR THE TRADITION OF THE ELDERS?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some authors have suggested that Paul in his writings for the Gentile mission was opposing the tradition of the elders rather than the Mosaic Law itself. But the following factors look away from such a reading of Paul’s concern.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For one thing, (1) Paul objected to circumcising Gentiles. Circumcision was a practice related to the Law itself, not just to the tradition of the elders. The apostle was evidently countering the meaning of that rite itself, which had associations with Jewish nationalism. Beyond that, circumcision identified people with law since it identified them with the Mosaic Law. Consequently, circumcision had a soteriological implication: in theory it committed people to maintaining relationship with God by committing them to the principle of personal perfection (Leviticus 18:5; Deuteronomy 27:26), the point Paul makes in Galatians 3:8-14. Succeeding at personally doing everything required by law is exactly what none of us do or have been able to do in a practical sense; we have all sinned, and we continue to fall short of perfection—“the glory of God” (Romans 3:23). Starting in spirit (that is, I think, with interpersonal processes with Christ) and trying to finish in flesh (law, perfection, nationality) attempts to mix contrary types of things in order to accomplish the righteousness that is prerequisite for being viewed as righteous, which in turn is prerequisite for fellowship with God. In effect, the Law was a yoke that neither first-century Jews nor their fathers were able to bear (Acts 15:10). It was the Law itself that was the yoke, not just the tradition of the elders, which built a hedge around it by making it stricter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DISTINCTION BETWEEN COVENANTS AND SOME</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-distinction-between-covenants-and-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-distinction-between-covenants-and-some/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DISTINCTION BETWEEN COVENANTS AND SOME&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RELEVANT APPLICATIONS: A SKETCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Central thesis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Old Covenant was a different covenant from the New Covenant, was a different kind of covenant, and was preparatory for the new. The Old Covenant was legal while the New Covenant is interpersonal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The former (L) was added to promise (IP) for a time to define and sensitize to sin till Christ (IP) would come for universal, permanent operation leading to (perhaps conceivable millennial “kingdom” before) the eternal state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE RELATIONSHIP OF THE LAW AND THE GOSPEL</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-the-law-and-the-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-the-law-and-the-gospel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE RELATIONSHIP OF THE LAW AND THE GOSPEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Christian gospel came into redemptive history, the status and nature of the Mosaic Law came into question. Not only was this question relevant to Jews, but Gentiles also had to cope with it, because Christianity came out of a heritage different from their own. Christendom has witnessed five ways of dealing with the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping the law constitutionally (code and content) and adding the gospel to it. The law and the gospel are conceived of as two stages of the same thing; they are compatible. Among the Jews the approach received significant impetus during the early years of the Gentile mission. Judaizing missionaries received strong opposition from Paul and Barnabas in Antioch and eventually in Jerusalem at the Conference on Circumcision recorded in Acts 15. In Galatians, 2 Corinthians 3, and Romans, Paul vigorously opposed the concept primarily on soteriological grounds, but other matters were also implicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A LETTER ABOUT SEXUAL IDENTITY DISORDER</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-letter-about-sexual-identity-disorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-letter-about-sexual-identity-disorder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A LETTER ABOUT SEXUAL IDENTITY DISORDER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;xxxxx,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several days ago your letter came, revealing your struggles with sexual identity disorder and what you have proposed to do about the matter. You will not be surprised, I am sure, to find a concerned ear for you in the situation you are handling, but you will not find a sympathetic ear for what you are contemplating doing with it. There is a distinction between the disorder itself and what a person proposes to do with it. The disorder may be understandable; what people decide to do with it is another matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAPITAL CRIMES IN MOSAISM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/capital-crimes-in-mosaism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/capital-crimes-in-mosaism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CAPITAL CRIMES IN MOSAISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adultery/Incest&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10‘If a man commits adultery with another man’s wife, execute them both.’ Lev 20:10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;22“If a man is caught lying with a married woman, both of them will die. That’s how you’re to remove evil from Israel.” Lev 20:10; Deut 22:22&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;23“If a virgin is engaged, and another man lies with her, 24take them both to the city gate and stone them to death—the girl, because she didn’t scream in the city, and the man because he violated his neighbor’s wife. That’s how you’re to remove evil from Israel.” Deut 22:23-24 (engaged woman)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIANS AND TEMPORAL AUTHORITIES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/christians-and-temporal-authorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/christians-and-temporal-authorities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIANS AND TEMPORAL AUTHORITIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In non-Christian societies, people wonder whether they can continue in their jobs if they become Christians. The minister of a new congregation in Moscow asked about that issue. A policeman had asked whether he would have to quit his job if he accepted Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A policeman would not have to give up his source of income in accepting Christ. Paul states the principle in 1 Corinthians 7:20: “Let people stay in the calling where they were when they were called.” Paul is addressing marriage issues, but he is drawing on a broader principle because he also connects it with slavery (7:21-24) and circumcision (7:18-19). Christianity is transcultural and trans-vocational; it has no racial, social, marital, economic, societal, or vocational association.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON DIVORCE: MATTHEW 5:32</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comments-on-divorce-matthew-532/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comments-on-divorce-matthew-532/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON DIVORCE: MATTHEW 5:32&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Everyone that puts away his wife—except for sexual immorality—treats* her like an adulteress, and whoever marries a divorced woman commits adultery.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For purposes here, we pass over some technicalities associated with the aorist passive infinitive (μοιχευθῆναι, moicheuthēnai, “makes her to be adulterated[?]”) and deal with more straightforward considerations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus teaches that divorce is contrary to God’s original intention for marriage. Marriage is no longer the way it was under the Mosaic Law, where a husband could legally divorce his wife even if she had not been unfaithful. No longer could he, for example, use divorce to avoid adultery—divorce his wife to marry “the other woman.” Such a thing amounts to adultery in motive and attitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETHICS AND THE GOLDEN RULE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ethics-and-the-golden-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ethics-and-the-golden-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETHICS AND THE GOLDEN RULE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Treating other people the way we want to be treated implies the fundamental continuity of humankind. Variations between people do exist, but they do not normally deal with matters that impinge on ethical considerations. Supposing the continuity of human nature as the background for the Golden Rule is preferable to supposing that the Golden Rule describes a non-content procedure, the approach of R. M. McIver, “The Deep Beauty of the Golden Rule” in Philosophy and Contemporary Issues, pp. 233-39.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETHICS STANDARDS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ethics-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ethics-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETHICS STANDARDS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the standard and the basis for it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In That Hideous Strength (p. 285) C. S. Lewis has Dr. Cecil Dimble telling his wife that polygamy was not wrong for Abraham. That comment seems misleading, but it does raise the question about standards. There seems to be more than one way of speaking of an “ethical standard.” There is (a) the ideal standard, the one that God has always had in mind for everyone everywhere. The ideal standard is based on the originating purpose of God before creation. PURPOSE&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIXED MARRIAGE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/mixed-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/mixed-marriage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MIXED MARRIAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture says so much about marriage because it is a universal experience. Besides, it is an intense experience. Married life calls for more skill and understanding than other relationships. It is harder than living alone because it is more complicated, especially when children enter the picture. It is harder than being a good neighbor, getting along with people at work, or even living together in the community of faith. Marriage affects the full range of life rather than just some aspects of it (total). The actions of one partner likely affect the other, and marriage involves a degree of intimacy. We find it possible—and even fulfilling—to relate to many people in varying degrees of “distance” or “closeness,” but in marriage there is no “distance,” and nothing is hidden. Besides, marriage is all the time whereas work is only part of the waking hours and not every day. Marriage is exclusive of all other relationships; its distinctives are not experienced with anyone else. Finally, marriage is permanent while other relationships are not necessarily for life. In a universal, total, permanent, exclusive relationship, it is imperative that the partners share at least the basic values by which marriage operates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIMARY FACTORS IN ETHICAL THEORY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/primary-factors-in-ethical-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/primary-factors-in-ethical-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRIMARY FACTORS IN ETHICAL THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preliminary Factors&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conclusions about specific moral matters depend on what framework we use when we think about them. Several fundamental constructs set limits on how Christians should act. The factors involved help us interpret scripture correctly when it does address moral issues we face. Those factors are particularly vital when we have to generalize biblical standards to questions that special revelation does not address.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first primary framework focuses on start-up factors that impact human behavior:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESPONDING TO ETHICAL RELATIVITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/responding-to-ethical-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/responding-to-ethical-relativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RESPONDING TO ETHICAL RELATIVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relativity in ethics seems sensible because (a) incompatible moral beliefs and practices exist, and (b) no one seems able to establish a universal basis for ethical theory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In response to the second point, (1) the presence of a universal God (creator, sustainer, intervener) provides that universal basis. It does so because he had purpose in creating and if he has created us in his image. Furthermore, (2) human nature is universal for humans. We should not do what is contrary to human nature physically, psychologically, and socially; we should practice what enhances well-being, peace, and unity under God’s values. Presumably there is a hierarchy of what yields greater or lesser satisfaction, gratification, peace, and happiness, according to how well actions correlate with the givens of human nature—matters like the desire to be loved, the drive for worth, the urge for security, the impulse for innocence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOME VALUES OF LOVE AS AN ETHICAL PRINCIPLE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/some-values-of-love-as-an-ethical-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/some-values-of-love-as-an-ethical-principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOME VALUES OF LOVE AS AN ETHICAL PRINCIPLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Love gets us past legal minimums of do’s and don’t’s. It provides a basis for going beyond the call of duty, takes into consideration other people’s differing preferences, watches out for negative effects on weaker brothers’ behavior, and concerns itself with good and better, not just with good and bad. Love fosters a concern for enhancing the quality of other people’s lives, not just with the rightness or wrongness of specific behaviors relative to some standard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STRAY NOTATIONS ON THE COMPLEXITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/stray-notations-on-the-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/stray-notations-on-the-complexity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STRAY NOTATIONS ON THE COMPLEXITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF ETHICAL BEHAVIOR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ethics and morality relate to the interpersonal realm, with humankind. Since persons in relationship constitutes the most complex reality there is, ethics is a complex discipline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. The complexity of ethical theory comes from the fact that several principles determine right and wrong, and these principles are not of equal value. There is a plurality of unequal principles. Purpose, relationship, and nature are three primary factors that form the morality matrix; but subsidiary ones come into the picture as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THREE THOUGHTS ON ABORTION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/three-thoughts-on-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/three-thoughts-on-abortion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THREE THOUGHTS ON ABORTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.  Not My Body, Not My Choice&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is the other within the mother. It has its own DNA, its own blood type, its own sex, its own body type, skin tone, eye color, and eventually all the features that make it a distinct individual. Choice does come into the picture; it comes in the mother’s behaviors prior to the pregnancy. We have no right to take out on the baby our own sexual irresponsibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A FORMAT FOR THINKING ABOUT FEET WASHING</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-format-for-thinking-about-feet-washing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-format-for-thinking-about-feet-washing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A FORMAT FOR THINKING ABOUT FEET WASHING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Washing feet comes up in three New Testament texts. (a) Luke 7:44 refers to it in an episode about a sinful woman who anointed Jesus’ feet with ointment, wet them with her tears, and wiped them with her hair (7:36-50). (b) Among characteristics of widows enrolled in the church’s benevolence program, Paul lists “washing the saints’ feet” together with parenting, showing hospitality to strangers, and works of Christian living (1 Timothy 5:10). (c) In the upper room the night of his betrayal, Jesus washed his disciples’ feet (John 13:1-16). The last text has prompted some Christians to consider feet washing an ordinance like communion and baptism—or as a part of the communion observance. The paragraphs below analyze this view, giving special attention to the reasoning that seems natural to the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“IN THE DAYS OF THOSE KINGS”: DANIEL 2:44</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/in-the-days-of-those-kings-daniel-244/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/in-the-days-of-those-kings-daniel-244/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“IN THE DAYS OF THOSE KINGS”: DANIEL 2:44&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Daniel 2:44 those kings [מֶלֶךְ] seems to refer to the preceding four kingdoms [מַלְכוּ] of 2:38-43. Daniel uses kingdom and king somewhat interchangeably in that king can by metonymy stand for the realm he rules, even though over a period of time there may be several kings in one kingdom. In 2:39 the writer says, “And after you, Nebuchadnezzar, will arise another kingdom inferior to you.” A similar shift of terms comes in 2:44, “In the days of those kings the God of heaven will set up a kingdom . . . it will break all these kingdoms in pieces and consume (them).” Later in 7:17 the four beasts from the sea (7:3; earth, 7:17) are said to represent four kings, whereas 7:23 says that “the fourth beast will be a fourth kingdom that will be different from all the kingdoms.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ANIMAL SYMBOLISM IN BIBLICAL APOCALYPTIC</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/animal-symbolism-in-biblical-apocalyptic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/animal-symbolism-in-biblical-apocalyptic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANIMAL SYMBOLISM IN BIBLICAL APOCALYPTIC&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within prophecy generally, apocalyptic has several distinguishing characteristics. As to content, apocalyptic deals with eschatological reference, angelic emphasis, cataclysm, universal-cosmic scope, pessimism in people, divine sovereignty, transcendence, the concept of final comfort. As to form, apocalyptic uses animal symbolism and numerology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In chronological order the apocalyptic passages in scripture are Isaiah 24-27 (+ 6); Ezekiel 33-48 especially; Daniel 2, 7-12; Zechariah generally (although in many places the book is non-apocalyptic prophecy); the Olivet Discourse in Matthew 24-25, Mark 13, and Luke 21; 1 Thessalonians 4:1-5:11; 2 Thessalonians 2:1-12; and the Book of Revelation generally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APPROACHING THE MILLENNIAL ISSUE WITH</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/approaching-the-millennial-issue-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/approaching-the-millennial-issue-with/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPROACHING THE MILLENNIAL ISSUE WITH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MINISTRY IN MIND&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regarding end times, we can learn a lesson from Jewish religious leaders of Jesus’ day. They had so exactly worked out their understanding of Messianic prophecy that they did not recognize the Messiah when he came. We will not be that wrong this time. We will recognize him, because his return will not be a local, private entrance into the human sphere (Matthew 24:23-27). Nevertheless, we need to hold tentatively to our expectations about the timing of that event, about its relationship to other future events, and about the very nature of some related events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETERNAL OPPORTUNITY FOR SALVATION THROUGH CHRIST?</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/eternal-opportunity-for-salvation-through-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/eternal-opportunity-for-salvation-through-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETERNAL OPPORTUNITY FOR SALVATION THROUGH CHRIST?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. An Unnecessary Concept&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the assumption, for the moment, that eternal opportunity for salvation through Christ could not be disproved, we should consider several matters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Other preferable observations adjust our understanding of hell so that eternal option is unnecessary. A big impetus for the doctrine of eternal option comes from the apparent impropriety of a loving God torturing sinners endlessly in hell for no remedial purpose; punitive purpose seems not to call for such severity if punishment should be commensurate with the crime. Several factors reduce the urgency of this “problem.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESURRECTION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/resurrection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/resurrection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RESURRECTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;Biblical References to Resurrection&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Old Testament&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exodus 3:6 (Matthew 22:29-32)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 19:25-27&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 26:19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Daniel 12:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ezekiel 37:1-14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Deliverance from Sheol”: Psalm 49:15; 73:24-25; Proverbs 23:14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note Hebrews 11:10, 13-16, 19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;New Testament&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 5:25-29&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 6:39-40, 44, 54&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 11:24-25&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 14:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 17:24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 5:1-10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Thessalonians 4:13-16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revelation 20:4-6?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revelation 20:13&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Resurrection of the wicked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Daniel 12:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 5:28-29&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DOCTRINE OF “SOUL-SLEEPING”</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-doctrine-of-soul-sleeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-doctrine-of-soul-sleeping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DOCTRINE OF “SOUL-SLEEPING”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Views of the human condition during the intermediate state differ as to whether it is a conscious existence. Conscious existence means that between death and the general resurrection, we experience the rewards and punishments later to be publicly declared at the great white throne judgment. Unconsciousness during that time has two possibilities: “soul sleeping” or non-existence. The second option means that when we die, we cease to exist objectively until God “recreates” us out of his memory, an event simultaneous with, or the same as, resurrection. For all practical purposes, soul sleeping amounts to the same thing though, strictly speaking, we do objectively exist. The following considerations go into evaluating the concept of “soul sleeping.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE OLIVET DISCOURSE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-olivet-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-olivet-discourse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE OLIVET DISCOURSE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two related questions may be asked regarding Matthew’s account of the Olivet Discourse. (1) Who or what is the “abomination of desolation” in 24:14? (2) If some events are still future, where is the dividing line between the ones now fulfilled and the ones still to come? All three synoptists record this sermon: Matthew 24-25; Mark 13; and Luke 21.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since answering the second question determines the answer to the first, we need to establish the dividing line between past and future events first. A harmony of the accounts helps track the progress of thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE SEVENTY-WEEK PROPHECY OF DANIEL 9</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-seventy-week-prophecy-of-daniel-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-seventy-week-prophecy-of-daniel-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE SEVENTY-WEEK PROPHECY OF DANIEL 9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The beginning time for the seventy “weeks/hebdomads” is best placed at the first year&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;of Darius, the son of Ahasuerus (538 B.C.).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;The word/commandment that goes forth in 9:25 seems to be the same as the word/&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;commandment that went forth in 9:23a.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The terminology is the same: “the going forth of the commandment” (מֹצָא דָבָר) in 9:25 is parallel to “the commandment went forth” (יָצָא דָבָר) in 9:23. (In appropriate circumstances דָּבָר may be translated “commandment”: Exodus 34:28; Joshua 1:13; 1 Chronicles 26:32; Esther 1:19, etc.) In 9:23 there may be another reference to the same thing in the expression “consider the commandment” (בִּין בַּדָּבָר), although usually the word דָּבָר is translated “matter” or some other indefinite way here. Gabriel may be telling Daniel to understand the outworking of this word of God that has been decreed (9:24) on Israel and Jerusalem. The vision (מַרְאָה) of 9:23b is then in reference to the whole of 9:24-27.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ATTRIBUTES OF GOD</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/attributes-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/attributes-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ATTRIBUTES OF GOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suggested breakdowns&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Communicable and incommunicable: attributes that can or cannot be&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;communicated to his creatures&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Absolute and relative: those which belong to God independently and those that he&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;shares with his creatures in varying degrees&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Immanent and transcendent: those which belong to God’s inner being and those&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;which pass over to his creatures&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Individual and relational&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two ways by which we speak of God’s nature even though by experience we do not know what spirit is like: (a) by negating the characteristics of the material/physical world; (b) by taking shared characteristics via imago dei and pushing them to absolutes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FATHER, SON, AND HOLY SPIRIT: THREE-IN-ONE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/father-son-and-holy-spirit-three-in-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/father-son-and-holy-spirit-three-in-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FATHER, SON, AND HOLY SPIRIT: THREE-IN-ONE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sense in which Father, Son, and Spirit are three&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and the senses in which they are one&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at the same time to the exclusion of all optons&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Distinctness within the One Deity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trinity question calls for analyzing activities between Father, Son, and Holy Spirit. Approaches based on words are less satisfactory because words can vary in their meanings. Many attempts to arrive at a scriptural understanding, however, rely on (unclear) words rather than on (clearer) relational behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOREKNOWLEDGE AND SIN</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/foreknowledge-and-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/foreknowledge-and-sin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOREKNOWLEDGE AND SIN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God’s reasons for creating us are summarized under divine self-fulfillment (delight), goodness (grace), glory and betterment. Of these four reasons the first and last are personal while the other two are interpersonal. The first two are the reasons for people; the third is the purpose of people beyond themselves. If we speak strictly about the purpose of people, we focus attention on God’s goodness and on what grow out of it, particularly dominion and commission. Self-fulfillment highlights the unnecessitated satisfaction that moves persons to express themselves. Goodness roughly corresponds with God-to-man action; glory corresponds with man-to-God re-action. We say “roughly” because we cannot draw a sharp line between these aspects, which is exactly what we expect in the highly complex, reciprocating, transacting activity that interpersonal process involves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOD KNOWN AS “HE”</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/god-known-as-he/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/god-known-as-he/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GOD KNOWN AS “HE”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture consistently characterizes God in masculine terms. At the grammatical level, that pattern expresses itself in Hebrew masculine pronouns, adjectives, and verbs. “She” never designates the God Yahveh in any book of either testament.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the noun אלהים, “God/god,” does rarely refer to a goddess (1 Kings 11:33, Ashtoreth), but that never happens with the God of Israel. Not only do masculine pronouns refer to אלהים—and all his other designations—but Hebrew verbs with it carry masculine gender terminations. (Hebrew verbs have gender in the second and third persons.) Masculine adjectives likewise modify אלהים. This characterization holds true for Greek texts as well, which show θεός in the New Testament and the Greek translation of the Old Testament (LXX).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAYOUT OF THOUGHTS ON DEUTERONOMY 6:4</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/layout-of-thoughts-on-deuteronomy-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/layout-of-thoughts-on-deuteronomy-64/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LAYOUT OF THOUGHTS ON DEUTERONOMY 6:4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;יהוה אלהינו יהוה אהד&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Yahveh our God is one Yahveh.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Yahveh is our God, Yahveh alone.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Yahveh is our God, Yahveh is one.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Yahveh is our God; Yahveh is unique.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Jewish                                &#x9;   &#x9;  A  Jewish&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Viewpoint      &#x9;Response      &#x9; Response                   &#x9;Counter-response&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deuteronomy 6:4  “us”              &#x9;(a) majestic plural        &#x9;Genesis   3:22*   “one   of   us”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;does not mean majestic plural;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;it is the clearest Old Testament&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;text   on   plurality   associated&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DIVINE TRINITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-divine-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-divine-trinity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DIVINE TRINITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Methodology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.  &#x9;Investigate the activities of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit (as well as statements about them) in passages where they are mentioned together, thus observing interaction in real circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Examples of relational activities are clearer than abstract statements about relationship. That procedure minimizes problems created by figurative language, the various meanings that words like “one” can have, and the possibility of accommodation to our mode of thinking and being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PROBLEM OF EVIL</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-problem-of-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-problem-of-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PROBLEM OF EVIL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ANTILOGISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Supposedly only two of these points of the antilogism may be affirmed at any one time. The solution to an antilogism comes by adding new factors, which implies that one of the factors is not an absolute bereft of circumstantial qualifications. Evil is not an absolute, and neither are the other two characteristics. As omnipotence is qualified by holiness, all three of these points are qualified by love. Love, for example, may allow free will to be used to do evil rather than stifle every attempt to misuse free will. The most important consideration in the presentation below is that a larger category surrounds the antilogism—the interpersonal one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRINITY THOUGHTS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/trinity-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/trinity-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRINITY THOUGHTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Letter to a friend&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I took the opportunity presented by your question Sunday to assemble some thoughts that can also be part of the internet ministry effort I am working on. There is probably enough here to founder a good-sized horse, but that is the risk you take when you raise a good question that is at the same time complex and controversial. The first attachment I wrote up new as a second-level treatment of the trinity issue as I have come to see it. The other two attachments are more elaborate because they are lifted from my notes on Christian Doctrine, a course I taught at Manhattan Christian College for many years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIEWS OF DEITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/views-of-deity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/views-of-deity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VIEWS OF DEITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God/god refers to ultimate reality. Christianity views God as eternal, ethical interpersonality with certain other knowable attributes. In contrast, the ancient nations around Israel as well as peoples living in modern times have concepts of deity that are incompatible with the biblical understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Theism. A general term for belief in God, usually considered transcendent and personal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Atheism. The disbelief in the existence of any deity. All reality has one level, non-theistic. God is not a direction-setting aspect within the universe (panentheism, theistic naturalism), nor is he transcendent to the universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIME FACTS ABOUT THE HOLY SPIRIT</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/prime-facts-about-the-holy-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/prime-facts-about-the-holy-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRIME FACTS ABOUT THE HOLY SPIRIT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Spirit is a person, not a force, idea, emotional surge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Spirit is deity: Psalm 138:7-10; Matthew 28:19; Acts 5:3 (+ 4/9?); 1 Corinthians 2:10-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11; 12:4-6; 13:14; 2 Corinthians 1:21-22; Ephesians 4:4-6; Hebrews 9:14.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Spirit “proceeds” from the Father and the Son: John 14:16.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a difference between the Spirit (personal) and manifestations of the Spirit:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;miraculous manifestation via direct descent, laying on of hands, and answered prayer;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RELATING TO GOD THROUGH</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/relating-to-god-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/relating-to-god-through/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RELATING TO GOD THROUGH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SUBJECTIVE EXPERIENCE AND OBJECTIVE REVELATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every perversion of Christianity has been some kind of departure from its interpersonal nature and purpose. The difficulties that have arisen in teaching, practice, and experience have resulted from depersonalizing God or people and from de-interpersonalizing Christian experience. Christianity addresses persons in relationship both vertically and horizontally because that is the most encompassing, most basic, and most complex reality we participate in. The Christian faith is distorted if it degenerates into impersonal experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY OBSERVATIONS ON BIBLICAL MIRACLES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-observations-on-biblical-miracles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-observations-on-biblical-miracles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY OBSERVATIONS ON BIBLICAL MIRACLES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Types of Occurrences: divine miracle, demonic miracle, answered prayer, psychological,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;magic&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II.&#x9;Characteristics of Biblical Miracle&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Many: vs. occasional&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Immediate: vs. taking place over a period of hours, days, or months as perhaps in&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;natural healing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Always successful: vs. occasional success as perhaps something merely unusual&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D.&#x9;Varied: vs. just certain kinds of things that might be more easily faked or misread&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE WORK OF THE SPIRIT</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-work-of-the-spirit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-work-of-the-spirit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE WORK OF THE SPIRIT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The Relationship of the Spirit’s Natural and Supernatural Operations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The diagram above pictures at least three truths about the Spirit’s work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;A person cannot have the miraculous without the interpersonal relationship. The non-miraculous must be in place before the miraculous becomes possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;The miraculous is a non-essential, non-uniform add-on, whereas the interpersonal, non-miraculous is uniform for all Christians, everywhere, in any age. The second tier does not have to be added on, and when it is added on it is not added on for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MANKIND</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/mankind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANKIND&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;&#x9;The Purpose of Mankind&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II.&#x9;&#x9;The Image of God in Mankind&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;III.&#x9;&#x9;The Effects of Sin on Mankind (See What the Bible Says About Salvation, pp. 38-45.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;&#x9;Section I: Consequences of sin: personal perversion and meaninglessness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;&#x9;Section II: Consequences of sin: guilt, alienation, and destruction of the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;environment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;&#x9;Section III: Perpetuating sin: ignorance&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once sin entered the human race, it moved from person to person, from generation to generation down to our own day. We get it started it on our own and keep it moving “unassisted”; we get a lot of help from other people! In this section we are thinking about the ways our ignorance can get sin started and keep it moving without the input other people often give.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PURPOSE OF MANKIND:</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-purpose-of-mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-purpose-of-mankind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PURPOSE OF MANKIND:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;QUESTIONS AND ANSWERS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Section I: God’s Delight&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given his nature, God decided on certain purposes. In light of those purposes, he made the creation, including humankind. So God made the nature of man the way he did because of the purposes he had for us in his creation and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God made mankind simply because he delighted in doing so. Aside from any further considerations, persons experience fulfillment in being creative. The same holds for our personal God. Because of sheer delight, God expressed himself creatively and “saw that it was good.” That recurring statement in Genesis 1 expresses his sense of satisfaction in doing so (Genesis 1:31; cp. 1:4, 10, 12, 18, 21, 25). In that respect, God created us for something of the same reason he made the rest of creation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNITY AND DIVERSITY IN THE UNIVERSAL BODY OF CHRIST</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/unity-and-diversity-in-the-universal-body-of-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/unity-and-diversity-in-the-universal-body-of-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UNITY AND DIVERSITY IN THE UNIVERSAL BODY OF CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By creation, all human persons have the image of God, which means they have the interpersonal capacity and equal inherent worth. Since the image exists at the individual level, we must view the created variants as “modes of the image.” Sex, race, size, intelligence, athletic ability, physique, age, and the like do not affect inherent worth and can therefore have no place in our attitude toward ourselves or other people. We do not have to be married to participate in the image, we do not have to become Jews to be a favored people, we do not have to speak English to be part of the kingdom, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THINKING ABOUT GOD’S WILL</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/thinking-about-gods-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/thinking-about-gods-will/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THINKING ABOUT GOD’S WILL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Asking whether something that happened was God’s will, depends on what the question means. There are two possibilities:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;what God causes/what he makes happen (prescriptive will) and&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;what he allows to happen (permissive will).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What he causes starts with him; he initiates it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What he allows starts outside of him; something/someone else initiates it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is also a difference between supernatural intervention and natural cause. In the first case, God directly does what occurs; in the second case, he allows built-in laws to carry things forward; he is working “indirectly.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NOTATIONS ON GENERAL REVELATION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/notations-on-general-revelation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/notations-on-general-revelation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTATIONS ON GENERAL REVELATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Terminology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;General revelation refers to natural experiences in the natural universe. Special revelation refers to what comes through visible divine intervention into the natural. The former deals with nature, natural processes, natural events, and can include social processes, human history, subjective experience. The latter deals with supernatural intervention that a person can recognize as supernatural because it does not occur naturally. Intervention labels what God causes beyond what natural process produces. It refers to supernatural occurrences and their meaning given through special revelation. For us, special revelation centers on the revelation preserved in scripture. General revelation comes through the aspects of reality that science studies. Special revelation comes through scripture and involves inspiration. General revelation serves as the basis of philosophy, which uses reason to “discover” truth from experience. Special revelation is the basis for theology, which uses reason to “understand” truth in light of experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE RELATIONSHIP OF GENERAL REVELATION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-general-revelation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-general-revelation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE RELATIONSHIP OF GENERAL REVELATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TO THEISTIC PHILOSOPHY IN ROMANS 1-2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpreters commonly take Romans 1:18ff as an instance where Paul lays out the theistic argument. Then they conclude that it is possible to establish the existence of the one infinite, true God and certain of his attributes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study proposes that Paul is not presenting an argument for God’s existence based on general revelation. Rather, he declares from special revelation the lostness of all people, against whom God’s wrath is revealed. Romans 1:18ff views collective humanity from the creation till the coming of the gospel. He presents (1) a collective anthropological viewpoint (2) in a revelational framework (3) from a total historical perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADDED NOTATIONS ON SABBATH OBSERVANCE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/added-notations-on-sabbath-observance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/added-notations-on-sabbath-observance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADDED NOTATIONS ON SABBATH OBSERVANCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discussions with seventh-day Christians include five questions. (1) The first question asks for the scripture basis for “changing” Saturday to Sunday as the day of observance. That question miswords the issue. It “begs the question” by assuming that the issue involves a change from one day to the other. Our approach notes that Sabbath was a memorial of the exodus, a Jewish national holiday; so there is no basis for Sabbath observance outside the context of Jewish national life. There will be no “scripture basis” for “changing” from Sabbath to Sunday, because there was no “change.” The two items are not in series but in parallel. The two days have different meanings relative to different “nations” and different founding events. It is not a matter of one continuing entity changing one of its national holidays from one day to another. Since this matter relates to the change of covenants, consult the essay entitled “Old Testament Covenants and the Messianic Covenant.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUNDAY WORSHIP</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/sunday-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/sunday-worship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUNDAY WORSHIP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Worship on Saturday after sundown&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the New Testament we encounter the Jewish custom of reckoning days from sundown to sundown as distinguished from the Roman reckoning from midnight to midnight. The question sometimes comes up whether Christians today could have church on Saturday evening instead of Sunday morning and/or Sunday evening.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do not conceive of Sunday as beginning at dark the night before. It is doubtful that we would be associating Saturday evening with the Lord’s resurrection day. It would still be, as we say, Saturday evening. Of course, not all Christian gatherings have to associate the time of gathering with the time of his resurrection; but it is most appropriate to incorporate that association into the “stated” gathering time. All clear passages about the time of gathering in the New Testament place it on Sunday rather than some other day. Meeting on the day of his resurrection was consistent enough that “the Lord’s Day” (κυριακὴ ἡμέρα) became a designation for the first day of the week (Revelation. 1:10).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE SABBATH AS A MEMORIAL OF THE EXODUS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-sabbath-as-a-memorial-of-the-exodus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-sabbath-as-a-memorial-of-the-exodus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE SABBATH AS A MEMORIAL OF THE EXODUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Sabbath observance was not a memorial of the creation. If it were, it would have been observed as long as this creation stands: from the beginning, by all nations, till the end of time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. The Sabbath is a memorial only of the exodus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;A memorial will not be a memorial of two unrelated events. The emphasis here is on realities. The creation and the Sabbath are both associated with the week, but they are not related by their nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“FRIENDS” OR “SONS”? IMPLICATIONS FOR PERSEVERANCE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/friends-or-sons-implications-for-perseverance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/friends-or-sons-implications-for-perseverance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“FRIENDS” OR “SONS”? IMPLICATIONS FOR PERSEVERANCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“He’s God’s friend.” That is about the nicest thing a person can say about someone. In the mouth of God himself, Isaiah says, “Abraham, my friend” (Isaiah 41:8; cp. James 2:23; 2 Chronicles 20:7). Friendship implies several things about our relationship to God. Jesus tells us what he is doing—revelation (John 15:15); so “friend” better describes us than “slave” or “servant” does. Besides, he cares about us—a lot, enough even to die an excruciating death for us (John 15:13-15; Romans 5:6-8, etc.). That implies doing for us whatever else we need and cannot do for ourselves; that is what a friend does (Romans 8:32; 1 John 3:17). Friendship with God separates us from people that are at cross purposes with him: “Friendship with the world is enmity with God” (James 4:4); so we have the same values and purposes that he does. Experience shows us a number of points that help us understand what ideal friendship is like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASPECTS OF HUMAN RIGHTEOUSNESS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/aspects-of-human-righteousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/aspects-of-human-righteousness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ASPECTS OF HUMAN RIGHTEOUSNESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Goodness has several aspects. In relation to a standard, goodness is humanly measurable behavior relative to the divine ideal—as to its “letter” and its “spirit.” As to the behavior, goodness is the overt behavior (which tends to correlate with what is humanly measurable) but the motive, attitude, and character—generalized pattern vs. specific act. As to the setting, goodness has a subjective and objective aspect. As to the kind of interpersonal behavior, there is morality, wisdom, and ministry. These dimensions of goodness are detailed under the headings below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PREDESTINATION IN SHORT</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/predestination-in-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/predestination-in-short/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PREDESTINATION IN SHORT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Choice, act, consequence (free vs. fixed)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The choice itself is free, but the act is not necessarily free.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The act may be free, but the consequences are fixed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Permeable, semi-permeable, impermeable&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We choose our thought (permeable limit), but God may intervene between our choice and its fulfillment (semi-permeable; Abraham’s choice to sacrifice Isaac).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We may fulfill our chosen act, but God determines the consequences (impermeable).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The principle is true for individual acts, the sum total of life, and the whole of history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRESENTING THE GOSPEL TO “THE GOOD MORAL MAN”</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/presenting-the-gospel-to-the-good-moral-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/presenting-the-gospel-to-the-good-moral-man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRESENTING THE GOSPEL TO “THE GOOD MORAL MAN”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What do you do with a man like “Bob”? He really is a “good guy.” A happy, outgoing person that is glad to see you and always willing to stop and talk. Several years ago he quit a good-paying job so he could spend more time working with his only son, who became a successful race-car driver in our part of the country. One day he told me, “When I was a kid, my dad never had any time to do things with me. I’m not going to be that way with ‘Earl.’” I don’t know that I ever heard him use a “cuss” word. He gets along well with his wife . . . As far as Christ is concerned, what do you do with a man like “Bob”?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SHORTENING UP THE STUDY OF SALVATION FROM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/shortening-up-the-study-of-salvation-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/shortening-up-the-study-of-salvation-from/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SHORTENING UP THE STUDY OF SALVATION FROM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What the Bible Says About Salvation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since What the Bible Says About Salvation is rather long, using it in a church setting requires reducing it somewhat. There are two ways to reduce the amount of material and get at it more efficiently. First, use only the positive presentations (instead of looking at the alternative beliefs together with the reasons for and against them). Second, use the booklet Questions and Answers on “What the Bible Says About Salvation” on just the chapters (or parts of chapters chosen from the text itself).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NATURE OF SALVATION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-salvation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NATURE OF SALVATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Salvation as reconciliation is the most distinctive feature of Christianity. Herein lies the primary difference between the gospel, on the one hand, and the Law, wisdom literature, and the prophets, on the other. In this respect, Christianity differs from the purposes of previous divine economies and from the goals of other religions and human agendas. In Christ, God is concerned with more than letting people know that he exists, what he is like, what his moral standards are, and what his expectancies are within his purposes. Salvation is not simply from ignorance, as by revelation; it is not deliverance from physical existence as in Gnosticism and Eastern dualism; it is not a deliverance from individuality as in Hinduism. Salvation is reconciliation from alienation and from all the negatives that come from separation from God and other people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE UNEVANGELIZED ELECT?</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-unevangelized-elect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-unevangelized-elect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE UNEVANGELIZED ELECT?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Notion in a Nutshell: An Opinion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The diagram above takes its cue from Paul’s comments in Romans 2. God can judge unevangelized people on the basis of where their conscience has properly led them, the shaded area in the diagram. For practical purposes in that non-standard situation, God can disregard honest ignorance—where the conscience has misled and where it has omitted the rest of what Christianity stands for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TWO RESPONSES TO SIN</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/two-responses-to-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/two-responses-to-sin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TWO RESPONSES TO SIN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sin involves two issues that correspond to the two sides of a sin situation. There is the doing of a moral wrong and the reacting to a moral wrong. Because sin takes place between people, there is the person who does evil and the one who suffers evil. In resolving that circumstance, repentance happens on one side and forgiveness happens on the other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What happens, though, when there is no repentance? The basic principle seems to be that “where there is no repentance there is no forgiveness.” What people have done in the past they would do again unless they have changed, or “repented.” Without a change of mind, a change of heart, a change of resolve to behave differently, they are the same as they were when they sinned. Since “sin separates,” the separation continues because nothing has changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TWO SYSTEMS FOR RIGHTEOUSNESS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/two-systems-for-righteousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/two-systems-for-righteousness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TWO SYSTEMS FOR RIGHTEOUSNESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LAW [Moses]&#x9;GRACE [Messiah] (IP)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purpose of both: human righteousness (Gal. 3:21)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Righteousness is for fellowship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;with God and other people (IP).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Law and grace are parallel1 as to identity and kind&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Jer. 31:31-34 &amp;lt;Heb. 8:7-10:18; John 1:17; Rom 4:13-14; Gal. 3:21).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Principle of personal perfection (1 person)&#x9;Principle of trust in another to consider us&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deut 27:26; Lev. 18:5 (works&#x9;as perfect (Gen. 15:6; Hab 2:4)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>x x x,</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/x-x-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/x-x-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;x x x x,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your presentation follows the pattern used by Roman Catholic missionaries and many others, where general revelation (through nature) and theistic proofs bring someone to belief in God, his eternality, omnipotence, and other natural attributes. Special revelation adds a saving knowledge of God through Christ as holy, good, and loving (through history regarding God’s moral attributes). The first format has its precursor in Paul’s Areopagus speech; the second step follows Gamaliel’s argument in Acts 5, a resurrectiono-centric format in which the existence of the church and the fact of Jesus’ resurrection stand or fall together: the church exists; therefore, the resurrection occurred, Christ’s claim are true because resurrection is supernatural, and miracle confirms the claims of the miracle worker, etc. In the modern day, that two-step process has been enhanced by increased awareness of the complexity of nature with its accompanying tendency away from the likelihood that gradual change could explain chemistry-to-man by “endogenous complexification,” upward increase in complexity only by factors inside the natural order. Natural evolution replaces the need—not the fact/disproof—of supernatural deity; so it has become the apparent option for replacing the creationist model. A relevant observation, I might add, is that it is not possible to put in sequence the origin of reciprocating parts (especially for the level of observable complexity culminating in human social relationships).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“GOD-BREATHEDNESS” AS THE CHARACTER OF SCRIPTURE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/god-breathedness-as-the-character-of-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/god-breathedness-as-the-character-of-scripture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“GOD-BREATHEDNESS” AS THE CHARACTER OF SCRIPTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A series of words has traditionally stated from various angles the character of scripture in positive and negative terms. The list begins with the biblical expression in 2 Timothy 3:16, which translates literally as (1) “God-breathed.” The rather unhappy term in popular vogue for this passage is “inspired”; so “inspiration” becomes the corresponding noun for getting at the concept Paul expressed in the text. “Inspire,” however, does not properly picture the idea because it (a) creates the image of breathing into something the characteristic the word denotes—as when God “breathed into Adam the breath of life” and he became something more than he was. Such imagery limits the meaning of the text to what can add to something already there. The word picture in God-breathedness is that of “exhaling” the thing itself, so the scripture is regarded as issuing directly from God’s mouth. Scripture stands apart from all other writing by being viewed as God’s direct speaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 TIMOTHY 2:8-15: SITUATIONAL OR GENERAL?</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-28-15-situational-or-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-28-15-situational-or-general/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 TIMOTHY 2:8-15: SITUATIONAL OR GENERAL?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpreters have proposed several ways for removing from present observance of New Testament directives about male-female role relationship in the church and the home: 1 Timothy 2:8-15; 1 Corinthians 11:2-16; 14:33b-36; Colossians 3:18-19; and 1 Peter 3:1-7.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One way has been to (1) consider female deference a fallen condition (Genesis 3:16). Now that Christ has removed the curse, the principle no longer obtains. But the New Testament injunctions appear after Christ would have removed this supposed “curse.” Besides, “rule” (מָשַׁל, mashal) in Genesis 3:16 does not mean “rule” in some unwholesome sense as in a “cursed” estate; elders are to “rule well” in the church (1 Timothy 5:17; Hebrews 13:7, 17) and in the home (1 Timothy 3:4; cp. deacons in 3:11). Paul argues for female deference because the man was created first and the woman was deceived. In 1 Corinthians 11:7-9 the apostle adds that she was created from man and for man, and that Adam was created in the image of God (in some sense, degree, directness, or manner that Eve was not (cp. Genesis 2:21-23, 18).1 The five observations pertain to events that occurred before any fallen condition existed.2 Moreover, the other elements of the “fallen situation” in Genesis 3:14-21 have not been removed. Lastly, it is not a fallen condition that God is the head of Christ and that Christ is the head of every man, observations that Paul lays parallel to the man as the head of the woman (1 Corinthians 11:3; cp. Ephesians 5:23-24).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 TIMOTHY 2:9-15</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-29-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-29-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 TIMOTHY 2:9-15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Paul’s Intended Connection Between Genesis 2-3 and Women’s Roles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul appeals to the sequence of creation and the manner of the fall for his not allowing women to teach or to exercise authority over men. One inference is that (1) Paul appeals to Genesis to confirm, rather than to prove, the propriety of his custom; it is a post facto appeal rather than an a priori one. He says what he says by his own authority rather than because of a historical divine reason. His authoritative conclusion rests on some practical consideration rather than a theological one. Then cultural propriety can be the basis; so outside the first-century circumstance, it does not necessarily apply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 TIMOTHY 3:16</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/2-timothy-316/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/2-timothy-316/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 TIMOTHY 3:16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;πᾶσα γραφὴ θεόπνευστος καὶ ὠφέλιμος&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pāsa graphē theopneustos kai ōphelimos&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Variables in the English wording of this verse&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;all vs. every&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;scripture vs. writing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;commas vs. no commas [restrictive vs. non-restrictive adjective “God-breathed”]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;placement of is&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and vs. also&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two wordings seem to fit the context, which shows Paul&amp;rsquo;s evident concern to encourage Timothy in a good thing:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) “All/every scripture [is] God-breathed and profitable . . .”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2. 	Xenoglossia</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/2-xenoglossia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/2-xenoglossia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Xenoglossia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Glossolalia covers a range of speaking phenomena, including ecstatic utterance and “angelic tongues.” Cases occasionally come up in which someone speaks an actual language—xenoglossia. The following possibilities may be kept in mind when evaluating these cases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. &#x9;Mistaken identification&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1)&#x9;Someone who knows a few words of a language might suppose, upon hearing these sounds in a tongues situation, that the whole utterance is in that language. These sounds may have happened into the expression or were snatches of that language previously heard by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABSTRACT OF CONCEPTS RELEVANT TO WOMEN’S STUDIES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/abstract-of-concepts-relevant-to-womens-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/abstract-of-concepts-relevant-to-womens-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT OF CONCEPTS RELEVANT TO WOMEN’S STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Something must explain why equally committed Christians come out on different sides of the same issue from the same Bible. It is either because of (1) unconscious presuppositions, (2) faulty reasoning, (3) misunderstanding of how language works, or (4) inadequate concept inventory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following notations attempt to (a) map out the issues, (b) isolate the relevant interpretation principles, (c) define the exegetical task, and (d) identify the biblical texts most involved. They also try to (e) narrow down the point at issue so that irrelevant matters are set aside so that what we are sure of can lessen the practical problem in the church.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADDENDUM: “MALE AND FEMALE”</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/addendum-male-and-female/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/addendum-male-and-female/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADDENDUM: “MALE AND FEMALE”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Old Testament Occurrences&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Man/&#x9;&#x9;      &#x9;Septuagint Readings: Ralphs’ &amp;amp; Brenton’s Editions Combined&#x9;      MT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Animal Gender &#x9;          (ἄρσην/θῆλυς)                                                                    נְקֵבָה/זָכָר&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M&#x9;&#x9;n&#x9;Gen. 1:27&#x9;ἄρσεν καὶ θῆλυ &#x9;(“[God] made them male and female”)      Gen. 1:27&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M&#x9;  &#x9;n&#x9;        5:2&#x9;             &amp;quot;        &#x9;(“[God] made them male and female”)&#x9;        5:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A&#x9;   &#x9;n&#x9;        6:19&#x9;             &amp;quot;        &#x9;(&amp;ldquo;They will be male and female&amp;rdquo;)*      &#x9;        6:19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A&#x9;    &#x9;n&#x9;        6:20&#x9;             &amp;quot;&#x9;(“They . . . male and female”)*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A2&#x9;    &#x9;n&#x9;        7:22&#x9;             &amp;quot;&#x9;(“seven and seven, male and female”)&#x9;&#x9;  7:22&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADDITIONAL THOUGHT ON WOMEN’S STUDIES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/additional-thought-on-womens-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/additional-thought-on-womens-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADDITIONAL THOUGHT ON WOMEN’S STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Ministry Before Consensus”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some additional questions arise from previous presentations on women’s studies. For one thing, I have used “ministry” in the title of a paper that centered on leadership in relation to women&amp;rsquo;s roles. “Ministry” is broader than leadership, but leadership is the area in which disagreement about women&amp;rsquo;s roles has arisen. One way to help resolve controversial issues is to appeal to the larger category in which they stand. A title about “ministry” is useful on this subject because women are clearly free to make significant contributions to kingdom work; the question is whether they are free to make contributions in formal leadership ministry over men. Ministry as the larger category sets the context for leadership ministry. Any distinctive elements in the latter must be added in such a way as not to contradict the larger framework. The thesis in “Ministry Before Consensus” has been that we can carry forward the kingdom&amp;rsquo;s work significantly and with minimal negatives even before we resolve the problem. We can do that if we keep the problem clearly defined, if we keep it from spilling over into foreign issues, and if we maintain a proper understanding of Christian leadership. Women&amp;rsquo;s formal and informal Christian leadership ministry needs to conform to Christian leadership ministry generally, Christian leadership ministry needs to take place in a way that harmonizes with Christian ministry, and Christian ministry of every sort must retain the characteristics of interpersonal process. Since it is ministry that we want to get done, ministry is the subject area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ANALYSIS OF AUGUSTINE’S DOCTRINE OF EVIL</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/analysis-of-augustines-doctrine-of-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/analysis-of-augustines-doctrine-of-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANALYSIS OF AUGUSTINE’S DOCTRINE OF EVIL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The view of mankind common in evangelicalism descends from Augustine of Hippo. His early efforts in philosophy centered on the problem of evil. Although he spent his earliest years under the influence of Catholic Christianity, he left that background to become an Auditor for nine years in a Gnostic-like sect that followed the teachings of Mani. At first, Manichaeism seemed to him to explain the problem by teaching that evil and good are two kinds of substances. They have become intermingled in mankind so that “salvation” consists of separating good from its mixture with evil. Because of internal inconsistencies that Augustine came to see in this dualistic philosophy, he eventually left it and returned to Christianity. The problem of evil stood at the beginning of his development as a philosopher-theologian; its solution stood near the center of the theological system he formulated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APPLYING NEW TESTAMENT TEACHING</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/applying-new-testament-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/applying-new-testament-teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPLYING NEW TESTAMENT TEACHING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ON MARRIAGE, FAMILY, AND PUBLIC DECORUM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CONCEPT 1:  Family is the basic unit of society, more than the individual.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CONCEPT 2:  When order is added to personal relationship, the qualities of person relationship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;are not set aside.  Structure retains the interpersonal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CONCEPT 3:  Worth and the sense of worth come from behavior compared to responsibility, not&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;person compared to person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Worth comes from accomplished responsibility, not “success” in competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEHAVIORAL AND PSYCHOLOGICAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/behavioral-and-psychological-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/behavioral-and-psychological-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BEHAVIORAL AND PSYCHOLOGICAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God created us to have fellowship with him, so he made us in his image by giving us the interpersonal capacity. But in practice there has always been a breakdown in the realization of that potential in every individual, a breakdown we may call depravity.1 Like Satan and the fallen angels earlier, every one of us has failed to express our capacity adequately or correctly. In different ways and to varying extents we fail to function interpersonally, in conformity to our own created nature, and in accordance with divine purpose. With the exception of Jesus Christ, each of us has misused the specific abilities that comprise interpersonal capacity and its derivatives, and thereby has affected all aspects of ourselves, our relations, and our destiny; so we say that everyone has total depravity. It turns out that in varying degrees, depravity has been universal since the beginning and all-pervasive in every person that ever lived. Depravity means that although everyone has the real creatable image, no one fully has the ideal ethical image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER I</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/chapter-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/chapter-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NON-DENOMINATIONAL UNITY IN PERSPECTIVE AND PREVIEW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;General Framework in Diagram&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The framework of thought for this entire presentation is previewed in the following diagram. The diagram delineates four aspects of Christian unity as it relates to salvation, and shows their general correspondence to proposed divisions of the whole topic of unity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fig. 1.  Four Aspects of Christian Unity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soteriological Context:  Being&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Salvation and Unity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Individual unity with Christ” refers to the interpersonal relationship with Christ made possible by his moral perfection. Individual salvation both precedes and pervades the subsequent horizontal group aspects of Christian unity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER II</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/chapter-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/chapter-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER II&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PRELIMINARY CONCEPTS IN ORGANIZATIONAL THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Influence and Authority&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Definitions of Influence and Authority&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physical force, legal authority, and personal influence are three means of controlling persons. The distinctness, compatibility, and relationship of the latter two are especially important in a study of church organization. Authority is the legal right to compel the behavior only of status inferiors. Influence is the personal ability to impel the behavior even of status superiors. A study of organizational structure concerns itself with the pattern of authority flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER III</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/chapter-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/chapter-iii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE NEW TESTAMENT STRUCTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basic Structure&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter sketches the original organization of the universal church according to the evidence of the New Testament taken alone. As respects authority the approach will be to determine what positions have authority and to consider the rest as functions. This procedure is possible not only because an either-or matter is under consideration, but more particularly because authority includes function. One cannot suppose that a function is seen as such only because the evidence recorded happens to be insufficient to show that it was really an office. That approach becomes an argument from silence and shifts the burden of proof onto the negative. The negative burden of proof in this instance would be impossible since the only available evidence would pertain to function, which is part of the larger concept of office.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHAPTER IV</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/chapter-iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/chapter-iv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER IV&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE NORMATIVENESS OF THE NEW TESTAMENT STRUCTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Divine Origination&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prescriptive Divine Origin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The normativeness of the first-century pattern may be conveniently discussed under three headings progressively arranged: divine origin, intended permanence, and inherent exclusive-ness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Formal application&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christ’s lordship. Jesus Christ is an appointed King of a granted kingdom (Luke 19:12). The givenness of that entity includes its form—“kingdom”—as well as the principles of kingdom government–formal authority prescriptively applied. The organization of the church did not result from a natural process of crystallization among the disciples of Jesus, for Jesus was not a teacher like Socrates, who wrote nothing, founded nothing, and died, only to leave behind a group of followers that evolved a tradition of thought and practice. As to essential nature the church is kingdom as well as brotherhood. As regards government, the church may be called a Christocratic monarchy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON CREEDS AND RELATED MATTERS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comments-on-creeds-and-related-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comments-on-creeds-and-related-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON CREEDS AND RELATED MATTERS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture alone (sola scriptura) means using the Bible as the sole authority for Christian belief and practice. It sets aside other normative sources for the Christian faith: creeds, tradition, apocryphal works, ecclesiastical pronouncements, additional primary literature beyond the sixty-six books of the canon, and persons claiming inner light and special revelation. The fundamental issue is not doctrinal error as much as practical authority. Going beyond the apostolic witness does open up the possibility—even likelihood—of false doctrine; but even if it did not, these other sources are disregarded. Other writings may have devotional value and helpful insight, but they do not determine what Christians are to believe and practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON ORDINATION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comments-on-ordination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/comments-on-ordination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON ORDINATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Across Christendom ordination has had a variety of meanings. The most extreme position has been that (1) ordination validates the “administration” of sacraments. Unless a duly qualified clergyman presides, the sacrament is invalid in much the same way that a wedding performed by a person “off the street” would not be recognized by the state. A Justice of the Peace must be duly appointed to perform wedding ceremonies as an agent of the state. In this view, ordination is for theological reasons. The clergy concept is part of the larger idea that grace flows through the church, that is, through those who validly stand as executors of divine administration. It is a legal conceptualization like that of Justice of the Peace, validity being based on “apostolic succession.” Legal administration of grace, however, is a contradiction of terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONCLUSION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CONCLUSION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The church is saved people serving in divine pattern. The body of Christ possesses essential oneness by virtue of individual unity with Christ and collective unity through Christ. This invisible oneness is manifest by a dynamic structure-function called the church. Functional unity in Christ combines with organizational unity under Christ to form this non-denominational entity that has a fivefold oneness of attitude, doctrine, fellowship, name, and organization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a first major concern the historical argument for non-denominationalism focused particularly on the last of these elements: the organizational pattern of the church established under direct apostolic administration. Although the first four elements have probably never been fully present in the visible church, it was anticipated that sufficient evidence was available to show that formal oneness did exist in the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITERIA FOR A BIBLICAL VIEW OF HUMAN ABILITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/criteria-for-a-biblical-view-of-human-ability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/criteria-for-a-biblical-view-of-human-ability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITERIA FOR A BIBLICAL VIEW OF HUMAN ABILITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prevenient grace and natural depravity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In place of the natural depravity of traditional theology, we prefer to speak of psychological depravity. In doing so, we acknowledge the power of sin without considering ourselves subject to a determinism that results in lostness. In the construct of depravity plus prevenient grace, psychological depravity functions on the analogy of habit. Prevenient grace consequently omits natural regeneration from God’s acts of grace that precede salvation. A view of human ability is developed below under five criteria listed according to the sequence in which they apply to the process of restoration to fellowship with God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITIQUE OF AUGUSTINE’S VIEW OF EVIL</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/critique-of-augustines-view-of-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/critique-of-augustines-view-of-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITIQUE OF AUGUSTINE’S VIEW OF EVIL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Augustine’s treatment of the problem of evil falls short for two related reasons. (1) He did not properly distinguish natural and moral evil, suffering and sin, pain and guilt. In his thought, they amounted to the same problem. (2) He attempted to examine even moral evil primarily in reference to the category of nature. In so doing, he glossed over the distinction between impersonal and interpersonal reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D. 	Applying tests to contemporary claims of speaking in languages (“tongues speaking”)</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/d-applying-tests-to-contemporary-claims-of-speaking-in-languages-tongues-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/d-applying-tests-to-contemporary-claims-of-speaking-in-languages-tongues-speaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;D. &#x9;Applying tests to contemporary claims of speaking in languages (“tongues speaking”)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Glossolalia: misidentification&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. &#x9;Eclipse of the adult inhibition against babbling&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1)&#x9;Basic proposition: Much of what goes under the term tongue speaking (glossolalia) is a matter of overcoming the adult inhibition against babbling, the inhibition against making meaningless sounds. Factors that help break this inhibition are mistakenly identified as the energizing work of the Holy Spirit. The phenomenon itself is then misidentified with New Testament language speaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETHICAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE AS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ethical-observations-on-the-image-as/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ethical-observations-on-the-image-as/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETHICAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE AS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ethical Use of Imago dei&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) The image as interpersonal capacity connects the natural and the ethical usages of the expression image of God. One pervasive concern of biblical content is wholeness, the big picture, the synthetic emphasis in contrast to a dichotomistic, analytical, reductionist approach. That concern carries over into the terminology. The penchant for integration accounts for the rather facile shifting back and forth between natural, behavioral, and relational usages of terms like image, life, sin, flesh, create, knowledge, and wisdom associated with the creation narrative. Integration accounts for places where such expressions may combine these rather different, though related, concepts when dealing with subjects in broad scope.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVANGELICAL PERSPECTIVES ON MEN-WOMEN RELATIONSHIP</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/evangelical-perspectives-on-men-women-relationship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/evangelical-perspectives-on-men-women-relationship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVANGELICAL PERSPECTIVES ON MEN-WOMEN RELATIONSHIP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introductory Observations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general, women’s studies relate to the genetic nature of men and women and cultural expectancy regarding their interaction. Discussing evangelical perspectives on men and women in relationship adds biblical interpretation to the inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On this subject what makes a viewpoint evangelical is not so much the viewpoint itself as the accompanying attitude toward scripture and the consequent method of interpretation which that attitude involves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EXTREMELY SINFUL: Psalm 51</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/extremely-sinful-psalm-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/extremely-sinful-psalm-51/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EXTREMELY SINFUL: Psalm 51&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psalm 51 records David’s response to his sin with Bathsheba:  heading of the Psalm, “When Nathan the prophet came to him after he had gone into Bathsheba” (2 Samuel 11-12).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David’s redeeming quality was admission of his sin, his willingness to repent, and his concern to reach out to God for forgiveness: Psalm 51:1-4, 7-17, which is the bulk of the Psalm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David felt totally characterized by sin as when we say someone is a “born liar.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FEMALE METAPHORS FOR GOD</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/female-metaphors-for-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/female-metaphors-for-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FEMALE METAPHORS FOR GOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:27 Women and Men created in God’s image&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Humankind was created as God’s reflection: in the divine image God created them; female and male, God made them.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hosea 11:3-4 God described as a mother&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God: “Yet it was I who taught Ephraim to walk, I who took them up in my arms; but they did not know that I healed them. I led them with cords of human kindness, with bands of love. I was to them like those who lift infants to their cheeks. I bent down to them and fed them.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIVE MODELS FOR COMPLETELY RELIABLE SCRIPTURE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/five-models-for-completely-reliable-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/five-models-for-completely-reliable-scripture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FIVE MODELS FOR COMPLETELY RELIABLE SCRIPTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do not need to decide between the “theories of inspiration” to understand how scripture came to have the character of “God-breathedness” (2 Timothy 3:16). As we can judge from scripture itself, God operated in more than one way in producing scripture. The models of origin may be organized according to what God specially gave to his human spokesmen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God gave the words. Probably no one holds the dictation theory of inspiration strictly understood, even though people often suppose that Christians have that explanation for the origin of the Bible. It might apply to a few cases, notably the Ten Commandments, which in the first copy were written by the finger of God (Exodus 31:18; cp. also Daniel 5:25-28). In this format God operates in a significantly positive fashion (Daniel 5).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GALATIANS 3:28: A TEST CASE FOR SOUND HERMENEUTICS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/galatians-328-a-test-case-for-sound-hermeneutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/galatians-328-a-test-case-for-sound-hermeneutics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GALATIANS 3:28: A TEST CASE FOR SOUND HERMENEUTICS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“There is no male and female because you are all one in Christ Jesus” (Galatians 3:28). The wording of that part-verse has become a popular way for Christians to express the egalitarian principle that (a) in the home and in the church, there are no necessary role distinctions between the sexes. A man or a woman has the same theoretical “right” to lead. In its healthiest form, egalitarianism calls for “a fair field and no favors” in all parts of the social arena.1 A more extreme alternative to male headship is the belief that (b) in the home and in the church, there is only interpersonal leadership. Not only is there is no designated final responsibility in marriage and ministry referenced to sex; there is no hierarchical arrangement at all; there is only natural vs. formal leadership.2 Cooperation rather than structure is the ideal modus operandi. At least the first of these viewpoints is a proposed meaning of Paul’s statement to the Galatians. This study evaluates that reading in light of the evident exegetical and theological import of the passage, and addresses various ways by which women’s roles come or might come into its sphere of meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GREEK ELEMENTS IN THE INTERPRETATION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/greek-elements-in-the-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/greek-elements-in-the-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GREEK ELEMENTS IN THE INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF EPHESIANS 5:21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;editorial question&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Ephesians 5:21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does “defer to one another in the fear of Christ” belong with the preceding or succeeding context?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The United Bible Society’s text of the Greek New Testament puts the injunction with the preceding material in the third edition, but with the succeeding context in the third edition (corrected). Grammatically the participle “submitting” parallels participles in the preceding two verses—participles that grammatically modify the subject of the finite verb in 5:18. A free-standing participle can be a command; but clear cases of that usage are infrequent in the New Testament (Mark 5:23; Romans 12:92, 10?, 11?, 123?, 132? 163?, 172?, 18, 19; 13:11; 1 Corinthians 8:24; Ephesians 5:21?; Titus 2:7; 1 Peter 2:18; 3:1). Moreover, nothing grammatical calls for invoking that usage in Ephesians 5:21 because of the parallel between “deferring” and the preceding participles of 5:19-20: “. . . speaking to one another . . . singing and making melody . . . giving thanks . . . deferring to one another . . .” Grammatically, “deferring” ties with the preceding flow of thought by being parallel to the three preceding participles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HERMENEUTICS AND NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-and-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-and-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HERMENEUTICS AND NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exegetical Impasse&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A standoff has persisted in exegesis between Calvinistic and non-Calvinistic interpreters largely because no resolution can come at the level of individual passages that have implications for anthropology. A few examples illustrate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) Psalm 51:10 says, “Create in me a clean heart, O God; and renew a right spirit within me.” Ezekiel 18:31 shows another emphasis, “Make for yourselves a new heart and a new spirit.” The difficulty is whether Psalm 51:10 interprets Ezekiel 18:31 or vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HUMAN DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/human-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/human-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HUMAN DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overview of Natural Depravity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late fourth century Augustine, bishop of Hippo in North Africa, gave classical expression to natural depravity as part of his understanding of the nature of evil. In his thought, evil is a lack (privation) in the form of substance relative to its original form. That relatively deformed condition produces evil action. The nature of evil is lack, the cause of evil is lack in form, and the criterion of evil is lack in form compared to pristine form&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMAGE AND LIKENESS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/image-and-likeness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/image-and-likeness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IMAGE AND LIKENESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have not made a distinction between “image” and “likeness,” even though Genesis 1:26 uses two words to compare mankind and God. (a) Nothing in the context distinguishes them. Furthermore, (b) in most other passages only one term occurs, image in Genesis 9:6-7; 1 Corinthians 11:7; James 3:9 and likeness in Genesis 5:2 in an otherwise word-for-word parallel to 1:26. Like in Genesis 3:5, 22 translates a different item than in 1:26.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMPERATIVAL INTENT</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/imperatival-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/imperatival-intent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IMPERATIVAL INTENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Description of Imperatival Intent&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imperative forms can convey a range of meanings; they have (1) varied quality. In language, authorial intent does not bear a one-to-one relationship with linguistic forms. In assessing a writer’s use of the imperative mood, we look beyond the form itself and infer its force from the near and distant literary context, the historical context, and the nature of the case.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) Imperatives may entreat, where one wants a benefit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INDWELLING SIN: ROMANS 7</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/indwelling-sin-romans-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/indwelling-sin-romans-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INDWELLING SIN: ROMANS 7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Paul speaks of sin resident within him (or indwelling sin), perhaps he means it phenomenologically; that is, the experience of sin feels like something inside him. His point is that sin is not just something outside us (environment, influence) trying to tempt us into misaction; it is something inside us as well. There is a subjective as well as objective component in the sin phenomenon. The implication is personal responsibility for subjective response to objective influence and stimulus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Title&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This thesis examines the historical argument for organizational church unity. The New Testament Basis for the Non-Denominational Church: The Historical Argument is used as the title for two reasons especially: (1) clarity–a concept is most definite in the context of contrast; (2) relevance–denominationalism is a feature of contemporary Christendom that stands in contrast to what will be presented as the nature of the church’s unity according to the New Testament.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISSUES IN WOMEN’S STUDIES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/issues-in-womens-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/issues-in-womens-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ISSUES IN WOMEN’S STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Guided Study&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below are six items for thought and research on women’s studies. Some points may be referred to in Hermeneutics: Getting the Point; check the scripture index for locations. As much as possible, consciously integrate into your write-up the principles studied in the course.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some items involve work with the original languages and may not seem fully understandable to those who have not studied Greek. There is no expertise in biblical languages required, however, since the exercises are vocabulary items that can be looked at through Englishman’s Greek Concordance to the New Testament. On some questions students may want to consult Dr. Warren’s “Preliminary Essays on Women’s Studies.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ITEMS AFFECTED BY THE DOCTRINE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/items-affected-by-the-doctrine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/items-affected-by-the-doctrine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ITEMS AFFECTED BY THE DOCTRINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the nature of mankind is a central consideration in Christian theology, the doctrine of natural depravity in mankind affects a variety of issues and impacts them in significant ways. The following enumeration of consequences may not be necessary in every case, but historically this concept has triggered them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anthropology itself is significantly different because mankind is understood as born without the full spiritual capacity that Adam and Eve had before they sinned. Beyond the consequences of their sin that Genesis 3 and elsewhere indicate, natural depravity adds to the silence of scripture by saying that in some way—either by built-in natural result or direct divine penalty—their sin led to a defective genetic nature that everybody has biologically inherited. Because we all have descended from the same pair, we are all infected with this defect in every aspect of our being. The will is weakened so that we cannot resist temptation even when we want to. The affections are so disoriented that often we do not even want to resist. We do not love what we should. Even emotional disorders may integrate with natural depravity. Bodily drives are perverted, which accounts for unwholesome sexual desires, homosexuality, bestiality, gluttony, drunkenness, as well as inhibitive and compulsive behaviors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intellect is skewed at least relative to spiritual matters, so that we are blind to what should be “as clear as the nose on our face.” Some have integrated the concept more broadly by connecting it with the idea that supposedly people use only 5-8% of the brain’s capacity. That somehow represents the difference between the IQ of fallen and unfallen man. Unfallen Adam could use 100% of his brain power and was more intelligent than afterward. He supposedly had great intuitive knowledge as well as greater intellectual power than anyone has now. Some have claimed that he had such a grasp of natural science as is unattainable today (John Laidlaw, The Bible Doctrine of Man, 1895; see Gordon Clark, pp. 20-21).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James B. Torrance. Worship, Community &amp; the Triune God of Grace. Downers Grove, Illinois: InterVarsity Press, 1997. 130pp. Reviewed by Virgil Warren, Manhattan, Kansas.</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/james-b-torrance-worship-community-the-triune-god-of-grace-downers-grove-illinois-intervarsity-press-1997-130pp-reviewed-by-virgil-warren-manhattan-kansas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/james-b-torrance-worship-community-the-triune-god-of-grace-downers-grove-illinois-intervarsity-press-1997-130pp-reviewed-by-virgil-warren-manhattan-kansas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November 1994, James Torrance, professor emeritus of systematic theology at the University of Aberdeen, presented the Didsbury Lectures in the Nazarene Theological College, Manchester. InterVarsity Press offers these lectures in written form with a preface and appendix added by the author.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Worship is the central concern of the volume, which brings the author to emphasize the nature of God particularly as trinitarian and gracious. Worship is described as “our participation through the Spirit in the Son’s communion with the Father” (p. 15; cp. 21). We “worship the Father through the Son in the Spirit” (p. 22). We “participate through the Spirit in the incarnate Son’s communion with the Father” (p. 59). “The real agent in all true worship is Jesus.” Granted the ambiguities in such phraseology as “participation through the Spirit” and “Jesus as the only true agent,” we nevertheless see that Christ’s “priesthood” is not simply in regard to something completed; it is the sole ongoing basis for perpetual relationship to God, in life generally and in worship especially.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man &amp; Woman in Christian Perspective, by Werner Neuer</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/man-woman-in-christian-perspective-by-werner-neuer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/man-woman-in-christian-perspective-by-werner-neuer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Man &amp;amp; Woman in Christian Perspective, by Werner Neuer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Werner Neuer. Man &amp;amp; Woman in Christian Perspective. Trans. from the 2nd German edition by Gordon J. Wenham. Wheaton, IL: Crossway Books, 1991 [1981]. 224 pp. pr&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neuer begins by placing the relevance of his topic in the contemporary challenge of secular feminism, an important point because the church, in being biblical, should not be needlessly countercultural. Subsequent chapters on male-female differences reflect the natural assumption that in the family and in the church God has assigned role emphases correlated with sex in keeping with the way he has gifted males and females. Five chapters deal with the view of man and woman found in the Old Testament, the gospels, the epistles of Paul, the rest of the New Testament, and in church history. Two chapters address the continuing validity of the biblical viewpoint and the urgency of practicing it. The volume concludes with a summary of main points. Along the way, five excursi expand on texts and issues that call for more extended treatment than the ongoing presentation itself allows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAN AND WOMAN IN ADAM AND IN CHRIST</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/man-and-woman-in-adam-and-in-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/man-and-woman-in-adam-and-in-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MAN AND WOMAN IN ADAM AND IN CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One major argument for egalitarianism in marriage and the church pictures female deference as a fallen condition that has been reversed in Christ. “Your husband will rule over you” (Genesis 3:16) has changed to “In Christ there is no male and female” (Galatians 3:28). New Testament comments about male headship merely temporalize the Christian ideal in the interests of Christian mission. The following comments attempt to show that this scenario artificially combines unrelated ideas and overextends the cultural variable. Genesis 3:16 does not indicate a result of the curse, Galatians 3:28 is not an absolute principle, and statements elsewhere about headship are not necessarily pragmatic concessions to cultural norms that no longer apply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MINISTRY BEFORE CONSENSUS ON WOMEN’S ROLES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ministry-before-consensus-on-womens-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ministry-before-consensus-on-womens-roles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MINISTRY BEFORE CONSENSUS ON WOMEN’S ROLES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN THE CHURCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Practical situations have a way of forcing us to “get on with it” despite unresolved questions. While pragmatics fosters “caving in” to illegitimate pressures, it also keeps us from letting theoretical matters make the system dysfunctional and pushes us to put things in perspective. Current differences of understanding about the range of women’s roles in the church and the home offer one more example of the qualifying effect of practical need on doctrinal theory. The need to fulfill the mission mandate suggests that we adopt an interim approach that does justice to everything we are sure about in connection with this issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATURAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/natural-observations-on-the-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/natural-observations-on-the-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NATURAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter we offered restrictive guidelines for identifying the image of God—boundaries within which the understanding of image must fall. The image must be a creatable likeness that applies to the whole individual even after the Fall. Then we offered two sets of positive evidence for the image as interpersonal capacity to build the view “from zero.” There were two deductive arguments: (1) the interpersonal purposes of mankind predict interpersonal nature of man as the image; (2) being in the image of an interpersonal God implies that mankind is interpersonal. Finally, we made inductive observations: human peculiarities observed in connection with image terminology end up being aspects of interpersonal capacity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NOTATIONS ON 1 TIMOTHY 2:11-12</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/notations-on-1-timothy-211-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/notations-on-1-timothy-211-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTATIONS ON 1 TIMOTHY 2:11-12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does αὐθεντεῖν mean “exercise authority” or “domineer”?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) The law of contrast implies that αὐθεντεῖν does not mean “dominate” since it is a correlative term with ὑποταγή in the previous verse. Ἐν πάσῃ ὑποταγῇ and αὐθεντεῖν seem to be correlative expressions like learn and teach, with which they appear. Correlative terms stand in a common larger category as natural contrasts: lost-saved, father-son, prophecy-fulfillment, faith-works, and the like. Within the same context the sense in which one is meant is the sense in which the other is used. If father means physical father, then son means physical son, not spiritual son. If prophesy means to state a significant principle, then fulfill means to be an example of that principle, not the occurrence of a prediction. Correlative terms obey the law of contrast/opposition/negation inside the law of harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORDINATION: WHO AND WHOM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ordination-who-and-whom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/ordination-who-and-whom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ORDINATION: WHO AND WHOM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ordination to ministry involves three considerations: (1) the understanding of New Testament offices and ministry, (2) the New Testament meaning of ordination, and (3) the meaning attached to ordination by society today and by the state.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Who should be ordained?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the standpoint of the church, the New Testament does not evidence an understanding of ordination that corresponds with the traditional clergy concept. Ordination does not validate a person’s ministry. It does not bestow the right to preach, “administer sacraments,” pronounce absolution. The only ordination observed in the New Testament is an appointment to specific tasks. If done, ordination today simply commends an individual to the general Christian community. It indicates that in the ordaining congregation believes the person has the character, abilities, and skills appropriate to the calling. That has been sufficient to qualify him also for the rights vouchsafed to religious leaders by the state. So ordination has been a matter of expediency rather than necessity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORIENTATION TO ORDINATION</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/orientation-to-ordination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/orientation-to-ordination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ORIENTATION TO ORDINATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Ordination is for the one ordained.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ordination is for impressing on the person ordained the importance of his calling. People set aside time for things that are important. By setting aside time to concentrate on what it means to minister, the body of believers shows the person their regard for that calling. Ordination provides a time to be impressed with the significance of the “ministry of reconciliation,” as Paul called it (2 Corinthians 5:18-21).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PARAMETERS IN WOMEN’S STUDIES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/parameters-in-womens-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/parameters-in-womens-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PARAMETERS IN WOMEN’S STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Biblical Passages Relevant to Women’s Studies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exodus 15:20-21: Miriam and the women of Israel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Judges 4:4-5:31: judgeship of Deborah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Kings 22:14-20: Huldah the prophetess&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proverbs 31:10-31: description of a worthy woman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luke 2:9: Anna prophesied&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 2:18 &amp;lt; Joel 2:28-29: “Your sons and daughters will prophesy”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 21:9: Philip’s four daughters tht prophesied&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romans 16:1-3: Phoebe, a servant in the church at Cenchrea that Paul sent to Rome&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PASSAGES RELEVANT TO INERRANCY*</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/passages-relevant-to-inerrancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/passages-relevant-to-inerrancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PASSAGES RELEVANT TO INERRANCY*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psalm    19:7      &#x9;“The Law of the Lord is perfect, converting the soul.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;119:42   &#x9;“Your Law is truth.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;119:160&#x9;“The sum of your word is truth, and every one of your righteous&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ordinances endures forever. “&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew  4:4      &#x9;“Man will not live by bread alone, but by every word that proceeds out of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God’s mouth.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5:18     &#x9;“Till heaven and earth pass away, not one dot or one tittle will in any way&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PREVENIENT GRACE AND NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/prevenient-grace-and-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/prevenient-grace-and-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PREVENIENT GRACE AND NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have set aside the doctrine of natural depravity because (a) natural depravity lacks adequate primary biblical evidence for it. (b) Natural depravity creates contradictions. One set of propositions summarizes an argument against natural depravity. Since God is self-consistent, the variable that explains the Great Dilemma must lie outside God. Since only God and we figure in salvation, that variable must lie in us. We must be capable of responding to God; otherwise, God would be choosing who is saved by choosing whom he enables to respond to him unto salvation while saying that he does not want anyone to perish (2 Peter 3:9). As natural depravity in effect means divine self-contradiction, natural ability maintains divine self-consistency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIMARY EVIDENCE FOR THE IMAGE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/primary-evidence-for-the-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/primary-evidence-for-the-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRIMARY EVIDENCE FOR THE IMAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From evidence presented in the next three chapters, we conclude that having the image of God means having interpersonal capacity. At the outset we want to make explicit three notable ideas in the designation “interpersonal capacity.” (a) Interpersonal means that the image of God has to do with persons instead of things, forces, animals, or ideas. (b) Interpersonal relates the image to the social setting. The image involves more than the individual because it pertains to marriage, community, church, society, humankind as well as God’s purposes for persons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROCEDURES CONSISTENT</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/procedures-consistent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/procedures-consistent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROCEDURES CONSISTENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WITH A COMPLETELY RELIABLE TEXT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, a totally reliable text in principle represents the guiding characteristic of “scripture.” On the other hand, a certain amount of variability may happen in the manner by which biblical writings originated and passed down. Two assumptions underlie the suggestions below. (a) We need not invoke the supernatural as long as natural means can accomplish the purposes. God does not generally do for people what they can do for themselves. (b) The concern is reliability of the information, not prescription of forms (words).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROLEGOMENA FOR MEN AND WOMEN IN CHRIST</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/prolegomena-for-men-and-women-in-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/prolegomena-for-men-and-women-in-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROLEGOMENA FOR MEN AND WOMEN IN CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Précis   Neglected or misunderstood factors complicate any endeavor, including the interaction between men and women in the home, the church, and society. An unnecessary “edge” gets into discussions on this matter because of unconscious preconceptions about (a) the bases for self-esteem, (b) the nature of leaders and led and their interaction, and (c) the impact that love has on all interpersonal processes formal or natural.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSYCHOLOGICAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/psychological-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/psychological-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PSYCHOLOGICAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary/Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proposition counter to natural depravity is as follows: there is no (1) clear (2) biblical basis for saying that Adam’s ability in regard to (3) spiritual things after the fall was any different from what it was (4) before the fall in a (5) biologically inheritable sense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By “clear” biblical base we mean that some passages could be understood the way natural depravity takes them, but no passage requires such an understanding. In fact, many texts offered in support of that concept cannot have that meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STRUCTURING THE HERMENEUTICAL TASK IN WOMEN’S STUDIES: WISDOM OR LAW?</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/structuring-the-hermeneutical-task-in-womens-studies-wisdom-or-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/structuring-the-hermeneutical-task-in-womens-studies-wisdom-or-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STRUCTURING THE HERMENEUTICAL TASK IN WOMEN’S STUDIES: WISDOM OR LAW?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are inclined to think that some reasonable explanation lies behind the variant understandings of gender roles by equally sincere and capable Christian interpreters. Something must be happening in the minds of some that is not happening in others who likewise take a proper view of scripture. We suspect that part of the difficulty lies at (a) the linguistic level. People do not remember that the imperative mood can have more than one quality, hence, our essay elsewhere on “Imperatival Intent,” which assembles the different values that imperatives and their equivalents may have. Another part of the difficulty lies at (b) the corpus level. People make different assumptions about the nature of the New Testament as a body of normative literature, hence, this essay on “wisdom” vs. “law” and the accompanying excerpt on “Confusing Advice and Commandment.” What we have to say here comes in association with the accompanying diagram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUBMITTING TO ONE ANOTHER:</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/submitting-to-one-another/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/submitting-to-one-another/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUBMITTING TO ONE ANOTHER:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 5:21-6:9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This portion of Ephesians deals with “household teaching” on the relationship of husbands and wives, parents and children, masters and slaves. Other comparable texts are Colossians 3:18-4:1 and 1 Peter 2:(13-)18-3:7.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In regard to each relationship, Paul appeals to interpersonal principles to set the tone for it. In other places, he does the same thing to solve problems that impact practical relationships in the body (languages, 1 Corinthians 12-14; leadership, 2 Corinthians 10-13; etc.). He can do that because personal relationship is always the context in which further considerations exist and must exist in a way that does not interfere with that context. Paul implies that interpersonalism should carry the process as much as possible. Only when influence for practical reasons is inadequate is there a need to invoke the principle of authority (much less force).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY STATEMENT AGAINST NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-statement-against-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-statement-against-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY STATEMENT AGAINST NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proposition counter to natural depravity is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;there is no (1) clear (2) biblical basis for saying that Adam’s ability in (3) spiritual matters after the Fall was different from what it was (4) before the Fall in a (5) biologically inheritable sense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By “clear” biblical base we mean that certain passages might be understood in the way natural depravity assumes, but no passage requires such a reconstruction; many texts proposed in support of that concept cannot have that meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY STATEMENT ON NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-statement-on-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-statement-on-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY STATEMENT ON NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proposition counter to natural depravity is as follows: there is no (1) clear (2) biblical basis for saying that Adam’s ability regarding (3) spiritual things after the fall was different from what it was (4) before the fall in a (5) biologically inheritable sense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By “clear” biblical base we mean that there are passages that we could interpret the way natural depravity takes them. But, no passage requires such an understanding. Many texts offered in support of that concept cannot have that meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY STATEMENT REGARDING NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-statement-regarding-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/summary-statement-regarding-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY STATEMENT REGARDING NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proposition counter to natural depravity is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no (1) clear (2) biblical basis for saying that Adam’s ability in regard to (3) spiritual things after the fall was any different from what it was (4) before the fall in a (5) biologically inheritable sense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By “clear” biblical base we mean that there are some passages that could be understood the way natural depravity takes them. However, no passage requires such an understanding. In fact, many texts offered in support of that concept cannot have that meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE “IMAGE OF GOD”</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-image-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-image-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE “IMAGE OF GOD”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much of my creative energies lately have been directed toward tracing through the implications of interpersonal relationship as the organizing reality for Christian truth. Nowhere has this observation appeared more relevant than in the study of the nature of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the centuries extensive thought has gone into the interpretation of Genesis 1:26-27 and related materials: “Let’s make mankind in our image after our likeness.” There have been four proposed aspects of the “image of God” together with their effects. Reason heads the list. The ability to think abstractly relates to the capacity for language communication, creativity, responsibility (dominion), conscience, even humor, self-transcendence, and the ability to project consciousness over behind the eyes of another person. People can penetrate a situation in thought and imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DENIAL OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY:</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-denial-of-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-denial-of-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DENIAL OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A DISTINCTIVE OF “THE RESTORATION MOVEMENT”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One distinctive of the Churches of Christ/Christian Churches has been their relatively high view of human nature. They have stood virtually alone in denying the traditional doctrine of natural depravity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late fourth century, Augustine, bishop of Hippo in North Africa, gave classical expression to this concept as part of his understanding of the nature of evil generally. In his thought, evil is a lack (privation) in the form of substance relative to its original form. This relatively de-formed condition produces evil action. Thus, the nature of evil is lack, the cause of evil is lack in form, and the criterion of evil is lack in form compared to original form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGE AND ETHICS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-image-and-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-image-and-ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGE AND ETHICS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theory of meaning, the basis for self-image, and the theory of ethics all three reference the same factors: being, action, and relationship. The previous chapter discussed meaning and self-image as the objective and subjective sides of the same thing. This chapter notes that ethics belongs to action in the interpersonal sphere. Since we have identified the image of God with the interpersonal capacity, it remains for us to explicate the principles for ethical theory that grow out of the construct established by God’s creating us in his (a) interpersonal image for (b) fellowship and (c) purpose. Action connects the first item with each of the last two. Image defines human nature/being, which behavior ties to relationship and purpose. Relationship and purpose are relational since action relates persons to others in fellowship and relates them to the results of their deeds. Action connects being to relations (ethics) even as action connected objective and subjective in the previous chapter (meaning).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGE AND THE BODY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-image-and-the-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-image-and-the-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGE AND THE BODY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Including the Body in the Image&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter we address more deliberately the issue noted before. A long-standing debate about the image concerns whether to include the body in it. There are three ways to relate the image and the body. The body might be (a) part of the image, (b) involved with the image, or (c) analogous to the image. Several considerations go into deciding whether the body is in, with, or like the image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGE OF GOD AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-image-of-god-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-image-of-god-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGE OF GOD AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Interpersonal capacity” includes three notable ideas about the image. (a) Interpersonal stresses the fact that the image of God has to do with characteristics of persons rather than that of things, forces, ideas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(b) Interpersonal relates the image to the social setting so that it involves more than the individual by addressing marriage, community, church, society, mankind as well as the purposes of God for us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGO DEI AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY:</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-imago-dei-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-imago-dei-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGO DEI AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BASES AND INTEGRATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study proposes that the image of God in us is the interpersonal capacity. It does not necessarily say something new, but endeavors to assemble relevant factors, to clarify a viewpoint that best incorporates them, and to show its consonance with the Christian worldview. In method, the approach sets aside a reductionism that strives after identifying our “essence” and “risks” reification, faculty psychology, depersonalization, and individualism, which are tendencies that derive from non-revelatory origins. It opts instead for a combinationalism that accounts for all the features of nature, function, and relationship that’s special revelation pictures us as having and called to have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE MEANING OF “SUBMISSION”</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-meaning-of-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-meaning-of-submission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MEANING OF “SUBMISSION”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As with other controversial matters, the biblical view of marriage and the family gets lost in the throes of pendulum thinking. Truth tends to lie between extremes, but on this issue unnecessary rigidness creates an extreme opposite and equal reaction. After a while,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;discussions on headship and submission get lost in a battle between those extremes and lose sight of the proper orientation for the subject. Emotions take over on one side, which wants to defend the accuracy of scripture in all matters whereof it speaks. The other side wants to breathe some fresh air of freedom for women and their service in the kingdom. Whenever something comes up that seems to foster one extreme, people on the other extreme react. As a result, discussion does not resolve the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NATURE OF MANKIND</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-mankind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NATURE OF MANKIND&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preface&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The present volume was a project during a year’s sabbatical at Manhattan Christian College in Manhattan, Kansas. I am grateful to fellow faculty members, administration, and trustees for approving the sabbatical proposal. To my colleagues—especially Steve Isom, Dr. Franklin Karns, and Dr. Scott Caulley—I owe a debt of thanks for shouldering increased teaching loads so the necessary courses for the l989-1990 academic year could be maintained. Students and family have been encouragements as well during the completion of this and other commitments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NECESSITY OF “TONGUE SPEAKING”: A CRITIQUE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-necessity-of-tongue-speaking-a-critique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-necessity-of-tongue-speaking-a-critique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NECESSITY OF “TONGUE SPEAKING”: A CRITIQUE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian groups have different expectancies about “tongue speaking.” Some think the gift is as available now as in the apostolic age. Others take the more extreme position that it is a sign with all genuine conversions. The following remarks address that latter position. These notes also adopt the New Testament phraseology “speaking in languages” instead of “tongue speaking” because the latter is an undefined expression that allows people to invest it with a special meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NEW TESTAMENT BASIS FOR THE NON-DENOMINATIONAL CHURCH:</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-basis-for-the-non-denominational-church/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-basis-for-the-non-denominational-church/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEW TESTAMENT BASIS FOR THE NON-DENOMINATIONAL CHURCH:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE HISTORICAL ARGUMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VIRGIL WARREN, PhD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NEW TESTAMENT BASIS FOR THE NON-DENOMINATIONAL CHURCH: THE HISTORICAL ARGUMENT</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-basis-for-the-non-denominational-church-the-historical-argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-new-testament-basis-for-the-non-denominational-church-the-historical-argument/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEW TESTAMENT BASIS FOR THE NON-DENOMINATIONAL CHURCH: THE HISTORICAL ARGUMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The church is saved people serving in divine pattern. The body of Christ possesses essential oneness by virtue of individual unity with Christ and collective unity through Christ. This invisible oneness is manifest by a dynamic structure-function called the church. Functional unity in Christ combines with organizational unity under Christ to form this non-denominational entity that has a fivefold oneness of attitude, doctrine, fellowship, name, and organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NEW TESTAMENT’S WITNESS TO THE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-new-testaments-witness-to-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-new-testaments-witness-to-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEW TESTAMENT’S WITNESS TO THE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OLD TESTAMENT’S INSPIRATION*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Direct Assertion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Specific scriptures attributing the Old Testament to the Holy Spirit&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Passages mentioning the human author&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;Acts 1:16-20 (Psalm 69:25; 109:8)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.&#x9;Matthew 22:43 (Luke 24:44; Mark 12:36 [Psalm 110:1])&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c.&#x9;Acts 4:25-26 (Psalm 2:1-2)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d.&#x9;Acts 28:25-27 (Isaiah 6:9-10); cp. 1 Peter 1:10-12 (general reference)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Passages not mentioning the human author&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;Hebrews 3:7-11 (Psalm 95:7-11)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRADITIONAL REASONS FOR GOD’S CREATING US</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/traditional-reasons-for-gods-creating-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/traditional-reasons-for-gods-creating-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRADITIONAL REASONS FOR GOD’S CREATING US&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Issues can be relatively simple in themselves; and so the question seems about God’s reason for creating us. Issues get complicated when we try to distinguish our own understanding from other ones and when we have to give reasons against such alternatives, especially if they overlap our own.1 As in our positive presentation so also in evaluating other positions, interpersonalism serves as the criterion for what is foreign and contradictory to what scripture says about the nature and purpose of God and man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRIMMING BACK THEOLOGY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/trimming-back-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/trimming-back-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRIMMING BACK THEOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BY SHEDDING NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Contribution of “Restorationism”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A less emphasized contribution of the Restoration Movement has been its dispensing with the centuries-old concept of natural depravity. The idea originated with Augustine of Hippo (354-430), who was emerging from the Greek philosophical tradition that did philosophy in the ontic category, in particular, Manichaeism. His seminal notion was that evil was a privation of form in being relative to its pristine condition, with perverted function arising from the deformation. That explanation of theodicy applied to the human condition and its behavioral outworking called sin. The Reformation and contemporary evangelicalism as well have incorporated that concept into their systematics. A student of historical theology has to go from the Stone-Campbell movement all the way into liberalism to find an absence of the natural depravity concept.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN MENTIONED IN THE BIBLE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/women-mentioned-in-the-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/women-mentioned-in-the-bible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN MENTIONED IN THE BIBLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To maintain a balanced approach in the current women’s studies debate, we should keep in mind what women did with divine approval in both Testaments. The following is a suggestive list.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anna: a “prophetess” in Jerusalem at the time of Jesus’ presentation in the temple. She “gave thanks to God and spoke of him to all that were looking for redemption in Israel” (Luke 2:36-38).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN’S STUDIES AND “STANDARD SITUATION”</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-and-standard-situation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-and-standard-situation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN’S STUDIES AND “STANDARD SITUATION”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One point in 1 Timothy 2 has to do with husband-wife vs. man-woman as Paul’s intended reference. Connecting the statements of 1 Timothy with (a) a husband-wife contrast rather than (b) a man-woman contrast represents a crucial variable between instruction on marriage roles vs. gender roles. A third approach to the text has something of the same effect but seems to be more straightforward and therefore less cumbersome: (c) Paul is addressing “standard situation,” that is, married with children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN’S STUDIES IN 1 TIMOTHY 2:</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-in-1-timothy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-in-1-timothy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN’S STUDIES IN 1 TIMOTHY 2:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FACTORS IN INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nature of the New Testament: body of law or book of wisdom (See essays on “Imperatival Intent” and “Law and Wisdom.”)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nature of the pastoral epistles: contain mandates on morality all the way through exhortations and cultural sensitivities down to bylaw material&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; The nature of 2 Timothy materials: directed to a local situation (Ephesus) or applicable to all the churches of the Gentile territories (note 2:7)?&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; The lack of homogeneity in lists: lifting up holy hands and dress code items need not be of the same sort as female subjection manifested in not teaching or exercising authority over men&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Quietness” (ἡσυχία, hēsychia, 2:11, 12) as a manifestation of the female deference principle (distinction between the principle itself and the cultural manner of manifesting it):  note the cognate term ἡσύχάζω (hēsychazō), meaning “to rest”; in Luke 23:56b, where it is used of “resting” on the Sabbath day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN’S STUDIES NOTATIONS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-notations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-notations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN’S STUDIES NOTATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In women’s studies, something is causing equally committed, intelligent, educated, hard-working, well-known Christians to come to incompatible conclusions, which leads to disagreement and division. Since this topic has behavioral correlates, we cannot treat it as we do the millennial question and go on about our work; this topic affects how we go on with our work. Since it is a broad-to-narrow issue, people with different persuasions find it hard to be equally tolerant; it is usually easier for a broader view to be accepting of a more restricted one than vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XENOGLOSSIA IN CORINTH</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/xenoglossia-in-corinth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/xenoglossia-in-corinth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;XENOGLOSSIA IN CORINTH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. METHOD OF RESEARCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One question about New Testament speaking in languages is whether there was more than one type. Among evangelicals it is agreed that speaking in languages was a first-century phenomenon involving actual human languages. Not everyone agrees that there was a “second type.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Terminological Approach&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a lack of finality in the vocabulary approach regarding γλῶσσα (tongue, language) as well as λαλέω (speak) and διερμηνεύω (interpret, translate). What a word means elsewhere does not necessarily determine its usage here, especially if it is a unique matter. The statistically most likely meaning may be set aside by the peculiarities of a special setting. Inasmuch as the meaning of an expression is ultimately determined by its context anyway, it is better to examine the characteristics of the situation than to rely on word usage elsewhere. Any uniformity that can be found, however, for γλῶσσα as a reference to actual human languages does tend to shift the burden of proof onto someone who claims a non-language character for speaking in languages. The positive evidence for glossolalia based on word usage becomes a difficulty for those who call for a special usage not evidenced elsewhere. One offsetting consideration might be that if there were no other examples of what was happening among the Christians, referring to it by the closest word available could explain a special meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ΑΥΘΕΝΤΗΣ  (AUTHENTĒS)</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/%CE%B1%CF%85%CE%B8%CE%B5%CE%BD%CF%84%CE%B7%CF%82-authent%C4%93s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/%CE%B1%CF%85%CE%B8%CE%B5%CE%BD%CF%84%CE%B7%CF%82-authent%C4%93s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ΑΥΘΕΝΤΗΣ  (AUTHENTĒS)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An important item in 1 Timothy 2 is a case of αὐθεντέω (authenteō) that Al Wolters pointed out at the November meeting of the Evangelical Theological Society in Lisle, Illinois.  It appears in Origen’s Commentary on 1 Corinthians, which, I believe, is one of Origen’s as-yet untranslated works. The full Greek text of the commentary is in Journal of Theological Studies, X (1909), 29-51. The reference appears in 74:20 of Origen’s Commentary. The text is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
