<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joshua on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Joshua on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After Moses died, God said to Joshua son of Nun, Moses&amp;rsquo; assistant, 2&amp;quot;Moses has died. You and the people, cross the Jordan to the land I&amp;rsquo;m giving you. 3Like I promised Moses, everywhere you go I&amp;rsquo;ll deliver it to you. 4Your territory will be from the desert and Lebanon to the big Euphrates River, the land of the Hittites to the Mediterranean Sea in the west. 5Nobody will be able to stand up to you all your life. I&amp;rsquo;ll be with you like I was with Moses; I won&amp;rsquo;t fail you or abandon you. 6Be strong and courageous. You&amp;rsquo;ll enable my people to inherit the land I swore to their ancestors I&amp;rsquo;d give them. 7Make sure you do everything in the Law that Moses commanded you. 8Think about it day and night. You&amp;rsquo;ll prosper and succeed. 9Haven&amp;rsquo;t I commanded you? Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid or intimidated. The LORD your God is with you.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Joshua sent two men secretly from Shittim to check out the land, Jericho in particular. They went to the house of a harlot named Rahab to lodge. 2The king of Jericho heard about it, &amp;ldquo;Some men from Israel have come here tonight to spy out the land.&amp;rdquo; 3He sent to Rahab, &amp;ldquo;Bring the men that have come to your house. They&amp;rsquo;re spies.&amp;rdquo; 4But the woman had hidden them, &amp;ldquo;Men did come, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know where they came from. 5They left when the gate closed at dark. I don&amp;rsquo;t know where they went. Follow them right away so you can catch up with them.&amp;rdquo; 6But she&amp;rsquo;d taken them up to the roof and hidden them under stalks of flax. 7The men pursued them toward the Jordan as far as the fords. As soon as they left, the gate was shut.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Joshua got up early and set out from Shittim with the people. They got to the Jordan and stayed there before they crossed. 2After three days the officers went through the camp 3and told the people, &amp;ldquo;When you see the priests pick up the Ark of the Covenant, follow it so you&amp;rsquo;ll know where to go. You haven&amp;rsquo;t gone this way before. 4Don&amp;rsquo;t get near it. Stay back about 3,000ft.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When they&amp;rsquo;d crossed, the LORD told Joshua, 2&amp;quot;Appoint a man from each tribe 3to take a rock from the Jordan, carry it over, and lay it down where they&amp;rsquo;ll spend the night.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Joshua called the twelve men, 5&amp;quot;Go on past the Ark to the middle of the Jordan and pick up a rock onto your shoulder. 6They&amp;rsquo;ll be a sign when your children ask what these rocks mean. 7Tell them the Jordan River held back ahead of the Ark as it crossed. These rocks serve as a permanent memorial for Israelites.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Amorite kings west of the Jordan and the Canaanite kings by the sea, heard that the LORD had dried up the Jordan for the Israelites to cross. Their hearts melted; there was no spirit in them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; At that time, the LORD told Joshua to make flint knives and circumcise the Israelites this second time. 3He did that at Gibeath-haaraloth. 4The fighting men who came out of Egypt 5had been circumcised, but the ones born in the desert hadn&amp;rsquo;t. 6The Israelites lived there 40 years till those fighting men died. The LORD swore they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see the land flowing with milk and honey that he&amp;rsquo;d promised their ancestors. 7So Joshua circumcised the offspring the LORD raised up to replace them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jericho was shut up; nobody was coming out or going in. 2The LORD told Joshua, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll deliver Jericho to you, its king and strong fighting men. 3Have Israel&amp;rsquo;s fighting men march around the city once a day for a week. 4Have seven priests each carry a ram&amp;rsquo;s horn ahead of the Ark. On the seventh day, march around the city seven times while the priests blow their rams&amp;rsquo; horns. 5As soon as you hear a long blast on the rams&amp;rsquo; horns, raise the battle cry as loud as you can, and the city wall will fall down flat. Every man, go straight in.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; But the people violated the instructions about the things set apart to the LORD. Achan son of Carmi son of Zabdi son of Zerah from the tribe of Judah, took some devoted things, and the LORD&amp;rsquo;s anger burned against Israel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Joshua sent men from Jericho to Ai near Beth-aven, east of Bethel to spy out the area. They spied it out, 3came back and said, &amp;ldquo;Just have 2,000 or 3,000 go up to attack Ai. There aren&amp;rsquo;t many of them.&amp;rdquo; 4About 3,000 went up but fled. 5The men from Ai killed about 36. They chased them from the gate as far as Shebarim and killed them at the descent. The people&amp;rsquo;s hearts melted and became like water.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD told Joshua, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid or intimidated. Take the fighting men up to Ai. I&amp;rsquo;ll deliver the king, his people, his city, and his land to you. 2Do to Ai and its king what you did to Jericho and its king. Just take its spoil and livestock for yourselves. Ambush the city from behind.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Joshua and the fighting men got up to go to Ai. Joshua chose 30,000 trained men and sent them out at night. 4He told them, &amp;ldquo;Lie in ambush behind the city. Stay fairly close to it and be ready. 5The people and I will approach the city. When they come out against us, we&amp;rsquo;ll flee. 6They&amp;rsquo;ll chase us till we&amp;rsquo;ve drawn them away from the city; they&amp;rsquo;ll think we&amp;rsquo;re running from them like the last time. 7Then rise up from the ambush and seize the city; the LORD your God will give it to you. 8When you&amp;rsquo;ve taken it, set it on fire like he said.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The kings heard about it in the hill country and the western foothills along the Mediterranean Sea up to Lebanon—the Hittites, Amorites, Canaanites, Perizzites, Hivites, and Jebusites. 2They formed an alliance against Israel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; But when the people in Gibeon heard what Joshua had done to Jericho and Ai, 4they resorted to trickery. They made fake preparations: worn-out sacks on their donkeys; worn-out, torn, and mended wineskins; 5worn-out and patched sandals, and worn-out clothes. Their provisions were dry and moldy. 6They went to Joshua in the camp at Gilgal, and told him and Israel, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve come from a distant country. Make a treaty with us.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Adonizedek, king of Jerusalem, heard how Joshua had taken Ai and destroyed it like Jericho and its king. He heard how Gibeon had made peace with Israel and was among them. 2He was really afraid because Gibeon was a big city, like a royal city. It was bigger than Ai and its men were strong. 3So he sent to Hoham king of Hebron, Piram king of Jarmuth, Japhia king of Lachish, and Debir king of Eglon, 4&amp;quot;Help me attack Gibeon; it has made peace with Israel.&amp;quot; 5Those five allied forces camped against Gibeon and attacked it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Jabin, king of Hazor, heard about it, he sent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; They came out with their troops, a large army like sand on the shore, with very many horses and chariots. 5All those kings joined forces, and came and camped together at the water by Merom.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD told Joshua, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of them. At this time tomorrow, I&amp;rsquo;ll deliver them to Israel. Hamstring their horses and burn their chariots.&amp;rdquo; 7He came suddenly on them with all his fighting men. 8The LORD gave them to Israel, who struck them and chased them to Great Sidon and Misrephoth-maim and eastward to the Valley of Mizpah. There weren&amp;rsquo;t any left. 9Joshua hamstrung their horses and burned their chariots.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; These are the kings the Israelites defeated and whose land they took east of the Jordan—from the Wadi Arnon to Mount Hermon with all the eastern Arabah:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Sihon, king of the Amorites. He lived in Heshbon, and ruled from Aroer, on the edge of the valley of Arnon—from the middle of the valley to the river Jabbok, which is the boundary with the Ammonites, that is, half of Gilead 3and the Arabah to the Sea of Chinneroth east, and in the direction of Beth-jeshimoth to the Sea of Arabah (the Dead Sea), south to the foot of Pisgah.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Joshua was getting along I years, the LORD told him, considered Canaanite. The Philistines have five rulers: in Gaza, Ashdod, Ashkelon, Gath, and Ekron.) and I&amp;rsquo;ll drive them out in front of Israel.  Allot the land to the nine tribes and the Manasseh half-tribe.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v8&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; The other Manasseh half-tribe together with Reuben and Gad had received their inheritance from Moses east of the Jordan: 9from Aroer, on the edge of the Arnon valley, the city in the middle of the valley, the whole tableland of Medeba as far as Dibon; 10the towns of Sihon, king of the Amorites; 11Gilead, the region of the Geshurites and Maacathites; all of Mount Hermon, the whole of Bashan to Salecah; 12the kingdom of Og in Bashan, who ruled in Ashtaroth and Edrei. (He was the only Rephaim left.) Moses had defeated them and driven them out. 13Yet the people of Israel didn&amp;rsquo;t drive out the Geshurites or Maacathites. They still live among the Israelites.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; These are the territories the Israelites inherited in Canaan, which Eleazar the priest, Joshua son of Nun, and the heads of families distributed. 2Their inheritance came by lot for the 9½ tribes. [3] 4Joseph&amp;rsquo;s people consisted of two tribes, Manasseh and Ephraim. Moses just gave the Levites towns to live in along with land for pasturing livestock and raising crops for them. 5The Israelites allotted the land like the LORD commanded. &amp;ldquo;You know what the LORD told Moses in Kadesh-barnea about you and me. 7I was 40 when Moses sent me to spy out the land. I brought back word to him as it was in my heart. 8But my brothers that went up with me made the people&amp;rsquo;s heart melt. Yet I wholly followed the LORD. 9Moses swore that day, &amp;lsquo;The land you&amp;rsquo;ve walked on will belong to you and your descendants permanently. You&amp;rsquo;ve followed the LORD my God.&amp;rsquo; 10He has kept me alive these 45 years since he said that to Moses in the desert. Today I&amp;rsquo;m 85. 11I&amp;rsquo;m still as strong as I was when Moses sent me—strong for war and everyday life. 12Give me this hill country the LORD spoke about that day. At that time, you heard that Anakim were there with big, fortified towns. the LORD maybe with me, and I can drive them out.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Judah&amp;rsquo;s allotment by clans reached the border of Edom, went south to the Wilderness of Zin at the farthest. 2Their south border went from the lower end of the Dead Sea, from the bay that turns south. 3It went on south to the ascent of Akrabbim and continued to Zin, then went up south of Kadesh-barnea, continued to Hezron, up to Addar, and turned to Karka. 4It went on to Azmon and the River of Egypt and ended at the Mediterranean Sea. That was their south border.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The allotment for Joseph&amp;rsquo;s descendants goes from the Jordan by Jericho to the open country to the hill country of Bethel. 2Then it goes from Bethel to Luz and passes along to Ataroth, the territory of the Archites. 3Then it runs west to the territory of the Japhletites as far as the area around Lower Beth-horon, then to Gezer, and ends at the Mediterranean Sea. 4Joseph&amp;rsquo;s people—Manasseh and Ephraim—received their inheritance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-17&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Manasseh, Joseph&amp;rsquo;s firstborn, received an allotment. Gilead and Bashan went to Machir, Manasseh&amp;rsquo;s firstborn and father of Gilead, because he was a soldier. 2Allotment came to the rest of Manasseh&amp;rsquo;s male descendants by clans: the sons of Abiezer, Helek, Asriel, Shechem, Hepher, and Shemida. 3However, Zelophehad son of Hepher (son of Gilead son of Machir son of Manasseh) only had daughters: Mahlah, Noah, Hoglah, Milcah, and Tirzah. 4They approached Eleazar the priest, Joshua, and the elders, &amp;ldquo;The LORD told Moses to give us an inheritance among our relatives.&amp;rdquo; So he gave them an inheritance among their uncles. 5Ten sections fell to Manasseh besides Gilead and Bashan beyond the Jordan, 6because Manasseh&amp;rsquo;s daughters received an inheritance with his sons. Gilead belonged to the rest of Manasseh&amp;rsquo;s sons.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-18&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The whole community of Israel gathered at Shiloh and set up the Tent of Meeting. The land had been conquered, 2but seven tribes hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet received their inheritance. 3Joshua said, &amp;ldquo;How long will you put off taking possession of what the LORD has given you? 4Select three men from each tribe that I can send through the land to write a description of their inheritance. 5-6Divide it into seven territories and describe them. Judah will stay in its territory on the south. Joseph will stay in its territory on the north. I&amp;rsquo;ll cast lots for you here in front of the LORD. 7The Levites don&amp;rsquo;t have any territory; the priesthood is their inheritance. Moses has given Gad, Reuben, and the Manasseh half-tribe their inheritance east of the Jordan.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-19&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The second lot came out for Simeon by clans. Its inheritance was inside Judah. 2It had Beer-sheba, Sheba, Moladah, 3Hazarshual, Balah, Ezem, 4Eltolad, Bethul, Hormah, 5Ziklag, Beth-marcaboth, Hazar-susah, 6Beth-lebaoth, Sharuhen—13 towns with their villages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; Ain, Rimmon, Ether, Ashan—4 towns with their villages, 8and the villages around those towns as far as Baalath-beer, Ramah in the Negev. That was Simeon&amp;rsquo;s inheritance by clans. 9They took his territory out of Judah&amp;rsquo;s because Judah&amp;rsquo;s share was too big.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-20&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then the LORD said to Joshua, 2&amp;quot;Have the people establish the cities of refuge I spoke to you about through Moses, 3so anyone that kills somebody accidentally can flee there from an avenger. 4Standing at the entrance to the city gate, the slayer will explain his case to the elders, and they&amp;rsquo;ll provide a place to stay in the city. 5They won&amp;rsquo;t betray the slayer to any avenger because the death was an accident, no previous animosity involved. 6The slayer will stay in that city for judgment till the death of the current high priest, and then go back home.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-21&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The heads of families among the Levites came to Eleazar the priest, Joshua, and the heads of families in Israel. 2They said, &amp;ldquo;The LORD commanded Moses to give us towns to live in along with pastures for our livestock.&amp;rdquo; 3Israel gave the Levites those towns and their pastures out of their inheritance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; The lot came out for the clans of Kohathites; the descendants of Aaron received 13 towns from Judah, Simeon, and Benjamin.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-22&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Joshua called Reuben, Gad, and the Manasseh half-tribe, 2&amp;quot;You&amp;rsquo;ve done everything Moses and I have commanded you. 3You haven&amp;rsquo;t abandoned your fellow Jews. You&amp;rsquo;ve kept the LORD&amp;rsquo;s charge, 4and he&amp;rsquo;s given them peace. Go to your possession beyond the Jordan. 5Observe the Law Moses commanded you: love the LORD your God, follow his ways, hold onto him, and serve him with all your heart and soul.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-23&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 23&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A good while later, when Joshua was old, 2he called in Israel&amp;rsquo;s elders, heads, judges, and officers, and told them, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m getting old. 3You&amp;rsquo;ve seen everything the LORD your God has done to those nations for you. He fought for you. 4I&amp;rsquo;ve allotted to your tribes those nations that remain, along with the nations I&amp;rsquo;ve already removed, from the Jordan to the Mediterranean Sea in the west. 5The LORD will push them back. 6Keep doing everything in the Law of Moses. 7Don&amp;rsquo;t mix with the nations left among you. Don&amp;rsquo;t mention their gods, swear by them, serve them, bow down to them. 8Hold onto the LORD like you&amp;rsquo;ve done so far. 9He has driven out big, strong nations. Nobody has been able to resist you. 10One of you puts a thousand to flight, because he fights for you like he promised. 11Give attention to loving him. 12If you join the remnants of nations left among you and intermarry with them, 13you can be sure he won&amp;rsquo;t keep driving them out. They&amp;rsquo;ll be a snare, a trap, a scourge in your sides, thorns in your eyes, till you perish from this good land he&amp;rsquo;s given you. 14&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;m going to die soon. You know in your hearts and souls that not one good thing has failed to happen that the LORD promised. 15Just as he has done all the good things he promised, he&amp;rsquo;ll bring about all the bad things till he&amp;rsquo;s destroyed you. 16If you sin against his covenant, serve other gods, and bow to them, his anger will flare at you, and you&amp;rsquo;ll soon perish.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joshua 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/joshua/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;joshua-chapter-24&#34;&gt;Joshua Chapter 24&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Joshua gathered the tribes to Shechem with their elders, heads, judges, and officers. They presented themselves to God. 2Joshua said, &amp;ldquo;The LORD God of Israel, says, &amp;lsquo;Your ancestors lived beyond the Euphrates River. Nahor and Terah, Abraham&amp;rsquo;s father, served other gods. 3I led Abraham from there all over Canaan and multiplied his offspring. I gave him Isaac, 4and gave Isaac Jacob and Esau. I gave Esau the hill country of Seir, but Jacob and his descendants went down to Egypt. 5I sent Moses and Aaron, and plagued Egypt in its own land. 6Afterwards I brought you out of there. You came to the Red Sea, and the Egyptians chased you with chariots and cavalry to the sea. 7When you cried out to me, I put darkness between you and them, and made the sea cover them. You saw that and lived a long time in the desert. 8Then I brought you to Amorite country east of the Jordan. They fought you, and I destroyed them in front of you. You took their land. 9Then Balak son of Zippor, king of Moab, rose up to oppose you. He sent for Balaam son of Beor and invited him to curse you. 10But I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t listen to Balaam. So he blessed you, and I delivered you from him. 11You crossed the Jordan to Jericho, and the people in Jericho fought you as did the Amorites, Perizzites, Canaanites, Hittites, Girgashites, Hivites, and Jebusites. I gave them to you. 12I sent hornets to drive out the two Amorite kings. Your sword and bow didn&amp;rsquo;t do it. 13I gave you a land you hadn&amp;rsquo;t worked and towns you didn&amp;rsquo;t build, and you lived in them. You&amp;rsquo;re eating the fruit from vineyards and olive orchards you didn&amp;rsquo;t plant.&amp;rsquo; 14&amp;quot;Now then, respect the LORD, serve him sincerely and faithfully. Put away the gods your ancestors served beyond the River and in Egypt. 15If you won&amp;rsquo;t serve him, choose today who you will serve: the gods of your ancestors beyond the River or the gods of the Amorites where you&amp;rsquo;re living. My house and I will serve the LORD.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
