<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speaking in Languages TONGUE SPEAKING on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/speaking-in-languages-tongue-speaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speaking in Languages TONGUE SPEAKING on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/speaking-in-languages-tongue-speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2. 	Xenoglossia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/2-xenoglossia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/2-xenoglossia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Xenoglossia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Glossolalia covers a range of speaking phenomena, including ecstatic utterance and “angelic tongues.” Cases occasionally come up in which someone speaks an actual language—xenoglossia. The following possibilities may be kept in mind when evaluating these cases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. &#x9;Mistaken identification&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1)&#x9;Someone who knows a few words of a language might suppose, upon hearing these sounds in a tongues situation, that the whole utterance is in that language. These sounds may have happened into the expression or were snatches of that language previously heard by the speaker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D. 	Applying tests to contemporary claims of speaking in languages (“tongues speaking”)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/d-applying-tests-to-contemporary-claims-of-speaking-in-languages-tongues-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/d-applying-tests-to-contemporary-claims-of-speaking-in-languages-tongues-speaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;D. &#x9;Applying tests to contemporary claims of speaking in languages (“tongues speaking”)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Glossolalia: misidentification&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. &#x9;Eclipse of the adult inhibition against babbling&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1)&#x9;Basic proposition: Much of what goes under the term tongue speaking (glossolalia) is a matter of overcoming the adult inhibition against babbling, the inhibition against making meaningless sounds. Factors that help break this inhibition are mistakenly identified as the energizing work of the Holy Spirit. The phenomenon itself is then misidentified with New Testament language speaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NECESSITY OF “TONGUE SPEAKING”: A CRITIQUE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-necessity-of-tongue-speaking-a-critique/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-necessity-of-tongue-speaking-a-critique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NECESSITY OF “TONGUE SPEAKING”: A CRITIQUE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian groups have different expectancies about “tongue speaking.” Some think the gift is as available now as in the apostolic age. Others take the more extreme position that it is a sign with all genuine conversions. The following remarks address that latter position. These notes also adopt the New Testament phraseology “speaking in languages” instead of “tongue speaking” because the latter is an undefined expression that allows people to invest it with a special meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XENOGLOSSIA IN CORINTH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/xenoglossia-in-corinth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/xenoglossia-in-corinth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;XENOGLOSSIA IN CORINTH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. METHOD OF RESEARCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One question about New Testament speaking in languages is whether there was more than one type. Among evangelicals it is agreed that speaking in languages was a first-century phenomenon involving actual human languages. Not everyone agrees that there was a “second type.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Terminological Approach&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a lack of finality in the vocabulary approach regarding γλῶσσα (tongue, language) as well as λαλέω (speak) and διερμηνεύω (interpret, translate). What a word means elsewhere does not necessarily determine its usage here, especially if it is a unique matter. The statistically most likely meaning may be set aside by the peculiarities of a special setting. Inasmuch as the meaning of an expression is ultimately determined by its context anyway, it is better to examine the characteristics of the situation than to rely on word usage elsewhere. Any uniformity that can be found, however, for γλῶσσα as a reference to actual human languages does tend to shift the burden of proof onto someone who claims a non-language character for speaking in languages. The positive evidence for glossolalia based on word usage becomes a difficulty for those who call for a special usage not evidenced elsewhere. One offsetting consideration might be that if there were no other examples of what was happening among the Christians, referring to it by the closest word available could explain a special meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
