<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ephesians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ephesians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul, (an) apostle of-Christ Jesus through the will of-God, to-the saints [the] being [in Ephesus]ms and faithful in Christ Jesus. 2Grace to-you and peace from God (the) Father of-us and (the) Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Blessed (be) the God and Father of-the Lord of-us Jesus Christ, the-One having-blessed us with every spiritual blessing in-regard-to heavenly matters in Christ, 4even-as he chose us in him before (the) foundation of-(the)-world for-us to-be holy and blameless in-the-presence-of him in love, 5having-predestined us to sonship through Jesus Christ to himself, according-to the good-pleasure of-the will of-him, 6to (the) praise of-(the) glory of-the grace of-him that he graced┘us└with in the Beloved; 7in whom we-have [the] redemption through the blood of-him, the forgiveness of-[the] trespasses, according-to the wealth of-the grace of-him 8that he-lavished on us in all wisdom and insight, 9having-made-known to-us the mystery of-the will of-him, according-to the good-pleasure of-him that he-purposed in him 10for responsibility of-the fullness of-[the] times, to-sum-up [the] all-things in [the] Christ—the-things in the heavens and the-things in the earth in him; 11in whom also we-were-made-an-inheritance, having-been-predestined according-to (the) purpose of-the-One working [the] all-things according-to the counsel of-the will of-him, 12unto [the] our being to (the) praise-(the)-glory of-him the-ones having-hoped in [the] Christ; 13in whom you also, having-heard the word of-[the] truth, the good-news of-the salvation of-us, in whom also having-believed you-were-sealed with-the Holy [the] Spirit of-[the] promise; 14[who is] (the) pledge of-the inheritance of-us, unto (the) redemption of-the possession, to (the) praise of-the glory of-him.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; And (he made) you (alive), being dead by-[the] trespasses and the sins of-you, 2in which once you-walked according-to the age of-[the] this world, according-to the ruling-one of-the power of-the air, of-the spirit [the] now working in the sons of-[the] disobedience; 3among whom also we all once lived in the lusts of-the flesh, doing the desires of-the flesh and the minds, and we-were children by-nature of-wrath like the rest. 4But [the] God, being rich in mercy on-account-of the great love of-him which he-loved us, 5and we, being dead because-of trespasses, he-made-alive-with Christ—by-grace you have-been-saved—6raised┘us└up-with (him) and seated┘(us)└with (him) in the heavenly (places) in Christ Jesus, 7in-order-that he-might-show in the ages [the-ones] coming the unlimited wealth of-the grace of-him in kindness toward us in Christ Jesus. 8For by-[the] grace you-have-been-saved2 through trust/faith, and that (salvation is) not from you; it&amp;rsquo;s the gift of-God, 9not from works, in-order-that not anybody should boast. 10For we-are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works that God prepared-ahead-of-time in-order-that we should walk in them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; For-the-sake-of this, I, Paul, (a) prisoner of-[the] Christ Jesus on-behalf-of you [the] Gentiles—2if indeed you-heard-about the stewardship of-the grace of-[the] God [the] given to-me for you, 3that/because according-to revelation the mystery was-made-known to-me, even-as I-wrote-earlier in brief, 4to which you-are-able, reading, to perceive the insight of-me in the mystery of-[the] Christ, 5which in-other generations was┘not└made-known to-the sons of-[the] men as now it-was-revealed to the holy apostles of-him and prophets by the spirit: 6(that) [the] Gentiles are joint-heirs and fellow-members-of-the-body, and fellow-partakers of-the promise in Christ Jesus through the gospel, 7of-which I-became (a) minister according-to the gift of-[the] grace of-[the] God [the] having-been-given to-me according-to the working of-[the] power of-him, 8to-me the least of-all saints [the] this was-given, to-preach to-the Gentiles the unfathomable wealth of-[the] Christ, 9and to-bring-to-light what (is) the administration of-the mystery the-one hidden from the ages in [the] God, the-One having-created all [the]-things, 10in-order-that the multi-faceted wisdom of-[the] God might-be-made-known to-the rulers and the authorities in-regard-to the heavenly-(matters) through the church, 11according-to (the) purpose of-the ages that he-made in [the] Christ Jesus the Lord of-us, 12in whom we-have [the] boldness and access in confidence through the faith of-him. 13Wherefore I-ask you not to-become-discouraged in the difficulties of-me for you, which is your glory.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So I, the/a prisoner in the Lord, urge you to walk worthily of-the calling which you-were called, 2with all humility and gentleness, with patience, being-patient-with one-another in love, 3being-diligent to-keep the unity of-the spirit in the bond of-[the] peace: 4one body and one Spirit, as you are-called in one hope of-[the] calling of-you; 5one Lord, one faith, one baptism, 6one God and Father of-all, the-One over all and through all and in all.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So be imitators of-[the] God as beloved children, 2and walk in love even-as also [the] Christ loved you and gave himself for you (as an) offering and sacrifice to-[the] God for (a) sweet fragrance. 3Let┘sexaul-immorality and every impurity or greed not-even└be-named among you, even-as is-appropriate for-saints. 4And(Let there be no) filthiness and foolish-talk or vulgar-talking, which-things are not fitting, but rather thanksgiving. 5For know this for-sure that every sexually-immoral or impure or covetous (person), which is idolatry, does┘not└have (an) inheritance in the kingdom of-[the] Christ and God.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/ephesians/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The] children, obey the parents of-you in (the) Lord, for this is right. 2&amp;quot;Honor the father of-you and the mothers,&amp;quot; which is (the) first commandment with promise, 3&amp;quot;in-order-that it-may-be well with-you, and you-will-be (a) long-time on the earth.&amp;quot; 4And [the] fathers, do┘not└make┘the children of-you└resentful, but raise them in (the) discipline and instruction of-(the)-Lord. 5[The] slaves, obey the/your masters according-to (the) flesh with fear and trembling with sincerity of-the heart of-you as to-[the[ Christ, 6not according-to eye-service as men-pleasers, but as slaves of-Christ, doing the will of-[the] God from (the) soul, 7with good-will serving as [the] Lord and not men, 8knowing that if you┘each└do anything good, this will-be-received-back from (the) Lord whether slave or free. 9And [the] lords, do the same-things to them, ceasing [the] threatening, knowing that both the Lord of-them and of-you is in heaven[s], and respect-of-persons is not with him.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
