<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matthew on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The genealogy of Jesus the Messiah, son of David, son of Abraham&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Abraham, father of&#x9;&#x9;Isaac, father of&#x9;  &#x9;Jacob, father of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Judah was father of&#x9;Peres and Zerah by Tamar;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v12&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt; After the exile,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v17&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt; There are 14 generations from Abraham to David,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v18&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt; This is how the birth of Jesus the Messiah took place. His mother Mary was engaged to Joseph. Before they got married, it was discovered that she was pregnant (by the Holy Spirit). 19Joseph, her husband, was a just man and not willing to disgrace her publicly, so he intended to break off the engagement privately. 20As he was struggling with the matter, an angel of the LORD appeared in a dream, &amp;ldquo;Joseph son of David, don&amp;rsquo;t have qualms about marrying her. She&amp;rsquo;s pregnant by the Holy Spirit. 21She&amp;rsquo;ll have a son you&amp;rsquo;re to name Jesus, because he&amp;rsquo;ll &amp;lsquo;save&amp;rsquo; his people from their sins.&amp;rdquo; 22That fulfilled what the LORD had said by the prophet Isaiah,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Jesus was born in Bethlehem, Judaea, during the reign of King Herod, Magi from the East arrived in Jerusalem, 2&amp;quot;Where&amp;rsquo;s the newborn king of the Jews? In the East we saw his star and have come to pay him homage.&amp;quot; 3That disturbed Herod and the whole city as well. 4He called in the chief priests and scribes of the people and asked them where the Messiah was to be born.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In time, John the Baptist camep preaching in the desert in Judaea, 2&amp;quot;Repent, the kingdom of heaven&amp;rsquo;s coming.&amp;quot; 3He&amp;rsquo;s the one Isaiah spoke about:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; John wore clothes woven from camel&amp;rsquo;s hair with a leather belt around his waist and lived on locusts and wild honey. 5People from Jerusalem, all over Judaea, and around the Jordan River were going out 6to have him baptize them in the Jordan as they confessed their sins.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then the Spirit led Jesus into the desert to be tempted by the devil. 2After fasting 40 days, he was hungry, 3and the tempter came, &amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re God&amp;rsquo;s Son, tell these stones to become loaves of bread.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; But he answered,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; The devil tookp him to the Holy City and stood him on the pinnacle of the Temple, 6&amp;quot;If you&amp;rsquo;re God&amp;rsquo;s Son, throw yourself down. Scripture says,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When he saw the crowd, he went up on a hillside and sat down. His disciples joined him, 2and he started teaching: 11&amp;quot;When people insult you, mistreat you, say all kinds of bad things about you falsely because of me, you are fortunate. 12Be glad, because you have a great reward in heaven. They treated the prophets the same way. 13&amp;quot;You are the salt of the earth; but if salt loses its saltiness, what can make it salty? It&amp;rsquo;s not good for anything but to throw out for people to walk on. 14You are the light of the world. A city on a hill can&amp;rsquo;t hide. 15Nobody lights a lamp and sticks it under a basket; they put it on a stand, and it gives light to everybody in the house. 16Let your light shine so people can see the good things you&amp;rsquo;re doing and praise your Father in heaven. 17&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t get the impression that I&amp;rsquo;m here to destroy the Law or the Prophets. I&amp;rsquo;m not here to destroy them, but to fulfill them. 18Earth and sky will pass away, but not one iota or one serif* will pass away from the Law till it&amp;rsquo;s fully accomplished its purpose. 19Whoever breaks one of its least commandments and teaches people to do that, is least in the kingdom of heaven; but whoever does and teaches them is great in that kingdom. 20Unless the way you live is better than the way the scribes and Pharisees live, you won&amp;rsquo;t even get into the kingdom of heaven. 21&amp;quot;You&amp;rsquo;ve heard that God said long ago, &amp;lsquo;Do not commit murder&amp;rsquo; [Ex 20:13; Deut 5:17]; &amp;lsquo;whoever commits murder faces condemnation.&amp;rsquo; 22I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, anybody that&amp;rsquo;s mad at someone faces judgment. Whoever says, &amp;lsquo;You good for nothing . . .&amp;rsquo; has the court to face. Whoever says, &amp;lsquo;You idiot,&amp;rsquo; faces a burning hell. 23So if you&amp;rsquo;re taking your gift to the altar and remember your brother has something against you, 24leave it at the altar and go reconcile with him. Then come and offer your gift. 25Come to terms with your opponent quickly while you&amp;rsquo;re on the way to court with him so he doesn&amp;rsquo;t deliver you to the judge, and the judge turn you over to the court assistant, and he put you in jail. 26You won&amp;rsquo;t get out till you pay the last penny. 27&amp;quot;You&amp;rsquo;ve heard, &amp;lsquo;Do not commit adultery&amp;rsquo; [Ex 20:14; Deut 5:18]. 28I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, anybody that looks at a woman to lust for her has already committed adultery with her in his heart. 29If your right eye is causing you problems, gouge it out and throw it away. It&amp;rsquo;s better to lose one part of your body than for your whole body to get thrown into hell. 30If your right hand is causing you problems, cut it off and throw it away. It&amp;rsquo;s better to lose one part of your body than for your whole body to go to hell.Mt 5:21-30 31&amp;quot;It&amp;rsquo;s been said, &amp;lsquo;Whoever divorces his wife has to give her divorce papers&amp;quot; [Deut 24:1]. 32I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, whoever divorces his wife—except for adultery—is treating her like an adulteress, and whoever marries a divorced woman commits adultery. 33&amp;quot;Again, you&amp;rsquo;vepl heard that God said long ago, &amp;lsquo;Dosg not swear falsely&amp;rsquo;; &amp;lsquo;perform yoursg oaths to the LORD&amp;rsquo; [Lev 19:12; Num 30:3; Deut 23:21]. 34I&amp;rsquo;m telling youpl not to swear at all—not by heaven, it&amp;rsquo;s God&amp;rsquo;s throne; 35not by the earth, it&amp;rsquo;s his footstool; not by Jerusalem, it&amp;rsquo;s the city of the Great King; 36not by your head, you can&amp;rsquo;t make one hair white or black. 37Just say &amp;lsquo;yes, I will&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;no, I won&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rsquo;; anything more than that comes from the evil one. 38&amp;quot;You&amp;rsquo;ve heard, &amp;lsquo;An eye for an eye,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;a tooth for a tooth&amp;rsquo; [Ex 21:24; Lev 24:20; Deut 19:21]. 39I&amp;rsquo;m telling you not to try to get even with evil. Whoever slaps you on the right cheek, offer the other one too. 40If somebody sues you for your shirt, give them your coat too. 41If somebody makes* you go one mile, go with them two. 42Give to whoever asks you, and don&amp;rsquo;t turn away from anybody that wants to borrow from you. 43&amp;quot;You&amp;rsquo;ve heard, &amp;lsquo;Love yoursg neighbor [Lev 19:18], and hate your enemy.&amp;rsquo; 44I&amp;rsquo;m telling youpl to love your enemies and pray for people that mistreat you 45so you can be like your Father in heaven. He raises his sun on the good and the bad, and sends rain on the just and the unjust. 46If you love the people that love you, what&amp;rsquo;s special about that? Don&amp;rsquo;t tax collectors do that? 47If you just say &amp;lsquo;Hi&amp;rsquo; to your buddies, what&amp;rsquo;s special about that? Don&amp;rsquo;t even pagans do that? 48You be perfect like your Father.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Be careful about practicing yourpl goodness in public so people will see you. Otherwise, you won&amp;rsquo;t have any reward from your Father in heaven. 2&amp;quot;When yousg donate to benevolence, don&amp;rsquo;t blow a trumpet like the hypocrites do in the synagogues and on the streets so people will admire them. They have all the reward they&amp;rsquo;re going to get. 3When you donate to benevolence, don&amp;rsquo;t let your left hand know what your right hand&amp;rsquo;s doing. 4That will keep your benevolence will be private, and your Father who sees private things will reward you. 5&amp;quot;When youpl pray, don&amp;rsquo;t do like the hypocrites. They like to pray standing in the synagogues and on the street corners so people will see them. I tell youpl, they have all the reward they&amp;rsquo;re going to get. 6When yousg pray, go to your private room, shut the door, and pray in private. Your Father, who sees private things, will reward you. 7&amp;quot;When youpl pray, don&amp;rsquo;t say things over and over like pagans do. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean anything. They think they&amp;rsquo;ll be listened to because they say lots of words. 8Don&amp;rsquo;t do that. Your Father knows what you need before you ask. 9You pray this way,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t criticize and youpl won&amp;rsquo;t get criticized. 2The criticism youpl criticize with, you&amp;rsquo;llpl be criticized by; the measure youpl measure with, you&amp;rsquo;llpl be measured by. 3Why looksg at a speck of sawdust in somebody else&amp;rsquo;s eye, and not see the log in yoursg own? 4How can yousg say, &amp;lsquo;Let me get the piece of sawdust out of yoursg eye,&amp;rsquo; when there&amp;rsquo;s a log in yours!? 5You foolish people, getsg the log out of your own eye so yousg can see to get the speck of sawdust out of theirs. 6&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t give sacred things to dogs or throw your pearls in front of pigs. They&amp;rsquo;ll trample them under their feet and turn on you and tear you apart. 7&amp;quot;Ask and you&amp;rsquo;ll get, seek and you&amp;rsquo;ll find, knock and it&amp;rsquo;ll open for you. 8People that ask get, people that seek find, and people that knock it opens for. 9If your boy asked for a loaf of bread, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t give him a rock, would you? 10If he asked for a fish, would you give him a snake? 11If you, who are sinful, know how to give good gifts to your kids, how much more will your Father in heaven give good things to people that ask him? 12Treat other people the way you want them to treat you. That covers the Law and the Prophets. 13&amp;quot;Go through the narrow gate. It&amp;rsquo;s a broad road and a wide gate that leads to destruction, and many go through it. 14How narrow the path is and tight the gate that leads to life! Not many find it. 15&amp;quot;Watch out for false prophets that come to you in wool, but inside they&amp;rsquo;re wolves. 16You can recognize them by what they produce. People don&amp;rsquo;t gather grapes from thorns or figs from thistles, do they? 17-18Good trees bear good fruit; bad trees bear bad fruit. 19Every tree that doesn&amp;rsquo;t bear good fruit gets chopped down and thrown into the fire. 20So, you can recognize them by what they produce. 21&amp;quot;Not everybody that says to me &amp;lsquo;Lord&amp;rsquo; is going to get into the kingdom of heaven. It&amp;rsquo;s the ones that do the will of my Father in heaven. 22A lot of people will try to say to me in that day, &amp;lsquo;Lord, didn&amp;rsquo;t we prophesy in your name, cast out demons in your name, and do lots of miracles in your name?&amp;rsquo; 23I&amp;rsquo;ll tell them, &amp;lsquo;I never knew you. Go away, sinners.&amp;rsquo; 24&amp;quot;Everybody that hears what I&amp;rsquo;m saying and does it, is like a wise man that built his house on bedrock. 25Rain fell, floods came, winds blew and beat on it; but it didn&amp;rsquo;t collapse. He&amp;rsquo;d built it on bedrock. 26&amp;quot;Everybody that hears what I&amp;rsquo;m saying and doesn&amp;rsquo;t do it, is like a foolish man that built his house on sand. 27Rain fell, floods came, winds blew and beat on it, and it collapsed—a total loss.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Jesus came down from the hillside, big crowds followed him. 2A leper came and knelt down to him, &amp;ldquo;Sir, if you&amp;rsquo;re willing, you can cleanse me.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus reached out and touched him, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m willing; be cleansed.&amp;rdquo; Instantly his leprosy disappeared. 4Jesus toldp him, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t tell anybody. Instead, for a public statement, show yourself to a priest and offer the gift Moses commanded.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; He went to Capernaum, and a centurion came and appealed to him, 6&amp;quot;Sir, my servant is laid up at home paralyzed and tormented terribly.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; They got in the boat and crossed back over to his town. 2Some men were trying to bring him a paralyzed man on a stretcher. When he saw their faith, he said to the man, &amp;ldquo;Take heart, son; I&amp;rsquo;ve forgiven your sins.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Some of the scribes said to themselves, &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s blaspheming!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus knew what they were thinking, &amp;ldquo;Why are you thinking critical things? 5Which is easier, to say, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve forgiven your sins&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Get up and walk&amp;rsquo;? 6So you can know that the Son of Man has the right on earth to forgive sins&amp;rdquo;—he saidp to the man, &amp;ldquo;Get up, pick up your stretcher, and go home.&amp;rdquo; 7He got up and went home. 8When the crowd saw it, they were afraid and praised God for giving such authority to mortals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He called his twelve disciples together and gave them authority to cast out unclean spirits and heal all kinds of disease and illness. 2These are the twelve apostles: Simon called Peter; his brother Andrew; James son of Zebedee, his brother John, 3Philip, Bartholomew, Thomas, Matthew the tax collector, James son of Alphaeus, Thaddaeus, 4Simon the Cananaean, and Judas Iscariot, who also betrayed him in the end.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Jesus had finished giving his disciples directions, he went off to teach and preach in their towns.    &#x9;Mt 10:34-11:1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; In prison John heard what the Messiah was doing and sent disciples 3to ask him, &amp;ldquo;Are you the One to come or should we wait for somebody else?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus answered them, &amp;ldquo;Tell John what you&amp;rsquo;re seeing: 5the blind see, the lame walk, lepers are cleansed, the deaf hear, the dead resurrect, and the poor are hearing the good news. 6He is blessed that&amp;rsquo;s not disappointed in me.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At that time, Jesus was walking along through grain fields on the Sabbath. His disciples were hungry and started picking off heads of wheat and eating the seeds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; When some Pharisees saw it, they said, &amp;ldquo;Your disciples are breaking the Law.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; He said, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve read, haven&amp;rsquo;t you, what David and his men did when they needed food? 4He went into God&amp;rsquo;s house, and he and his men ate the consecrated loaves that were against the Law for him and his men to eat, loaves that were only for priests. 5Or, you&amp;rsquo;ve read in the Law, haven&amp;rsquo;t you, how the priests in the Temple desecrate Sabbath and remain innocent? 6Something more important than the Temple is here. 7If you&amp;rsquo;d known what this means, &amp;lsquo;I want mercy more than sacrifice&amp;rsquo; [Hos 6:6], you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have criticized innocent people. 8A person is more important than the Sabbath.&amp;ldquo;lit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus left the house that day and sat down by the lake. 2So many people were gathering that he got in a boat and sat down while the crowd stood on the shore. 3He told parables for a long time. &amp;ldquo;A sower went out to sow his seed. 4As he sowed, some seed fell along the path, and birds came along and ate it. 5&amp;quot;Some fell on rocky ground. It sprouted up right away because there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much soil. 6But when the sun climbed high, the seed dried up because it didn&amp;rsquo;t have roots. 8&amp;quot;But others fell on good ground and yielded 30, 60, or 100 times as much as he planted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Herod the tetraarch heard about Jesus 2and told his servants, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s John the Baptist, risen from the dead. That&amp;rsquo;s why he has miraculous powers.&amp;rdquo; 3Herod had arrested John, bound him, and put him in prison over Herodias, his brother Philip&amp;rsquo;s former wife. 4John kept telling him, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s against the Law for you to be living with her.&amp;rdquo; 5Although Herod wanted to put him to death, he was afraid of the people. They considered John a prophet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Pharisees and scribes camep from Jerusalem, 2&amp;quot;Why don&amp;rsquo;t your disciples keep the tradition of the elders? They don&amp;rsquo;t wash their hands before they eat.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; He answered them, &amp;ldquo;Why do you transgress God&amp;rsquo;s commandment with your tradition? 4A case in point:  God said, &amp;lsquo;Honor your parents&amp;rsquo; [Ex 20:12; Deut 5:16], and &amp;lsquo;Execute whoever cusses at his father or mother&amp;rsquo; [Ex 21:17]. 5But you say, &amp;lsquo;Whoever says to his father or mother, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve given God what you could have used,&amp;rdquo; 6certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be honoring his father. You&amp;rsquo;ve negated God&amp;rsquo;s word with your tradition. 7You foolish people, Isaiah described you well,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Pharisees and Sadducees came, testing him, asking for a sign from the sky.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; He answered, &amp;ldquo;When evening comes, you say, &amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;ll be fair weather; the sky&amp;rsquo;s red.&amp;rsquo; 3In the morning, &amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;ll be bad weather today; the sky&amp;rsquo;s red and dark.&amp;rsquo; You can read the sky, but you can&amp;rsquo;t read the signs of the times. 4An sinful, adulterous generation keeps looking for a sign, but it&amp;rsquo;s not going to get one—except for the sign of Jonah.&amp;rdquo; He left.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-17&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Six days later, Jesus tookp Peter, James, and his brother John up on a tall mountain by themselves 2and was transfigured in front of them. His face glowed like the sun, and his clothes turned as white as light. 3Moses and Elijah appeared to them and were talking to him.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Peter responded, &amp;ldquo;Lord, it&amp;rsquo;s good to be here. If you want, I&amp;rsquo;ll put up three tents—one each for you and Moses and Elijah.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-18&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At that time the disciples came to Jesus, &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s greatest in the kingdom of heaven?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; He called a little child and stood him in front of them, 3&amp;quot;Unless you change and become like little children, you won&amp;rsquo;t even get into the kingdom. 4Whoever humbles himself like this little child is greatest in the kingdom of heaven, 5and whoever receives a little child like this in my name, receives me. 6&amp;quot;Whoever makes a little one stumble that believes in me, would be better off to have a large millstone hung around their neck and drown in the sea. 7Woe to the world because of temptations. They&amp;rsquo;ll come, but woe to the ones that bring them. 8If yoursg hand or foot causes you problems, cut it off and throw it away. It&amp;rsquo;s better to go about life deformed or lame than to have two hands and two feet to be thrown into the eternal fire. 9If yoursg eye is causing you problems, gouge it out and throw it away. It&amp;rsquo;s better to go about life with one eye than to have two eyes to be thrown into the burning hell. 10&amp;quot;Make sure youpl don&amp;rsquo;t look down on one of these little ones. I tell youpl, their angels in heaven can always see my heavenly Father. [11]ms 12What do youpl think? If a man has 100 sheep and one wanders off, doesn&amp;rsquo;t he leave the 99 on the hillside and go looking for the stray? 13If he finds it, he&amp;rsquo;s happier over it than over the 99 that didn&amp;rsquo;t stray. 14In the same way, your heavenly Father doesn&amp;rsquo;t want a one of these little ones to perish. 15&amp;quot;If yoursg brother sins against you, go show him his fault privately. If he listens, you&amp;rsquo;ve gained him back. 16If he doesn&amp;rsquo;t, take one or two with you so &amp;rsquo;two or three witnesses will confirm everything&amp;rsquo; [Deut 19:15]. 17If he won&amp;rsquo;t listen, tell the church. If he won&amp;rsquo;t even listen to the church, regard him like a Gentile or a tax collector. 18&amp;quot;Whatever youpl bind on earth will be bound in heaven, and whatever you loose on earth will be loosed in heaven. 19Again, if two of you agree on earth about anything you ask for, it&amp;rsquo;ll happen for you from my Father in heaven. 20Where two or three gather in my name, I&amp;rsquo;m with them.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-19&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Jesus finished, he left Galilee and went into the regions of Judaea on the other side of the Jordan. 2Big crowds followed him, and he healed them there.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Pharisees came to him, testing him, &amp;ldquo;Is it lawful to divorce a wife for any reason whatever?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; He answered, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve read, haven&amp;rsquo;t you, that ever since the beginning the Creator &amp;lsquo;made them male and female&amp;rsquo;? [Gen 1:27; 5:2] 5So &amp;lsquo;a man is to leave his parents and unite with his wife, and they&amp;rsquo;ll become a physical unit&amp;rsquo; [Gen 2:24]. 6So, they&amp;rsquo;re no longer two but one. What God has united, people are not to separate.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-20&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The kingdom of heaven is like a landowner that went out early to hire workers. 2He agreed to pay them a denarius for the day and sent them to his vineyard. 3About 9 o&amp;rsquo;clock he went out and saw some other men standing idle in the marketplace, 4&amp;rsquo;You go to my vineyard too, and I&amp;rsquo;ll pay you what&amp;rsquo;s right.&amp;rsquo; 5At noon and one o&amp;rsquo;clock, he did the same thing. 6About five o&amp;rsquo;clock he found some more standing around, &amp;lsquo;Why are you standing here idle all day?&amp;rsquo; 8&amp;quot;That evening, he told his foreman, &amp;lsquo;Call the workers and pay them from last to first.&amp;rsquo; 9When the five o&amp;rsquo;clock men came, they got a denarius apiece. 10When the first came, they thought they&amp;rsquo;d get more; but they got a denarius too. 11They complained, 12&amp;rsquo;These last hires worked an hour, and you made them equal to us who bore the burden and scorching heat of the day.&amp;rsquo; 13&amp;quot;The landowner answered one of them, &amp;lsquo;Friend, I&amp;rsquo;ve been fair with you. Didn&amp;rsquo;t you agree to a denarius? 14Take what&amp;rsquo;s yours and go. I want to pay this last hire what I paid you. 15Can&amp;rsquo;t I do what I want with what&amp;rsquo;s mine? Are you jealous because I&amp;rsquo;m generous?&amp;rsquo; 16That&amp;rsquo;s how the last will be first and the first, last.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-21&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When they got close to Jerusalem, to Bethany on the Mount of Olives, Jesus sent two disciples, 2&amp;quot;Go in the village across from you. Close by you&amp;rsquo;ll find a donkey tied and a colt with her. Untie them and bring them to me. 3If anybody says anything, say the Lord needs them; they&amp;rsquo;ll send them right away.&amp;quot; 4That fulfilled what the prophet said,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; The disciples did like Jesus said, 7brought the donkey and colt, and put their cloaks on them, and he sat on them. 8The big crowd spread cloaks on the road; others started cutting tree branches and spreading them on the road. 9The crowd ahead and behind started shouting,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-22&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus told them another parable. 2&amp;quot;The kingdom of heaven is like a king that prepared a wedding banquet for his son. 3He sent servants to call the people that he&amp;rsquo;d invited, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t want to come. 4He sent some other servants, &amp;lsquo;Tell the ones I&amp;rsquo;ve invited, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared my banquet. I&amp;rsquo;ve butchered my oxen and grain-fed calves; everything&amp;rsquo;s ready. Come on to the banquet.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; 5But they didn&amp;rsquo;t pay any attention and went on with their own affairs, one to his field, another to his business. 6The rest grabbed his servants, treated them disgracefully, and killed them. 7&amp;quot;The king was angry and sent troops to destroy those murderers and burn their town. 8Then he told his servants, &amp;lsquo;The wedding banquet is ready, but the people I invited didn&amp;rsquo;t deserve it. 9So go out to the main roads and invite everybody you find.&amp;rsquo; 10They went out in the roads and gathered everybody they could find, good and bad, and filled the wedding banquet with guests. 11&amp;quot;The king went in to inspect the guests and saw a man that wasn&amp;rsquo;t dressed for a wedding. 12He said, &amp;lsquo;How&amp;rsquo;d you get in here without being dressed for a wedding?&amp;rsquo; He was speechless. 13The king told the attendants, &amp;lsquo;Tie him up hand and foot, and throw him out in the dark. There&amp;rsquo;ll be crying and chattering of teeth out there. 14Many are called, but few are chosen.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-23&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 23&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus told the crowd and his disciples, 2&amp;quot;The scribes and Pharisees sit on Moses&amp;rsquo; seat. 3So do whatever they tell you, but don&amp;rsquo;t be like them; they say and don&amp;rsquo;t do. 4They strap heavy, awkward burdens on people&amp;rsquo;s shoulders, but they aren&amp;rsquo;t willing to move them with one of their fingers. 5They do everything for show—like making wide phylacteries and long tassels. 6They like places of honor at banquets, prominent seats in synagogues, 7greetings in marketplaces, and people calling them Rabbi. 8Don&amp;rsquo;t you be called Rabbi. You have one Rabbi; you&amp;rsquo;re all brothers. 9Don&amp;rsquo;t call anybody on earth your father. You have one Father, the One in heaven. 10Don&amp;rsquo;t be called leaders. You have one Leader, the Messiah. 11The greatest among you will be your minister. 12Whoever exalts himself will be humbled, and whoever humbles himself will be exalted. 13&amp;quot;Woe to you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites! You lock up the kingdom of heaven in front of people. You don&amp;rsquo;t go in yourselves or let them go in that are trying to. [14]ms 15&amp;quot;Woe to you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites! You travel all over land and sea to make one proselyte. Then you make him more destined for hell than you are. 16&amp;quot;Woe to you, blind guides that say, &amp;lsquo;Whoever swears by the sanctuary hasn&amp;rsquo;t taken a binding oath, but whoever swears by the gold of the sanctuary has taken a binding oath.&amp;rsquo; 17Blind fools! Which is more imporant, the gold or the sanctuary that makes it holy? 18&amp;quot;You also say, &amp;lsquo;Whoever swears by the altar hasn&amp;rsquo;t taken a binding oath, but whoever swears by the gift on the altar has taken a binding oath.&amp;rsquo; 19You blind people! Which is more important, the gift or the altar that makes it holy? 20So whoever swears by the altar swears by it and everything on it. 21Whoever swears by the sanctuary swears by it and the One that lives there. 22Whoever swears by heaven swears by God&amp;rsquo;s throne and the One that sits on it. 23&amp;quot;Woe to you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites! You give a tenth of mint, dill, and cumin; and neglect the more important things in the Law: justice, mercy, faith. You should&amp;rsquo;ve done these and not neglected those. 24Blind guides that strain out the gnat and swallow the camel! 25&amp;quot;Woe to you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites! You clean the outside of the cup and plate, but inside they&amp;rsquo;re full of greed and self-indulgence. 26Blind Pharisee! Clean the inside of the cup first so the outside of it becomes clean too. 27&amp;quot;Woe to you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites! You&amp;rsquo;re like whitewashed tombs that look beautiful on the outside, but inside they&amp;rsquo;re filled with filth and dead men&amp;rsquo;s bones. 28You look good on the outside, but inside you&amp;rsquo;re filled with hypocrisy and lawlessness. 29&amp;quot;Woe to you, scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites! You build the tombs of the prophets and decorate the graves of the righteous 30and say, &amp;lsquo;If we&amp;rsquo;d lived when our ancestors did, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have joined them in shedding the prophets&amp;rsquo; blood.&amp;rsquo; 31You speak against yourselves because you&amp;rsquo;re just like the ones that murdered the prophets. 32Go ahead and be as bad as your ancestors. 33You snakes! You nest of vipers! How will you escape condemnation in hell? 34For this reason I&amp;rsquo;ll send you prophets, wise men, and scribes. You&amp;rsquo;ll kill and crucify some of them; some you&amp;rsquo;ll flog in your synagogues and persecute from city to city. 35So on you will come all the righteous blood shed from Abel to Zechariah son of Berechiah, the one you murdered between the altar and the sanctuary. 36I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, it&amp;rsquo;ll all come down on this generation! 37&amp;quot;Jerusalem! Jerusalem! that murders prophets and stones my messengers! How many times I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to gather your people the way a hen gathers her chicks under her wings, but you didn&amp;rsquo;t want to! 38I leave your house to you deserted. 39You won&amp;rsquo;t see me again till you say, &amp;lsquo;Blessed is the One that&amp;rsquo;s coming in the name of the LORD&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; [Ps 118:26].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-24&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 24&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus was leaving the Temple when his disciples came to show him the buildings of the Temple complex.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; He responded, &amp;ldquo;See all this? There won&amp;rsquo;t be one stone left on another.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; When he was sitting on the Mount of Olives, the disciples came privately, &amp;ldquo;Tell us, when will that happen, what will be the sign that you&amp;rsquo;re coming and the end of the age?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-25&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 25&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At that time the kingdom of heaven will be like ten virgins that took their lamps to meet the groom. 2Five were foolish, five were wise. 3The foolish didn&amp;rsquo;t take any oil along. 4The wise took some along in flasks with their lamps. 5The groom was delayed, and they all got drowsy and fell sleep. 6At midnight the shout came, &amp;lsquo;The groom! Come out to meet him!&amp;rsquo; 7The virgins got up and trimmed their lamps. 8&amp;quot;The foolish said to the wise, &amp;lsquo;Give us some of your oil; our lamps are going out.&amp;rsquo; 9&amp;quot;The wise said, &amp;lsquo;No, there won&amp;rsquo;t be enough for all of us. Go to the dealers and get your own.&amp;rsquo; 10While they were gone, the groom came. The ones that were ready went in with him to the wedding feast, and the door was locked. 11Later, the rest of the virgins came, &amp;lsquo;Sir, let us in.&amp;rsquo; 12But he answered, &amp;lsquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know you.&amp;rsquo; 13So be alert; you don&amp;rsquo;t know the day or the hour.&amp;quot; 14&amp;quot;The kingdom of heaven is like a man going on a trip. He called his servants and entrusted them with things he owned. 15He gave five talents to one, two to another, and one to another—according to their abilities—and left. Right away 16the one with five talents went and traded with them and earned five more. 17The one with two talents did the same thing and earned two more. 18But the servant with one talent dug a hole and hid it. 19&amp;quot;After a long time, the master came back and settled accounts with them. 20The one he gave five talents came and said, &amp;lsquo;Master, you entrusted me with five talents; I&amp;rsquo;ve earned five more.&amp;rsquo; 21&amp;quot;&amp;lsquo;Well done, good, dependable servant. You were dependable in handling a few things; I&amp;rsquo;ll put you in charge of many. Enjoy my approval.&amp;rsquo; 22&amp;quot;The one he gave two talents came up, &amp;lsquo;You entrusted me with two talents; I&amp;rsquo;ve earned two more.&amp;rsquo;     &#x9;    Mt 25: 14-22 23&amp;quot;&amp;lsquo;Well done, good, reliable servant. You were reliable in handling a few things; I&amp;rsquo;ll put you in charge of many. Enjoy my approval.&amp;rsquo; 24&amp;quot;But the servant he gave one talent came up, &amp;lsquo;Master, I knew you were a hard man, reaping where you didn&amp;rsquo;t sow, gathering where you didn&amp;rsquo;t scatter. 25I was afraid and hid your talent in the ground. You have what&amp;rsquo;s yours.&amp;rsquo; 26&amp;quot;&amp;lsquo;You wicked, lazy servant. You knew, did you, that I reap where I don&amp;rsquo;t sow and gather where I don&amp;rsquo;t scatter? 27You should&amp;rsquo;ve taken my money to the bankers. When I came back, I would&amp;rsquo;ve received it back plus interest. 28Take the talent away from him and give it to the one with ten. 29Everybody that has will receive more; but the one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have will lose what he does have. 30Throw the worthless servant out into the dark. There&amp;rsquo;ll be crying and chattering of teeth out there. 31&amp;quot;When the Son of Man comes in his glory with the angels, he&amp;rsquo;ll sit on his glorious throne. 32The nations will stand in front of him, and he&amp;rsquo;ll separate them like a shepherd separates sheep from goats. 33He&amp;rsquo;ll put the sheep on his right and the goats on his left. 34The king will tell the sheep, &amp;lsquo;Come, my Father&amp;rsquo;s blessed ones, inherit the kingdom prepared for you from the founding of the world. 35I was hungry, and you fed me. I was thirsty, and you gave me a drink. I was a stranger, and you gave me a place to stay. 36I needed clothes, and you gave me some. I was sick, and you took care of me. I was in prison, and you visited me.&amp;rsquo; 37&amp;quot;Those good people will say, &amp;lsquo;When did we see you hungry and feed you, or thirsty and give you a drink? 38When did we see you a stranger and give you a place to stay, or needing clothes and give you some? 39When did we see you sick or in prison and take care of you.&amp;rsquo; 40&amp;quot;The king will answer, &amp;lsquo;When you did it for the of least of these friends of mine, you did it to me.&amp;rsquo; 41&amp;quot;Then he&amp;rsquo;ll say to the people on the left, &amp;lsquo;Go away, you accursed, into the eternal fire prepared for the devil and his angels. 42I was hungry, and you didn&amp;rsquo;t give me anything to eat. I was thirsty, and you didn&amp;rsquo;t give me anything to drink. 43I was a stranger, and you didn&amp;rsquo;t give me a place to stay. I needed clothes, and you didn&amp;rsquo;t give me any. I was sick and in prison and you didn&amp;rsquo;t take care of me.&amp;rsquo; 44&amp;quot;They&amp;rsquo;ll say, &amp;lsquo;When did we see you hungry, thirsty, a stranger, needing clothes, sick, or in prison, and not help you?&amp;rsquo; 45&amp;quot;He&amp;rsquo;ll answer, &amp;lsquo;Since you didn&amp;rsquo;t do it for the least of these of the friends of mine, you didn&amp;rsquo;t do it for me either.&amp;rsquo; 46Those will go away into eternal punishment, but the good people will go into eternal life.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-26&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 26&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Jesus finished, he told his disciples, 2&amp;quot;As you know, the Passover is two days from now. I&amp;rsquo;ll be handed over to be crucified.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Meantime the chief priests and the elders of the people met in the courtyard of Caiaphas, the high priest, 4and conspired to arrest Jesus by treachery and put him to death. 5But they said, &amp;ldquo;Not during the festival; the people will riot.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 27</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-27&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 27&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the morning, the chief priests and the elders of the people developed a strategy for getting Jesus executed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; They bound him and delivered him to Pilate, the governor.  &#x9;Mt 26:67-27:2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; When Judas the traitor saw Jesus was condemned, he regretted it and took the 30 silver shekels back to the chief priests and elders, 4&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;ve sinned. I betrayed innocent blood.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; He threw the shekels into the sanctuary and went and hanged himself.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matthew 28</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/matthew/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;matthew-chapter-28&#34;&gt;Matthew Chapter 28&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After the Sabbath, as the first day of the week began to dawn, Mary the Magdalene and the other Mary came to see the tomb. 2There was a violent earthquake. An angel of the LORD came down from heaven, rolled the stone away, and sat on it. 3His appearance was like lightning; his clothes were white as snow. 4The guards were so shaken they were paralyzed with fear like dead men.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
