<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 Peter on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-peter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 Peter on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-peter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2 Peter 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-peter/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-peter/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-peter-chapter-1&#34;&gt;2 Peter Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Simon Peter, servant and apostle of Jesus ChristMessiah, to those who&amp;rsquo;ve received a faith that&amp;rsquo;s equally precious to us—faith in the goodness of our God and Savior Jesus Christ. 2Grace and peace many times over because you know God and Jesus our Lord.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; His divine power has given us everything related to life and godliness. He has provided it all by our knowing the One who called us by his own honor and goodness. 4Through that honor and goodness he has provided us great, precious promises so we can partake of the divine character and escape the corruption that&amp;rsquo;s in the world from living by lust. 5So do your best to add to your faith virtue, to your virtue knowledge, 6to knowledge self-control, endurance, 7godliness, brotherly kindness, love. 8If these keep developing in you, they&amp;rsquo;ll make you useful and fruitful as a result of personally knowing our Lord Jesus Christ. 9Those who lack them are nearsighted and blind. They&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten that they were cleansed from their old sins. 10So be all the more diligent in confirming your calling and being chosen. As long as you live that way, you won&amp;rsquo;t stumble. 11You&amp;rsquo;ll be making abundant provision for entering the eternal kingdom of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Peter 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-peter/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-peter/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-peter-chapter-2&#34;&gt;2 Peter Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; As false prophets arose among the people before, false teachers will arise among you. Under false pretenses they&amp;rsquo;ll bring in destructive heresies. They&amp;rsquo;ll even deny the Master who bought them and bring swift destruction on themselves. 2Many will follow their sensual practices, and people will slander the true Way because of them. 3In their greed they&amp;rsquo;ll exploit you with their made-up ideas. Their sentence from of old won&amp;rsquo;t delay; their destruction won&amp;rsquo;t sleep.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Peter 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-peter/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-peter/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-peter-chapter-3&#34;&gt;2 Peter Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; This is the second letter I&amp;rsquo;ve sent you. In both of them, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to keep your sincere minds alert 2by reminding you about the message from the holy prophets and about your apostles&amp;rsquo; commandments from the Lord Savior. 3Get this, first of all: later, mockers will follow their lusts and say, 4&amp;quot;Where&amp;rsquo;s the promise about his coming? From the time our ancestors died, everything&amp;rsquo;s like it&amp;rsquo;s been since creation.&amp;quot; 5They choose to forget that by God&amp;rsquo;s word the skies came into existence long ago and the earth consisted of water and emerged from water. 6By God&amp;rsquo;s word, the flood destroyed that world. 7By that same word, the earth and sky that exist now are destined for fire; they&amp;rsquo;re being kept for the judgment day and the destruction of ungodly people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
