<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DISPESNATIONS on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/dispesnations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DISPESNATIONS on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/dispesnations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DISPENSATIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/dispensations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/dispensations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DISPENSATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Human history may be organized according to the ways God has operated with mankind. The accompanying diagram pictures that history in three periods, or “dispensations”: the patriarchal, Mosaic, and Christian. The patriarchal period is so called because during that era God operated through the heads of families, or “patriarchs.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God dispensed his grace through family heads all the way from the beginning up to the time when the Israelites left Egypt. The Mosaic period is so called because during that time God operated through the Law he gave through “Moses.” He called a nation to serve as a light to the other nations—the Gentiles. God worked in this fashion from Moses to Messiah, nearly 1500 years. Since the coming of Messiah, God has been dispensing his grace to individuals through “Christ.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EXEGESIS AND THE GOSPELS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/exegesis-and-the-gospels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/exegesis-and-the-gospels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EXEGESIS AND THE GOSPELS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Change of covenants deals only with what people do. That is why (a) there is no change regarding the nature of things (ontological matters) or matters of history (events, including prophecy). (b) Civil and ceremonial observances fall out because national Israel (Moses) and the Old Testament priesthood (Aaron) have been replaced by the interpersonal church with its ministry and message. (c) There are few new ceremonial matters—baptism and the Lord’s Supper—that have come in with Christ. (d) Some modifications in the moral code come in with progressive revelation. Marriage expectancy shifts from polygamy and divorce-remarriage possibilities to permanent monogamy standard. (See the broad arrow diagram in “Old Testament Backgrounds and the Messianic Covenant.”)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISRAEL’S CORE COMMANDMENTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/israels-core-commandments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/israels-core-commandments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ISRAEL’S CORE COMMANDMENTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The List of Commandments&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Do not serve any God but the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not make graven images or bow down to them&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Do not use the LORD as a byword.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Remember to set aside the Sabbath day for resting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Honor your father and mother.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Do not commit murder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Do not commit adultery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not steal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not lie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not covet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Structure and Content of the Laws&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OLD TESTAMENT BACKGROUNDS AND THE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/old-testament-backgrounds-and-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/old-testament-backgrounds-and-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OLD TESTAMENT BACKGROUNDS AND THE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MESSIANIC COVENANT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God is the Great Teacher. Readiness is an educational principle he observed in working to achieve his purpose of a new united mankind (Ephesians 2:15). Over the centuries he has increased people’s readiness for spiritual growth by (1) giving progressive revelation, (2) instituting present forms for later realities, and even (3) adopting human forms to serve as shadows of later substances. Establishing covenants illustrates this third use of readiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PAUL VS. THE LAW OR THE TRADITION OF THE ELDERS?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/paul-vs-the-law-or-the-tradition-of-the-elders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/paul-vs-the-law-or-the-tradition-of-the-elders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PAUL VS. THE LAW OR THE TRADITION OF THE ELDERS?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some authors have suggested that Paul in his writings for the Gentile mission was opposing the tradition of the elders rather than the Mosaic Law itself. But the following factors look away from such a reading of Paul’s concern.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For one thing, (1) Paul objected to circumcising Gentiles. Circumcision was a practice related to the Law itself, not just to the tradition of the elders. The apostle was evidently countering the meaning of that rite itself, which had associations with Jewish nationalism. Beyond that, circumcision identified people with law since it identified them with the Mosaic Law. Consequently, circumcision had a soteriological implication: in theory it committed people to maintaining relationship with God by committing them to the principle of personal perfection (Leviticus 18:5; Deuteronomy 27:26), the point Paul makes in Galatians 3:8-14. Succeeding at personally doing everything required by law is exactly what none of us do or have been able to do in a practical sense; we have all sinned, and we continue to fall short of perfection—“the glory of God” (Romans 3:23). Starting in spirit (that is, I think, with interpersonal processes with Christ) and trying to finish in flesh (law, perfection, nationality) attempts to mix contrary types of things in order to accomplish the righteousness that is prerequisite for being viewed as righteous, which in turn is prerequisite for fellowship with God. In effect, the Law was a yoke that neither first-century Jews nor their fathers were able to bear (Acts 15:10). It was the Law itself that was the yoke, not just the tradition of the elders, which built a hedge around it by making it stricter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DISTINCTION BETWEEN COVENANTS AND SOME</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-distinction-between-covenants-and-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-distinction-between-covenants-and-some/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DISTINCTION BETWEEN COVENANTS AND SOME&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RELEVANT APPLICATIONS: A SKETCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Central thesis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Old Covenant was a different covenant from the New Covenant, was a different kind of covenant, and was preparatory for the new. The Old Covenant was legal while the New Covenant is interpersonal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The former (L) was added to promise (IP) for a time to define and sensitize to sin till Christ (IP) would come for universal, permanent operation leading to (perhaps conceivable millennial “kingdom” before) the eternal state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE RELATIONSHIP OF THE LAW AND THE GOSPEL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-relationship-of-the-law-and-the-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-relationship-of-the-law-and-the-gospel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE RELATIONSHIP OF THE LAW AND THE GOSPEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Christian gospel came into redemptive history, the status and nature of the Mosaic Law came into question. Not only was this question relevant to Jews, but Gentiles also had to cope with it, because Christianity came out of a heritage different from their own. Christendom has witnessed five ways of dealing with the issue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keeping the law constitutionally (code and content) and adding the gospel to it. The law and the gospel are conceived of as two stages of the same thing; they are compatible. Among the Jews the approach received significant impetus during the early years of the Gentile mission. Judaizing missionaries received strong opposition from Paul and Barnabas in Antioch and eventually in Jerusalem at the Conference on Circumcision recorded in Acts 15. In Galatians, 2 Corinthians 3, and Romans, Paul vigorously opposed the concept primarily on soteriological grounds, but other matters were also implicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
