<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 Peter on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-peter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 Peter on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-peter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2 Peter 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-peter/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-peter/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-peter-chapter-1&#34;&gt;2 Peter Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Simon Peter, servant and apostle of-Jesus Christ, to-the-ones having-received (a) faith of-the-same kind-as to-us by (the) righteousness of-the God and Savior of-us Jesus Christ.  2Grace to-you and peace be-multiplied in (the) knowledge of-God and of-Jesus the Lord of-us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; As the divine power of-him having-been-given to-us with-respect-to-all-things [the] pertaining-to life and godliness through the knowledge of-the One having-called us by-his-own glory and virtue 4by which-things he-has-given to-us the precious and very-great promises, in-order-that through these-things you-might-become sharers of-(the)-divine nature, having-escaped the corruption in the world in lust.  5And because-of-this itself, having-exerted all diligence, in the faith of-you supply [the] virtue, and in the/your virtue (supply) [the] knowledge, 6and in the/your knowledge (supply) [the] self-control, and in the/your self-control (supply) [the] patience, and in the/your patience (supply) [the] godliness, 7and in the/your godliness (supply) brotherly-kindness, and in the/your brotherly-kindness (supply) love.  8For these-things being to-you and increasing, they-do┘not└make (you) useless or unfruitful unto the knowledge of-the Lord of-us Jesus Christ. 9For to-whom these-things are┘not└present, he-is blind, short-sighted, having-received forgetfulness of-the cleansing of-the old sins of-him.  10Wherefore rather, brothers, be-diligent to-make firm the calling and election of-you, for these-things doing you-will┘certainly not ever└stumble.  11For thus richly/abundantly will-be-supplied to-you [the] entrance into the eternal kingdom of-the Lord and Savior of-us Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Peter 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-peter/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-peter/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-peter-chapter-2&#34;&gt;2 Peter Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now also false-prophets arose among the people as also false-teachers will-be among you, who will-under-false-pretenses-bring-in heresies of-destruction, denying the Master having-bought them, bringing-on themselves swift destruction.  2And many will-follow-after the sensualities of-them on-account-of whom the way of-[the] truth will-be-blasphemed/maligned.  3And in greed they-will-exploit you with-made-up words, for-whom the condemnation of-old is┘not└inactive and the destruction of-then does┘not└sleep.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; For if [the] God did┘not└spare angels having-sinned, but having-cast-(them)-into- Tartarus to-pits of-darkness being-held for condemnation, 5and did┘not└spare (the) ancient world, but kept Noah, (the) eighth, (a) preacher of-righteousness, having-brought (a) flood on-(the)-world of-(the) ungodly, 6and having-reduced-to-ashes (the) cities of Sodom and Gomorrah to-destruction, he condemned (them) to-destruction, having-set (them) (as an) example of-ones-going to-live-ungodly, 7and rescuing righteous Lot oppressed by the sensual conduct of-the unprincipled-ones in ungodliness, (8for by-what-he-saw and heard, the righteous-(man) living among them burdened (his) righteous soul with-(the)-lawless deeds (of-them) from day to day) 9(the) Lord knows to-deliver devout-ones from trial, and to-keep unrighteous-ones punished to (the) day of-judgment, 10and above-all the-ones going after flesh with (the) desire of-corruption and despising authority. Daring, self-willed, they-do┘not└tremble blaspheming/railing-at glories/dignitaries, 11whereas angels being greater in might and power do┘not└bring railing condemnation against them before (the) Lord.  12But these like unreasoning animals born (as) creatures for capture and ruin, blaspheming/railing in what-things they-are-ignorant in the ruining they-are-ruined, 13wronged (as) reward of wrong-doing, considering [the] reveling in (the) daytime (a) pleasure, (they are) stains and blemishes reveling in the deceptions of-them, carousing-with you, 14having eyes full of-adultery and unceasing-from sins, luring unstable souls, having (a) heart trained with-greed, accursed children, 15forsaking (the) right way, they-went-astray, following-after the way of-[the] Balaam, (son) of-[the] Beor, who loved (the) reward of-injustice, 16and he-had rebuke for his transgressions; (a) mute donkey speaking in (the) voice of-(a)-man restrained the madness of-the prophet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Peter 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-peter/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-peter/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-peter-chapter-3&#34;&gt;2 Peter Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Indeed, brothers, I-am-writing to-you this, (a) second letter in whichpl I-am-stirring-up in remembrance the sincere mind of-you 2to-remember the beforehand-written words by the holy prophets and the commandment of-the apostles of-you, (the commandment) of-the Lord and Savior, 3knowing this first that mockers will-come with mockery (the) last of-the-days going/pursuing according-to [the] their-own lusts of-them, 4and saying, &amp;ldquo;Where is the promise of-the coming/presence of-him, for from which the fathers/ancestors fell-asleep, all-things remain thus from (the) beginning of-creation?&amp;rdquo;  5For them willing, this escapes-(their)-notice:  that skies were of-old and land standing out-of water and through water by the word of-[the] God, 6on-account-of whichms the then world was-destroyed having-been-flooded by water.  7But now the skies and the earth by the same word have-been treasured-up for-fire, being-kept for-(the)-day of judgment and destruction of-[the] ungodly men.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
