<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BAPTISM on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/baptism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BAPTISM on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/baptism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A POSITION STATEMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/a-position-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/a-position-statement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A POSITION STATEMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ON THE MEANING OF CHRISTIAN BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of our standard response to the gospel, God appointed baptism for expressing personal identification with Jesus Christ, which involves commitment to his lordship, values, and purposes. In consequence of our identity with him, God forgives our sin, grants fellowship with his Spirit, and numbers us among his children.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this description, (1) “standard response” means that special cases and impossible circumstances are not in view, circumstances where baptism cannot be performed or cannot be performed without endangering life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A SKETCH ON BAPTISM FROM ACTS 2:38</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/a-sketch-on-baptism-from-acts-238/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/a-sketch-on-baptism-from-acts-238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A SKETCH ON BAPTISM FROM ACTS 2:38&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Repent         be baptized  into    the name of Jesus Messiah   &#x9;remission of sins&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the Holy Spirit as a gift&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;membership in Christ’s body&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Identity with Jesus the Messiah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;means commitment to him:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;total (every aspect)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;permanent (all life long)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;exclusive (vs. all other&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;parallel possibilities)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The remission is based on identity with the One who is what we are called to be and aspire to be. God is willing to consider us righteous on the basis of identity with the One who is righteous. The remission is not based on the act of baptism per se, but on the One we commit to in doing it. [identity with Messiah]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABSTRACT OF DISTINCTIONS ABOUT THE NECESSITY OF BAPTISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/abstract-of-distinctions-about-the-necessity-of-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/abstract-of-distinctions-about-the-necessity-of-baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT OF DISTINCTIONS ABOUT THE NECESSITY OF BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A distinction needs to be made between standard situations and special cases. Denying the necessity of baptism applies only to special cases. Special cases include those in which&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) a person would be risking health or life in being baptized,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(b) people honestly misunderstand that baptism is immersion or should have been a personal adult response of their own,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(c) someone is “killed on the way to the baptistry.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BAPTISM AS IDENTIFICATION WITH CHRIST</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/baptism-as-identification-with-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/baptism-as-identification-with-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BAPTISM AS IDENTIFICATION WITH CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seeing baptism as identification with Christ provides a framework for working through several abnormal situations that arise and helps make sense even of normal situations that may be overlooked in the theory and practice of the ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Addressing first the normal situation, we observe clear cases of baptism that do not move lost people into a saved condition: righteous Jews called to John’s baptism for remission of sins, saved disciples of John called to Christian baptism, and the baptism of Jesus himself by John. Such examples show that Christian—and even Johannine—baptism has a bigger frame of reference than salvation from lostness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QUESTIONS ABOUT CHRISTIAN BAPTISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/questions-about-christian-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/questions-about-christian-baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;QUESTIONS ABOUT CHRISTIAN BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Doctrinal Questions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is baptism for (meaning)?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, in Christian baptism we identify with Jesus Christ. The New Testament means identification when it speaks of (a) being baptized “into Christ,” “into the name of Christ,” and similar expressions (Matthew 28:19; Acts 2:38; 8:16; 10:48; 19:5; Galatians 3:27). We identify with the Messiah instead of with Moses (1 Corinthians 10:1-2) or John the Baptist (Acts l9:1-7) or the apostle Paul (1 Corinthians 1:13-15). As a result, we belong to Christ (1 Corinthians 3:22-23; 1:12). Paul means identification when he says that by baptism we are (b) “united with Christ” (1 Corinthians 6:5). Baptism is a pledge of allegiance to him in which we commit ourselves to his purposes, values, and motivations. We make that commitment to the extent of the death that baptism pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REBAPTISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/rebaptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/rebaptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;REBAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wise policy is to let candidates make their own decision about rebaptism; after all, baptism is their obedience to God, not ours. Nevertheless, people usually take their cue from those they have come to trust on religious matters. For these reasons we will not always be able to leave the issue in the hands of candidates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The predominate opinion has been that rebaptism is not necessary even for those who understood their previous baptism as a testimony to other believers or as the way of entering the visible body of Christ on earth. That opinion seems wise for reasons like the following.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RETHINKING THE DESCRIPTION OF BAPTISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/rethinking-the-description-of-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/rethinking-the-description-of-baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RETHINKING THE DESCRIPTION OF BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following presentation gives the author’s understanding of Christian baptism even though it attempts to represent fairly a wider movement. What I am saying here may at first sound different to brethren from my background. That difference comes in part from the attention given to framework of thought and structure of presentation. We have tried to achieve wholeness, cohesiveness, and clarity by giving overt expression to our presuppositions. The difference comes also from the fact that there is some diversity in the movement, which is natural enough in a free-church heritage the size of this one. Unity through restoration assumes the desire to adjust toward a more New Testament understanding. Hopefully, this treatment will synthesize ideas and sharpen and improve what we believe and practice in regard to Christian baptism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIGHTLY DIVIDING THE WORD OF TRUTH IN ACTS 2:38</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/rightly-dividing-the-word-of-truth-in-acts-238/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/rightly-dividing-the-word-of-truth-in-acts-238/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RIGHTLY DIVIDING THE WORD OF TRUTH IN ACTS 2:38&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian baptism is a self-expression of personal identification with Jesus Christ, and God gives consequences on the basis of that identity more than on the basis of the act itself: forgiveness of sin, gift of the Spirit, and fellowship in the body of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 2:38 connects with the thesis above by making the full threefold affirmation: baptism, in the name of Christ, and forgiveness of sins. It does not say, “(Let each one of you) repent and be baptized for the remission of sins,” as sometimes misquoted. Strictly speaking, scripture nowhere uses the phraseology “baptism for remission of sins.” The point, of course, is not to disconnect baptism from forgiveness in every way, but to conceptualize the connection exactly. Ananias does tell Saul to be baptized and wash away his sins (Acts 22:16). Peter feels free even to say that baptism saves us (1 Peter 3:21), salvation being reconciliation from alienation caused by sin. Evidently in referring to baptism, Titus 3:5 declares that God “saved us through the washing of regeneration.”1 Even John’s baptism was a baptism of repentance unto/for remission of sins (Matthew 3:2; Mark 1:4; Luke 3:3; Acts 13:24; 19:4). Baptism texts include the forgiveness consequence, especially when sin figures prominently in the circumstance; hence, the deliberative question on Pentecost, “What are we going to do?” (Acts 2:37) and Ananias’ directive to “the chief of sinners,” distraught over having so severely persecuted Jesus’ disciples (Acts 22:16).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PURPOSE OF CHRISTIAN BAPTISM: A SYNOPSIS*</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-purpose-of-christian-baptism-a-synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-purpose-of-christian-baptism-a-synopsis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PURPOSE OF CHRISTIAN BAPTISM: A SYNOPSIS*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIANITY AS AN INTERPERSONAL “SYSTEM”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian baptism is an interpersonal act in which a repentant believer identifies with Jesus Christ. On the basis of identity with Christ, God promises to forgive our sins, grant us the presence of his Spirit, and add us to Christ&amp;rsquo;s body, the church.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TWO BASIC POINTS ABOUT BAPTISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/two-basic-points-about-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/two-basic-points-about-baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TWO BASIC POINTS ABOUT BAPTISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two points should be highlighted in presentations about baptism. First, baptism should not be too closely identified with outer response. That lends itself to distinguishing inner and outer, identifying faith with inner and baptism with outer, and then affirming that it is the inner dimension that justifies rather than the outer expressive act as well, thus trying to avoid baptism as a work and bringing it into conformity with the Pauline formula “salvation by faith” vs. works. But “faith” in Romans/Galatians does not mean inner action; that is the usage in James. Paul means action in the context of personal relationship (faith) vs. action in the context of legal process (works). We do well to unite inner and outer response in salvation and to consider baptism itself as comprised of both dimensions inseparably. That unity of aspects applies to all acts of obedience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TYPES OF SYSTEMS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/types-of-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/types-of-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TYPES OF SYSTEMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not all systems are alike. They often operate in respect to different kinds of matters, but the main contrast lies in the kinds of connectors in them that bind actions to results. Below are three types of systems that illustrate this diversity. We outline them here in order to clarify what causes people to differ so intensely about the role of Christian baptism in the salvation process. Basically what happens is that at various points in their total understanding of baptism they are shifting baptism back and forth between different systems without realizing it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNDERSTANDING CHRISTIAN ORDINANCES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/understanding-christian-ordinances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/understanding-christian-ordinances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UNDERSTANDING CHRISTIAN ORDINANCES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following presentation is, strictly speaking, the author’s understanding of Christian ordinances even though it attempts to represent fairly the view taken by a larger movement as well. There is some diversity in that movement, which is natural enough in a free-church heritage the size of ours; but that diversity makes it more difficult to state “our position.” Nevertheless, unity through restoration accomplishes one thing for us and for everyone here today: it assures the desire to continue adjusting toward a more biblical understanding. Hopefully, this treatment will synthesize our ideas and thereby sharpen and improve what we all believe and practice about Christian ordinances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHAT THE VERY EXISTENCE OF BAPTISM SHOWS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/what-the-very-existence-of-baptism-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/what-the-very-existence-of-baptism-shows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHAT THE VERY EXISTENCE OF BAPTISM SHOWS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The very fact that baptism exists shows that salvation is not by works of law, works in a legal sense, works in a legal context, acts that have some legal value. Furthermore, the very existence of baptism shows that salvation is not by human effort relative even to an interpersonal standard of behavior, which, as in law, is also a perfection standard. To make this claim convincing, we must show that baptism is not primarily for bringing about entrance into the institutional church or for communicating to other people that we have decided to follow Jesus. For present purposes, that point is sufficiently shown by the biblical expression “baptism into Christ,” not “baptism into the church” or some wording that indicates testimony to other people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
