<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ezra on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ezra on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the first year of Cyrus, king of Persia, to fulfill his message through Jeremiah, the LORD stirred up Cyrus. He sent a written proclamation everywhere in his kingdom: 2&amp;quot;Cyrus, king of Persia, says, &amp;lsquo;The LORD God of heaven has given me the kingdoms of the world and appointed me to build him a temple in Jerusalem, in Judah. 3Whoever is from his people, your God be with you! Go up and rebuild the Temple of the LORD God of Israel, the God in Jerusalem. 4Wherever there&amp;rsquo;s a survivor, support him with silver and gold, supplies and livestock, plus freewill offerings.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; &#x9;       Ezra 1:1-4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The People in the Province Who Went Up They went to Jerusalem and their towns in Judah 2with Zerubbabel, Jeshua, Nehemiah, Seraiah, Reelaiah, Mordecai, Bilshan, Mispar, Bigvai, Rehum, and Baanah: from the 27people from Michmas &#x9;122&#x9;28people from Bethel and Ai &#x9;        22 29people from Nebo &#x9;  52&#x9;30people from Magbish &#x9;      156 31people from the other Elam    1,254&#x9;32people from Harim &#x9;                  320 43the Temple servants: descendants of Ziha, Hasupha, Tabbaoth, 44Keros, Siaha, Padon, 45Lebanah, Hagabah, Akkub, 46Hagab, Shalmai, Hanan, 47Giddel, Gahar, Reaiah, 48Rezin, Nekoda, Gazzam, 49Uzza, Paseah, Besai, 50Asnah, Meunim, Nephisim, 51Bakbuk, Hakupha, Harshur, 52Bazluth, Mehida, Harsha, 53Barkos, Sisera, Temah, 54Neziah, Hatipha. 55descendants of Solomon&amp;rsquo;s servants: descendants of Sotai, Hassophereth, Peruda, 56Jaalah, Darkon, Giddel, 57Shephatiah, Hattil, Pochereth-hazzebaim, Ami. 58All the Temple servants and descendants of Solomon&amp;rsquo;s servants &#x9;&#x9;     392 59The following went up from Tel-melah, Tel-harsha, Cherub, Addan, and Immer, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t provide evidence that their families and their descendants were from Israel. This group included 60descendants of Delaiah, Tobiah, and Nekoda, &#x9;      652. 61descendants of the priests: descendants of Habaiah, Hakkoz, and Barzillai. (This Barzillai had married a daughter of Barzillai the Gileadite and took Barzillai&amp;rsquo;s name.) 62They searched among their genealogical records, but they couldn&amp;rsquo;t locate them. They were considered unqualified for the priesthood. 63The governor said they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t eat the most holy things till a priest stood up with Urim and Thummim. 64The whole assembly numbered &#x9;&#x9;42,360 66They had 736 horses, 245 mules, 67435 camels, and 6,720 donkeys. 68When some heads of families arrived at the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple in Jerusalem, they offered willingly for restoring God&amp;rsquo;s Temple on its foundation. 69According to their ability they gave to the treasury 1100 lbs 61,000 drachmas of gold, 6250 lbs 5,000 minas of silver, and 100 priestly vestments. 70The priests and Levites, some of the people, singers, gatekeepers, Temple servants, and all Israel lived in their towns.&#x9;                                                          Ezra 2:1-7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When the seventh month came and the Israelites were in the towns, they came together in Jerusalem. 2Jeshua son of Jozadak, his brothers the priests, Zerubbabel son of Shealtiel, and his brothers built God&amp;rsquo;s altar for offering burnt offerings as written in the Law of Moses, the man of God. 3They set up the altar on its original site despite their fear of the people around them. They offered burnt offerings to the LORD morning and evening. 4They celebrated the Festival of Booths as written and offered the set number of burnt offerings daily as required by the Law. 5From then on, there was continual burnt offering for new moons and the annual festivals the LORD had consecrated. Everyone offered a freewill offering to the LORD. 6From the first day, seventh month, they offered burnt offerings, but the foundation of the Temple hadn&amp;rsquo;t been laid. 7Then they donated money to the masons and carpenters as well as food, drink, and olive oil to the Sidonians and Tyrians to bring cedar from Lebanon by sea to Joppa with permission from Cyrus.&#x9;  Ezra 3:1-7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When the enemies of Judah and Benjamin heard that the exiles were rebuilding a temple to the LORD God of Israel, 2they approached Zerubbabel and the other leaders, &amp;ldquo;Let us build with you. We worship your God too. We&amp;rsquo;ve been sacrificing to him since Esarhaddon, king of Assyria, sent us here.&amp;rdquo; 3But Zerubbabel, Jeshua, and the other leaders said, &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t have anything in common with us building a temple to our God. We&amp;rsquo;ll build it like King Cyrus decreed.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The prophets Haggai and Zechariah son of Iddo served as prophets to the Jews in Judah and Jerusalem in the name of the God of Israel. 2Then Zerubbabel and Jeshua started again to rebuild God&amp;rsquo;s Temple. His prophets supported them. 3At that time, Tattenai, governor of the province Beyond the River, and Shethar-bozenai, and their colleagues came and asked, &amp;ldquo;Who issued a decree for you to rebuild this Temple and restore this structure?&amp;rdquo; 4We told them the names of the men that were reconstructing it. 5But God kept an eye on the elders of the Jews. They didn&amp;rsquo;t stop them till a report could go to Darius and a written reply could come back.     Ezra 5:1-6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; King Darius issued an order to search the Babylonian archives, which were housed in the treasury. 2But in the fortress in Ecbatana, in the province of Media, they found a scroll with the following written in it:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; In the first year of King Cyrus, he issued a decree: &amp;lsquo;As to God&amp;rsquo;s Temple in Jerusalem, rebuild it, where sacrifices are offered. Keep its foundations the same. Its height and width are 90ft 4with three courses of large stones alternating with one course of timbers. Pay for it out of the royal treasury. 5Take back to God&amp;rsquo;s Temple the gold and silver articles Nebuchadnezzar took from it.&amp;rsquo;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;         Ezra 6:1-5 6&amp;quot;Now then, Tattenai, governor of Beyond the River, Shethar-bozenai, and your associates, officials in the provinces Beyond the River, don&amp;rsquo;t interfere. 7Let the governor and elders of the Jews rebuild God&amp;rsquo;s Temple on its site. 8And, I decree what you&amp;rsquo;re to do for those elders in rebuilding this Temple: without delay pay them the full cost out of the royal treasury from taxes in the provinces Beyond the River. 9As the priests in Jerusalem request, give daily whatever they need: young bulls, rams, and lambs for burnt offerings, wheat, salt, wine, and anointing oil. 10Then they can offer acceptable sacrifices to the God of heaven and pray for the life of the king and his sons. 11For anybody who violates this edict, I decree that a timber be pulled out of his house, he be impaled on it, and his house be made a garbage pile. 12May the God that has put his name there overthrow any king or people that tries to violate this decree and destroy that Temple of God. I, Darius, have made this decree. Carry it out diligently.&amp;quot;&#x9;  &#x9;Ezra 6:6-12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, in the reign of Artaxerxes, king of Persia, came Ezra son of Seraiah (son of Azariah son of Hilkiah 2son of Shallum son of Zadok son of Ahitub 3son of Amariah son of Azariah son of Meraioth 4son of Zerahiah son of Uzzi son of Bukki 5son of Abishua son of Phinehas son of Eleazar) son of Aaron the chief priest. 6Ezra, a scribe, an expert in the Law of Moses, came up from Babylon. The king granted him everything he requested because the LORD&amp;rsquo;s hand was on him. 7Some Israelites, priests, Levites, singers, gatekeepers, and Temple servants came up to Jerusalem in the seventh year of King Artaxerxes. [8] 9On the first day, first month, Ezra started out from Babylon. On the first day, fifth month he arrived at Jerusalem because God&amp;rsquo;s good hand was on him. 10He had set his heart on studying the Law of the LORD, practicing it, and teaching its statutes and ordinances in Israel.&#x9;&#x9;  Ezra 7:1-10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Heads of Families and the Genealogies of Men 13from the family of Adonikam (coming later): Eliphelet, Jeuel, and Shemaiah plus 60 men;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v15&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt; I assembled them at the canal that runs to Ahava, where we camped for three days. When I looked over the people and the priests, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find any Levites. 16So I sent for Eliezer, Ariel, Shemaiah, Elnathan, Jarib, Elnathan, Nathan, Zechariah, and Meshullam (leaders), and for Joiarib and Elnathan (teachers). 17I sent them to Iddo, leader of the Levites at Casiphia, to tell him and his brothers (the Temple servants at that place) to bring ministers to us for God&amp;rsquo;s Temple. 18By God&amp;rsquo;s good hand on us, they brought Sherebiah (an insightful son of Mahli, descendant of Levi) as well as his sons and brothers, 18 men;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When these things had been completed, the officials approached me, &amp;ldquo;The people of Israel, the priests, and the Levites haven&amp;rsquo;t separated from the foreigners and the disgusting things of the Canaanites, Hittites, Perizzites, Jebusites, Ammonites, Moabites, Egyptians, and Amorites. 2They&amp;rsquo;ve taken some of their daughters as wives for themselves and their sons. The holy race has intermingled with foreigners. The officials and rulers have been the most prominent in this unfaithfulness.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/ezra/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; While Ezra was praying and confessing, crying and prostrating himself in front of God&amp;rsquo;s Temple, a big crowd of men, women, and children gathered around him, sobbing with him. 2Shecaniah son of Jehiel, one of Elam&amp;rsquo;s sons, told him, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve been unfaithful to our God and married foreign women from the land. But there&amp;rsquo;s still hope for Israel. 3Let&amp;rsquo;s make a covenant with God to put away the wives and their children as you&amp;rsquo;ve advised and do it according to the Law. 4Get up! This is your responsibility. We&amp;rsquo;ll be with you. Have the courage to do it.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
