<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sermons on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/categories/sermons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sermons on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/categories/sermons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>For All the Saints Who from Their Labors Rest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/for-all-the-saints-who-from-their-labors-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/for-all-the-saints-who-from-their-labors-rest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For All the Saints Who from Their Labors Rest&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;William Walsham How&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For all the saints who from their labors rest,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who Thee by faith before the world confessed,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thy name, O Jesus, be forever blest.  Alleluia!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou wast their rock, their fortress, and their might;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou, Lord, their captain in the well-fought fight;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou, in the darkness dread, their one true light.  Alleluia!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O may Thy soldiers, faithful, true, and bold,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IT IS GOOD TO REMEMBER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/it-is-good-to-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/it-is-good-to-remember/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT IS GOOD TO REMEMBER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the grand cycle of life, only four or five generations of humanity are accessible to our experience at any one moment in history. Those earlier men and women we must remember, and so we set aside this day to reflect on their contribution to our welfare.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is important to remember because doing so fosters appreciation. None of us are self-made people. Those who went before set the range of possibilities that we choose among and now enjoy. Were it not for their sacrifices and labors, we would not have the freedoms we prize or many of the possessions we own. Surely we shape our own lives and mold their direction by our efforts, but those efforts are largely exerted within the options that have been handed down to us. We owe our ancestors a great debt of gratitude, and we inherit an obligation in turn to leave our legacy—to respect, cherish, and protect the privileges inherited our forefathers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jennifer Chantell Wenzl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/jennifer-chantell-wenzl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/jennifer-chantell-wenzl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Chantell Wenzl&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Wenzls, I want to thank you for this wonderful demonstration of support for the family and for such an overwhelming expression of love for Jenny in this time of intense sorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grief is our response to loss, and the deepest loss is the loss of a person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not so much what a person does for/with us, but who she is as expressed through her actions toward us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MEMORIAL DAY ADDRESS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/memorial-day-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/memorial-day-address/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MEMORIAL DAY ADDRESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The saying goes, “The future of an event belongs to the event.” Let me explain. When something happens, it does not just happen disconnected from what is around it. Out of it flows what it leads to. That fact opens up a way to measure the importance of the occurrence. How long do its effects last? How many people does it impact? How much capacity does it have for its consequences to grow as time goes on?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memorial Day Meditation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/memorial-day-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/memorial-day-meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Memorial Day Meditation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Morrison,  Lutheran, Lillis Catholic,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vermillion Christian Church&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One obvious feature of this cemetery is the stones erected here. But they are not just stones; they have names on them: Dowd, Donahy, Kramer, Bramhall, Nocks. These markers focus our attention on specific individuals. They are like icons on a computer. When we click on them, they open up to a vast reservoir of memories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are sorrows we shared, hardships we endured together, disappointments we knew, happy times at the kitchen table, and honest labor in that field north of the house. These stones mean something because they direct our attention on a mother, a neighbor, a friend, someone else connected to us. In this cemetery people have indeed remembered, as shown by the flowers beside many graves and as shown by your presence in this gathering today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raymond F. Schober</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/raymond-f-schober/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/raymond-f-schober/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raymond F. Schober&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raymond F. Schober, 71, of Vermillion, Kansas, died Saturday evening, February 20, 1999, at the hospital in Onaga, Kansas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Schober owned and operated Schober’s Service in Vermillion since 1955 and Dutch’s Place since 1965.  From 1980 to 1994 he was a field engineer for Associated Engineers.  He served on a U. S. Navy minesweeper in the Pacific Theater during World War II.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born on March 14, 1927 in Rossville, Kansas, to Fred and Mary Schober, Raymond later attended school in Centralia.  He was a member of the Vermillion Christian Church, American Legion Post #257, VFW Post #1359, and was active in the city council of Vermillion.  He married Daisy Willard on December 24, 1950, in Westmoreland.  She survives of the home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SURPRISED AT SUNRISE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/surprised-at-sunrise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/surprised-at-sunrise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SURPRISED AT SUNRISE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Surprised at sunrise were two women,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;two women making their way to the tomb of a friend,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the tomb of a revered teacher,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;two women who came to perform an unwelcome task&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;that somebody had to do,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;two women who had watched in helpless horror the &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;                dying agony of a man condemned by jealousy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the mock trials and the gruesome visages that followed, they had had uncounted hours for the sights of that Friday to become fixed in their minds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE LEGACY OF DORCAS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/the-legacy-of-dorcas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/the-legacy-of-dorcas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE LEGACY OF DORCAS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 9:35-42&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What We Learn from Experience&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Peter came to Joppa that day, they began showing him the garments and coats Dorcas had made. I venture to say, they did not do that because the garments were nicely made, although no doubt they were. I venture to say, they did not do that because she was a good seamstress, although she probably was. I venture to say, they did not do that because the garments were expensive, although she may have used the best material she could find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PASSING OF JAIRUS’ DAUGHTER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/the-passing-of-jairus-daughter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/the-passing-of-jairus-daughter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PASSING OF JAIRUS’ DAUGHTER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 8:49-55)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Her name is not given, but she was twelve. The father, a ruler of the synagogue, did what desperate fathers do: he went to find the only help he knew, because she was ill and very weak. At the earnest urging of Jairus, our Lord turned that day from present labors and walked beside a worried man toward the object of his care.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Do You Have That You Didn’t Receive?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/what-do-you-have-that-you-didnt-receive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/what-do-you-have-that-you-didnt-receive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What Do You Have That You Didn’t Receive?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lord, today we consider our place in the larger scheme of things, and so acknowledge you, first of all, as the beginning of all else besides you, the sustainer of all you have made, and the basis for the hope that stretches out before us. Amen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the question: What do you have that you didn’t receive? Obviously, you have labored long and hard in the process of life. Yet what you have contributed could not have been done without the possibilities and opportunities already in place and the abilities passed down to you. In the countryside around, lie fields where you and your neighbors work the ground, plant the seed, harvest the crops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
