<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FUTURE THINGS (Eschatology) on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/future-things-eschatology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FUTURE THINGS (Eschatology) on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/future-things-eschatology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>“IN THE DAYS OF THOSE KINGS”: DANIEL 2:44</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/in-the-days-of-those-kings-daniel-244/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/in-the-days-of-those-kings-daniel-244/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“IN THE DAYS OF THOSE KINGS”: DANIEL 2:44&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Daniel 2:44 those kings [מֶלֶךְ] seems to refer to the preceding four kingdoms [מַלְכוּ] of 2:38-43. Daniel uses kingdom and king somewhat interchangeably in that king can by metonymy stand for the realm he rules, even though over a period of time there may be several kings in one kingdom. In 2:39 the writer says, “And after you, Nebuchadnezzar, will arise another kingdom inferior to you.” A similar shift of terms comes in 2:44, “In the days of those kings the God of heaven will set up a kingdom . . . it will break all these kingdoms in pieces and consume (them).” Later in 7:17 the four beasts from the sea (7:3; earth, 7:17) are said to represent four kings, whereas 7:23 says that “the fourth beast will be a fourth kingdom that will be different from all the kingdoms.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ANIMAL SYMBOLISM IN BIBLICAL APOCALYPTIC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/animal-symbolism-in-biblical-apocalyptic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/animal-symbolism-in-biblical-apocalyptic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANIMAL SYMBOLISM IN BIBLICAL APOCALYPTIC&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within prophecy generally, apocalyptic has several distinguishing characteristics. As to content, apocalyptic deals with eschatological reference, angelic emphasis, cataclysm, universal-cosmic scope, pessimism in people, divine sovereignty, transcendence, the concept of final comfort. As to form, apocalyptic uses animal symbolism and numerology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In chronological order the apocalyptic passages in scripture are Isaiah 24-27 (+ 6); Ezekiel 33-48 especially; Daniel 2, 7-12; Zechariah generally (although in many places the book is non-apocalyptic prophecy); the Olivet Discourse in Matthew 24-25, Mark 13, and Luke 21; 1 Thessalonians 4:1-5:11; 2 Thessalonians 2:1-12; and the Book of Revelation generally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APPROACHING THE MILLENNIAL ISSUE WITH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/approaching-the-millennial-issue-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/approaching-the-millennial-issue-with/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPROACHING THE MILLENNIAL ISSUE WITH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MINISTRY IN MIND&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regarding end times, we can learn a lesson from Jewish religious leaders of Jesus’ day. They had so exactly worked out their understanding of Messianic prophecy that they did not recognize the Messiah when he came. We will not be that wrong this time. We will recognize him, because his return will not be a local, private entrance into the human sphere (Matthew 24:23-27). Nevertheless, we need to hold tentatively to our expectations about the timing of that event, about its relationship to other future events, and about the very nature of some related events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETERNAL OPPORTUNITY FOR SALVATION THROUGH CHRIST?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/eternal-opportunity-for-salvation-through-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/eternal-opportunity-for-salvation-through-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETERNAL OPPORTUNITY FOR SALVATION THROUGH CHRIST?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. An Unnecessary Concept&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the assumption, for the moment, that eternal opportunity for salvation through Christ could not be disproved, we should consider several matters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Other preferable observations adjust our understanding of hell so that eternal option is unnecessary. A big impetus for the doctrine of eternal option comes from the apparent impropriety of a loving God torturing sinners endlessly in hell for no remedial purpose; punitive purpose seems not to call for such severity if punishment should be commensurate with the crime. Several factors reduce the urgency of this “problem.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESURRECTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/resurrection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/resurrection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RESURRECTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;Biblical References to Resurrection&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Old Testament&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exodus 3:6 (Matthew 22:29-32)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 19:25-27&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 26:19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Daniel 12:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ezekiel 37:1-14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Deliverance from Sheol”: Psalm 49:15; 73:24-25; Proverbs 23:14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note Hebrews 11:10, 13-16, 19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;New Testament&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 5:25-29&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 6:39-40, 44, 54&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 11:24-25&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 14:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 17:24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 5:1-10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Thessalonians 4:13-16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revelation 20:4-6?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revelation 20:13&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Resurrection of the wicked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Daniel 12:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John 5:28-29&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DOCTRINE OF “SOUL-SLEEPING”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-doctrine-of-soul-sleeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-doctrine-of-soul-sleeping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DOCTRINE OF “SOUL-SLEEPING”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Views of the human condition during the intermediate state differ as to whether it is a conscious existence. Conscious existence means that between death and the general resurrection, we experience the rewards and punishments later to be publicly declared at the great white throne judgment. Unconsciousness during that time has two possibilities: “soul sleeping” or non-existence. The second option means that when we die, we cease to exist objectively until God “recreates” us out of his memory, an event simultaneous with, or the same as, resurrection. For all practical purposes, soul sleeping amounts to the same thing though, strictly speaking, we do objectively exist. The following considerations go into evaluating the concept of “soul sleeping.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE OLIVET DISCOURSE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-olivet-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-olivet-discourse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE OLIVET DISCOURSE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two related questions may be asked regarding Matthew’s account of the Olivet Discourse. (1) Who or what is the “abomination of desolation” in 24:14? (2) If some events are still future, where is the dividing line between the ones now fulfilled and the ones still to come? All three synoptists record this sermon: Matthew 24-25; Mark 13; and Luke 21.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since answering the second question determines the answer to the first, we need to establish the dividing line between past and future events first. A harmony of the accounts helps track the progress of thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE SEVENTY-WEEK PROPHECY OF DANIEL 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-seventy-week-prophecy-of-daniel-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-seventy-week-prophecy-of-daniel-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE SEVENTY-WEEK PROPHECY OF DANIEL 9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The beginning time for the seventy “weeks/hebdomads” is best placed at the first year&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;of Darius, the son of Ahasuerus (538 B.C.).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;The word/commandment that goes forth in 9:25 seems to be the same as the word/&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;commandment that went forth in 9:23a.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The terminology is the same: “the going forth of the commandment” (מֹצָא דָבָר) in 9:25 is parallel to “the commandment went forth” (יָצָא דָבָר) in 9:23. (In appropriate circumstances דָּבָר may be translated “commandment”: Exodus 34:28; Joshua 1:13; 1 Chronicles 26:32; Esther 1:19, etc.) In 9:23 there may be another reference to the same thing in the expression “consider the commandment” (בִּין בַּדָּבָר), although usually the word דָּבָר is translated “matter” or some other indefinite way here. Gabriel may be telling Daniel to understand the outworking of this word of God that has been decreed (9:24) on Israel and Jerusalem. The vision (מַרְאָה) of 9:23b is then in reference to the whole of 9:24-27.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
