<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nehemiah on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nehemiah on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Memoirs of Nehemiah Son of Hacaliah In the month Chislev, the twentieth year, I was in Susa, the capital. 2Hanani, one of my brothers, and some men came from Judah. I asked them about the Jews that had survived the captivity and about Jerusalem. 3They told me, &amp;ldquo;The remnant in the province is in dire straits and dishonor. The wall around Jerusalem has been torn down and its gates burned.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the month Nisan, twentieth year of King Artaxerxes, wine was present, and I took it up to him. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been sad in his presence before. 2So he asked me, &amp;ldquo;Why do you look sad, but you&amp;rsquo;re not sick? This is nothing but sadness in you.&amp;rdquo; I was apprehensive. 3&amp;quot;Long live the King! Why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t I look sad when the city where my ancestors are buried lies in ruins and its gates are burned?&amp;quot; I prayed to the God of heaven 5and told the king, &amp;ldquo;If it pleases you, if I am pleasing to you, send me to Judah, to the city of my ancestors&amp;rsquo; tombs so I can rebuild it.&amp;rdquo; 6(The queen was sitting beside him.) He asked me, &amp;ldquo;How long will it take? When will you be back?&amp;rdquo; 7&amp;quot;If it pleases you, give me letters to the governors of Beyond the River to let me travel through to Judah. 8Also, give me a letter to Asaph the keeper of the king&amp;rsquo;s forest, to give me timber to make beams for the gates of the fortress that&amp;rsquo;s by the Temple, for the city wall and a house for myself.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Eliashib the high priest with his relatives the priests built the Sheep Gate. They consecrated it and hung its doors and consecrated the wall to the Tower of a Hundred and the Tower of Hananel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Next to him men from Jericho built, and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; The sons of Hassenaah built the Fish Gate. They laid its beams and hung its doors with its bolts and bars.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Sanballat heard we were rebuilding the wall, he was furious and ridiculed the Jews. 2In front of his relatives and wealthy men in Samaria, he asked, &amp;ldquo;What are these feeble Jews doing? Are they going to restore it for themselves? Can they offer sacrifices? Can they finish it in a day? Can they remake something out of the charred stones from dusty rubble?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Tobiah the Ammonite was close by and said, &amp;ldquo;Even a fox could jump on that stone wall they&amp;rsquo;re building and break it down!&amp;rdquo; 4&amp;quot;Listen how they despise us, God! Turn their mockery back on their heads and give them up for plunder in a land that takes them captive. 5Don&amp;rsquo;t forgive them; don&amp;rsquo;t blot out their sin. They&amp;rsquo;ve tried to demoralize the builders.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; There was a loud outcry by husbands and wives against their fellow Jews. 2Some were saying, &amp;ldquo;There are a lot of us along with our sons and daughters. We need more food to survive.&amp;rdquo; 3Others said, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re mortgaging our fields, vineyards, and houses for grain because of the famine.&amp;rdquo; 4Yet others were saying, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve borrowed money for the king&amp;rsquo;s tax on our fields and vineyards. 5Our flesh is like our brothers&amp;rsquo; flesh, our children like their children; yet we&amp;rsquo;re forcing our children to be slaves. Some of our daughters have already been forced into slavery. We&amp;rsquo;re helpless because we&amp;rsquo;ve mortgaged our fields and vineyards to other people.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Sanballat, Tobiah, Geshem the Arab, and the rest of our enemies found out I&amp;rsquo;d rebuilt the wall so there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any break in it—although I hadn&amp;rsquo;t set up the doors in the gates yet. 2Sanballat and Geshem sent me a message, &amp;ldquo;Meet us at Chephirim in the Plain of Ono.&amp;rdquo; They were planning to harm me. 3I sent messengers, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m in an extensive project. Why should the work stop while I&amp;rsquo;m with you?&amp;rdquo; 4They sent me four messages like that; I answered them the same way. 5Then Sanballat sent his servant a fifth time with an open letter in hand. 6He&amp;rsquo;d written, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s reported among the countries—and Gashmu tells me it&amp;rsquo;s true—that you and the Jews plan to revolt; that&amp;rsquo;s why you&amp;rsquo;re rebuilding the wall. Those reports say you&amp;rsquo;ll be their king. 7You&amp;rsquo;ve also appointed prophets to make a declaration in Jerusalem about you, &amp;lsquo;There&amp;rsquo;s a king in Judah!&amp;rsquo; Those reports will be passed on to the king. Come; let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The wall had been rebuilt, and I&amp;rsquo;d set up the doors and appointed gatekeepers, singers, and Levites. 2I put Hanani my brother—along with Hananiah commander of the fortress—in charge of Jerusalem because he was a reliable man that respected God more than most. 3I told them, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t open the gates till the sun is hot. While they&amp;rsquo;re standing guard, shut and bolt the doors. Appoint guards from the people that live inside Jerusalem, each at his post by his own house.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The people congregated in the square by the Water Gate, and asked Ezra to bring The Book of the Law of Moses the LORD had given Israel. 2On the first day, seventh month, he brought it to the assembly of men and women—anybody that could understand. 3He read from early morning till noon, and the people listened. 4He stood on a wooden podium built for that purpose. Beside him stood Pedaiah, Mishael, Malchijah, Hashum, Hash-baddanah, Zechariah, and Meshullam on his left; and Mattithiah, Shema, Anaiah, Uriah, Hilkiah, and Maaseiah on his right. 5He unrolled the scroll where everybody could see it, because he was standing above them. When he unrolled it, they stood up. 6He blessed the LORD the great God, and the people answered, &amp;ldquo;Amen! Amen!&amp;rdquo; and raised their hands. Then they bowed low in worship with their faces toward the ground. 7Jeshua, Bani, Sherebiah, Jamin, Akkub, Shabbethai, Hodiah, Maaseiah, Kelita, Azariah, Jozabad, Hanan, Pelaiah, and the Levites explained the Law while they stood in their places. 8As they read the Law, they translated it so the people could understand it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; On the twenty-fourth of that month, the Israelites gathered with fasting in burlap and doused with dust. 2They separated from foreigners and confessed their and their ancestors&amp;rsquo; sins. 3While they stood in their place, they read from the Law for a fourth of the day. For another fourth they confessed and worshiped the LORD their God. 4On the Levites&amp;rsquo; platform stood Jeshua, Bani, Kadmiel, Shebaniah, Bunni, Sherebiah, Bani, and Chenani, and appealed to the LORD their God.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The sealed document showed the names of these priests: Nehemiah the governor, son of Hacaliah; Zedekiah, Seraiah, Azariah, Jeremiah, Pashhur, Amariah, Malchijah, Hattush, Shebaniah, Malluch, Harim, Meremoth, Obadiah, Daniel, Ginnethon, Baruch, Meshullam, Abijah, Mijamin, Maaziah, Bilgai, and Shemaiah; 9the Levites: Jeshua son of Azaniah, Binnui of the family of Henadad, Kadmiel; 10and their brothers Shebanaih, Hodiah, Kelita, Pelaiah, Hanan, 11Mica, Rehob, Hashabiah, 12Zaccur, Sherebiah, Shebaniah, 13Hodiah, Bani, Beninu; 14the leaders of the people: Parosh, Pahath-moab, Elam, Zattu, Bani, 15Bunni Azgad, Bebai, 16Adonijah, Bigvai, Adin, 17Ater, Hezekiah, Azzur, 18Hodiah, Hashum, Bezai, 19Hariph, Anathoth, Nebai, 20Magpiash, Meshullam, Hezir, 21Meshezabel, Zadok, Jaddua, 22Pelatiah, Hanan, Anaiah, 23Hoshea, Hananiah, Hasshub, 24Hallohesh, Pilha, Shobek, 25Rehum, Hashabnah, Maaseiah, 26Ahiah, Hanan, Anan, 27Malluch, Harim, Baanah.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The people&amp;rsquo;s leaders already lived in Jerusalem, but the rest of the people cast lots to bring one in ten to live in Jerusalem, the holy city, while nine-tenths stayed in the other towns. 2The people commended those who volunteered to move to Jerusalem.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; These are the leaders of the province who lived in Jerusalem, but in the towns of Judah each lived on his own property: the Israelites, priests, Levites, Temple servants, and descendants of Solomon&amp;rsquo;s servants. 4Some of the people of Judah and Benjamin lived in Jerusalem. From Judah was Athaiah son of Uzziah (son of Zechariah son of Amariah son of Shephatiah) son of Mahalalel. From Perez was 5Maaseiah (son of Baruch son of Col-hozeh son of Hazaiah son of Adaiah son of Joiarib son of Zechariah) son of the Shilonite. 6The descendants of Perez that lived in Jerusalem were 468 capable men.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; These are the priests and Levites that came up with Zerubbabel the king, son of Shealtiel, and Jeshua the high priest: Seraiah, Jeremiah, Ezra, 2Amariah, Malluch, Hattush, 3Shecaniah, Rehum, Meremoth, 4Iddo, Ginnethoi, Abijah, 5Mijamin, Maadiah, Bilgah, 6Shemaiah and Joiarib, Jedaiah, 7Sallu, Amok, Hilkiah, and Jedaiah. These were the leaders of the priests and their relatives at the time of Jeshua.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v8&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; The Levites were Jeshua, Binnui, Kadmiel, Sherebiah, Judah, and Mattaniah, who with his brothers was in charge of the songs of thanksgiving. 9Bakbukiah and Unni, their brothers, stood across from them in their service divisions. 10Jeshua was father of Joiakim (father of Eliashib father of Joiada 11father of Jonathan father of Jaddua).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nehemiah 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/nehemiah/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nehemiah-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Nehemiah Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; That day they read out loud from the Book of Moses so the people could hear it. There they found that no Ammonite or Moabite should ever enter God&amp;rsquo;s assembly. 2That was because they didn&amp;rsquo;t provide the Israelites with bread and water, but hired Balaam to curse them. But our God turned the curse into a blessing. 3When they heard the Law, they excluded all foreigners from Israel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
