<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EVIL, Problem of (Theodicy) on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/evil-problem-of-theodicy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EVIL, Problem of (Theodicy) on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/evil-problem-of-theodicy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON EXTREME EVIL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-extreme-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-extreme-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON EXTREME EVIL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the problem of evil is not “easy” to answer, we can understand some things about how a degree of evil could occur in a holy God’s universe. But why an all-powerful God allows extreme evil to happen is more difficult. Scripture itself does not explain why he lets evil operate to the degree it does. Nevertheless, some observations make the issue more understandable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, whatever the reason(s), God does not place himself above the horrors of human suffering. It is beyond us how he can stand by and let atrocities take place before his very eyes when he could do something to stop them. We must remember, however, that the Father has not only stood by and let evil people mistreat other evil people and even abuse good people; he stood by and let sinful men crucify his own Son. No wonder Jesus cried out, “Why have you forsaken me?” (Matthew 27:46; etc., cp. Psalm 22:1). The human perspective of the dying divine Son is graphically evident in that “cry of dereliction.” That situation is even more difficult when he lets good men do evil, thinking they were doing him service (John 16:2). The crucifixion of Messiah involves both the Father standing by and the Son standing in the pain (John 18:6, etc.)—even though Jesus could have called twelve legions of angels to deliver him (Matthew 26:53). Whatever the reason, it is significant enough that deity went through it himself, not asking us to endure anything he was unwilling to suffer. Deity does not play favorites with his own, not even with his own Son, not even with himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVIL IN THE WORLD: IS GOD HOLY?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/evil-in-the-world-is-god-holy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/evil-in-the-world-is-god-holy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVIL IN THE WORLD: IS GOD HOLY?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction:  The Antilogism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.  &#x9;The origin of evil in the free will (intellect) of secondary agencies maintains the holiness of God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.  Persons involved&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Satan: John 8:44&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adam and Eve&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.  Origin of sin among people: Romans 15:12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.  Universality among people&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.  Why allow evil in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evil is a necessary potentiality of free will. God is not limited by the option, but&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOOD AND EVIL IN ETERNAL PERSPECTIVE:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/good-and-evil-in-eternal-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/good-and-evil-in-eternal-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GOOD AND EVIL IN ETERNAL PERSPECTIVE:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HELP FROM REVELATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good triumphs over evil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good and evil are not equal opposites in power or legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good and evil are not equally eternal. Evil has a beginning and an end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evil is allowed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evil does not simply take over and “bully” people around undeterred.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evil is temporary (limited in length).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In comparison to good, individual evils are short-lived along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Death removes it from the scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUFFERING IN THE WORLD: DOES GOD LOVE US?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/suffering-in-the-world-does-god-love-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/suffering-in-the-world-does-god-love-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUFFERING IN THE WORLD: DOES GOD LOVE US?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;Need to Get Rid of Parochial Self-Centeredness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;If God were holy, there would be no evil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. &#x9;If God were loving, he would not confine people to hell forever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obviously, if there is a final overthrow of evil, it must be forever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;People fuss at God on the one hand because there is evil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. &#x9;People desire on the other hand to practice freedom of the will.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
