<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Malachi on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Malachi on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Malachi 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;malachi-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Malachi Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; An Oracle from the LORD to Israel Through Malachi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve loved you.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Esau Jacob&amp;rsquo;s brother? Yet I&amp;rsquo;ve loved Jacob 3and set Esau aside, made his hill country desolate, and left his inheritance for desert jackals.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Esau&amp;rsquo;s descendants claim, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve been beaten down, but we&amp;rsquo;ll come back and rebuild the ruins.&amp;rdquo; But the LORD of Hosts says, &amp;ldquo;They may rebuild, but I&amp;rsquo;ll tear it down again. People will call them The Evil Country, The Nation the LORD Is Angry with Forever.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malachi 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;malachi-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Malachi Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Priests, I&amp;rsquo;m talking to you. 2If you don&amp;rsquo;t get serious about honoring me, I&amp;rsquo;ll put a curse on you and even curse the blessings you receive. Actually, I already have, because you&amp;rsquo;re not taking me seriously. 3I&amp;rsquo;ll bring misfortune on your descendants and spatter your faces with the offal from your feasts. I&amp;rsquo;ll throw you out with it. 4You&amp;rsquo;ll find out that I&amp;rsquo;m the One that sent this commandment so my covenant with Levi can continue. 5My covenant with him gives life and peace. I gave it to him so he&amp;rsquo;d show me reverence, and he did 6and gave true instruction. He followed me in peace and goodness, and turned people back from sin. 7A priest should preserve knowledge, and people should look to him for instruction because he&amp;rsquo;s a messenger from the LORD of Hosts. 8But you&amp;rsquo;ve gone off-road and made people stumble with your instruction; you&amp;rsquo;ve corrupted my covenant with Levi. 9So people despise you because you show favoritism in how you execute the Law.&amp;quot; 10&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t we all have the same Father? Hasn&amp;rsquo;t the same God created us? Why are we unfaithful to one another and violate our ancestors&amp;rsquo; covenant? 11Judah has been unfaithful and created an abomination in Israel and Jerusalem. He&amp;rsquo;s profaned the sanctuary the LORD loves and married the daughter of a foreign god. 12May the LORD cut off from Jacob anyone who does that and then tries to present him an offering. 13&amp;quot;Another thing you do is cover the LORD&amp;rsquo;s altar with tears, weeping, and groaning because he doesn&amp;rsquo;t accept your offerings anymore.&amp;quot; &amp;ldquo;Because he&amp;rsquo;s seen how unfaithful you&amp;rsquo;ve been to the wife you&amp;rsquo;ve had from your youth though she&amp;rsquo;s your partner, your wife by covenant. 15Nobody does that who has even an ounce of the spirit and wants godly offspring; so pay attention to your spirit so you won&amp;rsquo;t be unfaithful to her. 16I despise divorce and the one that tries to cover up his adultery with cruelty by divorcing his wife.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;By saying, &amp;lsquo;People that sin are as good in his sight as anybody else; he delights in them&amp;rsquo;; or &amp;lsquo;Where&amp;rsquo;s there a just God?&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malachi 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;malachi-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Malachi Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m going to send my messenger to fix the road ahead of me. Then the LORD you&amp;rsquo;re looking for will suddenly come to his Temple, the messenger of the covenant you delight in. 2But who can endure it when he comes? Who can withstand his appearing? He&amp;rsquo;ll be like a refiner&amp;rsquo;s fire and a fuller&amp;rsquo;s soap. 3He&amp;rsquo;ll sit like a refiner that smelts and purifies dross from silver. He&amp;rsquo;ll purify the Levites and refine them like gold and silver so they can present acceptable offerings. 4Then the offerings in Judah and Jerusalem will be pleasing to me like before. 5&amp;quot;Then I&amp;rsquo;ll put you on trial and eagerly testify against sorcerers, adulterers, people that swear falsely, cheat wage earners, abuse widows and orphans; are prejudiced against foreigners, and don&amp;rsquo;t respect me. 6&amp;quot;I don&amp;rsquo;t change. That&amp;rsquo;s why I haven&amp;rsquo;t consumed you yet, Jacob. 7From the time of your ancestors, you&amp;rsquo;ve repeatedly turned away from my statutes. Come back to me, and I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to you.&amp;quot; &amp;ldquo;Tithes and offerings. 9You&amp;rsquo;re accursed because the whole nation is stealing from me! 10Bring the whole tithe to the storehouse so there&amp;rsquo;ll be enough food for my Temple staff. Test me in that and see if I don&amp;rsquo;t open the sky and pour out blessing on you till there&amp;rsquo;s no more need. 11I&amp;rsquo;ll drive away diseases and locust plagues for you so they won&amp;rsquo;t ruin your produce and your grapevines won&amp;rsquo;t drop their grapes before they&amp;rsquo;re ripe. 12Other nations will say you&amp;rsquo;re fortunate to have such a delightful land.&amp;rdquo; 14&amp;quot;Like, &amp;lsquo;There&amp;rsquo;s no point in serving God. What good&amp;rsquo;s it do to keep his charges or mourn in front of him when we fail to do so? 15We may as well consider proud people fortunate: not only do they prosper; but when they make trial of God, they get away with it!&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malachi 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/malachi/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;malachi-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Malachi Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The time&amp;rsquo;s coming when the arrogant people you admire will be like stubble that burns up in a furnace—root, stem, and all. 2But for you that respect me, goodness will rise up like the sun with healing in its wings. You&amp;rsquo;ll break out, jump around for joy, and run all over like calves let out of a stall. 3At the time I&amp;rsquo;m planning for, you&amp;rsquo;ll stomp on sinners like ashes under your feet. 4&amp;quot;Remember the Law of Moses my servant, the statutes and ordinances I commanded him at Horeb/Sinai for you. 5I&amp;rsquo;ll send you Elijah the prophet before that awesome day comes. 6He&amp;rsquo;ll turn fathers&amp;rsquo; hearts back to their children and children&amp;rsquo;s hearts back to their fathers, so I won&amp;rsquo;t put a curse on the land.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
