<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Revelation on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Revelation on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The relevation God gave to Jesus CjhristMessiah to show his servants about what must happen soon. He sent it through his angel to his servant John, 2who has passed on everything he saw about God&amp;rsquo;s message and Jesus Christ&amp;rsquo;s revelation. 3Blessed is the one who reads and the ones that hear the prophecyfem and keep what&amp;rsquo;s written in itfem. It&amp;rsquo;s coming soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; John, to the seven churches in Asia. Grace and peace from him who is and was and is to come, from the seven spirits in front of his throne, 5-6and from Jesus Christ, the faithful witness, firstborn from the dead, ruler over the kings of the world. Glory and dominion forevermore to him who loved us, released us from our sins with his blood, and made us into a kingdom of priests to his God and Father. Amen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Write this to the evangelist for the church in Ephesus: &amp;lsquo;This is what he says who holds the seven stars in his right hand and walks among the seven gold lampstands: 2&amp;quot;I know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing—your labor and endurance. I know you can&amp;rsquo;t put up with sinful people. You&amp;rsquo;ve tested those who called themselves apostles and weren&amp;rsquo;t, and found them false. 3You&amp;rsquo;ve endured for me without wearing out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Write this to the evangelist for the church in Sardis: &amp;lsquo;This is what he says who has the seven spirits of God and the seven stars: &amp;ldquo;I know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing, that you&amp;rsquo;re alive in name only. 2Wake up and strengthen what&amp;rsquo;s left that&amp;rsquo;s about to die. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found your deeds perfect in front of my God. 3So remember what you&amp;rsquo;ve received, keep it, and repent. If you don&amp;rsquo;t wake up, I&amp;rsquo;ll come like a thief at night when you don&amp;rsquo;t expect it. 4You have a few in Sardis that haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten their clothes dirty. They&amp;rsquo;ll live with me in white because they&amp;rsquo;re worthy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, I saw a door standing open in heaven. The first voice I heard sounded like a trumpet, &amp;ldquo;Come up here, and I&amp;rsquo;ll show you what needs to happen.&amp;rdquo; 2Right away I was in the spirit and saw a throne in heaven and One sitting on it 3that looked like jasper and cardelian with an emerald rainbow arching over the throne. 4Around the throne, 24 elders were sitting on 24 thrones, dressed in white and wearing gold crowns. 5Lightning flashes and loud peals of thunder came out of the throne. In front of the throne, seven braziers were burning that were the seven spirits of God. 6What looked like a clear crystal sea lay in front of the throne. Close around the throne were four living beings with eyes all over them. 7The first looked like a lion, the second like a calf; the third had a man&amp;rsquo;s face, and the fourth looked like a flying eagle. 8The four living beings, each with six wings and eyes all over, kept saying day and night,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I saw a scroll in the right hand of the One on the throne. It had writing inside and out, and seven seals on it. 2A strong angel shouted, &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s worthy to break the seven seals and unroll the scroll?&amp;rdquo; 3Nobody in heaven, on earth, or under the earth could unroll it—or even look at it. 4I started to cry because nobody could unroll it. 5One of the elders said, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t cry. The Lion from the tribe of Judah, David&amp;rsquo;s descendant, has overcome death. He can break the seven seals and unroll it.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When I saw the Lamb break the first seal, I heard one living being say like thunder, &amp;ldquo;Come.&amp;rdquo; 2A white horse came out; its rider had a bow. He received a crown and went out to conquer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; When the Lamb broke the second seal, the second living being said, &amp;ldquo;Come.&amp;rdquo; 4A fiery red horse came out. Its rider was allowed to take peace away from the earth so people would kill each other. He received a large sword.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, I saw four angels standing at the four corners of the world. They were keeping the four winds from blowing on the land, sea, and trees. 2I watched another angel come down from the east with the seal of the living God. He shouted to the four angels that could harm the land and sea, 3&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t harm the land, sea, or trees till we seal our God&amp;rsquo;s servants on their foreheads!&amp;quot; 4I heard the number that were sealed: 144,000—from every tribe of Israel; 12,000 each 5from Judah, Reuben, Gad, 6Asher, Naphtali, Manasseh, 7Simeon, Levi, Issachar, 8Zebulun, Joseph, and Benjamin.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When the Lamb broke the seventh seal, heaven was silent for about a half hour. 2I saw seven angels standing in front of God, receiving seven trumpets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Another angel came and stood by the altar, holding a gold censer. He received a large amount incense to add to the prayers of the saints on the gold altar in front of the throne. 4The smoke from the incense rose up from the angel&amp;rsquo;s hand with the saints&amp;rsquo; prayers. 5The angel filled the censer with fire from the altar and threw it onto the earth. There came peals of thunder, lightning flashes, and an earthquake.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The fifth angel blew his trumpet. I saw a star that had just fallen* to earth. He received a key to the deep abyss. 2He opened it, and a cloud of smoke came out of it as from a huge furnace, and the sun and air grew dark from it. 3Locusts swarmed out of the cloud onto the earth with ability like scorpions have. 4They were told not to harm the grass, anything green, any tree—just people that didn&amp;rsquo;t have God&amp;rsquo;s seal on their foreheads. 5They weren&amp;rsquo;t to kill them, but to torment them for five months as with scorpion stings. 6The people would want to die but couldn&amp;rsquo;t; they&amp;rsquo;d long for death, but it would elude them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I watched another powerful angel come down from the sky, dressed in a cloud with a rainbow above his head. His face shined like the sun, and his legs were like pillars of fire. 2He was holding a little, open scroll in his right hand. With his right foot on the sea and his left one on land, 3he shouted like a roaring lion. When he shouted, seven thunders pealed. 4When they did, I was about to write, but a voice from the sky said, &amp;ldquo;Seal up what the seven thunders said; don&amp;rsquo;t write it down.&amp;rdquo; 5The angel that was standing on land and sea, lifted his right hand toward the sky 6and swore by the One who lives forevermore—who created earth, sky, sea, and everything in them—that there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be any more delay. 7When it&amp;rsquo;s time for the seventh angel to blow his trumpet, God&amp;rsquo;s unrevealed plan will come to completion like he&amp;rsquo;d told his servants the prophets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I received a measuring rod like a staff. &amp;ldquo;Measure God&amp;rsquo;s sanctuary, the altar, and the worshipers. 2Don&amp;rsquo;t measure the court outside the sanctuary because the Gentiles have received it, and they&amp;rsquo;ll trample the Holy City underfoot for 42 months. 3I&amp;rsquo;ll authorize my two witnesses to prophecy for those 1260 days in burlap and ashes.&amp;rdquo; 4They&amp;rsquo;re two olive trees, two lampstands in front of the Lord of the earth. 5If anybody tries to injure them, fire will come out of their mouths and burn them up. 6During the time they prophesy, they&amp;rsquo;ll have authority to keep it from raining, to turn water into blood, to strike the earth with any plague as often as they like. 7When they&amp;rsquo;ve finished speaking for God, the beast from the abyss will attack them, conquer, and kill them. 8Their corpses will lie in the street of the great city spiritually called Sodom and Egypt, where their Lord also was crucified. 9People from tribes, languages, and nations will look at their corpses for 3½ days and won&amp;rsquo;t let them be buried. 10They&amp;rsquo;ll celebrate and send gifts to each other because those two prophets had tormented them. 11After 3½ days, breath from God will return, and they&amp;rsquo;ll stand up and terrify everyone that sees them. 12I heard a loud voice from heaven tell them, &amp;ldquo;Come up here&amp;rdquo;; and they went up in a cloud while their enemies watched. 13Then a severe earthquake made a tenth of the city fall; 7,000 people died in the earthquake. Fear overwhelmed the rest, and they praised the God of heaven.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; An important sign appeared in the sky, a woman dressed in the sun with the moon under her feet and twelve crowns on her head. 2She was pregnant and cried out in labor, straining to give birth. 3Another sign appeared in the sky, a big red dragon with seven heads, ten horns, and seven diadems on its heads. 4Its tail dragged down a third of the stars and threw them onto earth. It stood in front of the woman, ready to devour her child. 5She had a Son that would rule the nations with an iron rod. He was snatched up to God and his throne, and 6the woman ran into the desert. God had prepared a place there for people to sustain her 1260 days.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The dragon stood on the sand on the seashore. I watched as a beast came up out of the sea. It had ten horns, seven heads, ten diadems, and blasphemous names on its heads. 2It looked like a leopard with bear&amp;rsquo;s feet and a lion&amp;rsquo;s mouth. The dragon gave it power, dominion, and great authority. 3One of its heads looked like it had been mortally wounded and its mortal wound had healed. The whole earth marveled at the beast 4and worshiped the dragon that gave it authority. They also worshiped the beast, &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s like it? Who can wage war with it?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I saw the Lamb standing on Mt. Zion with the 144,000 that had his and his Father&amp;rsquo;s name written on their foreheads. 2I heard a noise from heaven like crashing waves and loud thunder—like harpists playing harps. 3They sang a new song in front of the throne, the four living beings, and the elders. Nobody could learn the song except the 144,000 that had been purchased out of the earth. 4They hadn&amp;rsquo;t defiled themselves with women; they were virgins, who followed the Lamb wherever he went. They&amp;rsquo;d been purchased from among people as firstfruits to God and the Lamb. 5They&amp;rsquo;d never lied; they were blameless.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I saw another great, amazing sign: seven angels that had the seven last plagues. With them God will finish his anger.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; I saw what looked like a glass sea mixed with fire. Those who were victorious over the beast, its image, and the number of its name, stood on the glass sea, holding harps God gave them 3and singing the Song of Moses, God&amp;rsquo;s servant, and the Song of the Lamb:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I heard a loud voice from the sanctuary, telling the seven angels, &amp;ldquo;Pour out the seven bowls of God&amp;rsquo;s anger on the earth.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; The first poured out his bowl on the land. A foul, painful boil festered up on the ones that had the stamp of the beast and worshiped its image.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; The second poured out his bowl on the ocean. It became like dead men&amp;rsquo;s blood. Everything in the ocean died.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-17&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; One of the seven angels with the seven bowls came over to me, &amp;ldquo;Come here; I&amp;rsquo;ll show you the condemnation of the great prostitute that sits on a vast expanse of water. 2Kings committed immoral acts with her, and people got drunk on the wine of her immorality.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; He took me in spirit to a desert place, and I saw a woman on a red beast covered with blasphemous names and having seven heads and ten horns. 4She wore purple and scarlet with precious stones and pearls, and held a gold cup full of detestable, unclean things related to her immorality. 5On her headband was the mysterious name, &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Babylon&amp;rsquo; the Great, Mother of Prostitutes and Detestable Things.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-18&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, I watched a different angel come down from the sky with great authority, and his glory lit up the world. 2He shouted,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; All the nations have gotten drunk on the wine of her immoral fury.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; I heard another voice from the sky,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Her sins have piled up to the sky;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; Pay her back like she paid;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; As much as she glorified herself and lived sensuously,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-19&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, I heard what sounded like a great crowd in heaven,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; A second time they shouted, and her smoke rose up forevermore. 4The 24 elders and the 4 living beings knelt down and worshiped God Almighty, who sits on the throne,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; A voice came from the throne,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; I heard a great crowd like crashing waves and loud thunder,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s rejoice, be happy, and give him glory,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-20&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I watched an angel come down from heaven with the key to the abyss and a big chain in his hand. 2He seized the dragon—the old serpent, the devil, Satan—bound him for 1,000 years, 3and threw him into the abyss. He locked it and sealed it over him so he couldn&amp;rsquo;t deceive the nations till the 1,000 years were over. Afterward he&amp;rsquo;ll need to be released for a little while.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-21&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I saw a new earth and sky. The first earth and sky had passed away, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any ocean anymore. 2I watched the Holy City, the New Jerusalem, come down out of heaven from God, ready like a bride adorned for her husband. 3A loud voice came from the throne, &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rsquo;s tabernacle is with his people; he&amp;rsquo;ll live with them, and they&amp;rsquo;ll belong to him. 4He&amp;rsquo;ll wipe away every tear, and there won&amp;rsquo;t be any pain, weeping, crying, or death anymore. Former things will pass away.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revelation 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/revelation/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;revelation-chapter-22&#34;&gt;Revelation Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The angel showed me a crystal-clear river of life flowing from the throne of God and the Lamb. 2Between the city street and the river stood the tree of life, bearing twelve kinds of fruit and growing leaves that heal the nations. 3There won&amp;rsquo;t be any more curse. The throne of God and the Lamb will be in that city, and his servants will worship him. 4They&amp;rsquo;ll see his face and have his name on their foreheads. 5There won&amp;rsquo;t be any night; they won&amp;rsquo;t need a lamp or the sun because God will give them light, and they&amp;rsquo;ll reign forevermore.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
