<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JAMES on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/james/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JAMES on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/james/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO JAMES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-james/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-james/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO JAMES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. External Citation and Authorship Evidence (see Salmon, pp. 473ff.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Origen is the earliest writer to refer to its words by name and to cite it as scripture (Commentary on John 7:1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Eusebius puts it among the disputed books but accepted it for himself (comm. in Psalm 56—work of an apostle—and Psalm 100 as scripture), referring to it as the first of the catholic epistles. Eusebius notes that jew ancients quoted it, but (Salmon) Eusebius may have overlooked less direct allusions to it: Salmon notes Shepherd of Hermas; Clement of Rome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WISDOM LITERATURE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/wisdom-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/wisdom-literature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WISDOM LITERATURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The New Testament contains several literary genres:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;gospels (Matthew, Mark, Luke, John)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;history (Acts)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;epistles (Romans-Hebrews, 1 Peter-3 John)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;apocalyptic (Revelation)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;wisdom literature (Sermon on the Mount, James, Jude).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Content&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wisdom literature has some affinities with law. They both deal with human behavior and so use the imperative mood extensively. Wisdom, however, is a larger category than law even as advice is larger than commandment. The accompanying diagram shows their relationship. Advice vs. commandment, opinion vs. faith and fact, procedure vs. fundamental morality represent distinctions between the two types of material. Advice and commandment differ as to intent and scope. The advice in wisdom literature is not interested just in what&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(2) JAMES: CONVICTION CONVERTED TO WORKS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/2-james-conviction-converted-to-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/2-james-conviction-converted-to-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(2) JAMES: CONVICTION CONVERTED TO WORKS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the history of Christian thought, two opposite tendencies have plagued the church with respect to human obedience in salvation. From Jewish circles especially, the early decades of the Christian era saw strong influences to conceive of human action as producing relationship to God after the fashion of obedience under the Mosaic Law. The apostle Paul strenuously opposed that effort, especially in his letters to Rome and Galatia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(3) JAMES: SELF-DETERMINATION CONVERTED TO PRAYER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/3-james-self-determination-converted-to-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/3-james-self-determination-converted-to-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(3) JAMES: SELF-DETERMINATION CONVERTED TO PRAYER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps our prayer life most accurately indicates the level of our spiritual development. It is no surprise, then, to find James including encouragements about prayer in his letter to Christians beset by self-centeredness (1:5-8, 16-18; 4:2-3, 13-15; 5:13-18). They needed to convert their complaining, self-determination, and self-interest into prayer, dependence on God, and concern for one another. In this connection we have selected for special consideration the effectiveness of prayer, the importance of divine guidance, and the prayer ministry of elders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JAMES: COMPETITION CONVERTED TO LOVE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/james-competition-converted-to-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/james-competition-converted-to-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JAMES: COMPETITION CONVERTED TO LOVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Religion is not good for some people; it just makes them worse by putting God on their side. Because they know the truth, they look down on other people’s ignorance with greater boldness. The tendency to consider themselves better than their neighbors is reinforced by the status they have as one of God’s people. That phenomenon is curious since sin is always some kind of self-centeredness. If “getting religion” only reinforces such attitudes, what good is it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
