<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 Thessalonians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-thessalonians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 Thessalonians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-thessalonians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2 Thessalonians 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-thessalonians-chapter-1&#34;&gt;2 Thessalonians Chapter &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Paul, Silvanus, and Timothy to the church of the Thessalonians in God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ&lt;sup&gt;Messiah&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Grace and peace from God [our]&lt;sup&gt;ms&lt;/sup&gt; Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&#34;section-ref&#34;&gt;2 Th 1:1-2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;gratitude-for-the-thessalonians&#34;&gt;Gratitude for the Thessalonians&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;We’re always obliged to thank God for you because your faith is growing so much and your love for one another keeps increasing. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;As a result, among the churches, we say how proud we are of you because of your faith despite the persecution and hardships you’re dealing with. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Those&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; hardships&lt;/em&gt; show that in God’s just judgment you’re worthy of his kingdom you’re suffering for. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;He will be just when he pays back trouble to the ones that are giving you trouble, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;and in paying back relief to you that face trouble along with us. That vengeance will come when the Lord Jesus returns from heaven with his powerful angels &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;in flaming fire. He’ll take revenge on people that don’t know God or obey the good news about our Lord Jesus. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;They’ll undergo permanent destruction away from his presence and glorious power. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’ll&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; be &lt;/em&gt;the day when he comes, and you saints can praise him and be amazed at him because you believed our testimony. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;So we always pray for you, too, that our God will count you worthy of &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; calling and powerfully fulfill every good intention and faithful work. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;That way you’ll praise the Lord Jesus, and he’ll praise you in proportion to the grace of our God and Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Thessalonians 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-thessalonians-chapter-2&#34;&gt;2 Thessalonians Chapter &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;Now, about our Lord’s return and our gathering to him. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Don’t let a spirit, a message, a letter claiming to be from us disturb you if it says it’s time for the Lord to return. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;He won’t return till apostasy occurs and “the lawless one” appears. That “one destined for destruction” &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;will oppose &lt;em&gt;God&lt;/em&gt; and exalt himself above everything that’s called deity or is worshiped. He’ll seat himself in God’s Temple and claim to be deity. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;You remember me telling you that, don’t you, while I was there? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;You know what’s holding &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; back for now—till he’s revealed in his time. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;That secret lawlessness is already at work, but the one that’s holding &lt;em&gt;him&lt;/em&gt; back now &lt;em&gt;will continue to do so&lt;/em&gt; till he’s gone. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Then “the lawless one” will appear, the one the Lord will kill with his breath and destroy at his return. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The &lt;em&gt;lawless one’s&lt;/em&gt; coming will be like Satan’s working: with power, signs, false wonders, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;and every sinful deception, all aimed at people that perish, people that haven’t welcomed a love for the truth so they’d be saved. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;So God will send them a deluding influence to cause them to believe a lie. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then&lt;/em&gt; the truth will judge disbelievers who delight in doing wrong.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Thessalonians 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-thessalonians/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-thessalonians-chapter-3&#34;&gt;2 Thessalonians Chapter &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;Finally, pray for us that the Lord’s message can make progress and be honored like &lt;em&gt;it has&lt;/em&gt; with you. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Pray for God to deliver us from harmful, evil people, because not everybody believes. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;But, the Lord is faithful; he’ll strengthen you and keep &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; from the evil one. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;We’re confident in the Lord that you’re doing and will do what we tell you. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;May the Lord direct you to God’s love and the endurance that Christ gives you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
