<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deuteronomy on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deuteronomy on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Moses spoke to Israel in the open country east of the Jordan, in the Arabah across from Suph between Paran and Tophel, Laban, Hazeroth, and Dizahab. 2It takes 11 days to travel from Horeb/Sinai past Mount Seir to Kadesh-barnea. 3The first day, eleventh month, fortieth year, Moses told Israel everything the LORD had told him to give them. 4That was after he&amp;rsquo;d defeated Sihon, king of the Amorites, in Heshbon and Og, king of Bashan, in Ashtaroth and Edrei. 5East of the Jordan in Moab, Moses undertook to explain the Law. 6&amp;quot;The LORD our God told us at Horeb/Sinai, &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve stayed long enough at this mountain. 7Go to the Amorites and their neighbors in the Arabah, the hill country, the western foothills, the Negev, the seacoast, the land of the Canaanites, and Lebanon as far as the Euphrates River. 8I&amp;rsquo;ve put the land in front of you. Go in and take over what I swore to give to your ancestors Abraham, Isaac, Jacob, and their descendants.&amp;rsquo; 9&amp;quot;At that time, I told you, &amp;lsquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t handle the responsibility for you by myself. 10The LORD has multiplied you, and there are as many of you as stars in the sky. 11May he multiply you a thousand times and bless you like he promised, 12but I can&amp;rsquo;t handle the responsibility for you and your conflict by myself. 13Choose wise, insightful, experienced men from your tribes, and I&amp;rsquo;ll appoint them as your leaders.&amp;rsquo; 14You answered, &amp;lsquo;That&amp;rsquo;s good.&amp;rsquo; 15I took those wise, insightful men, and appointed them over thousands, hundreds, fifties, and tens. 16&amp;quot;I instructed your judges, &amp;lsquo;Hear cases between citizens. Judge justly between them or the foreigners among them. 17Don&amp;rsquo;t show favoritism; hear least and greatest the same way. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of people; it&amp;rsquo;s God&amp;rsquo;s judgment. Any case that&amp;rsquo;s too hard, bring to me. 18I&amp;rsquo;ve told you everything to do.&amp;rsquo; 19&amp;quot;Then we left Horeb/Sinai and went through that terrible desert you saw on our way to the hill country of the Amorites. We came to Kadesh-barnea. 20I told you, &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve come to the hill country of the Amorites that the LORD is about to give us. 21Look, he has put the land in front of you. Take it over like he told you. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid or intimidated.&amp;rsquo; 22Then you came and said to me, &amp;lsquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s send scouts ahead to look over the land, and report how to proceed against the towns we&amp;rsquo;ll enter.&amp;rsquo; 23I liked that idea and took a man from each tribe. 24They went to the hill country and the Valley of Eschol and spied it out. 25They brought some fruit down to us and reported, &amp;lsquo;The land the LORD our God is about to give us is a good land.&amp;rsquo; 26&amp;quot;But you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go up. You rebelled against the LORD. 27You complained in your tents, &amp;lsquo;The LORD hates us. He brought us out of Egypt to deliver us to the Amorites. 28Where can we go up? Our relatives made our hearts melt when they said the people are bigger and taller than we are. The towns are large and fortified to the sky. They saw Anakim there.&amp;rsquo; 29I told you, &amp;lsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of them. 30The LORD your God will go ahead of you and fight for you like you saw him do in Egypt. 31In the desert you saw how he carried you all the way here like a man carries his son.&amp;rsquo; 32Despite that, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t trust the One 33that goes ahead of you to find a place to camp and show you how to get there, the One that goes by fire at night and cloud by day. 34&amp;quot;What the LORD heard you say made him angry. He swore, 35&amp;rsquo;None of you sinful people from this generation will see the good land I swore to give your ancestors. 36Only Caleb son of Jephunneh will see it. I&amp;rsquo;ll give him and his descendants the land he set foot on, because he&amp;rsquo;s followed me faithfully.&amp;rsquo; 37The LORD was angry with me, too, as a lesson to you, &amp;lsquo;You won&amp;rsquo;t go in either. 38Your assistant, Joshua son of Nun, will go in. Encourage him; he&amp;rsquo;ll make Israel able to inherit the land. 39What&amp;rsquo;s more, yourpl little ones that you said would become prey, your offspring that don&amp;rsquo;t know good from bad, will go in. I&amp;rsquo;ll give it to them; they&amp;rsquo;ll take it over. 40You turn around and head out for the desert by the Red Sea.&amp;rsquo; 41&amp;quot;Then you said, &amp;lsquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve sinned against the LORD. We&amp;rsquo;ll go up and fight like he commanded.&amp;rsquo; Every man put on his weapons and thought it would be easy to go up to the hill country. 42&amp;quot;The LORD said to tell them, &amp;lsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t go up to fight. I&amp;rsquo;m not with you; they&amp;rsquo;ll defeat you.&amp;rsquo; 43But you ignored him. You acted on your own to go up to the hill country. 44The Amorites came out like bees and chased you and crushed you from Seir to Hormah. 45You came back and cried in the LORD&amp;rsquo;s presence, but he ignored you. 46So you stayed at Kadesh a long time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; We turned around and set out for the desert toward the Red Sea like the LORD instructed me, and we circled Mount Seir for a long time. 2He told me, 3&amp;rsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve circled this mountain long enough; turn north. 4Tell the people, &amp;ldquo;Go through the territory of your relatives, Esau&amp;rsquo;s descendants, who live in Seir. 5Don&amp;rsquo;t stir them up; I won&amp;rsquo;t give you a foot of their land. I&amp;rsquo;ve given Mount Seir to Esau. 6Buy food and water from them so you can eat and drink. 7The LORD has blessed you in everything you&amp;rsquo;ve done. He has known your wanderings through this big desert. He&amp;rsquo;s been with you 40 years. You haven&amp;rsquo;t lacked anything.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo; 8&amp;quot;So we went past Esau&amp;rsquo;s descendants in Seir, away from the Arabah Road, away from Elath and Ezion-geber. We turned and passed through the Wilderness of Moab. 9The LORD told me, &amp;lsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t harass Moab or stir them up to war, because I won&amp;rsquo;t give you any of their land. I&amp;rsquo;ve given Ar to Lot&amp;rsquo;s descendants. [10The Emim lived there before, a people as big, numerous, and tall as the Anakim. 11Like the Anakim they&amp;rsquo;re considered Rephaim, but the Moabites call them Emim. 12The Horites had previously lived in Seir, but Esau&amp;rsquo;s descendants destroyed them and replaced them, like Israel did to the land the LORD gave them.] 13Cross Wadi Zered.&amp;rsquo; 14It took 38 years to get from Kadesh-barnea across Wadi Zered. That whole generation of soldiers died—like the LORD swore. 15Besides, he opposed them, destroying them from inside the camp. 16&amp;quot;When those soldiers had perished, 17the LORD told me, 18&amp;rsquo;Cross over Ar, the border of Moab today. 19When you get across from Ammon, don&amp;rsquo;t harass them; I won&amp;rsquo;t give you any Ammonite land. I&amp;rsquo;ve given it to Lot&amp;rsquo;s descendants. [20It&amp;rsquo;s regarded as the land of Rephaim as well because they lived in it before. The Ammonites call them Zamzummin, 21a people as big, numerous, and tall as the Anakim, but the LORD destroyed them in front of the Ammonites. They drove them out and replaced them, 22like he did for Esau&amp;rsquo;s descendants in Seir. He destroyed the Horites. They drove them out and have settled in their place till now. 23The Philistines came from Crete and destroyed the Avvim that lived in villages as far as Gaza and lived in their place.]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then we turned and went up the highway to Bashan. Og king of Bashan and his people came out to battle at Edrei. 2But the LORD told me, &amp;lsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of him. I&amp;rsquo;ll deliver him, his people, and his land to you. Do what you did to Sihon.&amp;rsquo; 3He delivered Og and his people to us. We didn&amp;rsquo;t leave any survivors. 4&amp;quot;We captured all 60 of Og&amp;rsquo;s towns, the whole region of Argob, his kingdom in Bashan. 5They were fortified towns with high walls, gates, and bars—besides a great many country villages.  6We destroyed them—men, women, and children—in every city, 7and took the animals and the spoil. 8We took the land of two Amorite kings east of the Jordan from Wadi Arnon to Mount Hermon. [9Sidonians call Hermon Sirion; the Amorites call it Senir.] 10We took all the towns on the plateau, all Gilead and Bashan as far as Salecah and Edrei. [11Og was the only Rephaim left. He had an iron bed 6 x 13½ft. It&amp;rsquo;s in Rabbah with the descendants of Ammon.] 12&amp;quot;We took over that land. I gave Reuben and Gad the territory from Aroer by Wadi Arnon and half the hill country of Gilead and its towns. 13The rest of Gilead and all Bashan I gave to the Manasseh half-tribe—the whole region of Argob. [All Bashan is called The Land of Rephaim. 14Jair son of Manasseh took the whole region of Argob as far as the border of the Geshurites and the Maacathites. He called Bashan by his own name. It&amp;rsquo;s still Havvoth-jair.] 15I gave Gilead to Machir. 16I gave Reuben and Gad the territory from Gilead to the middle of the Arnon valley. Their territory continued to Wadi Jabbok, the border of the Ammonites. 17I also gave them the Arabah, with the Jordan for a border from Chinnereth to the Sea of Arabah [the Dead Sea] at the foot of Pisgah to the east. 18&amp;quot;I told you at that time, &amp;lsquo;The LORD your God has given you this land. You trained soldiers, cross over armed, with your relatives, the people of Israel. 19Your wives, little ones, and livestock—I know you have lots of livestock—can stay in the towns I&amp;rsquo;ve given you. 20Stay there till the LORD gives your fellow citizens peace like he&amp;rsquo;s given you, and they take over the land west of the Jordan. Then you can go back to your possession.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Listen, Israel, to the statutes and case laws I&amp;rsquo;m teaching you so you can take over the land. 2Don&amp;rsquo;t add to or take away from what I&amp;rsquo;m telling you. 3You&amp;rsquo;ve seen what the LORD did to you at Baal-peor: he destroyed everyone that followed Baal-peor. 4But every one of you is alive today that held onto the LORD your God. 5I&amp;rsquo;ve taught you statutes and case laws like the LORD commanded me so you&amp;rsquo;d do them in the land you&amp;rsquo;re entering. 6Keep them; that&amp;rsquo;s your wisdom and understanding in front of the nations that will hear those statues and say, &amp;lsquo;This great nation has wisdom and understanding.&amp;rsquo; 7What great nation has a god as near it as the LORD is when we call on him? 8What great nation has statutes and case laws as good as this Law I&amp;rsquo;m setting in front of you today? 9&amp;quot;Be careful not to forget what you&amp;rsquo;ve seen or let those memories ever leave your heart. Tell your sons and grandsons about them. 10Think back to when you stood in front of the LORD at Horeb/Sinai. He told me to gather you so you could hear what he was saying and learn to respect him all your lives and teach your children. 11You stood at the foot of the mountain, and it burned as high as the sky—black clouds and dense darkness. 12You heard him speak to you out of the fire, but you didn&amp;rsquo;t see any shape. 13He declared the covenant to you, the Ten Commandments he wrote on two stone tablets. 14He told me then to teach you statutes and case laws so you&amp;rsquo;d do them in the land. 15&amp;quot;Watch carefully 16not to do something corrupt by making a carved image of anything male or female, 17animal on land, bird in the sky, 18fish in the water, or what crawls on the ground. 19Don&amp;rsquo;t gaze at the sun, moon, and countless stars, and get drawn away into worshiping and serving what the LORD your God has allotted to everyone under the sky. 20He brought you out of the iron furnace (Egypt) to be his own people like you are now. [21] 22I&amp;rsquo;ll die here, but you&amp;rsquo;ll cross over and take possession of the land. 23Watch that you don&amp;rsquo;t forget his covenant and make a carved image of anything. He forbids it. 24He&amp;rsquo;s a consuming fire, an exclusive God. 25&amp;quot;Later on, if your descendants make an idol and anger the LORD, 26you&amp;rsquo;ll soon perish. I call earth and sky to witness against you today. You won&amp;rsquo;t live there very long. 27He&amp;rsquo;ll scatter you among the nations, and there won&amp;rsquo;t be many of you where he drives you. 28You&amp;rsquo;ll serve gods there made out of wood and stone, gods that can&amp;rsquo;t see, hear, eat, or smell. 29But you&amp;rsquo;ll look to the LORD your God from there, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find him if you look with all your heart and soul. 30When you&amp;rsquo;re in distress and those things come on you later, you&amp;rsquo;ll come back to him. 31He&amp;rsquo;s a merciful God. He won&amp;rsquo;t fail you, destroy you, or forget the covenant he swore with your ancestors. 32&amp;quot;Indeed, ask about any earlier time since God created people. Ask about any other place from one end of the sky to the other. Has anything like this ever happened? Has anything like this ever been heard of? 33Has any people heard God speak out of fire like you have, and lived? 34Has any god taken a nation from inside another nation by trials, signs, and wonders; by warfare, a strong hand and outstretched arm; by great terrifying displays like the LORD did for you in Egypt right in front of you? 35Those things happened so you could know the LORD is God. There&amp;rsquo;s no god but him. 36From the sky he let you hear his voice to discipline you. On the earth he let you see his great fire and hear him speak out of it. 37Because he loved your ancestors, he chose their descendants and brought you out of Egypt by his great power. 38He&amp;rsquo;s driving out nations bigger and stronger than you, and giving you their land. 39Take it to heart then that the LORD is God in heaven above and on earth below. There isn&amp;rsquo;t any other. 40Keep his statutes and commandments that I&amp;rsquo;m giving you. Then things will go well for you and your descendants, and you&amp;rsquo;ll live a long time in the land he&amp;rsquo;s giving you permanently.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Moses called Israel together, &amp;ldquo;Listen to these statutes and ordinances so you can learn them and observe them carefully. 2The LORD our God made a covenant with us at Horeb/Sinai. 3He didn&amp;rsquo;t make that covenant with our ancestors, but with us. 4Out of the fire he spoke to you directly at the mountain 5while I stood between him and you. I stood there to tell you what he said, because you were afraid of the fire and didn&amp;rsquo;t go up the mountain. He said, 8&amp;rsquo;Do not makef a carved image, any likeness of what is in the sky, on the ground, or in the water lower than the ground 9to worshipf or servef, because I am an exclusive God. I visit the consequences of parents&amp;rsquo; sins on their descendants for three or four generations that hate me. 10I am kind to thousands who love me and obey me. 11&amp;rsquo;Do not usef my name &amp;rsquo;the LORD&amp;rsquo; your God as a byword. I will punish whoever does that. 12&amp;rsquo;Observe the Sabbath. Set it apart like I&amp;rsquo;ve commanded. 13Workf six days, 14but the seventh day rest to me your God. Do not workf that day—you, your son or daughter, male or female servant, ox, donkey, cattle, foreigner among you. 15Rememberf that you were slaves in Egypt, and I brought you out with a strong hand and outstretched arm. That is why I have commanded you to observe the Sabbath. 16&amp;rsquo;Honor your parents so you can live a long time and things will go well for you in the land I your God am giving you. 21&amp;rsquo;Do not covetf someone else&amp;rsquo;s wife, his house, field, male servant, ox, donkey, or anything else.&amp;rsquo; 22&amp;quot;With a loud voice the LORD said that to your whole assembly at the mountain out of the fire, cloud, and dense darkness. He didn&amp;rsquo;t add anything else. He wrote it on two stone tablets and gave them to me. 23You heard him speak out of the blackness while the mountain was burning. The leaders and elders in your tribes came to me, 24&amp;rsquo;The LORD our God has shown us how great and glorious he is. We&amp;rsquo;ve heard him speak out of the fire. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen him speak to people, but they still live. 25But why should we die? This great fire will burn us up. If we hear him speak anymore, it&amp;rsquo;ll kill us. 26Who ever heard the living God speak out of fire like we have, and lived? 27You approach him and hear what he says. Then tell us, and we&amp;rsquo;ll do it.&amp;rsquo; 28&amp;quot;The LORD told me, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard what they said. They&amp;rsquo;ve done well in saying it. 29Oh that they had a heart to respect me and keep my commandments so it would be well with them and their descendants forever! 30Tell them to go back home. 31But you stand here with me so I can tell you the commandments, statutes, and case laws you&amp;rsquo;re to teach them.&amp;rsquo; 32Do exactly what he says. Don&amp;rsquo;t stray away from it. 33That way you&amp;rsquo;ll live, things will go well for you, and you&amp;rsquo;ll occupy the land a long time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD your God told me to teach you those statutes 2so you and your descendants would respect him and keep them your whole life and live a long time. 3Do them, Israel, so things will go well for you, and you&amp;rsquo;ll multiply in a land flowing with milk and honey. 4&amp;quot;Listen, Israel, the LORD is our God, the LORD only. 5Love him with all your heart, soul, and strength. 6Keep in mind the things I&amp;rsquo;m commanding you. 7Teach them diligently to your children. Talk about them when you&amp;rsquo;re sitting at home, walking down the road, lying down, or getting up. 8Tie them like signs on your hand and make them like frontlets on your forehead. 9Write them on your gates and doorposts. 10&amp;quot;The land the LORD is taking you to has big, splendid cities you didn&amp;rsquo;t build, 11houses full of good things you didn&amp;rsquo;t put there, hewn cisterns you didn&amp;rsquo;t dig, vineyards and olive trees you didn&amp;rsquo;t plant. When you eat and are satisfied, 12make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t forget him. 13Respect him only. Worship him and swear by him. 14Don&amp;rsquo;t follow the gods of people around you. The LORD is an exclusive God. 15If you follow other gods, his anger will flare at you and wipe you off the earth. 16&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t test the LORD like you did at Massah. 17Diligently keep his statutes. 18-19Do what he considers right and good so things will go well, so he&amp;rsquo;ll drive out your enemies and you&amp;rsquo;ll take over the good land. 20When your children ask you what his statutes mean, 21tell them, &amp;lsquo;We were Pharaoh&amp;rsquo;s slaves in Egypt, and he brought us out with a tremendous demonstration of power. 22He showed us great terrifying signs and wonders against Egypt, Pharaoh, and his household. 23He brought us out to give us this land. 24He told us to observe these statutes, to always respect him for our own good, for our survival, as is the case today. 25We&amp;rsquo;ll be good if we observe everything he&amp;rsquo;s commanded.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD will take you to the land and clear out the Hittites, Girgashites, Amorites, Canaanites, Perizzites, Hivites, Jebusites—seven nations bigger and stronger than you. 2He&amp;rsquo;ll deliver them to you, defeat them, and destroy them. Don&amp;rsquo;t make treaties with them or show them mercy 3or intermarry with them. 4They&amp;rsquo;ll turn your children away from following him to serving other gods. His anger will flare and soon destroy you. 5Tear down their altars, smash their sacred pillars, cut down their Asherah poles, burn their carved images. 6&amp;quot;You&amp;rsquo;ve been set aside to the LORD your God. Out of all the earth&amp;rsquo;s nations, he chose you as his own. 7He didn&amp;rsquo;t set his love on you because you were bigger than other nations; you were few compared to them. 8Because he loved you and wanted to keep his oath to your ancestors, he brought you out with power and redeemed you from slavery under Pharaoh. 9Know then that the LORD is faithful and keeps covenant and kindness to a thousand generations that love him and obey him. 10But he repays directly people that hate him. He won&amp;rsquo;t delay repaying them with destruction. 11Keep the commandments, statutes, and case laws I&amp;rsquo;m commanding you. 12&amp;quot;If you keep these case laws, he&amp;rsquo;ll keep you with his covenant and kindness. 13He&amp;rsquo;ll love you, bless you, and multiply you. He&amp;rsquo;ll bless your offspring and what your ground produces—grain, new wine, olive oil. He&amp;rsquo;ll increase your herd and the young in your flock. 14You&amp;rsquo;ll be more blessed than any other nation. No male or female will be sterile among you or your livestock. 15He&amp;rsquo;ll keep you from getting sick and not put on you any of the diseases you knew in Egypt. He&amp;rsquo;ll lay them on people that hate you. 16You&amp;rsquo;ll consume the nations he delivers to you. Don&amp;rsquo;t show them any mercy or serve their gods. That would be a snare to you. 17&amp;quot;If you say to yourselves, &amp;lsquo;These nations are bigger than we are. How can we overtake them?&amp;rsquo; 18You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be afraid of them. Remember what the LORD did to Pharaoh and to Egypt. 19Remember the great trials you saw, the signs and wonders, the strong hand and outstretched arm he delivered you with. That&amp;rsquo;s what he&amp;rsquo;ll do to the nations you&amp;rsquo;re afraid of. 20He&amp;rsquo;ll send hornets after them till they perish who hide from you. 21A great, awesome God is among you. 22He&amp;rsquo;ll clear them away little by little. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to put an end to them right away. Wild animals would take over. 23He&amp;rsquo;ll deliver them by throwing them into confusion till you destroy them. 24He&amp;rsquo;ll deliver their kings to you to wipe out. Nobody will be able to resist you. 25Burn the carved images of their gods. Don&amp;rsquo;t covet the silver or gold that&amp;rsquo;s on them or take it for yourselves. It would be a snare to you, and it&amp;rsquo;s detestable to the LORD. 26Don&amp;rsquo;t bring anything detestable into your house to serve as a devoted thing. Detest it completely; abhor it utterly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Do every commandment I&amp;rsquo;m giving you today, so you&amp;rsquo;ll live and multiply, and take over the land. 2Remember the way the LORD led you in the desert those 40 years to humble you. He was testing you to see if you were committed to obeying him. 3He let you get hungry, then fed you with manna, which you and your ancestors had never seen. He made you understand that a person doesn&amp;rsquo;t live by bread alone, but by everything the LORD says. 4All that time your clothes didn&amp;rsquo;t wear out; your feet didn&amp;rsquo;t swell. 5He was disciplining you like a father disciplines his children. 6So follow his commandments and respect him. 7He&amp;rsquo;s taking you to a good land with streams and fountains, springs flowing in the hills and valleys. 8It&amp;rsquo;s a land of wheat and barley; grapevines, fig trees, and pomegranates; olive oil and honey; 9a land where there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of food, whose stones contain iron, whose hills have copper you can mine. 10When you eat till you&amp;rsquo;re full, bless the LORD for the good land he&amp;rsquo;s given you. 11&amp;quot;Make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t forget him or neglect his commandments, ordinances, and statutes. 12That way you&amp;rsquo;ll eat till you&amp;rsquo;re full, build nice houses and live in them, 13have herds and flocks that multiply, and increase your silver and gold along with everything else you have. 14Then you won&amp;rsquo;t get proud and forget about him. 15He led you through the big, terrible desert, its poisonous snakes and scorpions, its thirsty ground with no water. He brought water out of flint rock. 16He fed you manna to test you and humble you, to do you good in the end. 17Otherwise, you might say to yourselves that your own power and strength have created this wealth. 18Remember that he&amp;rsquo;s giving you the opportunity to create wealth in confirmation of his covenant. 19If you ever forget him and go after other gods, I&amp;rsquo;m telling you today, you&amp;rsquo;ll certainly perish 20like the nations he&amp;rsquo;ll make perish in front of you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Israel, you&amp;rsquo;re crossing the Jordan now to take over nations bigger and stronger than you, to take over big cities fortified to the sky, 2to take over people big and tall, the Anakim you&amp;rsquo;ve heard people say about, &amp;lsquo;Who can stand up to the descendants of Anak?&amp;rsquo; 3&amp;quot;Understand that it&amp;rsquo;s the LORD your God who&amp;rsquo;s crossing over ahead of you like a consuming fire. He&amp;rsquo;ll conquer and destroy them so you can drive them out quickly. 4&amp;quot;When he drives them out, don&amp;rsquo;t tell yourselves it&amp;rsquo;s because of your goodness that he brought you to this land. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s because of their sinfulness that he drove them out. 5It&amp;rsquo;s not that you&amp;rsquo;re godly, but that they&amp;rsquo;re sinful. He&amp;rsquo;s confirming his oath to Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At that time, the LORD said, &amp;lsquo;Carve out your own two stone tablets like the first ones, come up to me on the mountain, and make a wooden Ark. 2I&amp;rsquo;ll write on the tablets what was on the ones you shattered. Put them in the Ark.&amp;rsquo; 3I made an Ark out of acacia wood and hewed out two stone tablets like the first ones and carried them up the mountain. 4He wrote the Ten Commandments on them that he&amp;rsquo;d given you on the mountain out of the fire when you assembled. He gave them to me. 5I came down and put the tablets in the Ark, and there they are.&amp;quot; [6The Israelites set out from Beeroth Benejaakan to Moserah. Aaron died and was buried there, and his son Eleazar began to serve as priest. 7From there they set out for Gudgodah, then to Jotbathah, a land full of streams. 8At that time, the LORD set apart the tribe of Levi to carry the Ark, to stand in his presence, to serve him, and bless in his name till now. 9That&amp;rsquo;s why Levi doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a territory with his kin. The LORD is his inheritance—like the LORD your God told him.] 10&amp;quot;I stayed on the mountain 40 days and nights like the first time. The LORD listened to me that time, too, and didn&amp;rsquo;t destroy you. 11He said, &amp;lsquo;Go on with your journey ahead of the people so they can take over the land.&amp;rsquo; 12&amp;quot;Now, Israel, what does the LORD require from you but to respect him, follow his ways, love him, serve him with all your heart and soul, 13and keep his commandments and statutes for your own good? 14The sky and highest heaven, the earth and everything in it belong to him. 15Yet he set his affection on your ancestors and chose their descendants above all the other nations, as it is now. 16Circumcise your heart and don&amp;rsquo;t stiffen your neck. 17He is the God of gods and Lord of lords, the great, strong, awesome God that doesn&amp;rsquo;t show favoritism or take bribes. 18He carries out justice for orphans and widows, and loves foreigners by giving them food and clothes. 19So love foreigners because you were foreigners in Egypt. 20Respect the LORD, serve him, hold onto him, swear by him. 21He&amp;rsquo;s your praise and your God, who has done for you the great, awesome things you&amp;rsquo;ve seen. 22Your ancestors went down to Egypt 70 people total. He&amp;rsquo;s made you as countless as the stars.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Love the LORD and always keep his ordinances. 2I&amp;rsquo;m not speaking to your sons today. They haven&amp;rsquo;t seen his discipline, his greatness, his strong hand and outstretched arm; 3his signs and works against Pharaoh, his country, 4his army, its horses and chariots. He made the Red Sea overwhelm them when they chased you. 5Your children didn&amp;rsquo;t see what he did to you in the desert before you got here. 6They didn&amp;rsquo;t see what he did to Dathan and Abiram, Eliab&amp;rsquo;s sons, when the ground swallowed them, their families, tents, and everything living with them. 7But you have seen his great work. 8&amp;quot;Keep every commandment I&amp;rsquo;m giving you so you&amp;rsquo;ll be strong enough to take over the land, 9so you&amp;rsquo;ll live a long time in that land flowing with milk and honey. 10That land is not like Egypt, where you sowed your seed and watered it by hand like a vegetable garden. 11The land you&amp;rsquo;re entering has hills and valleys that soak up rain, 12a land the LORD takes care of and watches over year around. 13&amp;quot;If you&amp;rsquo;ll love him and serve him with all your heart and soul, 14he&amp;rsquo;ll give you the autumn and spring rains so you can harvest your grain, new wine, and olive oil. 15He&amp;rsquo;ll grow grass in your pastures for your livestock, and you&amp;rsquo;ll eat till you&amp;rsquo;re satisfied. 16Don&amp;rsquo;t let your hearts deceive you into serving other gods. 17His anger will flare at you, and he&amp;rsquo;ll stop the sky from raining and the ground from growing crops, and you&amp;rsquo;ll soon perish. 18&amp;quot;Impress these things on your heart and soul, tie them to your hand, wear them on your forehead. 19Teach them to your children. Talk about them when you&amp;rsquo;re sitting at home, walking down the road, lying down, or getting up. 20Write them on your gates and doorposts 21so you and your children will flourish in the land for as long as the sky&amp;rsquo;s above the earth. 22If you keep these commandments carefully, 23the LORD will drive out the nations. You&amp;rsquo;ll take over nations bigger and stronger than you. 24Everywhere you step you&amp;rsquo;ll own. Your borders will stretch from the desert to Lebanon, from the Euphrates River to the Mediterranean Sea. 25Nobody will be able to withstand you. Your God will make the whole land afraid of you. 26&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;m setting in front of you a blessing and a curse: 27a blessing if you listen to what I&amp;rsquo;m giving you, 28a curse if you turn aside after other gods. 29When the LORD takes you to the land, put the blessing on Mount Gerizim and the curse on Mount Ebal. 30Aren&amp;rsquo;t they across the Jordan toward the sunset in the land of the Canaanites who live in the Arabah near Gilgal and the Oaks of Moreh? [31-32]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; You&amp;rsquo;re to observe these statutes and judgments as long as you live. 2Destroy the places where these nations worship their gods—on hills and mountains and under every green tree. 3Tear down their altars, smash their sacred pillars, burn their Asherah poles, cut down the carved images of their gods, erase their name from those places.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t conduct yourselves that way with the LORD your God. 5Look to him where he designates. 6Take your burnt offerings there, your sacrifices, your tithes and contributions, your offerings for fulfilling a vow, and your freewill offerings, the firstborn in your herds and flocks. 7Eat there with the LORD and celebrate in your endeavors. 8Don&amp;rsquo;t do like we&amp;rsquo;re doing here today, with all of you doing what seems right to you. 9You haven&amp;rsquo;t yet come to the resting place the LORD&amp;rsquo;s giving you. 10When he gives you security from your enemies, 14do everything I command you where he designates in one of your tribes—[11] 12byou, your children, your male and female servants, and the Levite inside your gates (since he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any inheritance with you). [12a, 13] 15&amp;quot;But, you can butcher and eat meat inside your gates however you like with the LORD&amp;rsquo;s blessing. The ceremonially clean and unclean can eat it, as with the gazelle and the deer. 16Only don&amp;rsquo;t eat the blood; drain it out on the ground. 17Don&amp;rsquo;t eat inside your gates the tenth of your grain, any offering for fulfilling a vow, or your freewill offerings and contributions. 18Eat them with the LORD where he designates and celebrate your endeavors. 19Make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t leave him anytime in life. 20&amp;quot;When the LORD extends your border and you want some meat, go on and eat it. 21If the place he designates is too far away, butcher animals from your herds and flocks where you live. 22Just like you eat a gazelle or deer, whether you&amp;rsquo;re ceremonially clean or unclean. [23-24] 25Don&amp;rsquo;t eat the blood, so things will go well for you and your descendants; you&amp;rsquo;ll be doing what&amp;rsquo;s right in front of God. 26But where he designates take your holy things and offerings to fulfill a vow. 27Offer your burnt offerings on the altar, pour out the blood on the altar, and eat the meat. [28] 29&amp;quot;When the LORD cuts off the nations you overtakesg, 30don&amp;rsquo;t asksg how they serve their gods so you can do that. 31They do for their gods every disgusting thing the LORD hates. They even burn their sons and daughters to their gods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; If a prophet or dreamer arises and gives you a sign or wonder 2that comes true, and uses it to say, &amp;lsquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s serve other gods,&amp;rsquo; 3ignore him. The LORD&amp;rsquo;s testing you to see if you love him with all your heart and soul. 4Follow him, respect him, keep his commandments, listen to him, serve him, hold onto him. 5Execute that prophet or dreamer. He has advocated rebellion against the LORD who brought you out of Egypt and redeemed you from slavery. He&amp;rsquo;s seducing you to leave the LORD. That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re to purge evil from among you. 6&amp;quot;If your brother, your son or daughter, the wife you love, your close friend tempts you privately to serve other gods—7of people near or far, from one end of the earth to the other—8don&amp;rsquo;t yield to them. Don&amp;rsquo;t show mercy or cover it up. 9Execute them. Be the first to strike against them, then the other people will join in. 10Stone them to death, because they have tried to tempt you away from the LORD your God that brought you out of slavery in Egypt. 11Israel will hear about it and show respect, and not do such a sinful thing again. 12-13&amp;quot;If you hear that some worthless individuals have tempted the people in their city to serve other gods, 14investigate the matter thoroughly. If it&amp;rsquo;s true, 15strike them with the sword. Destroy the city, its people, and their livestock. 16Gather its spoil in its open square and burn it as a whole burnt offering to the LORD. Make the city a permanent ruin; don&amp;rsquo;t rebuild it. 17Get rid of any plunder marked for destruction so the LORD will turn his furious anger away, have mercy on you, and make a big nation out of you—like he swore to your ancestors. [18]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; You&amp;rsquo;re the people of the LORD your God. Don&amp;rsquo;t cut yourselves or shave your eyebrows for the dead. 2You&amp;rsquo;re set apart to the LORD. Out of all the nations, he&amp;rsquo;s chosen you to be his nation. 3&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything detestable. 4You can eat these animals: cattle, sheep, goats, 5deer, gazelles, roebucks, wild goats, ibexes, antelopes, mountain sheep. 6You can eat any animal that has divided hoofs and chews their cud. 7Don&amp;rsquo;t eat camels, rabbits, and rock-badgers. They chew the cud, but don&amp;rsquo;t divide the hoof. They&amp;rsquo;re unclean. 8Don&amp;rsquo;t eat pigs. They divide the hoof, but don&amp;rsquo;t chew cud. They&amp;rsquo;re ceremonially unclean. Don&amp;rsquo;t touch their carcasses. 9&amp;quot;You can eat water animals that have fins and scales. 10If they don&amp;rsquo;t have both, they&amp;rsquo;re ceremonially unclean. 11&amp;quot;You can eat any clean bird. 12You can&amp;rsquo;t eat eagles, vultures, buzzards, 13red kites, falcons, kites of any kind, 14ravens of any kind, 15horned owls, screech owls, sea gulls, hawks of any kind, 16the little owls, great horned owls, white owls, 17pelilcans, carrion vultures, cormorants, 18storks, herons of any kind, hoopoes, or bats. 21&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything that dies on its own. You can give or sell it to foreigners in your town to eat. You&amp;rsquo;re a holy people. 22&amp;quot;Make sure to present a tenth of everything you sow in the field each year. 23Eat it in the LORD&amp;rsquo;s presence where he designates—a tenth of your grain, new wine, olive oil, the firstborn in your herd and flock so you&amp;rsquo;ll learn to respect him always. 24If you live too far away to take the tenth itself, 25sell it and take the money where he designates. 26You and your family can spend it on whatever you want—cattle, sheep, wine, alcohol—and eat it in his presence and celebrate. 27Don&amp;rsquo;t neglect the Levites in your town. They don&amp;rsquo;t have a territory to inherit. 28&amp;quot;At the end of the year, deposit a tenth of your produce in your town. 29The Levites (who don&amp;rsquo;t have an inheritance), foreigners, orphans, and widows in your town can come and eat till they&amp;rsquo;re full; the LORD your God will bless you in your work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At the end of every seven years, cancel debts. 2Creditors are to let go of what they&amp;rsquo;ve loaned to their fellow Hebrews. Don&amp;rsquo;t exact it from them; the LORD has canceled the debt. 3You can exact it from a foreigner, but not from fellow citizens. 4There won&amp;rsquo;t be any poor among you because the LORD will bless you like he promised 5if you obey this commandment. 6Lend to other nations, but don&amp;rsquo;t borrow from them. You&amp;rsquo;ll rule other nations; they won&amp;rsquo;t rule you. 7&amp;quot;If there are poor fellow citizens in your town, be sensitive. 8Be willing to lend them what they need. 9Don&amp;rsquo;t harbor the selfish thought, &amp;lsquo;The seventh year is coming, the year of debt cancelation,&amp;rsquo; and not help them. They may call out to the LORD, and it&amp;rsquo;ll be a sin on you. 10Give generously without regret so the LORD will bless what you undertake. 11You&amp;rsquo;ll always have poor people in your land. Be willing to open your hand to your kin, the needy, the poor. 12&amp;quot;If you buy Hebrew men or women, they&amp;rsquo;ll serve you six years and go free the seventh. 13When you set them free, don&amp;rsquo;t send them away with nothing. 14Supply them liberally from your flock, your threshing floor, your wine vat. Give to them in proportion to how the LORD has blessed you. 15Remember, you were a slave in Egypt, and he redeemed you. 16If a servant says he doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to leave, because he loves you and your household and gets along well with you, 17pierce his ear with an awl. He&amp;rsquo;ll be your servant permanently. Do the same thing with a maidservant. 18Don&amp;rsquo;t let it bother you to set servants free. They&amp;rsquo;ve given you six years with twice the service a hired hand gives. That way the LORD will bless you in whatever you do. 19&amp;quot;Consecrate to the LORD the male firstborn in your herd and flock. Don&amp;rsquo;t work the firstborn in your herd or shear the firstborn in your flock. 20You and your family will eat it every year with the LORD where he designates. 21Don&amp;rsquo;t sacrifice it if it has any serious defect like lameness or blindness. 22Eat it at home; ceremonially clean and unclean alike can eat it—like a gazelle or deer. 23Only don&amp;rsquo;t eat its blood. Drain it out on the ground.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the month Abib, celebrate Passover to the LORD your God. That&amp;rsquo;s when he brought you out of Egypt at night. 2Sacrifice the Passover from the flock and the herd where he designates. 3For a week, only eat bread without yeast—the bread of suffering (you came out in a hurry)—so you&amp;rsquo;ll remember all your life when you left Egypt. 4For a week no yeast will be anywhere in any of your houses. None of the meat you sacrifice the first evening is to remain till morning. 5You can&amp;rsquo;t sacrifice the Passover anywhere except where the LORD designates for his name. 6Sacrifice it at sundown, which is when you left Egypt. 7Cook it and eat it where he designates. In the morning go back home. 8For six days, eat bread with no yeast. On the seventh, hold a solemn assembly to the LORD. Don&amp;rsquo;t do any work that day. 9&amp;quot;Count seven weeks from when you start using the sickle on standing grain. 10Then celebrate the Festival of Weeks to the LORD with a freewill offering. Give in proportion to how he blesses you. 11Celebrate in his presence—you, your son and daughter, male and female servant, the Levite in your town, the foreigner, orphan, and widow among you. 12Remember that you were a slave in Egypt. Observe these statutes carefully. 13&amp;quot;Celebrate the Festival of Booths for a week after you&amp;rsquo;ve gathered in the grain from your threshing floor and the wine from your vat. 14Celebrate at the festival—you, your son and daughter, male and female servants, the Levite, foreigner, orphan, and widow in your towns. 15Celebrate a festival to the LORD for a week where he designates. He&amp;rsquo;ll bless everything you do and what you produce. You&amp;rsquo;ll be altogether joyful. 16&amp;quot;Three times a year, males are to appear in the LORD&amp;rsquo;s presence where he designates: at the Festival of Unleavened Bread, the Festival of Weeks, and the Festival of Booths. They&amp;rsquo;re not to appear empty-handed. 17Every man will give as he can, in proportion to the LORD&amp;rsquo;s blessing. 18&amp;quot;Appoint judges and officers in your towns by tribes. Judge the people with justice. 19Don&amp;rsquo;t distort justice. Be impartial. Don&amp;rsquo;t take bribes; they blind the wise and pervert the just. 20Pursue justice and justice only, so you can live and possess the land the LORD&amp;rsquo;s giving you. 21&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t set up a wooden Asherah pole beside an altar you make for the LORD. 22Don&amp;rsquo;t set up sacred pillars. That&amp;rsquo;s something he despises.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-17&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t sacrifice an ox or sheep that has a blemish. The LORD detests that. 2-4&amp;quot;In any of your towns, if you hear about a man or woman that breaks the covenant by serving other gods or worshiping the sun, moon, or stars, verify that detestable thing thoroughly. 5Then take the person to your city gates and stone that man or woman to death. 6You need the testimony of two or three witnesses to execute anyone. Don&amp;rsquo;t execute anybody on the word of one witness. 7The accuser needs to throw the first stone. Then the people will join in. That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re to purge evil from among you. 8&amp;quot;If a case is too hard for you to decide in your courts—between one kind of homicide and another, between one kind of lawsuit and another, between one kind of assault and another—go to where the LORD designates. 9Go to the Levitical priest or judge that&amp;rsquo;s in office and lay the case in front of him. He&amp;rsquo;ll render a verdict. 10Carry out all its terms. 11Follow the law he teaches you in the verdict he gives. 12The person will die that ignores the priest or judge. That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re to purge evil from Israel. 13The other people will hear about it and show respect, and not act presumptuously again. 14&amp;quot;When you&amp;rsquo;re in the land, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to install a king like the nations around you. 15Install a fellow citizen that the LORD chooses. 16He must not multiply horses for himself or send people to Egypt to multiply them. The LORD has said never to go back there. 17He must not multiply wives; they&amp;rsquo;ll turn his heart away. He must not amass silver and gold for himself. 18&amp;quot;When he sits on the throne, he&amp;rsquo;s to write a copy of this Law on a scroll in the presence of the Levitical priests. 19It&amp;rsquo;ll be with him to read all his life&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-18&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Levitical priests won&amp;rsquo;t inherit territory. They&amp;rsquo;ll eat the LORD&amp;rsquo;s offerings by fire and his portion. 2He is their inheritance like he promised. 3&amp;quot;This is what the people owe the priests. When they offer a sacrifice—ox or sheep—they&amp;rsquo;ll give the priest the shoulder, two cheeks, and stomach. 4They&amp;rsquo;ll give him the first part of the harvest of their grain, new wine, and olive oil, as well as the first shearing of their sheep. 5Out of all the tribes, the LORD has permanently chosen Levi and his descendants to stand and serve in his name. 6&amp;quot;If a Levite living in a town in Israel solemnly wants to come to where the LORD designates, 7then he&amp;rsquo;ll serve there in the LORD&amp;rsquo;s name like his fellow Levites. 8He&amp;rsquo;ll eat equal portions as well as what he receives from selling his fathers&amp;rsquo; property. 9&amp;quot;When you go to a land, don&amp;rsquo;t do the disgusting things its people do. 10No one will burn a son or daughter as an offering, use fortunetelling, practice witchcraft, interpret omens, use sorcery, 11cast spells, call up the dead, be a medium or spiritualist. 12The LORD detests whoever does those things. It&amp;rsquo;s because of such detestable things that he&amp;rsquo;s going to drive those people out. 13Be blameless toward him. 14&amp;quot;Those nations listen to witches and fortunetellers, but the LORD your God doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow that. 15He&amp;rsquo;ll raise up a prophet like me from among you; listen to him. 16That corresponds to what you asked the LORD in assembly at Horeb/Sinai, &amp;lsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t let us hear his voice again or see this great fire anymore. We&amp;rsquo;re afraid we&amp;rsquo;ll die.&amp;rsquo; 17The LORD told me, &amp;lsquo;They&amp;rsquo;ve spoken well. 18I&amp;rsquo;ll raise up a prophet from among their fellow citizens like you. I&amp;rsquo;ll give him my message, and he&amp;rsquo;ll tell them everything I&amp;rsquo;ve told him. 19I&amp;rsquo;ll hold responsible whoever ignores what he says in my name. 20But any prophet will die that tries to speak in my name when I haven&amp;rsquo;t authorized it. The same thing applies to anybody that speaks in the name of other gods. 21You may wonder how you can tell what I haven&amp;rsquo;t said. 22When a prophet speaks in my name and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen, I didn&amp;rsquo;t say it. The prophet has spoken without my authority. Don&amp;rsquo;t pay any attention to him.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-19&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When the LORD cuts off the nations whose land he&amp;rsquo;s giving you and you settle in their towns and houses, 2set aside three towns, 3build roads to them, and section the land into three parts so a person that&amp;rsquo;s killed someone can flee to them. 4&amp;quot;This provision is for someone that kills another accidentally to flee to and live. 5It&amp;rsquo;s for cases like when a couple friends go to the woods to cut wood. When one of them swings the axe to cut down a tree and the iron head comes off and kills the friend, the slayer can flee to one of these towns. 6That way the avenger of blood can&amp;rsquo;t pursue in the heat of anger and take the slayer&amp;rsquo;s life. The slayer doesn&amp;rsquo;t deserve death because it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen because of hate. 7So set aside three towns. [8If the LORD enlarges your territory and gives you the land he promised your ancestors, 9and you always love him and follow his ways, then add three more towns.] 10That way you won&amp;rsquo;t become guilty of shedding innocent blood. 11&amp;quot;But it&amp;rsquo;s another thing if one person hates another, lies in wait, commits murder, and flees to one of these towns. 12The elders back home are to get the slayer returned for the avenger of blood to execute. 13Don&amp;rsquo;t show mercy. Purge from Israel the guilt for shedding innocent blood so things will go well for you. 15&amp;quot;A single witness can&amp;rsquo;t accuse somebody of a sin. It takes two or three witnesses to establish a matter. 16If a malicious witness accuses someone, 17both people will stand in the presence of the LORD, that is, in front of the priests and judges in office. 18The judges will investigate thoroughly. If the witness has accused falsely, 19do to him what he&amp;rsquo;d intended to do to the fellow citizen. That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re to purge sin from you. 20The rest of the people will show respect and not do such a sinful thing. 21Don&amp;rsquo;t show mercy: life for life, eye for eye, tooth for tooth, hand for hand, foot for foot.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-20&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When you go to battle and see horses, chariots, and people more numerous than you, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid. The LORD your God, who brought you out of Egypt, is with you. 2When you&amp;rsquo;re getting ready for battle, the priests will come to remind you, 3&amp;rsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be fainthearted, Israel. Don&amp;rsquo;t panic or tremble. 4The LORD is with you to fight for you and save you.&amp;rsquo; 5The officers will also say, &amp;lsquo;Who has built a house and not dedicated it? He can go home so he won&amp;rsquo;t die in battle and somebody else dedicate it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-21&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; If a slain body turns up in open country and nobody knows who killed it, 2your elders and judges will figure how far it is to the towns nearby. 3The elders in the nearest town will take a heifer that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been worked, 4and go down to a valley with running water—a valley that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been plowed or sown—and break her neck. 5Then the priests, the Levites, will come—because the LORD has chosen them to serve him—to bless in his name, to settle assaults. 6The elders in that city will wash their hands over the heifer 7and say, &amp;lsquo;We haven&amp;rsquo;t shed this blood and don&amp;rsquo;t know who did. 8Forgive your people that you&amp;rsquo;ve redeemed, LORD. Don&amp;rsquo;t hold the guilt for innocent blood against us.&amp;rsquo; He&amp;rsquo;ll forgive the murder. 9That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;ll remove the guilt for murder when you do what God considers right. 10&amp;quot;When the LORD delivers your enemies to you in battle, 11and you see among the captives a beautiful woman you want to take as your wife, 12take her home and have her shave her head and trim her nails. 13She&amp;rsquo;ll change from the clothes you captured her in and live with you in your house for a full month, mourning her parents. After that you can sleep with her, and she&amp;rsquo;ll be your wife. 14If she becomes displeasing to you, let her go wherever she wants to. But don&amp;rsquo;t sell her or mistreat her, because you&amp;rsquo;ve humiliated her. 15&amp;quot;If a man has two wives, one loved and the other loved less, and both have had male firstborn, he can&amp;rsquo;t put the firstborn of the loved ahead of the firstborn of the one loved less if the latter is older. 16-17When he wills his possessions, he must give the double portion to the firstborn of the one less loved. The one that first issued from his virility holds the right of the firstborn. 18&amp;quot;If anyone has a stubborn, rebellious son that won&amp;rsquo;t obey his parents or pay attention when they discipline him, 19they&amp;rsquo;re to take hold of him and take him to the elders in court in his hometown. 20They&amp;rsquo;ll tell them, &amp;lsquo;Our son is stubborn, rebellious, and disobedient. He&amp;rsquo;s a glutton and a drunk.&amp;rsquo; 21The men in the city are to stone him to death. That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re to purge evil from among you. All Israel will hear about it and show respect. 22&amp;quot;If someone has been hung on a tree for a crime that deserves death, 23don&amp;rsquo;t leave the corpse on the tree overnight. Bury it the same day so you don&amp;rsquo;t defile the land the LORD is giving you. (God considers cursed a person that&amp;rsquo;s been hanged.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-22&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t watch your fellow citizen&amp;rsquo;s ox or sheep stray off and not take it to its owner. 2If the owner doesn&amp;rsquo;t live close by or you don&amp;rsquo;t know who the owner is, take it home till the owner comes looking for it and then return it. 3Do the same thing with someone&amp;rsquo;s donkey, piece of clothing, or anything a person lost. You can&amp;rsquo;t confiscate it. 4Don&amp;rsquo;t watch your fellow citizen&amp;rsquo;s donkey or ox fall down on the road and not help it get it up. 5&amp;quot;A woman is not to wear a man&amp;rsquo;s clothes or vice versa. Whoever does that is detestable to the LORD. 6&amp;quot;If you find a bird&amp;rsquo;s nest in a tree or on the ground with a mother sitting on eggs or chicks, 7you can take the young, but let the mother go so you&amp;rsquo;ll prosper and have a long life. 8&amp;quot;When you build a house, build a short wall around the flat roof so you won&amp;rsquo;t be responsible for somebody falling off and dying. 9&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t sow in your vineyard a second kind of crop interspersed and thereby make both crops unusable. 10Don&amp;rsquo;t plow with an ox and donkey together. 11Don&amp;rsquo;t wear clothing made from wool and linen mixed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-23&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 23&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Nobody that&amp;rsquo;s been castrated or has his penis cut off, can go into the LORD&amp;rsquo;s assembly. 2No illegitimate person or his descendant can go into the LORD&amp;rsquo;s assembly for ten generations. 3No Ammonite, Moabite, or their descendant can go into the LORD&amp;rsquo;s assembly for ten generations. 4They didn&amp;rsquo;t meet you with food and water when you came out of Egypt. They hired Balaam son of Beor from Mesopotamia to curse you, 5but the LORD wouldn&amp;rsquo;t listen to him. He turned the curse into a blessing because he loves you. 6Never seek peace or prosperity with them. 7&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t detest Edomites; they&amp;rsquo;re kin. Don&amp;rsquo;t detest Egyptians; you lived as foreigners in their land. 8The third generation can enter the LORD&amp;rsquo;s assembly. 9&amp;quot;When you go out as an army, keep yourselves away from anything impure. 10If a man is ceremonially unclean from night emissions, he must leave the camp the rest of the day. 11In the evening, he can take a bath and come back. 12Have a place outside the camp to go to. 13Keep a spade among your tools. When you defecate, dig a hole and cover up your feces. 14Since the LORD lives in your camp to deliver you from your enemies, your camp must be holy. He must not see anything detestable among you, or he&amp;rsquo;ll turn away from you. 15&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t hand over to their master any slaves that escape to you. 16Let them live among you where they choose. Don&amp;rsquo;t mistreat them. 17&amp;quot;No son or daughter will be a cult prostitute. 18Don&amp;rsquo;t take the hire of a female or male prostitute* to the LORD&amp;rsquo;s house for an offering to fulfill a vow. They&amp;rsquo;re detestable to your God. 19&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t charge your fellow citizens interest on money, food, or anything that can be loaned at interest, 20so the LORD can bless what you undertake. You can charge a foreigner interest. 21&amp;quot;When you vow to the LORD, don&amp;rsquo;t delay paying it. That would be a sin, and he&amp;rsquo;ll certainly hold you to it. (22Not taking any vow isn&amp;rsquo;t a sin.) 23You have to do what you voluntarily promise your God. 24&amp;quot;You can go into someone else&amp;rsquo;s vineyard and eat as many grapes as you want, but you can&amp;rsquo;t put any in a container. 25You can go into someone&amp;rsquo;s standing grain and pick off heads, but you can&amp;rsquo;t use a sickle on it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-24&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 24&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When a man gets married and his wife becomes displeasing to him because he finds something wrong with her, he&amp;rsquo;s to give her a certificate of divorce and send her away. 2If she marries another man 3and he divorces her or dies, 4her first husband can&amp;rsquo;t marry her again because she&amp;rsquo;s been defiled. That would be detestable to the LORD. Don&amp;rsquo;t bring sin on the land he&amp;rsquo;s giving you. 5&amp;quot;When a man gets married, he won&amp;rsquo;t be charged with any military duty for a year. He&amp;rsquo;ll be free at home to make his wife happy. 6&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t take a hand mill or upper millstone as a pledge. You&amp;rsquo;d be taking a livelihood as a pledge. 7&amp;quot;If someone kidnaps and enslaves or sells a fellow citizen, execute the kidnapper. That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;re to purge evil from among you. 8&amp;quot;Keep an eye on a spot of leprosy and follow the priests&amp;rsquo; instructions. 9Remember what the LORD did to Miriam on the way from Egypt. 10&amp;quot;When you loan somebody something, don&amp;rsquo;t go into his house to get it. 11Let him bring it out to you. 12If he&amp;rsquo;s poor, don&amp;rsquo;t keep his pledge overnight. 13Give it back at sundown so he can sleep in his cloak and have a good attitude toward you. The LORD will consider you good. 14&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t oppress hired hands that are poor, citizen or foreign. 15Pay them each day before sundown. They&amp;rsquo;re poor and their livelihood depends on it. That way they won&amp;rsquo;t call out to the LORD, and it becomes sin in you. 16&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t execute parents for children or vice versa. Execute each person for that person&amp;rsquo;s sin. 17&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t pervert justice with a foreigner or orphan, or take a widow&amp;rsquo;s cloak as a pledge. 18Remember that you were a slave in Egypt and the LORD freed you. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m telling you this. 19&amp;quot;When you harvest your field and overlook a bundle, don&amp;rsquo;t go back to get it. Leave it for foreigners, orphans, or widows. The LORD your God will bless you in your work. 20When you beat the limbs on your olive tree, don&amp;rsquo;t go back over them. Leave them for foreigners, orphans, and widows. 21When you gather grapes from your vineyard, don&amp;rsquo;t pick back over them. Leave them for foreigners, orphans, and widows. 22Remember that you were a slave in Egypt. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m telling you this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-25&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 25&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When people go to court and the judges decide their case, 2if the offender deserves to be scourged, the judge will make the offender lie down and be scourged in his presence the number of stripes appropriate to the offence. 3He can scourge him 40 times at most. More than that would be despising him. 5&amp;quot;When brothers live together and one dies with no son, the wife of the deceased can&amp;rsquo;t remarry outside the family. Her brother-in-law will take her as his wife and perform the duty of a brother-in-law. 6Her first son will carry on her dead husband&amp;rsquo;s lineage so it won&amp;rsquo;t disappear from Israel. 7If the brother-in-law doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to take his brother&amp;rsquo;s wife, she&amp;rsquo;s to go to the elders at the gate and say, &amp;lsquo;My brother-in-law refuses to carry on my husband&amp;rsquo;s name in Israel. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to perform the duty of a brother-in-law to me.&amp;rsquo; 8The elders will send for him and talk to him about it. If he persists and says, &amp;lsquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to take her,&amp;rsquo; 9she&amp;rsquo;s to take his sandal off, spit in his face, and declare, &amp;lsquo;That&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s done to the man who doesn&amp;rsquo;t build up his brother&amp;rsquo;s house.&amp;rsquo; 10His name in Israel will be &amp;lsquo;The house of the man whose sandal&amp;rsquo;s off [Bet-chaluts-hanna&amp;rsquo;al].&amp;rsquo; 11&amp;quot;If two men are fighting and one of the wives comes to help her husband by grabbing his attacker&amp;rsquo;s testicles, 12cut her hand off. Don&amp;rsquo;t show mercy. 13&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t have different-sized weights in your bags, 14and don&amp;rsquo;t have different-sized measures in your houses. 15Use full-sized, exact weights and measures so you&amp;rsquo;ll live long in the land. 16The LORD detests whoever cheats with weights and measures. 17&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget what Amalek did when you came out of Egypt. 18He attacked the stragglers in the rear when you were faint and tired. He didn&amp;rsquo;t fear God. 19When the LORD your God has given you peace from all your other enemies, remember to totally erase the memory of Amalek.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-26&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 26&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Once you&amp;rsquo;re living in the land, 2put some of its first produce in a basket and go where the LORD chooses to put his name. 3Go to the priest and say, &amp;lsquo;I declare to the LORD my God that I&amp;rsquo;ve entered the land he swore he&amp;rsquo;d give us.&amp;rsquo; 4The priest will set the basket down at the altar. 5You&amp;rsquo;ll answer, &amp;lsquo;My ancestor was an Aramean nomad. He went down to Egypt and lived few in number, but he became a big strong nation there. 6The Egyptians abused us with hard labor, 7and we cried out to our ancestors&amp;rsquo; God. He heard us and saw our misery, toil, and oppression. 8He brought us out of Egypt with a strong hand and outstretched arm, with terror, signs, and wonders. 9He brought us here and gave us this land, flowing with milk and honey. 10I&amp;rsquo;ve brought the first produce of the ground you&amp;rsquo;ve given me.&amp;rsquo; Set it down by the LORD and worship him there. 11You, the Levite, the foreigner among you will celebrate over the good he&amp;rsquo;s given you and your family. 12&amp;quot;When you pay a tenth of your crop the third year, give it to the Levite, foreigner, orphan, and widow in your towns so they can eat till they&amp;rsquo;re satisfied. 13Say in front of the LORD, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve removed the sacred portion from my house, and given it to the Levite, foreigner, orphan, and widow. I haven&amp;rsquo;t disobeyed any of your commandments: 14I&amp;rsquo;ve not eaten some of it while in mourning, removed any of it while ceremonially unclean, or offered any of it to the dead. 15Look down from your holy house in heaven and bless your people Israel and the land you&amp;rsquo;ve given us, a land flowing with milk and honey—like you swore to our ancestors.&amp;rsquo; 16&amp;quot;Today the LORD commands you to do these ordinances with all your heart and soul.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 27</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-27&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 27&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Moses and the elders in Israel charged the people, &amp;ldquo;Keep the commandments I&amp;rsquo;m giving you. 2When you cross the Jordan, set up large stones coated with lime. 3Write this Law on them clearly so you can go to the promised land that&amp;rsquo;s flowing with milk and honey. 4Set up these stones on Mount Ebal. 5Build an altar there out of uncut stones—don&amp;rsquo;t use any iron tools on them. 6Offer a burnt offering to the LORD on it, 7and sacrifice peace offerings. Eat there and celebrate in his presence.&amp;rdquo; [ 8]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 28</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-28&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 28&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; If you diligently obey the LORD your God, he&amp;rsquo;ll set you high above every nation on earth. 2These blessings will come on you:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v21&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;21&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD will send disease on you till none of you are left in the land.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v22&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;22&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD will strike you with consumption, fever, inflammation,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v23&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;23&lt;/sup&gt; The sky above you will be bronze, and the ground under you will be&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v24&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD will turn rain into dust. It&amp;rsquo;ll come down on you till you&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 29</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-29&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 29&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD told Moses to make this covenant with Israel in Moab besides the covenant he made with them at Horeb/Sinai. 2Moses called Israel together and said, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve seen what the LORD did in Egypt to Pharaoh, his officials, and his land. 3You saw the great trials, signs, and wonders. 4Yet he still hasn&amp;rsquo;t given you a heart to know, eyes to see, or ears to hear. 5I&amp;rsquo;ve been leading you for 40 years in the desert. Your clothes and sandals haven&amp;rsquo;t worn out. 6You didn&amp;rsquo;t eat bread or drink wine or alcohol, but he provided for you so you would know he&amp;rsquo;s the LORD your God. 7When you got here, Sihon and Og came out to meet us, but we defeated them. 8We gave their land to Reuben, Gad, and the Manasseh half-tribe. 9So keep this covenant so you can prosper in everything you do. 10&amp;quot;You&amp;rsquo;re standing today in the LORD&amp;rsquo;s presence: your chiefs, tribes, elders, officers, all the men in Israel, 11your children and wives, foreigners in your camps from the ones that chop your wood to the ones that draw your water. 12You&amp;rsquo;re standing here to enter the covenant with the LORD and into the oath he&amp;rsquo;s taking with you today 13to establish you as his people and himself as your God—like he swore to Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob. 14&amp;quot;It&amp;rsquo;s not just with you that he&amp;rsquo;s making this covenant and taking this oath. 15It&amp;rsquo;s with the ones that aren&amp;rsquo;t standing here yet. (16You know how we lived in Egypt, and how we passed through the nations. 17You&amp;rsquo;ve seen their detestable things and their idols made out of wood, stone, silver, and gold.) 18He&amp;rsquo;s making this covenant so there won&amp;rsquo;t be any man or woman, family or tribe, whose heart turns away from him to serve those nations&amp;rsquo; gods. He&amp;rsquo;s doing it so there won&amp;rsquo;t be among you a root that bears bitter, poisonous fruit, 19or anyone that gloats with this curse, &amp;lsquo;I have peace though I&amp;rsquo;m living in stubbornness to destroy the watered land with the dry.&amp;rsquo; 20The LORD will never forgive such people. His anger and jealousy will burn against them. Every curse in this scroll will lie on them, and he&amp;rsquo;ll erase their names from under the sky. 21He&amp;rsquo;ll single them out for adversity. 22&amp;quot;Your future generations and the foreigners from distant lands will see the plagues and diseases the LORD inflicts on this land. They&amp;rsquo;ll say, 23&amp;rsquo;This whole land is sulfur and salt, a burning wasteland, unsown, unproductive, and without vegetation. It&amp;rsquo;s like Sodom and Gomorrah, Admah and Zeboiim, which he overthrew.&amp;rsquo; 24The nations will ask, &amp;lsquo;Why&amp;rsquo;d the LORD do that to it? Why&amp;rsquo;s he so angry?&amp;rsquo; 25People will answer, &amp;lsquo;Because they forsook his covenant with them and their ancestors when he brought them out of Egypt. 26They served other gods he hadn&amp;rsquo;t given them. 27So his anger burned against their land, and he brought on it every curse in this scroll. 28He uprooted them and threw them into other lands, like they are now.&amp;rsquo; 29&amp;quot;The secret things belong to the LORD, but the revealed things belong to us and our descendants permanently so we can observe everything in this Law.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 30</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-30&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 30&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When these blessings and curses have come down on you, and you and your descendants remember them where the LORD banishes you, and you change and obey him with all your heart and soul—3then he&amp;rsquo;ll show you mercy and bring you back from captivity in the nations where he&amp;rsquo;s scattered you. 4Even if you&amp;rsquo;re far away, he&amp;rsquo;ll return you 5to your ancestors&amp;rsquo; land to possess it again. He&amp;rsquo;ll prosper you and multiply you more than your forebears. 6He&amp;rsquo;ll circumcise your and your descendants&amp;rsquo; hearts so you&amp;rsquo;ll love him heart and soul, and have life. 7The LORD will inflict these curses on people that hate you and persecute you. 8You&amp;rsquo;ll obey him again in everything I&amp;rsquo;m telling you now. 9Then he&amp;rsquo;ll prosper you in what you do, in the offspring from your body and your livestock, and in the produce from your ground. He&amp;rsquo;ll delight in you again like he did in your ancestors. [10] 11&amp;quot;This commandment&amp;rsquo;s not too hard for you. It&amp;rsquo;s not out of reach 12in the sky, that would make you say, &amp;lsquo;Who&amp;rsquo;ll go up to get it for us so we can hear it and do it?&amp;rsquo; 13It&amp;rsquo;s not beyond the ocean that would make you say, &amp;lsquo;Who&amp;rsquo;ll go get it for us so we can hear it and do it?&amp;rsquo; 14It&amp;rsquo;s right beside you, in your mouth and heart, so you can do it. 15&amp;quot;Look, today I&amp;rsquo;m setting life and prosperity in front of you, death and adversity. 16It&amp;rsquo;s prosperity if you love the LORD, follow his ways, and keep his commandments so you can live and multiply, and he can bless you in the land. 17It&amp;rsquo;s adversity if your heart turns away and you go serve other gods.  18You&amp;rsquo;ll completely perish. You won&amp;rsquo;t live long in the land you&amp;rsquo;re crossing the Jordan to possess. 19I call earth and sky as witnesses: I&amp;rsquo;ve set life and death in front of you, a blessing and a curse. Choose life so you and your descendants will live. Choose life 20by loving the LORD your God, obeying him, holding tight to him. This is your life and length of days: to live in the land he swore to give Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 31</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-31&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 31&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Moses went and told all Israel, 2&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;m 120 years old today. I can&amp;rsquo;t do like I used to, and the LORD has told me I won&amp;rsquo;t cross the Jordan. 3He&amp;rsquo;llY cross ahead of you and destroy those nations, and you&amp;rsquo;ll take over their land. Joshua will cross ahead of you like the LORD said. 4The LORD will do to them what he did to Sihon, Og, and their lands. 5He&amp;rsquo;ll deliver them up to you, and you&amp;rsquo;ll do to them like I&amp;rsquo;ve commanded you. 6Be strong and courageous; don&amp;rsquo;t tremble with fear at them. The LORD&amp;rsquo;s going with you. He won&amp;rsquo;t fail you or abandon you.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 32</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-32&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 32&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Listen, sky; let me speak;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Let my teaching fall like rain;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; His work is perfect;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; His people have acted corruptly toward him;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; Is that the way you repay the LORD,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; Remember the old days;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v8&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; When the Most High gave the nations their inheritance,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v9&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; For the LORD&amp;rsquo;s people are his portion;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v10&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; He found them a desert land;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v11&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt; Like an eagle that stirs up its nest,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 33</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-33&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 33&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Moses the man of God gave this blessing to Israel before he died:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; He loved his people;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; The LORD became king in Jeshurun,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; He said about Judah,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v8&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; He said about Levi,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v10&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; He&amp;rsquo;ll teach Jacob your ordinances&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v11&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt; LORD, bless his substance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v12&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt; He said about Benjamin,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v13&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; He said about Joseph,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v17&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt; He has the majesty of a young bull&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v18&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt; He said about Zebulun and Issachar,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deuteronomy 34</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/deuteronomy/chapter-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;deuteronomy-chapter-34&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy Chapter 34&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Moses went up from the plains of Moab to Mount Nebo, to the top of Pisgah across from Jericho. The LORD showed him the land, Gilead to Dan; 2Naphtali, Ephraim and Manasseh; the land of Judah to the Mediterranean Sea; 3the Negev and the Valley of Jericho, the City of Palms as far as Zoar. 4He told him, &amp;ldquo;This is the land I swore to Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll give it to your descendants.&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve let you see it, but not enter it.&amp;rdquo; 5So Moses died in Moab. 6The LORD buried him in an unknown place in a valley in Moab across from Beth-peor. 7Although he was 120 when he died, his sight was still clear, and his energy was good. 8Israel mourned him for 30 days in the plains of Moab.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
