<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMMUNION MEDITATIONS on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/communion-meditations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COMMUNION MEDITATIONS on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/communion-meditations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Communion Meditation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/communion-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/communion-meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Communion Meditation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;092715&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Only One Qualified&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The greatest responsibility goes to the most capable person. The hardest work leads to the highest honor. Those superlatives come together at this table. God could not assign Christ’s role to just anyone, because it had such widespread importance; there could be no risk of failure. No one else qualified.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We acknowledge here that we’re benefactors of special greatness. He took the perfect life and produced a perfect life in the human condition. He took life in the human condition and produced a perfect life in the face of the worst opposition. So it’s no off-handed sign of appreciation that we give a nod to on our way to other things. It’s a focal point of worship, a culmination of prepared hearts and minds and wills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMUNION MEDITATIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/communion-meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/communion-meditations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMUNION MEDITATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sources of communion meditation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recorded events that accompanied his death-resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deliberately working backwards from the sermon. There are so many appropriate facets of this event. Finding natural connections with the subject of the day’s sermon triggers some thoughts that might not come to mind otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Festival cycle: The religious year provides associations with communion observance. Later, the meaning of the Lord’s Supper may come back to mind by what people encounter after gathered worship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
