<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acts on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Acts on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Acts 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the earlier volume, most excellent Theophilus, I gave an account of what Jesus did and taught 2up to when by the Holy Spirit he commissioned the apostles he&amp;rsquo;d chosen. 3During 40 days after he suffered, he showed himself alive to them in a variety of unmistakable proofs and discussed God&amp;rsquo;s kingdom. 4While he was eating with them, he told them to wait in Jerusalem for &amp;ldquo;the Father&amp;rsquo;s promise I told you about: 5John immersed in water, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be &amp;lsquo;immersed&amp;rsquo; in the Holy Spirit in a few days.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Pentecost came, they were together. 2All of a sudden a roar from the sky like a violent windstorm filled the house where they were sitting. 3Divided tongues like fire sat on each one of them. 4The Holy Spirit filled them, and they started speaking in other languages as the Spirit enabled them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Devout Jews from many countries were living in Jerusalem. 6When that roar erupted, the crowd came together bewildered. Each one was surprised to hear them speaking in their own language. 7&amp;quot;Aren&amp;rsquo;t these men Galileans? 8How can we be hearing our native languages? 9Parthians, Medes, Elamites; people living in Mesopotamia, Judaea, and Cappadocia, Pontus and Asia, 10Phrygia and Pamphylia, Egypt and the parts of Libya near Cyrene; Roman visitors, 11Jews and proselytes; Cretans and Arabians—we&amp;rsquo;re hearing them speak in our own languages about those outstanding things God has done.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Peter and John were going up into the Temple at 3 o&amp;rsquo;clock prayer. 2Daily, people had been carrying a man crippled from birth and taking him to the Temple gate called Gate Beautiful to ask for alms from people going into the Temple. 3When he saw Peter and John about to go in, he asked for alms. 4Peter looked at him with John and said, &amp;ldquo;Look at us.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; While they were speaking to the people, the priests, the captain of the Temple, and the Sadducees confronted them. 2They resented them teaching the people and claiming in Jesus the resurrection. 3They arrested them and put them in jail till the next day because it was already evening. 4Many who heard the message believed; the number of men rose to about 5,000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; The next day their rulers, elders, and scribes assembled in Jerusalem with 6Annas the high priest and Caiaphas, John, Alexander, and the members the high priest&amp;rsquo;s family. 7They stood Peter and John in the assembly, &amp;ldquo;By what power or name did you do this?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A man named Ananias and his wife Sapphira also sold a piece of land. 2He kept part of the price and took the rest to the apostles. (She was in on it.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Peter said, &amp;ldquo;Ananias, why did Satan prompt you to lie to the Holy Spirit, when you kept part of the price of the field? 4While you had it, wasn&amp;rsquo;t it yours? When you sold it, didn&amp;rsquo;t you control it? Why decide to do this? You didn&amp;rsquo;t just lie to people, but to God.&amp;rdquo; 5When Ananias heard that, he collapsed and died. Great respect came on everybody that heard about it. 6The young men got up, wrapped him up, carried him out, and buried him.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At that time when the number of disciples was multiplying, the Hellenists started grumbling against the Hebrews for overlooking their widows in daily food distribution. 2The Twelve assembled the disciples, &amp;ldquo;We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t step aside from serving God&amp;rsquo;s message to serving tables. 3So pick out seven men with good reputations, who have the Spirit and wisdom, and we&amp;rsquo;ll appoint them to take care of this. 4We&amp;rsquo;ll continue in prayer and serving the message.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The high priest said, &amp;ldquo;Is that true?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; He said, &amp;ldquo;Brothers and fathers, listen. Our glorious God appeared to Abraham our ancestor in Mesopotamia before he settled in Haran. 3He said, &amp;lsquo;Leave your land and relatives, and go to the land I&amp;rsquo;ll show you&amp;rsquo; [Gen 12:1]. 4He left Chaldea and settled in Haran. After his father died, God moved him to where we live now. 5He didn&amp;rsquo;t give him an inheritance in it, not even a place to put his foot, but promised &amp;rsquo;to give it to him and his descendants&amp;rsquo; [Gen 12:7] even though he didn&amp;rsquo;t have a child yet. 6God said his descendants would live in a foreign land that would enslave them and abuse them for 400 years. 7&amp;rsquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll judge that nation, and afterwards I&amp;rsquo;ll bring them out, and they&amp;rsquo;ll serve me here&amp;rsquo; [Gen 15:13-14]. 8He gave them the covenant of circumcision, so Abraham became the father of Isaac and circumcised him the eighth day. Isaac became the father of Jacob, father of the twelve patriarchs. 9&amp;quot;The other patriarchs resented Joseph and sold him into Egypt, but God was with him. 10He delivered him from difficult circumstances and gave him grace and wisdom in front of Pharaoh king of Egypt. Pharaoh made him governor over Egypt as well as his own household.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Saul was approving of his death.               &#x9;Acts 7:54-8:1a Severe persecution broke out against the church in Jerusalem. Disciples scattered all over Judaea and Samaria—except for the apostles. 2Devout men buried Stephen and mourned him greatly. 3Saul continued to destroy the church, entering every house, dragging men and women to jail.&#x9;       Acts 8:1b-3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; The ones that scattered went around presenting the message. 5Philip went down to the city of Samaria and presented the Messiah to them. 6The crowds paid attention to what he said and to the signs he did. 7Unclean spirits came out crying loudly, and he healed paralyzed and lame people. 8A lot of joy came to that city.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Saul was still making murderous threats against the Lord&amp;rsquo;s disciples. He went to the high priest 2and asked for letters to synagogues in Damascus so, if he found any belonging to The Way—men or women, he could bring them bound to Jerusalem. 3As he was getting close to Damascus, all of a sudden, a light from the sky shined around him. 4He fell to the ground and heard a voice,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A centurion in Caesarea named Cornelius, from the Italian cohort, 2was a devout God-fearer along with his household. He gave considerable charitable gifts to the people and prayed to God constantly. 3In a vision about 3 o&amp;rsquo;clock, he saw an angel of God coming in and saying, &amp;ldquo;Cornelius.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; He looked at him and was afraid, &amp;ldquo;Yes, Sir?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Your prayers and charitable gifts have come up as a memorial to God. 5Send some men to Joppa and summon Simon called Peter. 6He&amp;rsquo;s staying with Simon a tanner whose house is by the sea.&amp;rdquo; 7When the angel left, he called two household servants—his personal assistants—and a devout soldier. 8He went through everything with them and sent them to Joppa.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The apostles and believers in Judaea heard that Gentiles had accepted God&amp;rsquo;s message. 2When Peter went up to Jerusalem, members of the Circumcision took issue with him, 3&amp;quot;You went in and ate with uncircumcised men.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Peter explained step by step, 5&amp;quot;I was in Joppa praying when I saw a vision in a trance, something like a big sheet came down from the sky by four corners. It came to me, 6and I stared into it and saw four-footed animals, wild animals, reptiles, and birds. 7I heard a voice, &amp;lsquo;Kill and eat them, Peter.&amp;rsquo; 9&amp;quot;The voice spoke a second time out of the sky, &amp;lsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t you consider unclean what God has cleansed.&amp;rsquo; 10That happened three times, and everything went back up into the sky. 11&amp;quot;Right then, three men from Caesarea stood at the house where we were staying. 12The Spirit told me to go with them without scruples. These six brothers went along and entered the man&amp;rsquo;s house. 13He told us how he&amp;rsquo;d seen an angel standing in his house, saying, &amp;lsquo;Send to Joppa for Simon called Peter. 14He&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what will save you and your household.&amp;rsquo; 15&amp;quot;While I was speaking, the Holy Spirit fell on them like on us in the beginning. 16I remembered what the Lord had said, &amp;lsquo;John immersed in water, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be &amp;ldquo;immersed&amp;rdquo; in the Holy Spirit.&amp;rsquo; 17If God gave them the same gift he gave us when we trusted in the Lord Jesus the Messiah (&amp;lsquo;Christ&amp;rsquo;), who was I to oppose God?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; About that time, King Herod Agrippa I reached out to abuse some in the church. 2He killed James, John&amp;rsquo;s brother, with a sword. 3When he saw the Jews liked that, he arrested Peter too (during the days of Unleavened Bread). 4He put him in jail, with four detachments of four soldiers to guard him. After Passover he meant to bring him out to the people, 5but the church prayed sincerely to God about him.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the church at Antioch, there were prophets and teachers: Barnabas; Simeon called Niger; Lucius the Cyrenian; Manaen, brought up with Herod the tetraarch; and Saul. 2As they served the Lord and fasted, the Holy Spirit said, &amp;ldquo;Set Barnabas and Saul apart to the work I&amp;rsquo;ve called them for.&amp;rdquo; 3They fasted and prayed, laid hands on them, and sent them off.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; So sent by the Holy Spirit, and they went down to Seleucia and sailed to Cyprus. 5At Salamis they delivered God&amp;rsquo;s message in the synagogues of the Jews, with Mark as their assistant. 6When they&amp;rsquo;d gone the length of the island, they came upon a sorcerer, a Jewish false prophet named Barjesus. 7He was with the proconsul Sergius Paullus, an intelligent man, who called for Barnabas and Saul, and wanted to hear God&amp;rsquo;s message. 8Elymas (&amp;ldquo;Sorcerer&amp;rdquo;) opposed them and tried to turn the proconsul away from the faith.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At Iconium they went into the Jews&amp;rsquo; synagogue as usual and spoke so convincingly that a great number of Jews and Greeks believed. 2But the disbelieving Jews stirred up the Gentiles and poisoned their minds against the Christians. 3For a good while, they stayed and kept speaking boldly for the Lord, and he confirmed his message about grace by providing signs and wonders they performed. 4The city was divided, some with the Jews, some with the apostles. 5The Gentiles and Jews instigated an attempt to mistreat them and stone them. 6When the apostles found out, they hurried to Lycaonia to the cities Lystra and Derbe, as well as the surrounding area. 7They were delivering the good news there as well.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Some men came down from Jerusalem and started teaching the believers, &amp;ldquo;Unless you&amp;rsquo;re circumcised according to the custom of Moses, you can&amp;rsquo;t be saved.&amp;rdquo; 2Paul and Barnabas strongly opposed them. The believers appointed Paul, Barnabas, and some others to go up to the apostles and elders in Jerusalem about this controversy. 3The church sent them forward through Phoenicia and Samaria, reporting extensively on Gentile conversions and bringing a great deal of excitement to those Christians.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He arrived at Derbe and Lystra. A disciple was there named Timothy, son of a Greek father and a Jewess who believed. 2The Christians in Lystra and Iconium spoke well of him. 3Paul wanted him to go with him; so he circumcised him because of the Jews in the region; everybody knew his father was a Greek. 4As they went through the cities, they delivered the decrees to keep that the apostles and elders in Jerusalem had determined. 5So the churches were growing in faith and number every day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-17&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; They traveled through Amphipolis and Apollonia to Thessalonica. A Jewish synagogue was there. 2As usual, Paul went in and for three Sabbaths reasoned with them from the scriptures. 3He showed from predictions that the Messiah had to suffer and arise from the dead, and that, &amp;ldquo;This Jesus I&amp;rsquo;m presenting to you is the Messiah.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Some were persuaded and joined Paul and Silas—a good number of God-fearers and prominent women. 5The Jews got jealous and took some riffraff from the marketplace to form a mob. They set the city in an uproar and assaulted Jason&amp;rsquo;s house, intending to bring Paul and Silas out to the public assembly. 6When they didn&amp;rsquo;t find them, they dragged Jason and some other converts to the city authorities, shouting, &amp;ldquo;These insurgents against the empire elsewhere have come here too. 7Jason has welcomed them. They act contrary to Caesar&amp;rsquo;s decrees, saying there&amp;rsquo;s another king—Jesus.&amp;rdquo; 8That stirred up the crowd and the authorities, 9who made Jason and the rest post bond, then released them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-18&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, he left Athens for Corinth. 2He found a Jew named Aquila, a native from Pontus, who was recently displaced from Italy with his wife Priscilla. Claudius had ordered all Jews to leave Rome. Paul went to them. 3Since he had the same trade, he stayed with them and worked because they were leatherworkers. 4He reasoned in the synagogue every Sabbath in an effort to persuade Jews and Greeks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-19&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; While Apollos was in Corinth, Paul took the route through the higher country, and came down to Ephesus and found some disciples. 2He said, &amp;ldquo;Did you receive the Holy Spirit when you believed?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Paul said, &amp;ldquo;John baptized to repentance and told the people to trust in the One that would come after him, that is, in Jesus.&amp;rdquo; 5When they heard that, they were baptized into the Lord Jesus. 6When Paul laid hands on them, the Holy Spirit came on them, and they began to speak in languages and prophesy. 7There were about twelve of those men.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-20&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After the uproar, Paul sent for the disciples. When he&amp;rsquo;d encouraged them and said goodbye, he left for Macedonia. 2After he passed through that area and encouraged them a lot, he went to Greece 3for three months. The Jews laid a plot against him as he was getting ready to sail to Syria; so he decided to go back through Macedonia. 4With him were Sopater son of Pyrrhus from Berea; the Thessalonians Aristarchus and Secundus; Gaius of Derbe; Timothy, and the Asians Tychicus and Trophimus. 5They went on ahead and waited for us in Troas. 6After the days of Unleavened Bread, we sailed from Philippi and met them in Troas in five days and stayed seven.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-21&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When we&amp;rsquo;d left them, we sailed directly to Cos, the next day to Rhodes, and from there to Patara. 2We found a ship crossing over to Phoenicia, boarded it, and set sail. 3We came within sight of Cyprus; we passed it on the left, kept sailing to Syria, and landed at Tyre, where the ship was to unload its cargo. 4We looked up the disciples and stayed there a week. They kept telling Paul by the Spirit not to go to Jerusalem. 5When our time there was over, we started our trip. With their wives and children, they escorted us outside the city. After kneeling on the beach and praying, 6we said goodbye to one another. We got on the ship, and they went back home.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-22&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Brothers and fathers, listen to my defense.&amp;quot; 2When they heard him speaking Hebrew, they got quieter. 3&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;m a Jew; I was born in Tarsus in Cilicia but raised in this city. I was educated under Gamaliel strictly according to the law of our ancestors and was as zealous for God as you are today. 4I persecuted The Way to death, binding and jailing men and women 5as the high priest and presbytery can confirm. I got letters to go to Damascus and bind the ones that had gone there and extradite them to Jerusalem to punish them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-23&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 23&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul looked straight at the Sanhedrin, &amp;ldquo;Brothers, in good conscience I&amp;rsquo;ve conducted myself as a citizen toward God up to this day.&amp;rdquo; 2Ananias the high priest commanded the ones that were standing by him to slap him in the mouth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Paul said, &amp;ldquo;God&amp;rsquo;s going to slap you, you whitewashed wall! You sit judging me by the Law and command them to slap me in violation of the Law.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-24&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 24&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Five days later, the high priest Ananias came down with some elders and an orator, Tertullus. They brought charges to the governor against Paul. 2After Felix called for Paul, Tertullus began accusing him to the governor, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve experienced considerable peace because of you, and your foresight has led to reforms for this nation. 3With gratitude we welcome them, most excellent Felix, in every way and everywhere. 4But not to detain you further, kindly grant us a brief hearing. 5We&amp;rsquo;ve found this man a troublemaker, who stirs up Jews all over the empire, the ringleader of a sect, the Nazarenes. 6He even tried to desecrate the Temple, and we arrested him. [7]ms 8You can question him yourself and find out the things we&amp;rsquo;re accusing him of.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-25&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 25&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Festus arrived in the province and after three days went up to Jerusalem from Caesarea. 2The chief priests and leading men of the Jews filed charges against Paul. 3They were demanding a favor against him—to call him to Jerusalem (laying an ambush along the way). 4Festus answered that he would keep Paul in Caesarea and that he himself was going there soon. 5&amp;quot;Have qualified men come down with me and prosecute him if something&amp;rsquo;s wrong with him.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-26&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 26&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Agrippa said to Paul, &amp;ldquo;You can speak for yourself.&amp;rdquo; 2&amp;quot;In light of the things the Jews accused me of, King Agrippa, I consider myself fortunate to present my own defense today, 3especially since you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with Jewish customs and issues. So please listen patiently.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; The Jews know my way of life from my youth, which I spent in my own nation in Jerusalem. 5If they&amp;rsquo;re willing to admit it, they know I lived before as a Pharisee, the strictest sect of our religion. 6Now I stand in judgment for having hope in God&amp;rsquo;s promise to our ancestors. 7Our twelve tribes sincerely hope to obtain that promise as they serve God every day. In regard to that hope, the Jews are accusing me. 8Why do youpl consider it unbelievable that God raises the dead? 9At one time I thought I needed to do a lot of things against Jesus the Nazarene. 10That&amp;rsquo;s what I did in Jerusalem. Not only did I lock up many saints in jail with authority from the chief priests; but when they were being sentenced to execution, I voted against them. 11I punished them often in every synagogue and tried to make them blaspheme. I was insanely furious and persecuted them even to foreign cities. 12&amp;quot;In that effort, I was traveling to Damascus with authority from the chief priests. 13In the middle of the day, King Agrippa, I saw a light from the sky brighter than the sun, shining around me and the ones that were with me. 14When we&amp;rsquo;d fallen to the ground, I heard a voice speaking in Hebrew, &amp;lsquo;Saul, Saul, why are you persecuting me? It&amp;rsquo;s hard for you to keep kicking against the goads.&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m Jesus that you&amp;rsquo;re persecuting. 16Get up. I&amp;rsquo;ve appeared to you to appoint you as a witness to what you&amp;rsquo;ve seen and what I&amp;rsquo;ll show you. 17I&amp;rsquo;ll protect you from the people and from the Gentiles, where I&amp;rsquo;m sending you. 18Open their eyes so they&amp;rsquo;ll turn from darkness to light, from the power of Satan to God, so they&amp;rsquo;ll receive forgiveness and an inheritance among the ones that become holy by trusting in me.&amp;rdquo; 19&amp;quot;So, King Agrippa, I obeyed the heavenly vision. 20First to the people in Damascus, Jerusalem, and Judaea, then to the Gentiles, I continually declared they should repent toward God and do what&amp;rsquo;s appropriate to repentance. 21That&amp;rsquo;s why some Jews grabbed me in the Temple and tried to murder me. 22I&amp;rsquo;ve obtained help from God till today and speak to small and great simply what the Prophets and Moses said would happen: 23the Messiah needed to suffer, and by resurrection he would present light first to the Jews and then to the Gentiles.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 27</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-27&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 27&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When they decided we would sail to Italy, they turned Paul and some other prisoners over to Julius, a centurion of the Augustan cohort. 2We boarded a ship out of Adramyttium, ready to sail to places along the coast of Asia. We put out to sea along with Aristarchus, a Macedonian from Thessalonica. 3The next day we harbored at Sidon. Julius was nice to Paul and let him go to friends and refresh himself. 4We launched from there and sailed under the shelter of Cyprus because the winds were against us. 5After we navigated the open sea along the coast of Cilicia and Pamphylia, we landed at Myra in Lycia. 6The centurion found an Alexandrian ship there that was sailing for Italy and put us on board. 7For a number of days, we sailed slowly, and barely made it to Cnidus. Since the wind didn&amp;rsquo;t let us sail under the shelter of Crete along Salmone, 8we drifted along it with difficulty and came to a place called Fair Havens near the city of Lasea.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acts 28</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/acts/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acts-chapter-28&#34;&gt;Acts Chapter 28&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When we&amp;rsquo;d made it safely, we learned the island was Malta. 2The locals were especially nice to us and received us all. Because of the rain and cold that had set in, they built a fire. 3When Paul had gathered a bundle of sticks and laid them on the fire, a snake came out of the wood from the heat and fastened on his hand. 4The locals saw it and said to one another, &amp;ldquo;He must be a murderer that survived the sea, but Justice didn&amp;rsquo;t let live.&amp;rdquo; 5He shook it loose into the fire and wasn&amp;rsquo;t harmed. 6They were expecting him to swell up or suddenly fall down dead. But after a good while not seeing anything unusual, they started saying he was a god.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
