<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leviticus on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leviticus on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh called to Moses from the Tent of Meeting and told him, 2&amp;quot;When you take an offering to Yahveh, take it from the herd or flock. 3For a burnt offering from the herd, offer a male without defect. Offer it at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting 4and put your hand on its head to make it acceptable to atone for you. 5Slaughter the young bull, and the sons of Aaron, the priests, will offer up its blood and sprinkle it around on the altar at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting.  6Skin the burnt offering and butcher it. 7The sons of Aaron will put fire on the altar, arrange wood on the fire, 8and arrange the pieces, head, and fat on the wood. 9But you&amp;rsquo;ll wash its entrails and legs, and the priest will offer it up in smoke for a burnt offering, Burnt Offering from the Flock 10&amp;quot;If your burnt offering is a sheep or goat from the flock, it&amp;rsquo;ll be without defect. 11Slaughter it on the north side of the altar in front of Yahveh, and the sons of Aaron will sprinkle its blood around on the altar. 12Then butcher it with its head and fat, and the priests will arrange the pieces on the wood on the altar. 13You&amp;rsquo;ll wash the entrails and legs, and the priest will offer it up in smoke for a burnt offering on the altar, an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. Burnt Offering of Birds 14&amp;quot;If it&amp;rsquo;s a burnt offering of birds, bring an offering of a turtledove or young pigeon. 15The priest will take it to the altar, wring it neck, and offer it up in smoke. He&amp;rsquo;ll drain out its blood on the side of the altar, 16take away its crop and feathers, and cast it on the east side of the altar toward the place for the ashes. 17Then he&amp;rsquo;ll tear it by its wings—but not cut it in two—and offer it up in smoke on the altar. It&amp;rsquo;s a burnt offering, an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. Grain Offerings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; A grain offering to Yahveh will consist of fine flour with olive oil and frankincense added. 2Take it to the sons of Aaron the priests. The priest will take a handful of the mix and offer it up in smoke on the altar as God&amp;rsquo;s portion, an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. 3The rest is for Aaron and his sons, something most holy of the offerings to Yahveh by fire. 4&amp;quot;When you bring a grain offering baked in an oven, it&amp;rsquo;ll be flat cakes of fine flour mixed with olive oil or wafers with no yeast in them, basted with olive oil. 5If you make it on a griddle, make it out of fine flour without yeast and mixed with olive oil. 6Break it up into pieces and pour the oil on it. 7If you make your grain offering in a pan, make it out of fine flour mixed with olive oil. 8When you bring a grain offering like that, present it to the priest at the altar. 9He&amp;rsquo;ll take out God&amp;rsquo;s portion and offer it up in smoke by fire, an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. 10The rest is for Aaron and his sons, something most holy from the offerings to Yahveh by fire. 11&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t put yeast or honey in grain offerings. 12For an offering of the first part of the harvest, bring it to Yahveh, but it&amp;rsquo;s not to rise up as a pleasing aroma on the altar. 13Season grain offerings with salt to put the salt of your God&amp;rsquo;s covenant in them. 14&amp;quot;If you bring a grain offering of the first part of the harvest, bring heads of crushed new growth roasted in fire, 15and put olive oil and incense on them. 16The priest will offer them up in smoke as God&amp;rsquo;s portion. Laws About Peace Offerings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; If you&amp;rsquo;re offering a peace offering, offer from the herd a male or female without defect. 2Put your hand on its head and slaughter it at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. The sons of Aaron will sprinkle its blood around on the altar. 3From the sacrifice the priest will present an offering by fire to Yahveh: the fat around and on the entrails, 4the two kidneys in the loins and their fat, and the lobe of the liver that he&amp;rsquo;ll remove with the kidneys. 5The sons of Aaron will offer up in smoke the burnt offering that&amp;rsquo;s on the wood over the fire, an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. 6&amp;quot;If your peace offering comes from the flock, offer a male or female without defect. 7If it&amp;rsquo;s a lamb, 8put your hand on its head and slaughter it in front of the Tent of Meeting. The sons of Aaron will sprinkle its blood around on the altar. 9From the sacrifice he&amp;rsquo;ll remove the entire fat tail close to the backbone, the fat that&amp;rsquo;s around and on the entrails, 10the two kidneys in the loins with their fat, and the lobe of the liver that he&amp;rsquo;ll remove with the kidneys. 11The priest will offer it up in smoke on the altar as food, an offering by fire to Yahveh. 12&amp;quot;If your offering is a goat, 13put your hand on its head and slaughter it in front of the Tent of Meeting. The sons of Aaron will sprinkle its blood around on the altar. 14From it the priest will present an offering by fire to Yahveh: the fat around and on the entrails, 15the two kidneys in the loins with their fat, and the lobe of the liver that he&amp;rsquo;ll remove with the kidneys. 16The priest will offer them up in smoke on the altar as food, an offering by fire for a pleasing aroma. &amp;ldquo;The fat belongs to Yahveh. 17It&amp;rsquo;s an ongoing permanent statute everywhere: don&amp;rsquo;t eat fat or blood.&amp;ldquo;e&amp;rsquo;ll put his hand on its head and slay it in front of the tent of meetin; the sons of Aaron will sprinkileHhHadfkdkdlslsm sdc ;c Laws About Sin Offerings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to tell Israel, &amp;ldquo;If an anointed priest sins unintentionally 3and brings guilt on the people, he needs to offer to Yahveh a bull without defect as a sin offering. 4He is to take it to the entrance to the Tent of Meeting, put his hand on its head, and slaughter it. 5The anointed priest will take some of its blood to the Tent of Meeting, 6dip his finger in it, and sprinkle it seven times in front of Yahveh in front of the sanctuary curtain. 7He&amp;rsquo;ll put some of it on the horns of the altar of fragrant incense, and pour the rest at the base of the altar that&amp;rsquo;s at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. 8&amp;quot;He&amp;rsquo;ll remove from the bull the fat of the sin offering: the fat around and on the entrails, 9the two kidneys in the loins with their fat, and the lobe of the liver, which he&amp;rsquo;ll remove with the kidneys 10(like it&amp;rsquo;s removed from the herd animal in the sacrifice for peace offerings), and the priest will offer them up in smoke on the altar of burnt offering. 11But everything else—the bull&amp;rsquo;s hide, meat, head, legs, entrails, and refuse—12he&amp;rsquo;ll take to a ceremonially clean place outside the camp where they pour ashes and burn it on wood. 13&amp;quot;If the whole community sins without realizing it, 14when it does become known, the assembly will offer a bull for a sin offering and take it to the Tent of Meeting. 15The elders of the community will put their hands on its head and slaughter it in front of Yahveh. 16The anointed priest will take some of its blood to the Tent of Meeting, 17dip his finger in it, and sprinkle it seven times in front of the curtain. 18He&amp;rsquo;ll put some on the horns of the altar and pour the rest at the base of the altar that&amp;rsquo;s at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. 19He&amp;rsquo;ll offer up its fat in smoke on the altar, 20and do with the bull what he did with the bull for the sin offering. The priest will atone for the assembly, and they&amp;rsquo;ll be forgiven. 21Then he&amp;rsquo;ll take the bull outside the camp and burn it like he did the first bull. It&amp;rsquo;s a sin offering for the assembly. 22&amp;quot;When a leader unintentionally does something Yahveh forbids 23and then realizes it, he&amp;rsquo;s to bring a male goat without a defect, 24put his hand on its head, and slaughter it where they slaughter the burnt offering to Yahveh; it&amp;rsquo;s a sin offering. 25The priest will take some of its blood with his finger and put it on the horns of the altar for a burnt offering. He&amp;rsquo;ll pour the rest at the base of the altar, 26and offer up its fat in smoke on the altar as with the fat of a peace offering. The priest will atone for him, and he&amp;rsquo;ll be forgiven. 27&amp;quot;If any of the common people sin unintentionally 28and then realize it, they&amp;rsquo;ll bring a female goat without defect. 29They&amp;rsquo;ll put a hand on its head and slaughter it at the place for the burnt offering. 30The priest will take some of its blood with his finger and put it on the horns of the altar for a burnt offering. He&amp;rsquo;ll pour the rest at the base of the altar. 31He&amp;rsquo;ll remove its fat as with a peace offering and offer it up in smoke on the altar for an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. The priest will atone for them, and they&amp;rsquo;ll be forgiven. 32&amp;quot;If they bring a lamb for a sin offering, it&amp;rsquo;s to be a female without defect. 33They&amp;rsquo;ll put their hand on its head and slaughter it where they slaughter the burnt offering. 34The priest will take some of its blood with his finger and put it on the horns of the altar of burnt offering, and pour the rest at the base of the altar. 35Then he&amp;rsquo;ll remove its fat as with a peace offering and offer it up in smoke on the altar. The priest will atone for them, and they&amp;rsquo;ll be forgiven. Laws About Guilt Offerings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; If you receive a summons to testify about something you&amp;rsquo;ve seen or otherwise known and you don&amp;rsquo;t do it, you&amp;rsquo;re considered guilty. 2If you touch anything ceremonially unclean, even unintentionally—swarming things or the carcass of an unclean animal—you&amp;rsquo;re considered defiled. 3If you unintentionally touch such human uncleanness and then realize it, you&amp;rsquo;re considered defiled. 4If you swear rashly to do good or bad and come to realize it, you&amp;rsquo;re considered guilty. 5When you become guilty, report what you&amp;rsquo;ve done 6and bring a female lamb or goat as a guilt offering. The priest will atone for you. 7&amp;quot;If you can&amp;rsquo;t afford a lamb, bring two turtledoves or young pigeons. 8The priest will offer one as a sin offering. He&amp;rsquo;ll wring its neck, but not pull it off. 9He&amp;rsquo;ll sprinkle some of its blood on the side of the altar and pour out the rest at the base of the altar—a sin offering. 10He&amp;rsquo;ll prepare the second bird as a burnt offering according to the ordinance. The priest will atone for you, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be forgiven. 11&amp;quot;If you can&amp;rsquo;t afford two turtledoves or young pigeons, take .11 bushel .1 ephah of fine flour for a sin offering. Don&amp;rsquo;t put olive oil or incense on it; it&amp;rsquo;s a sin offering. 12Take a handful of it to the priest as God&amp;rsquo;s portion to offer up in smoke on the altar as a sin offering. 13The priest will atone for you in one of those ways and you&amp;rsquo;ll be forgiven. The rest is for the priest—like a grain offering.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses, 2&amp;quot;If you act unfaithfully against Yahveh and deceive your companion—about a deposit, a security entrusted to you, something you stole or extorted from someone, 3have found that was lost and lied about it and sworn falsely, or sin in any way like that—4then you need to return what you stole, what you got by extortion, what was entrusted to you, what lost thing you found, 5or anything you swore about falsely. Add a fifth and give it to the one it belongs to when you present your guilt offering. 6Then take to the priest your offering to Yahveh, a ram without defect, as you evaluate for a guilt offering. 7The priest will atone for you to Yahveh, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be forgiven.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; This is the law for the guilt offering; it&amp;rsquo;s most holy. 2They&amp;rsquo;re to kill the guilt offering where they kill the burnt offering. The priest will sprinkle its blood around on the altar. 3Then he&amp;rsquo;ll offer its fat: the fat tail, the fat that covers the entrails, 4the two kidneys in the loins with the fat that&amp;rsquo;s on them, and the lobe on the liver. 5The priest will offer them up in smoke on the altar as an offering by fire to Yahveh. 6Any male among the priests can eat it in a holy place. 7The same law applies to the guilt offering and sin offering. The priest that makes atonement with it will have it. 8The priest that presents anybody&amp;rsquo;s burnt offering also gets its skin. 9Every grain offering that&amp;rsquo;s baked in an oven or prepared in a pan or on a griddle is for the priest that presents it. 10Every grain offering, dry or mixed with olive oil, will be for any of Aaron&amp;rsquo;s descendants. 11&amp;quot;This is the law for a peace offering. 12If you offer it as a thanksgiving, then along with it, offer cakes without yeast mixed with olive oil, wafers without yeast anointed with olive oil, and cakes of stirred fine flour mixed with olive oil. 13Present your offering with cakes of bread without yeast. 14Present one of each offering as a contribution to Yahveh. It belongs to the priest that sprinkles the blood from the peace offerings. 15&amp;quot;Eat the meat from a thanksgiving peace offering the day it&amp;rsquo;s offered. Don&amp;rsquo;t leave any of it till morning. 16If it&amp;rsquo;s an offering for fulfilling a vow or a freewill offering, eat it that day or the next. 17Burn any meat that&amp;rsquo;s left over till the third day. 18If you eat meat from it on the third day, you will not be accepted. It&amp;rsquo;s an offense that makes you guilty. 19&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat meat that touches anything ceremonially unclean; burn it. Otherwise, anybody that is clean can eat it. 20But an unclean person that eats the meat from a peace offering will be excluded from the community. 21Anybody that touches something unclean—human, animal, or something detestable—and then eats the meat from a peace offering, will be excluded from the community.&amp;quot; 22-23Yahveh told Moses to tell Israel, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat the fat from an ox, sheep, or goat 24or from an animal that dies or wild animals tear apart. Put it to other uses. 25Whoever eats the fat of an animal offered by fire to Yahveh will be excluded from the community. 26Don&amp;rsquo;t eat the blood of any bird or animal at home. 27Whoever does, will be excluded from the community.&amp;rdquo; 28-29Yahveh told Moses to say to Israel, &amp;ldquo;When you offer a peace offering, take it to Yahveh 30with the breast and fat of the animal so you can present it with your hands as a wave offering to Yahveh. 31The priest will offer up the fat in smoke on the altar, but the breast will be for Aaron and his sons. 32Give the right thigh to the priest as a contribution from the peace offering. 33That portion is for the one that offers its blood and fat. 34I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the breast of the wave offering and the thigh of the contribution from the people&amp;rsquo;s peace offerings, and given them to Aaron the priest and his sons as their permanent due from the people. 35&amp;quot;That&amp;rsquo;s what God has consecrated to Aaron and his sons from the offerings by fire to Yahveh when he presents them to serve as priests. 36Yahveh commanded the Israelites to give them from the day he anointed them. It&amp;rsquo;s their permanent due.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses, 2&amp;quot;Take Aaron and his sons, their vestments and anointing oil, the bull for the sin offering, the 2 rams, and the basket of bread containing no yeast, 3and gather the community at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; When they came, 5Moses told them, &amp;ldquo;Yahveh has commanded this.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; Moses had Aaron and his sons come near and bathed them. 7He put the tunic and sash on Aaron, dressed him in the robe, put the ephod on him, and tied it on with the artistic band of the ephod. 8He placed the pouch on him and put the Urim and the Thummin in it. 9He placed the turban on his head, and on the front of the turban he put the golden plate, the holy crown.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; On the eighth day, Moses called Aaron, his sons, and the elders in Israel. 2He told Aaron, &amp;ldquo;Take a bull calf for a sin offering and a ram for a burnt offering—both without defect—and offer them to Yahveh. 3Then tell the Israelites, &amp;lsquo;Take a male goat for a sin offering, a year-old calf and lamb without defect for a burnt offering,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; an ox and ram for peace offerings, and a grain offering mixed with olive oil because Yahveh is going to appear to you today.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Nadab and Abihu, Aaron&amp;rsquo;s sons, put fire in their firepans. They put incense on it and offered before Yahveh fire different from what he&amp;rsquo;d commanded them. 2Fire came out from Yahveh and consumed them, and they died. 3Moses told Aaron, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s what Yahveh meant when he said, &amp;lsquo;Those who come near me will treat me as holy in front of the people.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; So Aaron kept quiet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Again Yahveh told Moses and Aaron to tell the Israelites, &amp;ldquo;You can eat animals 3that have a split hoof and chew cud. 4-6Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything that just chews cud or only has a split hoof: a camel or rock-badger or rabbit. 7Don&amp;rsquo;t eat a pig; it has a split hoof but doesn&amp;rsquo;t chew cud. 8Don&amp;rsquo;t eat their meat or touch their carcasses; they&amp;rsquo;re ceremonially unclean. 9&amp;quot;You can eat anything in the water—seas and rivers—that has fins and scales. 10-11Any marine life that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have fins and scales is repulsive to you; detest their carcasses. [12] 13&amp;quot;Detest these birds and don&amp;rsquo;t eat them: eagles, vultures, buzzards, 14kites, falcons of any kind, 15ravens of any kind, 16ostrices, owls, sea gulls, hawks of any kind, 17little owls, cormorants, ibises, 18water hens, pelicans, carrion vultures, 19storks, herons of any kind, hoopoes, or bats. 20&amp;quot;Detest most winged insects that walk on four legs. 21Eat only the ones that have jointed legs and hop on the ground: 22any kind of locust, cricket, or grasshopper. [23] 24&amp;quot;Touching a carcass makes you ceremonially unclean. 25If you pick it up, you have to wash your clothes and be unclean until evening. 26Touching a ceremonially unclean animal—that doesn&amp;rsquo;t chew cud and split hoofs—makes you unclean. 27Any four-footed animal that walks on paws is ceremonially unclean. Touching its carcass makes you unclean. 28If you pick it up, wash your clothes and be unclean till evening. 29&amp;quot;These things that crawl on the ground are ceremonially unclean: moles, mice, big lizards of any kind, 30gechos, crocodiles, lizards, sand lizards of any kind, and chameleons. 31Whoever touches them when they&amp;rsquo;re dead is unclean till evening. 32Anything they fall on when they&amp;rsquo;re dead is also unclean: wooden articles, clothes, skins, sacks, anything you use. Put them in water till evening, and they&amp;rsquo;ll be clean. 33&amp;quot;Any clay container that one of these ceremonially unclean things falls into is ceremonially unclean. Break it. 34Any food in it that water gets on is likewise unclean. Water or any liquid a person might drink in any container becomes unclean. 35Anything that part of their carcass falls on becomes unclean. Smash an oven or stove; they&amp;rsquo;re permanently unclean. 36A spring or cistern that collects water is clean even though the one that has touched their carcasses is unclean. 37If any part of their carcass falls on any seed for sowing, it&amp;rsquo;s clean. 38But, if water gets on that seed, it&amp;rsquo;s ceremonially unclean. 39&amp;quot;If an animal dies that you have for food, touching its carcass makes you ceremonially unclean till evening. 40If you pick it up or eat some of it, wash your clothes and be unclean till evening. 41&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything that crawls on the ground: 42anything that crawls on its belly, walks on four legs, or has many feet is detestable. 43Don&amp;rsquo;t make yourselves ceremonially unclean by them. 44Consecrate yourselves and be holy. 45I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh that brought you up from Egypt to be your God. Be holy because I&amp;rsquo;m holy.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to tell Israel, &amp;ldquo;When a woman has a boy, she&amp;rsquo;s ceremonially unclean for a week like during her menstruation. 3On the eighth day, circumcise his foreskin. 4For 33 more days, she&amp;rsquo;ll be impure from her bleeding at childbirth. She&amp;rsquo;s not to touch anything consecrated or enter the sanctuary until after her purification time. 5If she has a girl, she&amp;rsquo;s ceremonially unclean for two weeks like during menstruation. For 66 more days, she&amp;rsquo;ll be impure from her bleeding at childbirth. 6&amp;quot;When her purification days are over for a son or daughter, she&amp;rsquo;ll take to the priest at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting, a year-old lamb for a burnt offering and a young pigeon or turtledove for a sin offering. 7He&amp;rsquo;ll offer it to Yahveh for her purification, and she&amp;rsquo;ll be ceremonially cleansed from her bleeding at childbirth. That&amp;rsquo;s the law for a woman that has a male or female child. 8If she can&amp;rsquo;t afford a lamb, she can take two turtledoves or young pigeons, one for a burnt offering, the other for a sin offering. The priest will offer them for her, and she&amp;rsquo;ll be ceremonially clean.&amp;rdquo; The Tests for Leprosy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses and Aaron, 2&amp;quot;When any of you has a swelling, rash, or skin discoloration that could become leprous, go to Aaron the priest or one of his sons as priests. 3He&amp;rsquo;ll examine the spot. If the hair in the spot has turned white and the infection appears to be deeper than the skin, it&amp;rsquo;s leprosy. The priest will pronounce you unclean. 4But if the discoloration doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to go that deep and the hair on it hasn&amp;rsquo;t turned white, the priest will quarantine you for a week 5and examine it on the seventh day. If the spot has changed or spread, he&amp;rsquo;ll quarantine you for another week 6and examine it again. If the spot has faded and not spread, he&amp;rsquo;ll pronounce you ceremonially clean; it&amp;rsquo;s just a rash. Wash your clothes and be clean. 7&amp;quot;But if the rash spreads, go to the priest again, 8and he&amp;rsquo;ll pronounce you unclean. It&amp;rsquo;s leprosy. 9&amp;quot;If you get leprosy, you need to go to the priest 10to be examined. If there&amp;rsquo;s a white swelling in the skin that has turned the hair white and there are open sores in the swelling, 11it&amp;rsquo;s chronic leprosy. The priest will pronounce you unclean. He won&amp;rsquo;t quarantine because you&amp;rsquo;re definitely unclean. 12If the leprosy spreads from head to toe, 13he&amp;rsquo;ll pronounce you clean if it has all turned to normal skin color. 14But if open sores appear, 15it&amp;rsquo;s leprosy. 16If the open sores turn to normal skin color again, 17the priest will pronounce you clean. 18&amp;quot;When a boil heals 19and a discoloration or reddish-white swelling comes up in its place, show it to the priest. 20If it appears to be deeper than the skin and the hair on it has turned white, he&amp;rsquo;ll pronounce you unclean. It&amp;rsquo;s leprosy that has broken out in the boil. 21But if there aren&amp;rsquo;t any white hairs in it, it&amp;rsquo;s not deeper than the skin, and it&amp;rsquo;s faded, you&amp;rsquo;ll quarantine for a week. 22If it spreads, the priest will pronounce you unclean; it&amp;rsquo;s an infection. 23But if the discoloration doesn&amp;rsquo;t spread, it&amp;rsquo;s just a scar from the boil. You&amp;rsquo;re clean. 24&amp;quot;If your body gets a burn on the skin and an open sore becomes a bright white or reddish-white spot, 25the priest needs to examine it. If the hair in the bright spot has turned white and appears to be deeper than the skin, it&amp;rsquo;s leprosy that broke out of the burn. He&amp;rsquo;ll pronounce you unclean. 26If there&amp;rsquo;s no white hair in the bright spot and it&amp;rsquo;s no deeper than the skin, but has faded, you&amp;rsquo;ll quarantine for a week. 27The priest will examine you on the seventh day. If it spreads on the skin, he&amp;rsquo;ll declare you unclean; it&amp;rsquo;s leprosy. 28But if the bright spot doesn&amp;rsquo;t spread, but has faded, it&amp;rsquo;s the swelling from the burn. The priest will declare you clean; it&amp;rsquo;s just a scar from the burn. 29&amp;quot;If any of you, man or woman, has an infection on the head—or in the beard, 30the priest needs to examine it. If it appears to be deeper than the skin and there&amp;rsquo;s thin yellowish hair in it, he&amp;rsquo;ll pronounce you unclean. It&amp;rsquo;s a sore, leprosy of the head or beard. 31But if it appears to be no deeper than the skin and there&amp;rsquo;s no black hair in it, quarantine for a week. 32On the seventh day, the priest will examine it. If the sore hasn&amp;rsquo;t spread, no yellowish hair has grown in it, and the scale appears to be no deeper than the skin, 33then shave except for the spot and quarantine for another week. 34On the seventh day, the priest will examine it. If the spot hasn&amp;rsquo;t spread and doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be deeper than the skin, he&amp;rsquo;ll pronounce you clean. 35If the spot spreads after that cleansing, 36the priest need not look for yellowish hair; you&amp;rsquo;re definitely unclean. 37If the priest thinks the spot hasn&amp;rsquo;t spread and black hairs have grown in it, the sore has healed. He&amp;rsquo;ll pronounce you ceremonially clean. 38&amp;quot;If any of you, man or woman, has a white bright spot on the skin, 39the priest needs to examine it. If it&amp;rsquo;s faint white, it&amp;rsquo;s eczema breaking out on the skin. You&amp;rsquo;re ceremonially clean. 40&amp;quot;If a man loses his hair and becomes bald; he&amp;rsquo;s clean. 41If his head becomes bald in the front and temples and he&amp;rsquo;s bald on the forehead; he&amp;rsquo;s clean. 42But if a reddish infection occurs on the bald head or brow, it&amp;rsquo;s leprosy breaking out. 43The priest needs to examine him. If the swelling is reddish white, 44he has leprosy. The priest will pronounce him unclean; it&amp;rsquo;s an infection. 45&amp;quot;If you&amp;rsquo;re a leper, you need to tear your clothes, uncover your head, cover your upper lip, and call out, &amp;lsquo;Unclean! Unclean!&amp;rsquo;  46You&amp;rsquo;re unclean as long as you have the infection. Live outside the camp apart from the rest of society.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses, 2&amp;quot;This is the law about lepers that are ceremonially cleansed. Take them to the priest 3outside the camp to see if the leprosy has healed. 4He&amp;rsquo;ll give orders to take two live clean birds, cedar wood, a scarlet string, and hyssop. 5He&amp;rsquo;ll have one bird killed in a clay basin over running water. 6He&amp;rsquo;ll take the live bird, the cedar wood, scarlet string, and hyssop, and dip them and the live bird in the blood of the bird killed over running water. 7Then he&amp;rsquo;ll sprinkle seven times the one to be cleansed, pronounce the person ceremonially clean, and let the live bird go free in an open field. 8The ones cleansed will wash their clothes, shave off their hair, take a bath, and be clean. Afterwards they can go into the camp, but they&amp;rsquo;ll stay outside the tent for a week. 9On the seventh day, they&amp;rsquo;ll shave off their hair, beard, and eyebrows; wash their clothes, take a bath, and be ceremonially clean. 10&amp;quot;On the eighth day, the one cleansed will take 2 male lambs without defect, a yearling ewe without defect, .33 bushel .3 ephah of fine flour mixed with olive oil for a grain offering, and 1 pint 1 log of oil. 11The priest will present them and the person to Yahveh at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. 12The priest will bring 1 male lamb for a guilt offering with the pint 1 log of olive oil and present them as a wave offering. 13He&amp;rsquo;ll slaughter the male lamb where they slaughter the sin offering and burnt offering, because the guilt offering (like the sin offering) is for the priest; it&amp;rsquo;s most holy. 14He&amp;rsquo;s to take some blood from the guilt offering and put it on the right earlobe, thumb, and big toe of the one to be cleansed. 15He&amp;rsquo;ll pour some of the pint log of olive oil into his left palm, 16dip his right-hand finger in it, and sprinkle it seven times in front of Yahveh. 17Some of the oil still in his palm he&amp;rsquo;ll put on the right earlobe, thumb, and big toe of the one to be cleansed—on top of the blood from the guilt offering. 18The rest of the oil in his palm goes on the head of the one to be cleansed. 19Next, he&amp;rsquo;ll offer the sin offering to atone for the person. Last, he&amp;rsquo;ll slaughter the burnt offering 20and offer it up with the grain offering on the altar. Then the person will be ceremonially clean. 21&amp;quot;But someone that&amp;rsquo;s poor can take 1 male lamb for a guilt offering as a wave offering for atonement, .11 bushel .1 ephah of fine flour mixed with olive oil for a grain offering, a pint log of oil, 22and two turtledoves or young pigeons. One will be a sin offering, the other a burnt offering. 23On the eighth day the person will take them to the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. 24The priest will take the lamb for the guilt offering and the pint log of olive oil and offer them for a wave offering to Yahveh. 25He&amp;rsquo;ll slaughter the lamb for the guilt offering and put some of its blood on the right earlobe, thumb, and big toe of the one to be cleansed. 26He&amp;rsquo;ll pour some of the olive oil into his left palm 27and with his right-hand finger sprinkle it seven times to Yahveh. 28He&amp;rsquo;s to put some of it on the right earlobe, thumb, and big toe of the one to be cleansed—on top of the blood from the guilt offering. 29The rest of the oil that&amp;rsquo;s in his palm goes on the head of the one to be cleansed. 30Then he&amp;rsquo;ll offer one of the turtledoves or young pigeons, 31one for a sin offering, the other for a burnt offering—together with the grain offering. The priest will purify the one to be cleansed.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses and Aaron to say to Israel, &amp;ldquo;When a man has a discharge from his body, it&amp;rsquo;s ceremonially unclean 3whether it keeps flowing or stops on its own. 4Anything he lies on or sits on is unclean. 5-6If any of you touch his bed or anything he sits on, wash your clothes, take a bath, and be unclean till evening. 7Any of you that touch a person with a discharge will do the same and be unclean till evening. 8If someone with a discharge spits on any of you that are clean, wash your clothes, take a bath, and be unclean till evening. 9Any saddle a person with a discharge rides on is unclean. 10If any of you touch anything what was under him, wash your clothes, take a bath, and be unclean till evening. 11Likewise, if the one with the discharge touches any of you without rinsing his hands, wash your clothes, take a bath, and be unclean till evening. 12Break any clay container he touches and rinse any wooden container in water. 13&amp;quot;To become ceremonially clean, a man with a discharge will count off a week for his cleansing. He&amp;rsquo;ll wash his clothes and take a bath in running water and be clean. 14On the eighth day, he&amp;rsquo;ll take two turtledoves or young pigeons, and give them to the priest at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. 15The priest will offer one for a sin offering and the other for a burnt offering. He&amp;rsquo;ll purify him from his discharge before Yahveh. 16&amp;quot;If a man has a discharge of semen, he&amp;rsquo;ll take a bath and be ceremonially unclean till evening. 17He&amp;rsquo;ll wash any piece of clothes or leather that has semen on it, and it&amp;rsquo;ll be unclean till evening. 18If a man has relations with a woman so that there&amp;rsquo;s an emission of semen, they&amp;rsquo;ll both take a bath and be unclean till evening. 19&amp;quot;When a woman has her period, she&amp;rsquo;ll be in her menstrual impurity for a week. If any of you touch her, you&amp;rsquo;ll be ceremonially unclean till evening. 20Anything she lies on or sits on is unclean. [21] 22-23If any of you touch anything she sits on or lies on, wash your clothes, take a bath, and be unclean till evening. 24If a man has relations with her during her period, he&amp;rsquo;ll be unclean for a week, and any bed he lies on will be unclean. 25&amp;quot;If a woman has a discharge of blood many days outside her period or beyond her period, she&amp;rsquo;ll be ceremonially unclean like during her period. 26Any bed she lies on or anything she sits on is unclean like during her period. 27If any of you touch them, you&amp;rsquo;ll be unclean. Wash your clothes, take a bath, and be unclean till evening. 28To become clean from her discharge, she&amp;rsquo;ll count off a week; afterward she&amp;rsquo;ll be clean. 29On the eighth day, she&amp;rsquo;ll take two turtledoves or young pigeons, and take them in to the priest, to the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. 30He&amp;rsquo;ll offer one for a sin offering and the other for a burnt offering to purify her. 31&amp;quot;That&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;ll keep Israelites separated from their ceremonial uncleanness so they won&amp;rsquo;t die for defiling my Tabernacle.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After Aaron&amp;rsquo;s two sons died from approaching Yahveh, he told Moses, 2&amp;quot;Tell your brother Aaron not to enter the Holy Place at just any time—the place inside the curtain in front of the Mercy Seat that&amp;rsquo;s on the Ark. He&amp;rsquo;ll die because I&amp;rsquo;ll appear in the cloud above the mercy seat. 3He&amp;rsquo;ll enter the Holy Place with a bull for a sin offering and a ram for a burnt offering. 4After he takes a bath, he can put on the linen holy vestments: the tunic, underclothes, sash, and turban. 5He&amp;rsquo;s to take from the community 2 male goats for a sin offering and 1 ram for a burnt offering. 6He&amp;rsquo;ll offer the bull for the sin offering to atone for himself and his family, 7and present the 2 goats at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. 8He&amp;rsquo;ll cast lots for them, one for Yahveh, the other as a scapegoat. 9Then he&amp;rsquo;ll offer the one as a sin offering to Yahveh 10and present the other one alive to Yahveh to make atonement by sending it into the open country. 11&amp;quot;Aaron will slaughter the bull as a sin offering to atone for himself and his family. 12He&amp;rsquo;ll take a firepan of coals from the altar that&amp;rsquo;s in front of Yahveh and two handfuls of finely ground sweet incense and carry them inside the curtain. 13When he puts the incense on the fire, a cloud of incense will cover the mercy seat so he won&amp;rsquo;t die. 14With his finger, seven times he&amp;rsquo;ll sprinkle the bull&amp;rsquo;s blood in front of the Mercy Seat. 15&amp;quot;Then he&amp;rsquo;ll slaughter the goat as a sin offering for the people and take its blood inside the curtain. He&amp;rsquo;ll do with its blood what he did with the bull&amp;rsquo;s blood. 16He&amp;rsquo;ll atone for the Holy Place because of the Israelites&amp;rsquo; impurities, transgressions, and sins. He is to do the same thing for the Tent of Meeting that stands with them among their impurities. 17When he makes atonement in the Holy Place, nobody will be in the Tent of Meeting till he comes back out, so he can atone for himself, his family, and the whole assembly. 18Then he&amp;rsquo;ll go out to the altar that&amp;rsquo;s in front of Yahveh and atone for it by putting some of the bull&amp;rsquo;s and goat&amp;rsquo;s blood on the horns of the altar. 19With his finger he&amp;rsquo;ll sprinkle blood on it seven times to cleanse it and consecrate it from the impurities of the Israelites. 20&amp;quot;When he finishes atoning for the Holy Place, the Tent of Meeting, and the altar, he&amp;rsquo;ll offer the live goat. 21He&amp;rsquo;ll put both hands on its head and confess over it the Israelites&amp;rsquo; iniquities, transgressions, and sins. He&amp;rsquo;ll put them on the goat&amp;rsquo;s head and send it into the open country by a man standing by. 22The goat will carry their sins to a solitary place, and the man will release it. 23&amp;quot;Then Aaron will come into the Tent of Meeting, change out of the linen vestments, and leave them there. 24He&amp;rsquo;ll take a bath in a holy place, put on his own clothes, and come out to offer burnt offerings to atone for himself and the people. 25He&amp;rsquo;ll offer up in smoke the fat from the sin offering on the altar. 26The one that released the scapegoat will wash his clothes and take a bath. Then he can come into camp. 27But take outside the camp the bull and goat for the sin offering—whose blood was brought in to make atonement in the Holy Place. Burn their hides, meat, and refuse. 28The one that burns them will wash his clothes and take a bath before he comes back into camp. 29&amp;quot;This is a permanent statute: the tenth day, seventh month, you and any foreigner living among you will fast and not work. 30That day, the priest will atone for your sins in front of Yahveh. 31It&amp;rsquo;s a fast and solemn rest for you. 32The priest that&amp;rsquo;s anointed and ordained to serve as priest in his father&amp;rsquo;s place will make atonement. He&amp;rsquo;ll put on the holy linen vestments 33and atone for the holy sanctuary, the Tent of Meeting, the altar, the priests, and the whole assembly. 34That&amp;rsquo;s a permanent statute to atone for the Israelites&amp;rsquo; sins once a year.&amp;quot; Moses did what Yahveh said.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-17&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to tell Aaron, his sons, and all Israel, &amp;ldquo;Yahveh has commanded 3that no one in Israel is to slaughter an ox, lamb, or goat inside or outside the camp 4instead of taking it to the Tent of Meeting to present it to Yahveh. God will hold him guilty of shedding blood. Exclude him from the community. 5Instead, people need to take their animals to the priest at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting and sacrifice them as peace offerings. 6The priest will sprinkle the blood on the altar at the entrance of the Tent of Meeting and offer up the fat in smoke as an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. 7They&amp;rsquo;ll no longer sacrifice to the goat-idols they commit prostitution with. That&amp;rsquo;s a permanent statute. 8&amp;quot;Anyone in Israel or a foreigner living there who offers a burnt offering or sacrifice 9without taking it to Yahveh, will be excluded from the community. 10&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;ll oppose and exclude from the community anyone in Israel or a foreigner living there who eats blood. 11The life is in the blood, and I&amp;rsquo;ve given it to you on the altar to atone for you. It&amp;rsquo;s the lifeblood that atones.&amp;rdquo; 12I told Israel, &amp;ldquo;Nobody among you or foreigner among you can eat blood. 13When you hunt an animal or bird that can be eaten, drain out its blood and cover it with dirt. 14&amp;quot;In all kinds of flesh, blood is identified with its life; so I told the Israelites not to eat blood. If any of you eat it, you&amp;rsquo;ll be excluded from the community. 15Whether native or foreign, if you eat an animal that has died or wild animals have torn to pieces, wash your clothes, take a bath, and remain ceremonially unclean till evening. 16If you don&amp;rsquo;t do that, you&amp;rsquo;re considered guilty.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-18&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to say to Israel, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God. 3Don&amp;rsquo;t do what they do in Egypt where you lived or in Canaan where I&amp;rsquo;m taking you. Don&amp;rsquo;t follow their statutes. 4If you obey my regulations and keep my statutes, 5you&amp;rsquo;ll have life. 6&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t have sexual relations with any blood relative; I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh. 7Don&amp;rsquo;t uncover the nakedness of your father by uncovering the nakedness of your mother 8or your father&amp;rsquo;s wife. 9Don&amp;rsquo;t have sexual relations with your sister or half-sister, born in your home or elsewhere. 10Don&amp;rsquo;t uncover the nakedness of your granddaughter; her nakedness is your nakedness. [11] 12-14Don&amp;rsquo;t uncover the nakedness of your aunt; she&amp;rsquo;s your parent&amp;rsquo;s blood relative. You uncover your uncle&amp;rsquo;s nakedness by approaching his wife. 15Don&amp;rsquo;t have sexual relations with your daughter-in-law; she&amp;rsquo;s your son&amp;rsquo;s wife. 16Don&amp;rsquo;t have sexual relations with your sister-in-law; it&amp;rsquo;s your brother&amp;rsquo;s nakedness. 17Don&amp;rsquo;t uncover the nakedness of a woman and her daughter or granddaughter; they&amp;rsquo;re blood relatives. It&amp;rsquo;s sinful. 18Don&amp;rsquo;t marry a woman and her sister and they become rivals. 19&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t have sexual relations with a woman during her period. 20Don&amp;rsquo;t have sexual relations with your neighbor&amp;rsquo;s wife and be defiled with her. 21Don&amp;rsquo;t offer any of your offspring to Molech or profane your God; I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh. 22Don&amp;rsquo;t lie with a male as one lies with a female; it&amp;rsquo;s detestable. 23Don&amp;rsquo;t have sexual relations with any animal; you defile yourself. No woman is to stand in front of an animal to mate with it; it&amp;rsquo;s perverse. 24&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t defile yourselves with such things. The nations I&amp;rsquo;m chasing out ahead of you defiled themselves that way. 25They&amp;rsquo;ve defiled the land; so I&amp;rsquo;ve brought punishment on it; it has spewed out its people. 26You are to keep my statutes and judgments; don&amp;rsquo;t any native or foreigner among you do any of those disgusting things. [27] 28That&amp;rsquo;s so the land won&amp;rsquo;t spew you out for defiling it. 29Exclude from the community whoever does any of those disgusting things. 30&amp;quot;You&amp;rsquo;re to keep my charge so you won&amp;rsquo;t defile yourselves. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-19&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to tell the whole community of Israel, &amp;ldquo;Be holy because I&amp;rsquo;m holy. 3Respect your parents and keep my Sabbaths. 4Don&amp;rsquo;t turn to idols or make molten gods. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God. 5&amp;quot;When you offer a peace offering to Yahveh, offer it so he&amp;rsquo;ll accept it. 6Eat it the day you offer it and the next day. Burn what&amp;rsquo;s left over till the third day. 7If you eat it on the third day, Yahveh won&amp;rsquo;t accept it. 8You&amp;rsquo;ll be guilty of profaning what&amp;rsquo;s holy to him and be excluded from the community. 9&amp;quot;When you harvest, don&amp;rsquo;t harvest the corners of your field or pick up the gleanings of your harvest. 10Don&amp;rsquo;t glean your vineyard or pick up its fallen fruit. Leave it for the needy and foreigners. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God. 11&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t steal, lie, or deal falsely with one another. 12Don&amp;rsquo;t swear falsely by me and profane my name. 13&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t oppress or rob anyone or keep a hired hand&amp;rsquo;s wages overnight. 14Don&amp;rsquo;t curse the deaf or trip the blind. Respect your God. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh. 15&amp;quot;Be just when you judge. Don&amp;rsquo;t be partial to the poor or defer to someone with status. Judge fairly. 16Don&amp;rsquo;t slander or act against anyone&amp;rsquo;s life. 17&amp;quot;You can reprove but not sin against or hate a fellow citizen. 18Don&amp;rsquo;t take revenge or bear a grudge. Love your neighbor as yourself. 19&amp;quot;Keep my statutes. Don&amp;rsquo;t crossbreed two kinds of cattle, sow your field with two kinds of seed, or wear a piece of clothes that blends two kinds of material. 20If a man lies carnally with a slave woman that&amp;rsquo;s engaged to another man but not yet redeemed or given her freedom, punish them. Don&amp;rsquo;t put them to death; she wasn&amp;rsquo;t free. 21He&amp;rsquo;ll take a ram to Yahveh at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. 22The priest will atone for him with the ram, and he will be forgiven. 23&amp;quot;When you go into the land and plant fruit trees, consider their fruit forbidden for three years. 24In the fourth year, their fruit will be holy, a praise offering to Yahveh. 25The fifth year, you can eat it so it&amp;rsquo;ll increase for you. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God. 26&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t eat anything with blood in it or practice fortunetelling or soothsaying. 27&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t trim off the hair on your temples or trim the edges of your beard. 28&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t make cuts on your body for the dead or wear tattoos. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh. 29&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t profane your daughter by making her a prostitute, so your country won&amp;rsquo;t fall into prostitution and fill up with lewdness. 30&amp;quot;Keep my Sabbaths and respect my sanctuary. 31&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t defile yourself by appealing to mediums or spiritualists. 32&amp;quot;Stand up for the gray headed, honor the aged, respect God. 33&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t mistreat foreigners living in your country. 34Treat them like the natives among you. Love them like yourself. You were foreigners in Egypt. Yahveh your God. 35&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t cheat in judgment in measuring weight or volume. 36Have accurate balances, weights, ephahs, and hins. 37Observe my statutes and ordinances. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh that brought you out of Egypt.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-20&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to say to Israel, &amp;ldquo;Stone to death people that sacrifice their offspring to Molech. 3I&amp;rsquo;ll oppose them and exclude them from the community; they&amp;rsquo;ve defiled my sanctuary and my holy name. 4If you don&amp;rsquo;t execute them, 5I&amp;rsquo;ll oppose them and their families, and exclude both them and the ones that carried on prostitution with them. 6&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;ll oppose people that turn to mediums or spiritualists and carry on prostitution with them. I&amp;rsquo;ll exclude them from the community. 7-8So consecrate yourselves and be holy. Practice my statutes because I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh that sanctifies you. 9&amp;quot;Exclude from the community anyone that cusses at father or mother. That&amp;rsquo;s a crime punishable by death. 10&amp;quot;If a man commits adultery with another man&amp;rsquo;s wife, execute them both. 11A man that lies with his father&amp;rsquo;s wife, has uncovered his father&amp;rsquo;s nakedness. Execute them both. They&amp;rsquo;ve committed a crime punishable by death. 12If a man lies with his daughter-in-law, execute them both; they&amp;rsquo;ve committed incest. They&amp;rsquo;ve committed a crime punishable by death. 13A man that lies with a male like the ones that lie with a woman—both of them have committed a disgusting act. Execute them. They&amp;rsquo;ve committed a crime punishable by death. 14It&amp;rsquo;s immoral for a man to marry a woman and her mother. Burn them both so there won&amp;rsquo;t be immorality among you. 15Execute a man that lies with an animal and kill the animal. 16Execute any woman that approaches an animal to mate with it; kill the animal. They&amp;rsquo;ve committed a crime punishable by death. 17&amp;quot;It&amp;rsquo;s a disgrace for a man to take his sister—his father&amp;rsquo;s or mother&amp;rsquo;s daughter—so he sees her nakedness and she sees his. Exclude them from the community. He has uncovered his sister&amp;rsquo;s nakedness. He bears his guilt. 18A man that lies with a menstruating woman has laid bare her flow, and she has exposed the flow of her blood. Cut both of them off from the community. 19Don&amp;rsquo;t have sexual relations with your aunt; you&amp;rsquo;ve made naked a blood relative. You&amp;rsquo;ll be guilty. 20A man that lies with his uncle&amp;rsquo;s wife has uncovered his uncle&amp;rsquo;s nakedness. They&amp;rsquo;ll bear their sin and die childless. 21A man that takes his brother&amp;rsquo;s wife is repulsive; he has uncovered his brother&amp;rsquo;s nakedness. Both will die childless. 22&amp;quot;Keep my statutes and ordinances so the land where I&amp;rsquo;m taking you won&amp;rsquo;t spew you out. 23Don&amp;rsquo;t follow the customs of nations I drive out ahead of you. It&amp;rsquo;s because they did those things that they&amp;rsquo;re repulsive to me. 24Take their land; I&amp;rsquo;ll give it to you, a land flowing with milk and honey. 25So distinguish between ceremonially clean and unclean animals or birds. Don&amp;rsquo;t make yourselves disgusting by animals, birds, or what crawls on the ground that I&amp;rsquo;ve separated from you as unclean. 26Be holy to me because I, Yahveh, am holy. I&amp;rsquo;ve set you apart from the nations to be mine. 27&amp;quot;Stone a medium or spiritualist, man or woman. They&amp;rsquo;ve committed a crime punishable by death.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-21&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to tell the sons of Aaron the priests, &amp;ldquo;None of you are to defile yourselves for a dead person 2except for a close relative: mother, father, son, daughter, brother—3or virgin sister, since she doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a husband. 4Don&amp;rsquo;t profane yourselves as a relative by marriage. 5Don&amp;rsquo;t shave your heads, trim your beards, or make cuts on your bodies. 6Be holy to your God and not profane him, because you present the offerings by fire to Yahveh, the food of your God. 7Priests can&amp;rsquo;t marry a prostitute or divorced woman. They&amp;rsquo;re holy to God&amp;rdquo; 8&amp;quot;Consecrate them because they offer the food of your God. They&amp;rsquo;ll be holy to you because I, Yahveh, that sanctifies you am holy. 9If a priest&amp;rsquo;s daughter profanes herself by prostitution, she profanes her father. Burn her. 10&amp;quot;A high priest—the one that&amp;rsquo;s anointed and consecrated to wear the vestments—will not uncover his head or tear his clothes, 11approach any dead person or defile himself even for his father or mother. 12He&amp;rsquo;s not to leave the sanctuary or profane it, because he has on him God&amp;rsquo;s consecrating oil. 13He has to marry a virgin from his own people. 14He can&amp;rsquo;t marry a widow, divorced woman, or prostitute; 15he would profane his offspring among his people. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh that sanctifies him.&amp;ldquo;eHe 16-17The LORD told Moses to tell Aaron, &amp;ldquo;None of your offspring with a defect can offer the bread of his God: 18a blind or lame man, one with a disfigured face or deformed limb, 19a man with a broken foot or hand, 20a hunchback or dwarf, one with a defect in his eye, one with eczema, scabs, or crushed testicles. 21None of your descendants that has a defect can offer Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s offerings by fire. 22He can eat the bread of his God, holy and most holy, 23but he can&amp;rsquo;t go in to the curtain or approach the altar. He&amp;rsquo;s not to profane my sanctuary. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh that sanctifies him.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-22&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to tell Aaron and his sons, &amp;ldquo;Handle the holy gifts carefully that the Israelites dedicate to me so you don&amp;rsquo;t profane my name. 3Don&amp;rsquo;t approach the holy gifts while you&amp;rsquo;re ceremonially unclean. I&amp;rsquo;ll remove you from me. 4If you&amp;rsquo;re a leper or have a discharge, you can&amp;rsquo;t eat the holy gifts till you&amp;rsquo;re clean. Touching anything made ceremonially unclean by a corpse or seminal emission, 5or touching any teeming thing that makes any person unclean, 6makes you unclean till evening. You can&amp;rsquo;t eat the sacred gifts till you take a bath. 7When the sun sets, you&amp;rsquo;ll be clean and can eat them. 8You can&amp;rsquo;t eat an animal that dies or is torn to pieces by wild animals; that makes you ceremonially unclean. 9Keep my charge so you won&amp;rsquo;t be considered defiled and die for profaning my name. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh that sanctifies them. 10&amp;quot;No layman, visitor with a priest, or hired hand can eat the sacred gifts. 11But a slave that a priest buys with his own money can eat them; so can slaves born in his house. 12If a priest&amp;rsquo;s daughter marries a layman, she can&amp;rsquo;t continue to eat the gifts. 13But if she becomes a widow or is divorced, doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any children, and goes back to her father&amp;rsquo;s family, she can eat her father&amp;rsquo;s food. 14If any of you laymen unintentionally eat a sacred gift, add a fifth to it and give it to the priest. 15Laymen are not to profane the sacred gift Israelites offer to Yahveh; 16so they&amp;rsquo;re fined for it. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh that sanctifies them.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; 17-18Yahveh told Moses to tell Aaron, his sons, and all Israel: &amp;ldquo;When an Israelite or foreigner presents a burnt offering, an offering for fulfilling a vow, or a freewill offering, 19for God to accept it, it must be a male without defect from the cattle, sheep, or goats. 20Don&amp;rsquo;t offer anything that has a defect. 21When anyone sacrifices a peace offering to Yahveh to fulfill a special vow or for a freewill offering from the herd or flock, it must be perfect. 22Don&amp;rsquo;t offer a blind, crippled, or injured animal, or one with a running sore, eczema, or scab. Don&amp;rsquo;t make it an offering by fire on the altar to Yahveh.  23An ox or lamb that has an enlarged or undersized member, you can present for a freewill offering, but not for a vow. 24Don&amp;rsquo;t offer anything that has its testicles bruised, crushed, torn to pieces by wild animals, or castrated. 25Don&amp;rsquo;t accept anything like that from a foreigner for an offering as the food of your God. It has a defect; he won&amp;rsquo;t accept it.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-23&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 23&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to tell Israel, &amp;ldquo;Yahveh has appointed these times: 3six days you can work, but the seventh day is a Sabbath for complete rest, a holy convocation. It&amp;rsquo;s a Sabbath to Yahveh wherever you live. 4&amp;quot;These are his appointed times, holy convocations that you&amp;rsquo;ll declare at their appointed times. 5The fourteenth day, first month at twilight is Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s Passover. 6Then on the fifteenth, there&amp;rsquo;s a Festival of Unleavened Bread to him. Eat bread without yeast for a week. 7The first day, hold a holy convocation; don&amp;rsquo;t work. 8Present an offering by fire to Yahveh for a week. On the seventh day, hold a holy convocation; don&amp;rsquo;t work.&amp;rdquo; 9-10Yahveh told Moses to say to Israel, &amp;ldquo;When you harvest the land I&amp;rsquo;m giving you, take a bundle of the first part of the harvest to the priest. 11The day after Sabbath he&amp;rsquo;ll wave it back and forth in front of Yahveh for you to be accepted. 12When you wave it, offer a male lamb a year old without defect for a burnt offering. 13Its grain offering will be .22 bushel .2 ephah of fine flour mixed with olive oil, an offering by fire to Yahveh for a pleasing aroma, with its liquid offering, 3pts ¼ hin of wine. 14Before you take the offering to your God, don&amp;rsquo;t eat bread or roasted grain from the new growth. It&amp;rsquo;s an ongoing permanent statute wherever you live. 15&amp;quot;Count seven Sabbaths from the day after the Sabbath when you brought the bundle for the wave offering. 16Count 50 days to the day after the seventh Sabbath. Then present a new grain offering to Yahveh. 17Take in 2 loaves of bread for a wave offering, made from .22 bushel .2 ephah. They&amp;rsquo;ll consist of fine flour baked with yeast as the first of the harvest to Yahveh.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-24&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 24&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh said to Moses, 2&amp;quot;Tell the people to bring you clear oil from pressed olives that can keep a lamp burning continually. 3-4Outside the curtain of Testimony in the Tent of Meeting, Aaron will keep the lamps on the lampstand in order from evening to morning continually. It&amp;rsquo;s an ongoing permanent statute. 5&amp;quot;Take fine flour and bake 12 cakes. Put .22 bushels .2 ephah in each one. 6Set them in two stacks, six to a stack on the pure gold table. 7Put pure frankincense beside each stack for the bread as God&amp;rsquo;s portion, an offering by fire to Yahveh. 8Every Sabbath Aaron will set this bread in order in front of Yahveh, a permanent covenant for Israel. 9It&amp;rsquo;ll be for Aaron and his sons to eat in a sacred place. It&amp;rsquo;s the most sacred to them from Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s offerings by fire, their permanent portion.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-25&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 25&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses at Mount Sinai to tell Israel, &amp;ldquo;When you go into the land I&amp;rsquo;m giving you, the ground will have a rest to Yahveh. 3Plant your fields, prune your vineyards, harvest your crops for six years. 4But the seventh year, the ground will rest to Yahveh. Don&amp;rsquo;t plant your fields or prune your vineyards. 5Don&amp;rsquo;t store up volunteer growth or gather grapes from untrimmed vines. Let the ground lie feral for a year. 6You&amp;rsquo;ll have for food what the ground grows on its own during its sabbath year—yourselves, your male and female slaves, hired hands, and foreigners living with you. 7Your livestock and the wild animals on your land will have its produce to eat directly. 8&amp;quot;Count off 7 weeks of years (49 years). 9Then blow the ram&amp;rsquo;s horn all over the country on the tenth day, seventh month, the Day of Atonement. 10Consecrate the fiftieth year as a nation-wide release for its people, a jubilee. You&amp;rsquo;ll go back to your own property and family. 11Don&amp;rsquo;t plant, store up volunteer growth, or pick clean the untrimmed vines. 12It&amp;rsquo;s a Year of Jubilee, set aside for you. Eat its produce directly out of the field. 13&amp;quot;In the Year of Jubilee, each of you may go back to your own property. 14If you sell or buy something from one another, don&amp;rsquo;t wrong one another. 15Corresponding to the number of years since the last Year of Jubilee, you&amp;rsquo;ll buy and sell it based on the number of crops. 16Calculate its price by the number of crops you&amp;rsquo;re buying or selling. 17Don&amp;rsquo;t cheat one another; respect God. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God. 18&amp;quot;In that way, observe my statutes and obey my regulations so you can live securely on the land. 19Then the ground will yield its produce so you can eat your fill. 20But if you wonder what you&amp;rsquo;re going to eat in the seventh year if you don&amp;rsquo;t plant or harvest crops, 21I&amp;rsquo;ll order my blessing for you in the sixth year so the ground will produce a crop sufficient for three years. 22When you&amp;rsquo;re planting the eighth year, you&amp;rsquo;ll still be eating from the old crops till the ninth year&amp;rsquo;s crop comes in. 23&amp;quot;You can&amp;rsquo;t sell land permanently because it&amp;rsquo;s mine. You&amp;rsquo;re foreigners that live temporarily with me. 24So provide for the redemption of every piece of property. 25If you become so poor you have to sell some of your property, your nearest relative can buy it back. 26If you don&amp;rsquo;t have any relatives but accumulate enough, you have the right to buy it back yourself. 27To reclaim it, calculate the years since its sale and refund the balance. 28If you don&amp;rsquo;t accumulate enough to buy it back, it remains with the buyer till the Year of Jubilee and then reverts to you. 29&amp;quot;If you sell a house in a walled city, you have a right to buy it back for a full year. 30If you don&amp;rsquo;t buy it back within a year, it passes permanently to the buyer; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t go back to you in the Year of Jubilee. 31Houses in villages without walls, however, are like property in the open country; you can buy them back, and they revert to you in the Year of Jubilee. 32In Levitical towns, Levites have an ongoing right to buy back their houses, 33and their houses revert to them in the Year of Jubilee. Their houses are their possessions among the Israelites, 34but they can&amp;rsquo;t sell pastures attached to their towns; they&amp;rsquo;re permanent possessions. 35&amp;quot;If citizens become poor, sustain them like foreigners or temporary residents so they can keep living with you. 36Don&amp;rsquo;t charge them interest; respect God. 37Don&amp;rsquo;t lend them your silver or food at interest. 38I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God that brought you out of Egypt to give you Canaan and be your God. 39&amp;quot;If citizens become so poor that they sell themselves to you, don&amp;rsquo;t subject them to slavery. 40Till the Year of Jubilee, treat them like hired hands or foreigners with you. 41Then they and their offspring will go back to their family and ancestors&amp;rsquo; property. 42They&amp;rsquo;re my servants that I brought out of Egypt. Don&amp;rsquo;t sell them in the slave trade. 43Don&amp;rsquo;t rule them harshly; respect me. 44You can acquire male and female slaves from pagan nations,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-26&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 26&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t make idols, set up images or sacred pillars, or put stone figurines in your country to bow to. 2Keep my Sabbaths and reverence my sanctuary. 3If you follow my statutes and keep my commandments, 4I&amp;rsquo;ll give you rain in its season so the ground will grow crops and the trees will bear fruit. 5Threshing time will last till grape harvest, and grape harvest will last till planting season. You&amp;rsquo;ll have plenty to eat, and you&amp;rsquo;ll live securely in your country. 6I&amp;rsquo;ll grant peace so you can lie down without feeling afraid. I&amp;rsquo;ll eliminate dangerous wild animals from the land, and no sword will pass through your land. 7You&amp;rsquo;ll chase your enemies, and they&amp;rsquo;ll fall by your sword. 8Five of you will chase 100, and 100 will chase 10,000. 9I&amp;rsquo;ll favor you, multiply you, and confirm my covenant with you. 10You&amp;rsquo;ll eat the old supply and clear out the old because of the new. 11I&amp;rsquo;ll live among you 12and be your God, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be my people. 13I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God that brought you out of Egypt so you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be their slaves. I broke the bars of your yoke and made you walk erect. Punishment for Disobedience 14&amp;quot;If you don&amp;rsquo;t carry out these commandments, 15if you reject my statutes, abhor my ordinances, and break my covenant, 16I&amp;rsquo;ll bring panic over you. Consumption and fever will make your eyes sink in and depress you. You&amp;rsquo;ll plant your seed for nothing because your enemies will eat it. 17I&amp;rsquo;ll oppose you, and your enemies will strike you down. The ones that hate you will rule you. You&amp;rsquo;ll run when nobody&amp;rsquo;s chasing. 18&amp;quot;If you still don&amp;rsquo;t obey me, I&amp;rsquo;ll punish you seven times over 19and break your strong pride. I&amp;rsquo;ll make your sky like iron and your ground like bronze. 20You&amp;rsquo;ll spend your strength for nothing, because the ground won&amp;rsquo;t grow crops and the trees won&amp;rsquo;t bear fruit. 21&amp;quot;If you&amp;rsquo;re still hostile toward me and refuse to obey, I&amp;rsquo;ll strike you with plague seven times over. 22I&amp;rsquo;ll let wild animals loose among you to terrorize your children, destroy your livestock, and decimate your population till your roads are deserted. 23&amp;quot;If you&amp;rsquo;re still hostile toward me and don&amp;rsquo;t return to me, 24I&amp;rsquo;ll be hostile toward you and strike you seven times over. 25I&amp;rsquo;ll bring on you a sword to avenge the covenant. When you retreat to your towns, I&amp;rsquo;ll send a plague and deliver you to your enemies. 26When I break your staff of bread, ten women will bake your bread in one oven and bring it to you in rations. You&amp;rsquo;ll eat and not be satisfied. 27&amp;quot;If you still don&amp;rsquo;t obey me, but act hostile toward me, 28I&amp;rsquo;ll act hostile toward you and punish you seven times over. 29You&amp;rsquo;ll eat your sons and daughters. 30I&amp;rsquo;ll destroy your high places, cut down your incense altars, and heap your remains on the remains of your idols because I&amp;rsquo;ll abhor you. 31I&amp;rsquo;ll lay waste your towns too, and make your sanctuaries desolate. I won&amp;rsquo;t smell your pleasing aromas. 32I&amp;rsquo;ll make the land so desolate it will appall your enemies that settle in it. 33I&amp;rsquo;ll scatter you among the nations and draw out a sword after you as your land grows desolate and your towns become ruins. 34&amp;quot;The land will enjoy its Sabbaths during its desolation while you&amp;rsquo;re in your enemies&amp;rsquo; country. 35It will get the rest it didn&amp;rsquo;t get on the Sabbaths while you were living in it. 36You that are left, I&amp;rsquo;ll make lose heart in your enemies&amp;rsquo; countries. The sound of a blown leaf will chase you. You&amp;rsquo;ll run when nobody&amp;rsquo;s chasing you. 37You&amp;rsquo;ll stumble over each other and fall like you&amp;rsquo;re running from the sword, even though nobody&amp;rsquo;s chasing you. You won&amp;rsquo;t have the strength to stand up to your enemies. 38You&amp;rsquo;ll perish among the nations that consume you. 39You that are left will rot away in your enemies&amp;rsquo; countries because of your ancestors&amp;rsquo; sin. Future Restoration 40&amp;quot;If you confess your and your ancestors&amp;rsquo; sin in your unfaithfulness and hostility toward me—41if your uncircumcised heart becomes humble and you make amends for your sin, 42I&amp;rsquo;ll remember my covenant with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob as well, and I&amp;rsquo;ll remember the land. [43] 44I won&amp;rsquo;t reject you so completely that I destroy you and break my covenant with you. 45I&amp;rsquo;ll remember the covenant with your ancestors that I brought out of Egypt in front of the nations so I could be your God. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leviticus 27</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cyv/leviticus/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;leviticus-chapter-27&#34;&gt;Leviticus Chapter 27&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Again Yahveh told Moses, &amp;ldquo;When people make difficult vows, appraise them before Yahveh. 3Appraise a male that&amp;rsquo;s 20 to 60 years old at 20 oz of silver 50 shekels of the sanctuary 4and a female at 12 oz 30 shekels of silver. 5Appraise a male that&amp;rsquo;s 5 to 20 years old at 8 oz 20 shekels and a female at 4 oz 10 shekels. 6Appraise a male that&amp;rsquo;s a month to 5 years old at 2 oz 5 shekels of silver and a female at 1⅕ oz 3 shekels. 7Your appraisal for males above 60 will be 6 oz 15 shekels and 4 oz 10 shekels for females. 8But if you can&amp;rsquo;t afford that appraisal, you can have the priest appraise you according to your means. 9If it&amp;rsquo;s an animal you can offer to Yahveh, it will be holy. 10You won&amp;rsquo;t exchange it good for bad or vice versa. If you do exchange it, both it and the substitute become holy. 11-12But if it&amp;rsquo;s a ceremonially unclean animal, which people don&amp;rsquo;t offer to Yahveh, the priest will appraise it. His appraisal is final. 13But if you ever want to buy it back, add a fifth to the appraisal. 14&amp;quot;If you consecrate your house to Yahveh, the priest will appraise it. His appraisal is final. 15But if you want to buy it back, add a fifth to the appraisal. 16&amp;quot;If you consecrate part of your field to Yahveh, the priest&amp;rsquo;s appraisal will be in proportion to the seed for sowing it: 11 bushels 1 homer of barley at 20 oz 50 shekels of silver. 17If you consecrate your field in relation to the Year of Jubilee, it will stand according to the priest&amp;rsquo;s appraisal. 18If you consecrate your field after the Year of Jubilee, the priest will calculate the price in proportion to the years till the next Year of Jubilee and deduct it from its appraisal. 19If you ever want to buy it back, add a fifth to the appraisal. 20If you sell it, you can&amp;rsquo;t buy it back. 21When it reverts in the Year of Jubilee, it will be holy to Yahveh like a field set apart and will belong to the priest. 22If you consecrate a field to Yahveh that you&amp;rsquo;ve bought—not a part of your own property—23then the priest will calculate for it the amount of your valuation as holy to Yahveh. 24In the Year of Jubilee, the field will go back to its original owner. 25Appraisals will be in shekels of the sanctuary (20 gerahs per shekel). 26&amp;quot;However, you can&amp;rsquo;t consecrate firstborn animals—ox or sheep; they already belong to Yahveh. 27But if it&amp;rsquo;s a ceremonially unclean animal, you can buy it back according to its appraised value plus a fifth. If you don&amp;rsquo;t buy it back, the priest will sell it for its appraised value. 28&amp;quot;Nevertheless, nothing devoted to Yahveh—man, animal, or field—can be sold or bought back. It&amp;rsquo;s most holy. 29No one that&amp;rsquo;s been sentenced to death can be ransomed. Execute that person. Laws About Tithes 30&amp;quot;Set apart to Yahveh a tenth of the land, produce of the ground and fruit of the trees. 31If you want to buy back part of that tenth, add a fifth to it. 32Set apart to Yahveh every tenth member of a herd and flock. 33Whether it&amp;rsquo;s good or bad, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to substitute for it. If you do, both it and the substitute become holy, and you can&amp;rsquo;t buy them back.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
