<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christian Ministry 101 on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/christian-ministry-101/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christian Ministry 101 on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/christian-ministry-101/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BEGINNING A MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/beginning-a-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/beginning-a-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BEGINNING A MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Physical Matters&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Changes of address on all mailings: periodicals, credit cards, friends and relatives you want to keep in contact with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Car tags, car inspection&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Utilities: garbage, gas and electric, water and sewage, phone. Count on expenses associated with these items, especially any deposits that may be involved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D.&#x9;Medical Care: family doctor, dentist, hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;E.&#x9;Places to do business with:  grocery stores and the like, car repairs, banks&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONCLUDING A MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/concluding-a-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/concluding-a-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CONCLUDING A MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Under most circumstances when you take a ministry of any kind, do it as an open-ended experience.  Give no thought to how long you will be there, because you should not be interested in climbing ladders so much as serving Christ. Your motive is to “bloom where you are planted” rather than look past what you are doing in order to discover “greener pastures” elsewhere. As a primary motive if you focus on moving up the ladder, you are probably not so much concerned to improve the upcoming situation as to improve your own standing. It is a form of “building on another man’s foundation.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DISTINCTIVES OF A RURAL MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/distinctives-of-a-rural-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/distinctives-of-a-rural-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DISTINCTIVES OF A RURAL MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Intergenerational&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rural people are more intergenerational than city people. Their normal activities are less age-graded because there are fewer people and because family ties are generally stronger. As a result, they are less likely to warm up to the idea of putting their small children in a nursery during Sunday school and church. The children themselves are less accustomed to being left with a sitter while the parents go to some purely adult activity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERVIEWING FOR A MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interviewing-for-a-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interviewing-for-a-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERVIEWING FOR A MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9; General Considerations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past, extreme positions have been taken on both sides of the “preacher competition” issue in hiring a minister. At one extreme is the practice of bringing in three or four ministers for “trial sermons” and then taking a vote on which one the people want. At the other extreme is the policy ministers may advocate that search committees look at only one candidate at a time and decide yes or no before passing on to the next one. It seems curious that ministers want to look at several congregations and decide which one to take, but they do not want a congregation looking at more than one minister.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAKING APPLICATION FOR MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/making-application-for-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/making-application-for-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MAKING APPLICATION FOR MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Cover Letter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Applying for a ministry can have two written aspects beyond any (a) verbal contacts with the prospective church by phone or otherwise. The first is a (b) cover letter and the second is a (c) resumé. In the cover letter you can indicate how you became aware of the opening and why you are interested in the job. Depending on the circumstance, you may reinforce your interest in that ministry by relating you background briefly as well as the reason for your sense of calling to ministry. You may include some statement about your family’s commitment with you to this work. Giving a general statement of faith helps those who review applications know where you are doctrinally. They will want to know about your view of the nature and work of Christ, the nature of scripture, the process of salvation, and so forth. Christian churches will be interested in your commitment to the restoration plea. Giving your concept of ministry may also be useful. In the statement of background applicants may give an account of their conversion, especially if they became Christians after their high school years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PERSONAL HABITS A MINISTER NEEDS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/personal-habits-a-minister-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/personal-habits-a-minister-needs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PERSONAL HABITS A MINISTER NEEDS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TO BE DEVELOPING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Cleanliness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Body odor and bad breath are highly offensive in American culture–more so than in many parts of the world. This situation is particularly bad because (a) people will rarely say anything to you about it. They may hold back until it makes them angry and then when they say something about it, it is probably too late for you to do anything about it in order to keep it from ruining your ministry. These problems are also bad because (b) you do not smell your own bad breath or your own body odor. Consequently, you have to do what it takes to prevent these problems even though you do not sense any need to do so. (c) Once your clothes and shoes have picked up body odor, you may not be able to get it out of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PERSONAL QUALITIES A MINISTER NEEDS TO BE DEVELOPING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/personal-qualities-a-minister-needs-to-be-developing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/personal-qualities-a-minister-needs-to-be-developing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PERSONAL QUALITIES A MINISTER NEEDS TO BE DEVELOPING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The qualities for a good minister begin with the virtues of good Christian living. In preparation becoming a Christian minister, you cannot bypass Christian virtues and start with the developing professional skills or learning religious information. After all, ministry exists for the express purpose of bringing people into a pattern of living that is more appropriate to, and consistent with, relationship to God and other people. Below is a suggestive list of personal qualities that ministers particularly need to have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROFESSIONAL SKILLS A MINISTER NEEDS TO BE DEVELOPING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/professional-skills-a-minister-needs-to-be-developing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/professional-skills-a-minister-needs-to-be-developing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROFESSIONAL SKILLS A MINISTER NEEDS TO BE DEVELOPING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ministry calls for a wider range of useful skills than most vocations do. Obviously you cannot be top notch in everything useful to this calling, but the more skills you have at your disposal the less you limit your ministry. Within the congregation you need to surround yourself with people who can do what you are weak at or do not have time do. You also need to develop a network of people to whom you can make referrals. Needless to say, some churches and communities do not have people who can do some of the things you need help with. In those cases, play to your strengths and do the best you can with weaker areas, improving them as you have opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOCIAL SKILLS A MINISTER NEEDS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/social-skills-a-minister-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/social-skills-a-minister-needs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOCIAL SKILLS A MINISTER NEEDS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TO BE DEVELOPING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Expressing caring&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of us are not as good as we could be at communicating to people that we care about them. We can use a number of techniques for expressing love. They include taking time to listen, to talk about seemingly purposeless things, to identify with people’s interests and problems, looking them in the eye– focusing on them, smiling, giving a firm handshake or a hug, using touch, doing something for them without being asked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDENT PREACHING MINISTRIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/student-preaching-ministries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/student-preaching-ministries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDENT PREACHING MINISTRIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For many years a number of congregations have used upper division students as preachers. The churches are small (30-75 in attendance) and rural or small town with memberships that reflect their surroundings. They are spread out across the northeastern sector of the state. Student ministries can be Sunday-only, weekend, or living at the church in a parsonage and commuting to school. The arrangements you enter into depend on your age, marital status, the financial condition of the particular church, and the kind of mix you want between practical experience and academic preparation. If a student takes a ministry in one of these situations, he needs to view his work as a learning experience of service in the church more than a leadership position. There are a number of benefits that such an opportunity can give him. For one thing, he can develop his skill at preaching. In fact, preaching is his main job and other responsibilities fill in around it. Attached to preaching is the discipline of preparing messages on a regular basis, which entails finding topics for sermons, organizing thoughts so they can be presented understandably, and gaining experience at actually making the public oral presentation. Since most of you have not done much like this before, developing preaching skill will probably take quite a bit of emotional energy the first few times until you gain some confidence and sense some acceptance by the congregation. You will probably feel “out of place” for a while since a good number of the people will be old enough to be your parents and grandparents. So the best course is to approach this task as sharing a message addressed to yourself that you are letting them overhear. You will not be “telling them what to do”; you are too young for that–if indeed you ever get old enough to look at preaching that way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMPACT OF INTERPERSONALISM ON</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-impact-of-interpersonalism-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-impact-of-interpersonalism-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMPACT OF INTERPERSONALISM ON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE METHODS AND MANNER OF MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;In Anticipation of Ministry&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ministry to other people proceeds out of a relationship to God and then out of relationship to them. Vertical and horizontal interpersonal relationship reinforce each other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general, personal relationship with people must precede spiritual ministry to them. Authenticating yourself has to occur before are likely to let you lead them or turn to you when they need help. A minister is best able to influence other people if first they are convinced that he can be influenced by them—if he is listening rather than just telling or commanding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
