<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Reviews on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/book-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Reviews on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/book-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comments by Virgil Warren on “Disorder and Revolt” in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-by-virgil-warren-on-disorder-and-revolt-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-by-virgil-warren-on-disorder-and-revolt-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authentic Cosmopolitanism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by R. J. Snell &amp;amp; Steven D. Cone&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Stone-Campbell Conference; April 2017)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chapter 4, entitled “Disorder and Revolt,” addresses the impact of sinning on thinking as one aspect of depraved behavior generally. Perverted thought amidst general depravity connects in turn with university, most relevantly to formal Christian university as part of the over-all Christian enterprise mandated in the Great Commission (cosmopolitanism).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The approach traces the depravity phenomenon from elements in the thought of Aristotle through Aquinas to Lonergan, taking notice of Augustine and the Reformed tradition along the way—without necessarily appealing to the hypostatic and legal elements of their theories of sin as distinct from phenomenology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>February 2, 1998</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/february-2-1998/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/february-2-1998/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;February 2, 1998&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1600 Stewart Court&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Manhattan, KS 66502&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Bill Baker&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;St. Louis Christian College&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1360 Grandview Drive&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Florissant, MO 63033&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bill,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enclosed is a copy of my review of James Torrance’s book.  Apologies again for the long delay.  Along with the review, please find a copy of an essay on evangelism as integrated with interpersonalism.  Let me know either way whether you think you can or cannot use the unsolicited material.  It will likely go up on the Internet with the other essays if there is no other avenue of publication for it.  Both the book review and the essay are on a floppy disk that I have sent along with the hard copy.  The disk is in MicroSoft Word 97; if you can use it from the disk, it may save you some editing time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
