<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HEBREWS on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/categories/hebrews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HEBREWS on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/categories/hebrews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF HEBREWS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-hebrews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-hebrews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF HEBREWS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the only canonical New Testament epistle without any statement of authorship (John’s three epistles do not very clearly identify their author either.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;has the most extensive use of the Old Testament numerically and proportionately of any New Testament book. Every major point in the book is based on an Old Testament reference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the only New Testament book to develop the priesthood theme in connection with Jesus&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EXTERNAL TESTIMONY TO THE AUTHORSHIP OF HEBREWS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/external-testimony-to-the-authorship-of-hebrews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/external-testimony-to-the-authorship-of-hebrews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EXTERNAL TESTIMONY TO THE AUTHORSHIP OF HEBREWS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Presentation of Evidence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Early Christian writers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eastern tradition&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;Direct statement regarding authorship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1)&#x9;Pantaenus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order of time, Pantaenus is the earliest witness to the Eastern Tradition about the authorship of Hebrews. He flourished about A.D. 180 as president of the catechetical school in Alexandria, Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photius says that Pantaenus heard men who had seen the apostles.   Eusebius tells us that Julian, bishop of Alexandria, sent Pantaenus eastward as far as India as a missionary because of his piety and scholarship (Ecclesiastical History 5:10). Alexander, bishop of Alexandria about A.D. 212, highly commended him. (See Eusebius’ Ecclesiastical History 6:14.) Eusebius himself and Jerome also speak of him as a learned, influential Christian leader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HEBREWS AND THE ALEXANDRIAN ORIGIN OR DESTINY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/hebrews-and-the-alexandrian-origin-or-destiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/hebrews-and-the-alexandrian-origin-or-destiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HEBREWS AND THE ALEXANDRIAN ORIGIN OR DESTINY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The only reasons for associating Hebrews with Alexandria are that (1) the earliest favorable attestation comes from there and that (2) it supposedly uses the allegorical method of interpretation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philo joined Greek philosophy and Jewish revelation by allegorical method. He stood at&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the head of a line of scholars who did the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hebrew writer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allegorical interpretation is like using the Acts 27 trip to Rome as an allegory about life with its rough seas, throwing sins overboard, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HEBREWS’ RHETORICAL STYLE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/hebrews-rhetorical-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/hebrews-rhetorical-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HEBREWS’ RHETORICAL STYLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hebrews uses the Old Testament text more than any other New Testament book does. (Matthew is next.) It has the longest Old Testament quotation of any book in the New Testament: 8:8-12 &amp;gt; Jeremiah 31:31-34.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author makes every major point from an Old Testament quotation. There is a deliberate exegetical pattern (especially Psalm 110:4). This pattern represents profound insight in exegesis rather than allegorical method of interpretation, as some suppose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERNAL EVIDENCE ON CRITICAL MATTERS: HEBREWS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/internal-evidence-on-critical-matters-hebrews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/internal-evidence-on-critical-matters-hebrews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERNAL EVIDENCE ON CRITICAL MATTERS: HEBREWS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Authorship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hebrews makes no claim to authorship. Certain points about the book may have&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;relevance to the authorship question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;2:3-4: “How will we escape if we neglect such a great salvation, which having at the first been spoken through the Lord, was confirmed to us by them that heard, God also bearing witness with them both by signs and wonders and by many powers and by gifts of the Holy Spirit according to his own will.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPRETATION IN HEBREWS CONTRASTED TO</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/interpretation-in-hebrews-contrasted-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/interpretation-in-hebrews-contrasted-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPRETATION IN HEBREWS CONTRASTED TO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE ALLEGORICAL METHOD OF PHILO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historical backgrounds are important because they illuminate scripture. They often confirm the biblical record and may help prove its trustworthiness on things that can be tested. So we view historical backgrounds as a valuable resource. This presentation, however, stresses another observation. Like all sources of information, historical backgrounds misused can harm rather than help biblical studies. It can detract from hermeneutical and apologetic concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SKETCH OF PROPOSITIONS AND PRESUPPOSITIONS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/sketch-of-propositions-and-presuppositions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/sketch-of-propositions-and-presuppositions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SKETCH OF PROPOSITIONS AND PRESUPPOSITIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;on the use of 2 Samuel 7:14 in Hebrews 1:5b&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;While 2 Samuel 7:14 must refer to Solomon because Solomon so understood it (1 Kings 6:11-13; 8:17-21), it cannot refer exclusively to him since the context speaks of an eternal seed (2 Samuel 7:16).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II.&#x9;By the nature of the case, there can be only one universal eternal kingdom.  So Daniel 2:(35) 44; Psalm 89:27 + 4, 36; and therefore the universal kingdom of Psalm 2 (first quotation) and the eternal kingdom of Psalm 110 (last quotation) must all refer to the same thing as the eternal kingdom of 2 Samuel 7 (as well as Psalm 89; Isaiah 9; etc.).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
