<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CREATION on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/creation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CREATION on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/creation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A RATIONALE FOR THE STRUCTURE OF GENESIS 1:1-2:3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/a-rationale-for-the-structure-of-genesis-11-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/a-rationale-for-the-structure-of-genesis-11-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A RATIONALE FOR THE STRUCTURE OF GENESIS 1:1-2:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Précis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author of Genesis 1:1-2:3 presents a picture of creating earth and sky from the time viewpoint of Israel’s founding. Specific creative acts appear in a set analogous to the intended six-day-week-plus-Sabbath that God established at the same time for his special people. The presentation is topical without concern for exact sequence, duration, parallel entry, completeness, and necessary divisions. The sequence of creation itself can differ from the sequence of the presentation about creation in a sensible order. Analogy describes the connection between the creation of National Israel and the presentation about the creation of the universe (Isaiah 43:1ff). Inspiration guides and protects the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIG LESSONS IN GENESIS 1-3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/big-lessons-in-genesis-1-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/big-lessons-in-genesis-1-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BIG LESSONS IN GENESIS 1-3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;The God-universe distinction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II.&#x9;The people-animal distinction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;III.&#x9;The man-woman distinction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IV.&#x9;The origin of the cosmos (vs. eternal matter)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;V.&#x9;The good-evil distinction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VI.&#x9;The goodness of the material universe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VII.&#x9;People as responsible beings&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VIII.&#x9;The origin of evil: If all that is not God has been created, then evil can begin outside&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;of God in secondary agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IX.&#x9;The origin of suffering&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPRETING THE CREATION NARRATIVE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/interpreting-the-creation-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/interpreting-the-creation-narrative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPRETING THE CREATION NARRATIVE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An Interpretative Approach&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1 uses the week as a literary device for organizing a topical presentation of God’s prominent creative activities. It is without strict concern for sequence and duration. While Genesis 1 uses the week as a literary device, Genesis 2-3 uses parable to organize important truths around historical persons. It is not necessarily that the events of Genesis 3 led to new effects after sin occurred; these characteristics of mankind and nature were put in place by God from the start. God knew beforehand that people would sin, and built factors into their situation that would limit the extent to which they could rebel and factors that would force them to recognize their dependent situation. This approach derives from Genesis several fundamental beliefs about God, people, nature, sin, and God’s connection to these aspects of the human circumstance. It stresses meaning (theological perspectives) over time (historical account).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MANAGING THE CREATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/managing-the-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/managing-the-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANAGING THE CREATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God maintains contact with his creation and control over it. Especially in contrast to deism, God did not create the universe and leave it to operate entirely according to built-in laws for self-perpetuation. God is actively involved with what he made. There is built-in NATURAL LAW such as gravity that apparently operates “on its own” now that God has set it up to work in a particular way. But in addition, there is SUPERNATURAL INTERVENTION, where God enters the natural process and brings about results that would not have occurred had he not intervened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OVERVIEW OF CREATION AND EVOLUTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/overview-of-creation-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/overview-of-creation-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OVERVIEW OF CREATION AND EVOLUTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Preliminary Definitions and Concepts&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;God: label for ultimate reality&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;God’s relationship to the universe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natural imminence: God is not distinct in kind from the universe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*2.&#x9;Natural transcendence: God is distinct from the universe. Overlapping in immanence has to do with availability; overlapping in kind has to do with personal creation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Change&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Modification: change without increasing the number of factors.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*2.&#x9;Complexification: change with increasing the number of actors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROPOSED RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN GENESIS 1:1 AND 1:2-2:3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/proposed-relationship-between-genesis-11-and-12-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/proposed-relationship-between-genesis-11-and-12-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROPOSED RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN GENESIS 1:1 AND 1:2-2:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.   &#x9;Genesis 1:1, Caption for the Creation Account (Hebrew construct form)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this view, Genesis 1:1 does not necessarily provide a statement of absolute origin in the “book of beginnings.” (Day 4 may cover the origin of the heavens.) This view leaves open the possibility of eternal matter and, when in combination with a parabolic understanding of Genesis 1-11, poses no difficulties for a theistic evolutionary system. Observations against this view, however, include the following:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROVIDENCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/providence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/providence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROVIDENCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God controls his universe and directs its functioning by the operations diagramed below. (1) Reality combines freedom and determinism with freedom occurring inside the determinism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we add advancing time, providence takes on the form of a “broad arrow,” which can represent the idea that (2) history is going somewhere rather than moving in a circle, that is, just moving back and forth among the old options. History is going somewhere intentionally rather than merely eventuating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DOCTRINE OF CREATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-doctrine-of-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-doctrine-of-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DOCTRINE OF CREATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The doctrine of creation is unique to the Judaeo-Christian and Islamic heritages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Biblical Materials&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Genesis 1:1; 2:4; Isaiah 45:18; note other statements about “made” heaven and&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;earth (Acts 4:24; 14:15; 17:24-25; Exodus 20:11; Psalm 146:6; Hebrews 1:2;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Revelation 14:7; 1 Peter 3:5)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;John 1:1-3: “All things were made through him, and without him nothing was&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;made that was made.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Colossians 1:15-17: “In [the Firstborn] all things were created in the heavens&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE MOSES-TIME VIEWPOINT OF GENESIS-DEUTERONOMY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-moses-time-viewpoint-of-genesis-deuteronomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-moses-time-viewpoint-of-genesis-deuteronomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MOSES-TIME VIEWPOINT OF GENESIS-DEUTERONOMY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presentation in Genesis is from Moses’ viewpoint in time and place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The narrowing scope from Genesis 1:1 till Moses’ time in history. See herein “The Structure of Genesis-Deuteronomy.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comment about the Sabbath. 2:1-3 comes from a day when Sabbath observance had been enacted as a memorial of the exodus (Deuteronomy 5:12-15). The purpose of the Sabbath was to serve as a memorial of the exodus, when God “created” Israel (Isaiah 43:15, “I am Yahveh, your Holy One, the Creator of Israel . . .”); the manner of observance correlated with God’s creative work: as a rest, weekly, at the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
