<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SCRIPTURE on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/scripture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SCRIPTURE on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/scripture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>“GOD-BREATHEDNESS” AS THE CHARACTER OF SCRIPTURE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/god-breathedness-as-the-character-of-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/god-breathedness-as-the-character-of-scripture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“GOD-BREATHEDNESS” AS THE CHARACTER OF SCRIPTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A series of words has traditionally stated from various angles the character of scripture in positive and negative terms. The list begins with the biblical expression in 2 Timothy 3:16, which translates literally as (1) “God-breathed.” The rather unhappy term in popular vogue for this passage is “inspired”; so “inspiration” becomes the corresponding noun for getting at the concept Paul expressed in the text. “Inspire,” however, does not properly picture the idea because it (a) creates the image of breathing into something the characteristic the word denotes—as when God “breathed into Adam the breath of life” and he became something more than he was. Such imagery limits the meaning of the text to what can add to something already there. The word picture in God-breathedness is that of “exhaling” the thing itself, so the scripture is regarded as issuing directly from God’s mouth. Scripture stands apart from all other writing by being viewed as God’s direct speaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 TIMOTHY 3:16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/2-timothy-316/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/2-timothy-316/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 TIMOTHY 3:16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;πᾶσα γραφὴ θεόπνευστος καὶ ὠφέλιμος&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pāsa graphē theopneustos kai ōphelimos&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Variables in the English wording of this verse&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;all vs. every&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;scripture vs. writing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;commas vs. no commas [restrictive vs. non-restrictive adjective “God-breathed”]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;placement of is&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and vs. also&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two wordings seem to fit the context, which shows Paul&amp;rsquo;s evident concern to encourage Timothy in a good thing:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) “All/every scripture [is] God-breathed and profitable . . .”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON CREEDS AND RELATED MATTERS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-creeds-and-related-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-creeds-and-related-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON CREEDS AND RELATED MATTERS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture alone (sola scriptura) means using the Bible as the sole authority for Christian belief and practice. It sets aside other normative sources for the Christian faith: creeds, tradition, apocryphal works, ecclesiastical pronouncements, additional primary literature beyond the sixty-six books of the canon, and persons claiming inner light and special revelation. The fundamental issue is not doctrinal error as much as practical authority. Going beyond the apostolic witness does open up the possibility—even likelihood—of false doctrine; but even if it did not, these other sources are disregarded. Other writings may have devotional value and helpful insight, but they do not determine what Christians are to believe and practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FIVE MODELS FOR COMPLETELY RELIABLE SCRIPTURE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/five-models-for-completely-reliable-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/five-models-for-completely-reliable-scripture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FIVE MODELS FOR COMPLETELY RELIABLE SCRIPTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do not need to decide between the “theories of inspiration” to understand how scripture came to have the character of “God-breathedness” (2 Timothy 3:16). As we can judge from scripture itself, God operated in more than one way in producing scripture. The models of origin may be organized according to what God specially gave to his human spokesmen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God gave the words. Probably no one holds the dictation theory of inspiration strictly understood, even though people often suppose that Christians have that explanation for the origin of the Bible. It might apply to a few cases, notably the Ten Commandments, which in the first copy were written by the finger of God (Exodus 31:18; cp. also Daniel 5:25-28). In this format God operates in a significantly positive fashion (Daniel 5).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PASSAGES RELEVANT TO INERRANCY*</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/passages-relevant-to-inerrancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/passages-relevant-to-inerrancy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PASSAGES RELEVANT TO INERRANCY*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psalm    19:7      &#x9;“The Law of the Lord is perfect, converting the soul.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;119:42   &#x9;“Your Law is truth.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;119:160&#x9;“The sum of your word is truth, and every one of your righteous&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ordinances endures forever. “&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew  4:4      &#x9;“Man will not live by bread alone, but by every word that proceeds out of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God’s mouth.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5:18     &#x9;“Till heaven and earth pass away, not one dot or one tittle will in any way&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROCEDURES CONSISTENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/procedures-consistent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/procedures-consistent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROCEDURES CONSISTENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WITH A COMPLETELY RELIABLE TEXT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, a totally reliable text in principle represents the guiding characteristic of “scripture.” On the other hand, a certain amount of variability may happen in the manner by which biblical writings originated and passed down. Two assumptions underlie the suggestions below. (a) We need not invoke the supernatural as long as natural means can accomplish the purposes. God does not generally do for people what they can do for themselves. (b) The concern is reliability of the information, not prescription of forms (words).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NEW TESTAMENT’S WITNESS TO THE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-new-testaments-witness-to-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-new-testaments-witness-to-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NEW TESTAMENT’S WITNESS TO THE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OLD TESTAMENT’S INSPIRATION*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Direct Assertion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Specific scriptures attributing the Old Testament to the Holy Spirit&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Passages mentioning the human author&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;Acts 1:16-20 (Psalm 69:25; 109:8)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.&#x9;Matthew 22:43 (Luke 24:44; Mark 12:36 [Psalm 110:1])&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c.&#x9;Acts 4:25-26 (Psalm 2:1-2)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d.&#x9;Acts 28:25-27 (Isaiah 6:9-10); cp. 1 Peter 1:10-12 (general reference)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Passages not mentioning the human author&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;Hebrews 3:7-11 (Psalm 95:7-11)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
