<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ORDINATION on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/ordination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ORDINATION on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/ordination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON ORDINATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-ordination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-ordination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON ORDINATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Across Christendom ordination has had a variety of meanings. The most extreme position has been that (1) ordination validates the “administration” of sacraments. Unless a duly qualified clergyman presides, the sacrament is invalid in much the same way that a wedding performed by a person “off the street” would not be recognized by the state. A Justice of the Peace must be duly appointed to perform wedding ceremonies as an agent of the state. In this view, ordination is for theological reasons. The clergy concept is part of the larger idea that grace flows through the church, that is, through those who validly stand as executors of divine administration. It is a legal conceptualization like that of Justice of the Peace, validity being based on “apostolic succession.” Legal administration of grace, however, is a contradiction of terms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORDINATION: WHO AND WHOM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ordination-who-and-whom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ordination-who-and-whom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ORDINATION: WHO AND WHOM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ordination to ministry involves three considerations: (1) the understanding of New Testament offices and ministry, (2) the New Testament meaning of ordination, and (3) the meaning attached to ordination by society today and by the state.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Who should be ordained?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the standpoint of the church, the New Testament does not evidence an understanding of ordination that corresponds with the traditional clergy concept. Ordination does not validate a person’s ministry. It does not bestow the right to preach, “administer sacraments,” pronounce absolution. The only ordination observed in the New Testament is an appointment to specific tasks. If done, ordination today simply commends an individual to the general Christian community. It indicates that in the ordaining congregation believes the person has the character, abilities, and skills appropriate to the calling. That has been sufficient to qualify him also for the rights vouchsafed to religious leaders by the state. So ordination has been a matter of expediency rather than necessity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORIENTATION TO ORDINATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/orientation-to-ordination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/orientation-to-ordination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ORIENTATION TO ORDINATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Ordination is for the one ordained.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ordination is for impressing on the person ordained the importance of his calling. People set aside time for things that are important. By setting aside time to concentrate on what it means to minister, the body of believers shows the person their regard for that calling. Ordination provides a time to be impressed with the significance of the “ministry of reconciliation,” as Paul called it (2 Corinthians 5:18-21).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
