<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MINISTRY on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/categories/ministry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MINISTRY on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/categories/ministry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A MINISTER AND HIS FAMILY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/a-minister-and-his-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/a-minister-and-his-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A MINISTER AND HIS FAMILY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New Testament qualifications for leadership deal not only with the person himself, but also with his domestic situation. Being qualified for ministry includes, then, how your wife and kids act and how you all relate to one another. The ongoing relationship within your family follows the reciprocal pattern characteristic of all social relationships. How you treat them affects how they treat you, and how they treat you affects how you treat them. Consequently, the burden does not fall just on the minister in the family. The emphasis here is, however, is on your side of the interaction. It stresses the fact that your relationship toward them is preliminary to how they subsequently enhance or detract from your ministry. Their actions do not wholly reflect how you have first loved them and their actions reflect other influences in their past and present lives, but there is a correlation between the quality of how you treat them and how they conduct themselves as a result.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A MINISTER’S FILING SYSTEM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/a-ministers-filing-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/a-ministers-filing-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A MINISTER’S FILING SYSTEM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will not remember! That is the bottom line when it comes to libraries and filing systems. The efficiency with which a minister discharges his responsibilities is directly proportionate to the degree of ready access he has to his materials. The quality of his work is determined by the extent to which he can organize and preserve the information that he generates and that comes to him from a wide range of sources. A person needs to organize his files because he will remember only a small percent of what he learns and needs to know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ARRANGING A MINISTER&#39;S SCHEDULE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/arranging-a-ministers-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/arranging-a-ministers-schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ARRANGING A MINISTER&amp;rsquo;S SCHEDULE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The Nature and Purpose of a Schedule&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A minister&amp;rsquo;s schedule is not structured so automatically as most people&amp;rsquo;s schedules are. Larger congregations with multiple staffs may foster developing a schedule pattern more like that of a business, but most churches do not lend themselves naturally to such an arrangement. Ministry is highly open-ended with many different kinds of activities. Furthermore, it varies so much from day to day and week to week and can involve all hours of the day and night. The “work-week hours” do not form so definite a block of time. For this last reason a minister should deliberately schedule his professional and non-professional activities. If he does not scheduling deliberately, before long the professional side of his work can take over the non-professional (or conceivably vice versa) and become overwhelming, or the professional part can get lopsided in favor of certain things–things wherein skills are best and interests are greatest or things in which “the tyranny of the urgent/immediate” takes over. Under these conditions laying out a minister’s schedule is both difficult and essential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEGINNING A MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/beginning-a-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/beginning-a-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BEGINNING A MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Physical Matters&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Changes of address on all mailings: periodicals, credit cards, friends and relatives you want to keep in contact with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Car tags, car inspection&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Utilities: garbage, gas and electric, water and sewage, phone. Count on expenses associated with these items, especially any deposits that may be involved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D.&#x9;Medical Care: family doctor, dentist, hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;E.&#x9;Places to do business with:  grocery stores and the like, car repairs, banks&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BENEDICTIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/benedictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/benedictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BENEDICTIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The benediction slot appears at the end of the service. In popular usage “benediction” has become a label for the closing prayer, but a benediction is really a pronouncement of blessing on those assembled for worship or on God as a final statement of praise. The biblical texts given below can serve as a word of praise to God or a word of blessing on the worshipers as they are about to leave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CALLS TO WORSHIP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/calls-to-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/calls-to-worship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CALLS TO WORSHIP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Call to worship is a slot often used at the beginning of services designed to inspire awe, reverence, humility before God. Such services are more contemplative than celebrative, more vertically than horizontally oriented. The call to worship is a shorter scripture portion intended to focus attention of all participants and to prepare for a prayer of invocation. Other scripture readings may be longer in keeping with their purpose to inform, inspired, comfort and the like. The following texts are suggestions; there are may others that may be used for this purpose. The Book so Psalms is particularly useful as a resource for calls to worship. The texts below appear in vertical format so that notations can be made about subject matter, occasions when used, and the like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIAN LIBERAL ARTS EDUCATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/christian-liberal-arts-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/christian-liberal-arts-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIAN LIBERAL ARTS EDUCATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People have different reasons for getting an education. (a) Education for knowledge is a German emphasis. The goal is accuracy and completeness in any field of study. If anything develops out of that knowledge, well and good; but the stress falls on knowledge for its own sake and the love for learning as such.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What has been a British emphasis is (b) education for culture. The goal consists of fulfilling expectancies associated with a person’s position in the social structure. Cultured people should know their way around in the world, be able to converse intelligently about what goes on there, and be able to place themselves and their society in the proper historical niche. The upper classes serve as tradition bearers who give stability to the present social structure. As a primary function, education reinforces social position.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIAN MINISTRY INTERNSHIP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/christian-ministry-internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/christian-ministry-internship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIAN MINISTRY INTERNSHIP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.   Initial Report&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Identify the church/organization in which the internship is being done.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Identify/describe the position/role you have for the internship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;In a brief statement, identify the purpose/overall goal if the internship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D.&#x9;Describe/outline the regular duties and responsibilities you have in the internship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;E.&#x9;Outline/list the educational objectives of your internship (“As a result of this internship, I will be able to . . . “).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHURCH POLICIES ON WEDDINGS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/church-policies-on-weddings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/church-policies-on-weddings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHURCH POLICIES ON WEDDINGS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this church’s facilities what officiating personnel may be used? May weddings be performed by persons other than a paid staff member? Is there a church receptionist in charge of scheduling, planning, and supervising rehearsals and ceremonies?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May musicians other than the congregation’s regular organist(s) or pianist(s) play for a wedding? May the couple bring in outside soloists and musicians who have their own instruments? Are there any limitations on what kinds of instrumentation or music styles may be used for the wedding ceremony and reception time?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communion Meditation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/communion-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/communion-meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Communion Meditation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;092715&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Only One Qualified&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The greatest responsibility goes to the most capable person. The hardest work leads to the highest honor. Those superlatives come together at this table. God could not assign Christ’s role to just anyone, because it had such widespread importance; there could be no risk of failure. No one else qualified.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We acknowledge here that we’re benefactors of special greatness. He took the perfect life and produced a perfect life in the human condition. He took life in the human condition and produced a perfect life in the face of the worst opposition. So it’s no off-handed sign of appreciation that we give a nod to on our way to other things. It’s a focal point of worship, a culmination of prepared hearts and minds and wills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMUNION MEDITATIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/communion-meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/communion-meditations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMUNION MEDITATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sources of communion meditation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recorded events that accompanied his death-resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deliberately working backwards from the sermon. There are so many appropriate facets of this event. Finding natural connections with the subject of the day’s sermon triggers some thoughts that might not come to mind otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Festival cycle: The religious year provides associations with communion observance. Later, the meaning of the Lord’s Supper may come back to mind by what people encounter after gathered worship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMUNION SCRIPTURES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/communion-scriptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/communion-scriptures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMUNION SCRIPTURES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many aspects to the total meaning of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Supper, and there are many ways of applying those meanings to Christian life and worship. As a result any number of scripture passages connect naturally to the experience of coming around the Lord&amp;rsquo;s table with fellow Christians. Below are several portions of scripture that belong among those that speak of matters relevant to this worship experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psalms 23&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONCLUDING A MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/concluding-a-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/concluding-a-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CONCLUDING A MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Under most circumstances when you take a ministry of any kind, do it as an open-ended experience.  Give no thought to how long you will be there, because you should not be interested in climbing ladders so much as serving Christ. Your motive is to “bloom where you are planted” rather than look past what you are doing in order to discover “greener pastures” elsewhere. As a primary motive if you focus on moving up the ladder, you are probably not so much concerned to improve the upcoming situation as to improve your own standing. It is a form of “building on another man’s foundation.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DISTINCTIVES OF A RURAL MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/distinctives-of-a-rural-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/distinctives-of-a-rural-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DISTINCTIVES OF A RURAL MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Intergenerational&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rural people are more intergenerational than city people. Their normal activities are less age-graded because there are fewer people and because family ties are generally stronger. As a result, they are less likely to warm up to the idea of putting their small children in a nursery during Sunday school and church. The children themselves are less accustomed to being left with a sitter while the parents go to some purely adult activity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDUCATION FOR USE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/education-for-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/education-for-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EDUCATION FOR USE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Teaching Task&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bible colleges adapt higher education in partial preparation for ministry. On the one hand, they obviously differ from “secular” institutions by presenting courses from a Christian perspective. Unlike seminaries, Bible colleges begin ministry preparation at the undergraduate level. They differ also from Christian liberal arts institutions by including mostly those courses that have the greatest transfer to ministry, by teaching them with a view to ministering, by reducing the emphasis on liberal arts as such, and by including practical courses. On the other hand, Bible colleges do not try to become simply vocational-technical schools. In both practical and conceptual aspects of the curriculum, a governing principle for Bible colleges is “education for use.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For All the Saints Who from Their Labors Rest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/for-all-the-saints-who-from-their-labors-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/for-all-the-saints-who-from-their-labors-rest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For All the Saints Who from Their Labors Rest&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;William Walsham How&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For all the saints who from their labors rest,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who Thee by faith before the world confessed,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thy name, O Jesus, be forever blest.  Alleluia!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou wast their rock, their fortress, and their might;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou, Lord, their captain in the well-fought fight;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou, in the darkness dread, their one true light.  Alleluia!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O may Thy soldiers, faithful, true, and bold,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FORMAL PREPARATION FOR MINISTRY: THE 18-30 YEARS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/formal-preparation-for-ministry-the-18-30-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/formal-preparation-for-ministry-the-18-30-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FORMAL PREPARATION FOR MINISTRY: THE 18-30 YEARS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graduating someone with a ministry degree does not necessarily increase the number of personnel in permanent ministry. Several factors contribute to significant attrition, especially during the early years of ministry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes opportunities come for pursuing other interests that are more financially rewarding. More often, however, leaving the ministry stems from disillusionment, lack of fulfillment, inability to get people to respond to one’s leadership, frustration, little sense of progress. Adjusting the manner of preparation will not eliminate the problem, but adjustments in the way we conceive of ministry preparation will preserve for service a greater number of ministerial graduates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GROUP PRAYER PATTERNS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/group-prayer-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/group-prayer-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GROUP PRAYER PATTERNS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayers may be spontaneous or planned, vocal or silent, informal or formal depending on the setting and the desired impact. Group prayer corporately acknowledges our creaturely dependence on God and our fundamental orientation toward him. Group prayer may take various forms but any form we choose needs to evoke an I-You experience with God. Prayer should be sincere and &amp;ldquo;real,&amp;rdquo; and therefore should avoid deadness born of unnatural formalism, perfunctory language full of clichés and trite expressions, vain repetitions, and the like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HANDLING CRITICISM IN THE MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/handling-criticism-in-the-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/handling-criticism-in-the-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HANDLING CRITICISM IN THE MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We reserve the word criticism for illegitimate fault-finding. It means something negative because it has negative cause, result, or both. Criticism is evil because it does not edify of others but aggrandizes self. A critic’s conscious motive may be to hurt or offend, and the person criticized feels that hurt. Criticism does not build up anyone or improve the situation. It is not done the same way constructive efforts are done. Many times critics do not go to the person himself, but air their complaints to third parties or in public situations. They make their statements in condemnatory tone of voice and in ways which imply their doubt that the other person to be willing or able to make adjustments that correct. Their aim is to evaluate rather than ameliorate–to condemn rather than to help&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interim Ministry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/interim-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/interim-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interim Ministry&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May 24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr._______,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week _______, who takes care of speaker arrangements here at _________, forwarded to me your letter requesting information on interim ministry. Since coming to the faculty in 1977, I have been involved in interim ministries in Kansas, Nebraska, and Missouri almost constantly for sixteen years. Earlier while teaching at The Cincinnati Bible Seminary (1971-1974), I did this kind of work in several churches in Indiana, Ohio, and Kentucky. On the accompanying pages I have noted some values that I have seen come to the congregation from those kinds of experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/interment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/interment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;020317&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to suppose that we stand here at the end of a life to pay our “final respects” at a “final resting place.” Existence appears to be over because life is over. What remains seems to be dealing with the impact on us who remain. The happiness of good memories combines with the sadness of losing the source of that happiness. Sunshine on this cold winter’s day pictures our conflicted feelings. We have only to wait till time turns the winter of our loss to the summer of new things to come in life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERVIEWING FOR A MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/interviewing-for-a-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/interviewing-for-a-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERVIEWING FOR A MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9; General Considerations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past, extreme positions have been taken on both sides of the “preacher competition” issue in hiring a minister. At one extreme is the practice of bringing in three or four ministers for “trial sermons” and then taking a vote on which one the people want. At the other extreme is the policy ministers may advocate that search committees look at only one candidate at a time and decide yes or no before passing on to the next one. It seems curious that ministers want to look at several congregations and decide which one to take, but they do not want a congregation looking at more than one minister.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISSUES THAT UNDERLIE MARRIAGE POLICIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/issues-that-underlie-marriage-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/issues-that-underlie-marriage-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ISSUES THAT UNDERLIE MARRIAGE POLICIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is marriage a Christian institution or a social/racial/human one?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deciding that marriage is a racial institution means that a minister may conceive of himself as serving primarily an agent of the state rather than the church. In that case he feels freer to perform weddings for non-Christians or even for mixed couples. A minister may still want to consider whether a “minister’s” performing the wedding has the appearance of religious approval of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IT IS GOOD TO REMEMBER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/it-is-good-to-remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/it-is-good-to-remember/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IT IS GOOD TO REMEMBER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the grand cycle of life, only four or five generations of humanity are accessible to our experience at any one moment in history. Those earlier men and women we must remember, and so we set aside this day to reflect on their contribution to our welfare.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is important to remember because doing so fosters appreciation. None of us are self-made people. Those who went before set the range of possibilities that we choose among and now enjoy. Were it not for their sacrifices and labors, we would not have the freedoms we prize or many of the possessions we own. Surely we shape our own lives and mold their direction by our efforts, but those efforts are largely exerted within the options that have been handed down to us. We owe our ancestors a great debt of gratitude, and we inherit an obligation in turn to leave our legacy—to respect, cherish, and protect the privileges inherited our forefathers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IV.  PRACTICAL MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/iv-practical-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/iv-practical-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IV.  PRACTICAL MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;Administration&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leadership&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Church organization&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By-laws&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Filing system outline&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Records:  new-member records, non-member records, calling records, geographical records, demographic records, counseling records, legal documents, attendance records, sermon records, committee meeting minutes, talent records, library records, records for income tax, recommendations written, important correspondence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Benevolence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Education&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;History of Christian Education&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Education work&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philosophy of Christian education&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teaching methods:  team teaching&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teaching age groups:  nursery, children, youth, adults&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jennifer Chantell Wenzl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/jennifer-chantell-wenzl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/jennifer-chantell-wenzl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Chantell Wenzl&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Wenzls, I want to thank you for this wonderful demonstration of support for the family and for such an overwhelming expression of love for Jenny in this time of intense sorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grief is our response to loss, and the deepest loss is the loss of a person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not so much what a person does for/with us, but who she is as expressed through her actions toward us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KEEPING CURRENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/keeping-current/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/keeping-current/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KEEPING CURRENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. In World Affairs&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Radio and television&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Local and national newspapers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Subscribe to Christianity Today (religious world news), Christian Century (religious world news).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D. Get on the mailing lists of missionary agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. In Practical Ministry Skills&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Subscribe to Leadership, Pulpit Helps, Discipleship, Christian Standard, and the like.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Attend seminars (National Pastors Conference), ministerial gatherings, conventions (North American Christian Convention, National Missionary Convention, preaching conventions associated with several Bible colleges)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LANGUAGE, EXEGESIS, AND THEOLOGY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/language-exegesis-and-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/language-exegesis-and-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LANGUAGE, EXEGESIS, AND THEOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biblical languages, texts, and topics naturally combine for study that undergirds personal growth and Christian ministry. Acquaintance with the original languages of scripture raises options not suggested by the English, eliminates possibilities English wording might allow, and gives access to additional study tools. Furthermore, a knowledge of Greek and Hebrew facilitates the evaluation of points made by other commentators on the biblical text, a great advantage to ministers, because we are constantly called upon to deal with doctrinal issues purportedly based on “the original.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LEADING SONG SERVICES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/leading-song-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/leading-song-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LEADING SONG SERVICES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ways of Structuring Song Services&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Begin with a passage of scripture, an event, a parable, etc. Hymnals normally have a scripture index that indicates the connection between hymns and scripture passages. Before each song the leader or someone in the assembly can read a passage that correlates with the overall theme or the distinctive point of the upcoming song.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pick a theme and sing songs that fit with it.  Hymnals have topical indices in the back that facilitate finding songs in that hymnal which belong to many relevant topics. If the body of the hymnal is topically arranged, you can turn to that section of the hymnal and sing one song after another. This format is useful especially if the whole service is dedicated to singing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAKING APPLICATION FOR MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/making-application-for-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/making-application-for-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MAKING APPLICATION FOR MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Cover Letter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Applying for a ministry can have two written aspects beyond any (a) verbal contacts with the prospective church by phone or otherwise. The first is a (b) cover letter and the second is a (c) resumé. In the cover letter you can indicate how you became aware of the opening and why you are interested in the job. Depending on the circumstance, you may reinforce your interest in that ministry by relating you background briefly as well as the reason for your sense of calling to ministry. You may include some statement about your family’s commitment with you to this work. Giving a general statement of faith helps those who review applications know where you are doctrinally. They will want to know about your view of the nature and work of Christ, the nature of scripture, the process of salvation, and so forth. Christian churches will be interested in your commitment to the restoration plea. Giving your concept of ministry may also be useful. In the statement of background applicants may give an account of their conversion, especially if they became Christians after their high school years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MEMORIAL DAY ADDRESS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/memorial-day-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/memorial-day-address/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MEMORIAL DAY ADDRESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The saying goes, “The future of an event belongs to the event.” Let me explain. When something happens, it does not just happen disconnected from what is around it. Out of it flows what it leads to. That fact opens up a way to measure the importance of the occurrence. How long do its effects last? How many people does it impact? How much capacity does it have for its consequences to grow as time goes on?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memorial Day Meditation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/memorial-day-meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/memorial-day-meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Memorial Day Meditation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Morrison,  Lutheran, Lillis Catholic,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vermillion Christian Church&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One obvious feature of this cemetery is the stones erected here. But they are not just stones; they have names on them: Dowd, Donahy, Kramer, Bramhall, Nocks. These markers focus our attention on specific individuals. They are like icons on a computer. When we click on them, they open up to a vast reservoir of memories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are sorrows we shared, hardships we endured together, disappointments we knew, happy times at the kitchen table, and honest labor in that field north of the house. These stones mean something because they direct our attention on a mother, a neighbor, a friend, someone else connected to us. In this cemetery people have indeed remembered, as shown by the flowers beside many graves and as shown by your presence in this gathering today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PASSAGE USEFUL FOR BAPTISM MEDITATIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/passage-useful-for-baptism-meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/passage-useful-for-baptism-meditations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PASSAGE USEFUL FOR BAPTISM MEDITATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statements of the Great Commission&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 28:18-20; Mark 16:15; Luke 24:44-49; Acts 1:8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Accounts of Baptism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 8:4-8 + 12-13&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;8:26-39&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9:10-19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10:34-48&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:12-15a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:25-34&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(19:1-7)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;22:6-16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;26:12-20&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Texts that describe John’s baptism or give accounts of Johannine baptism are not particularly appropriate for Christian baptisms. The meaning of the two baptisms is different as illustrated by the baptizing in the name of Christ those disciples of John Paul found in Ephesus (Acts 19:1-7). Reading the account of Jesus’ own baptism would not be natural for this same reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PERSONAL HABITS A MINISTER NEEDS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/personal-habits-a-minister-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/personal-habits-a-minister-needs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PERSONAL HABITS A MINISTER NEEDS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TO BE DEVELOPING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Cleanliness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Body odor and bad breath are highly offensive in American culture–more so than in many parts of the world. This situation is particularly bad because (a) people will rarely say anything to you about it. They may hold back until it makes them angry and then when they say something about it, it is probably too late for you to do anything about it in order to keep it from ruining your ministry. These problems are also bad because (b) you do not smell your own bad breath or your own body odor. Consequently, you have to do what it takes to prevent these problems even though you do not sense any need to do so. (c) Once your clothes and shoes have picked up body odor, you may not be able to get it out of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PERSONAL QUALITIES A MINISTER NEEDS TO BE DEVELOPING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/personal-qualities-a-minister-needs-to-be-developing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/personal-qualities-a-minister-needs-to-be-developing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PERSONAL QUALITIES A MINISTER NEEDS TO BE DEVELOPING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The qualities for a good minister begin with the virtues of good Christian living. In preparation becoming a Christian minister, you cannot bypass Christian virtues and start with the developing professional skills or learning religious information. After all, ministry exists for the express purpose of bringing people into a pattern of living that is more appropriate to, and consistent with, relationship to God and other people. Below is a suggestive list of personal qualities that ministers particularly need to have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROFESSIONAL SKILLS A MINISTER NEEDS TO BE DEVELOPING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/professional-skills-a-minister-needs-to-be-developing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/professional-skills-a-minister-needs-to-be-developing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROFESSIONAL SKILLS A MINISTER NEEDS TO BE DEVELOPING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ministry calls for a wider range of useful skills than most vocations do. Obviously you cannot be top notch in everything useful to this calling, but the more skills you have at your disposal the less you limit your ministry. Within the congregation you need to surround yourself with people who can do what you are weak at or do not have time do. You also need to develop a network of people to whom you can make referrals. Needless to say, some churches and communities do not have people who can do some of the things you need help with. In those cases, play to your strengths and do the best you can with weaker areas, improving them as you have opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raymond F. Schober</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/raymond-f-schober/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/raymond-f-schober/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raymond F. Schober&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raymond F. Schober, 71, of Vermillion, Kansas, died Saturday evening, February 20, 1999, at the hospital in Onaga, Kansas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Schober owned and operated Schober’s Service in Vermillion since 1955 and Dutch’s Place since 1965.  From 1980 to 1994 he was a field engineer for Associated Engineers.  He served on a U. S. Navy minesweeper in the Pacific Theater during World War II.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born on March 14, 1927 in Rossville, Kansas, to Fred and Mary Schober, Raymond later attended school in Centralia.  He was a member of the Vermillion Christian Church, American Legion Post #257, VFW Post #1359, and was active in the city council of Vermillion.  He married Daisy Willard on December 24, 1950, in Westmoreland.  She survives of the home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Showers of Blessings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/showers-of-blessings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/showers-of-blessings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Showers of Blessings&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;041766&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunday. PRAYER. “The prayer of a good person accomplishes a lot.” God gives liberally to us if we ask in faith for blessings that accord with his will. He is approachable. When we pray, he will not rebuke us for being so presumptuous as to ask him for something. (Read James 1:5-6; 4:3; 5:16b; Matthew 7:7.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Monday. WORK. When we pray for spiritual blessings, there are things we must do. The condition for the fulfillment of any appropriate request is “If you do your part.” There is no value in asking God for new clothes if we’re not willing to work to buy them. Prayer never serves as a shortcut or substitute for work. (Read James 2:14-26.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOCIAL SKILLS A MINISTER NEEDS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/social-skills-a-minister-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/social-skills-a-minister-needs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOCIAL SKILLS A MINISTER NEEDS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TO BE DEVELOPING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Expressing caring&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of us are not as good as we could be at communicating to people that we care about them. We can use a number of techniques for expressing love. They include taking time to listen, to talk about seemingly purposeless things, to identify with people’s interests and problems, looking them in the eye– focusing on them, smiling, giving a firm handshake or a hug, using touch, doing something for them without being asked.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STEWARDSHIP PASSAGES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/stewardship-passages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/stewardship-passages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STEWARDSHIP PASSAGES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Samuel 24:24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Chronicles 29:14-17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psalms 24:1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ecclesiastes 5:10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 6:2-4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6:19-21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10:8b (7-10)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;19:16-26&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark 12:41-44 (= Luke 21:1-4)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luke 3:11-12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6:27-35&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18:28-30&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 2:44-47a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:32-35&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11:27-30&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20:35&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romans 12:3-6a, 8b&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 4:7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6:19b-20a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15:54-16:8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 8-9: a number of passages in these two chapters are useful for stewardship &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;thoughts. Among them are particularly 8:2-3, 5, 7-8, 14-15; 9:6-7, 10-11, &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;12-13&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 1:4-14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:28&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Straight Thinking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/straight-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/straight-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Straight Thinking&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;101567&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;COMMITTED TO CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunday. You committed yourself and your life to Christ by obeying God’s plan of salvation to the extent of being baptized. You must not submit to the temptation of the teen years when the lure of sins is especially strong. If you forsake the love you had for Christ at the first, you relinquish the hope you have through him in the end. (Read Revelation 2:4, 5, 7.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDENT PREACHING MINISTRIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/student-preaching-ministries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/student-preaching-ministries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDENT PREACHING MINISTRIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For many years a number of congregations have used upper division students as preachers. The churches are small (30-75 in attendance) and rural or small town with memberships that reflect their surroundings. They are spread out across the northeastern sector of the state. Student ministries can be Sunday-only, weekend, or living at the church in a parsonage and commuting to school. The arrangements you enter into depend on your age, marital status, the financial condition of the particular church, and the kind of mix you want between practical experience and academic preparation. If a student takes a ministry in one of these situations, he needs to view his work as a learning experience of service in the church more than a leadership position. There are a number of benefits that such an opportunity can give him. For one thing, he can develop his skill at preaching. In fact, preaching is his main job and other responsibilities fill in around it. Attached to preaching is the discipline of preparing messages on a regular basis, which entails finding topics for sermons, organizing thoughts so they can be presented understandably, and gaining experience at actually making the public oral presentation. Since most of you have not done much like this before, developing preaching skill will probably take quite a bit of emotional energy the first few times until you gain some confidence and sense some acceptance by the congregation. You will probably feel “out of place” for a while since a good number of the people will be old enough to be your parents and grandparents. So the best course is to approach this task as sharing a message addressed to yourself that you are letting them overhear. You will not be “telling them what to do”; you are too young for that–if indeed you ever get old enough to look at preaching that way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SURPRISED AT SUNRISE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/surprised-at-sunrise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/surprised-at-sunrise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SURPRISED AT SUNRISE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Surprised at sunrise were two women,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;two women making their way to the tomb of a friend,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the tomb of a revered teacher,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;two women who came to perform an unwelcome task&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;that somebody had to do,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;two women who had watched in helpless horror the &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;                dying agony of a man condemned by jealousy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the mock trials and the gruesome visages that followed, they had had uncounted hours for the sights of that Friday to become fixed in their minds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEMPTATIONS IN THE MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/temptations-in-the-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/temptations-in-the-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TEMPTATIONS IN THE MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Temptations appeal to two basic aspects of our nature–physical and social. Temptation addresses legitimate physical drives in an effort to get us to fulfill them in illegitimate ways either in excess or in the wrong way. In the social dimension, temptations come through evil example, social pressure, social reinforcement, even misunderstood good example. Temptations also play on our ignorance, taking advantage of what we do not know, misreading God&amp;rsquo;s invisibility of God as absence so as to remove that curb our impulses, and turning our viewpoint of consciousness into selfishness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE GOAL OF A “THEOLOGICAL” EDUCATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-goal-of-a-theological-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-goal-of-a-theological-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE GOAL OF A “THEOLOGICAL” EDUCATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People have different reasons for pursuing an education. (a) Education for knowledge has been considered a German emphasis. The goal consists of accuracy and completeness in any field of study. If anything develops out of that knowledge, well and good; but the stress falls on knowledge for its own sake and the love for learning as such.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What has been regarded as a British emphasis is (b) education for culture. The goal here consists of fulfilling expectancies associated with one’s position in the social structure. Cultured people should know their way around in the world, be able to converse intelligently about what goes on there, and be able to place themselves and their society in the proper historical niche. The upper classes serve as tradition bearers who contribute to the stability of the present social structure. As a primary function, education reinforces social position.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMPACT OF INTERPERSONALISM ON</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-impact-of-interpersonalism-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-impact-of-interpersonalism-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMPACT OF INTERPERSONALISM ON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE METHODS AND MANNER OF MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;In Anticipation of Ministry&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ministry to other people proceeds out of a relationship to God and then out of relationship to them. Vertical and horizontal interpersonal relationship reinforce each other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general, personal relationship with people must precede spiritual ministry to them. Authenticating yourself has to occur before are likely to let you lead them or turn to you when they need help. A minister is best able to influence other people if first they are convinced that he can be influenced by them—if he is listening rather than just telling or commanding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE LEGACY OF DORCAS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-legacy-of-dorcas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-legacy-of-dorcas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE LEGACY OF DORCAS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 9:35-42&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What We Learn from Experience&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Peter came to Joppa that day, they began showing him the garments and coats Dorcas had made. I venture to say, they did not do that because the garments were nicely made, although no doubt they were. I venture to say, they did not do that because she was a good seamstress, although she probably was. I venture to say, they did not do that because the garments were expensive, although she may have used the best material she could find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE MINISTER’S PERSONAL POLICIES ON WEDDINGS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-ministers-personal-policies-on-weddings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-ministers-personal-policies-on-weddings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MINISTER’S PERSONAL POLICIES ON WEDDINGS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Specific Questions About Policies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Will you perform ceremonies only for members of the congregation where you serve?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your congregation has an especially fine facility, you will have more requests from people outside the church to have their weddings there. Many larger churches have more than one sanctuary. Besides the main auditorium they may have a chapel that seats a hundred or so and maybe even a prayer chapel that will accommodate a dozen or so. Consequently, the church is ideally equipped to handle private weddings, moderate-sized ceremonies, as well as large gatherings. Under those conditions the facility meets the needs of practically all possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PASSING OF JAIRUS’ DAUGHTER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-passing-of-jairus-daughter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-passing-of-jairus-daughter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PASSING OF JAIRUS’ DAUGHTER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 8:49-55)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Her name is not given, but she was twelve. The father, a ruler of the synagogue, did what desperate fathers do: he went to find the only help he knew, because she was ill and very weak. At the earnest urging of Jairus, our Lord turned that day from present labors and walked beside a worried man toward the object of his care.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THOUGHTS ON INTERIM MINISTRIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/thoughts-on-interim-ministries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/thoughts-on-interim-ministries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THOUGHTS ON INTERIM MINISTRIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An interim ministry buys time for a congregation to find a capable minister suited to its needs. That factor alone is a significant gain among churches that practice local autonomy because they have no official centers for organizing information about the needs of congregations and information about potential ministers. Besides word of mouth, some Christsian colleges are about the only places that make a deliberate effort to put ministers and congregations in contact with one another. Having more time is helpful also because it sometimes takes a while to check out references thoroughly, conduct interviews, arrange visits to the church, and make arrangements to close a previous ministry and relocate. When school-age children are involved, it is often not convenient or advisable to move during semesters; waiting till the end of a term might mean a three- or four-month delay. Sometimes ministers’ spouses have employment that is not easy to leave quickly. There may be property that has to be sold. Having time takes the pressure off so a church does not feel they must take the first possibility that presents itself; they can wait for the right man for a few months even, if need be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRUTH AND EDUCATION IN A CHRISTIAN WORLDVIEW</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/truth-and-education-in-a-christian-worldview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/truth-and-education-in-a-christian-worldview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRUTH AND EDUCATION IN A CHRISTIAN WORLDVIEW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the trial of Jesus, Pilate remarked, “What is truth?” Jesus had just explained that he came into the world to “bear witness to the truth.” Interestingly, the truth issue does occupy the central reason for the personal incarnation of God into the world of human persons. It establishes the agenda for the followers of Christ, for “education that is Christian,” and for ministry preparation through an education process. As goes the view of truth, so goes the nature of education and the process of preparing for that education of the world that is called evangelism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Do You Have That You Didn’t Receive?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/what-do-you-have-that-you-didnt-receive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/what-do-you-have-that-you-didnt-receive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What Do You Have That You Didn’t Receive?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lord, today we consider our place in the larger scheme of things, and so acknowledge you, first of all, as the beginning of all else besides you, the sustainer of all you have made, and the basis for the hope that stretches out before us. Amen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the question: What do you have that you didn’t receive? Obviously, you have labored long and hard in the process of life. Yet what you have contributed could not have been done without the possibilities and opportunities already in place and the abilities passed down to you. In the countryside around, lie fields where you and your neighbors work the ground, plant the seed, harvest the crops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YOUTH MINISTER SEARCH COMMITTEE: SUMMARY REPORT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/youth-minister-search-committee-summary-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/youth-minister-search-committee-summary-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YOUTH MINISTER SEARCH COMMITTEE: SUMMARY REPORT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;______________ ____________ Church&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 28, ____&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Principles of the Search&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The numbered items below came into the candidate’s description either from the committee that developed the job description, from the elders as a group before the search committee was appointed, from the search committee itself, or from informal comments made by other people and passed along to the search committee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These factors go beyond the assumed traits expected for youth ministers: good character, good social skills, able to establish rapport with young people, biblically sound, intelligent in ways that pertain to ministry work and doctrinal understanding, balanced in being an activist and a learner, articulate; willing to listen to peers, parents, teens, and other church workers; spiritually mature, a finisher, a planner who does not try to “work out of his hip pocket,” flexible, self-motivated, a team player, someone who can balance fun with seriousness and knows when and how much of each is appropriate, someone that does not have large ego needs, someone who can trust without being gullible, a natural leader who can let other people do things, a person with a sense of propriety in talk and dress as well as personal associations particularly with those of the opposite sex, someone who can keep confidentialities. Many of these traits are degree matters, which means they strengthen over time. Some of them are difficult to assess before the fact; for now, they can be addressed by comments from references, inferred from basic behavior, and assumed in mutual trust until experience can give verification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
