<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Numbers on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Numbers on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; On the first day, second month, second year after they left Egypt, Yahveh told Moses at Sinai in the Tent of Meeting, 2&amp;quot;Take a census by families. Count the men 320 years old and up that can go to war. You and Aaron count them by armies. 4To help you, appoint one man from each tribe as head of his ancestor&amp;rsquo;s house. 5They&amp;rsquo;ll stand with you: from Reuben, Elizur Ben-Shedeur;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Israelites will camp with the banners of their families facing the Tent of Meeting. 3-4On the east side of the Tabernacle, Judah will camp by its standard—the army of Nahshon (74,600). 5-6Issachar will camp next to him—the army of Nethanel (54,400). 7-8Zebulun will camp with its leader Eliab (57,400). 9The Judah camp totals 186,400. It will move out first. 10-11&amp;quot;On the south side of the Tabernacle, Reuben will camp by its standard—the army of Elizur (46,500). 12-13Simeon will camp next to him—the army of Shelumiel (59,300). 14-15Gad will camp with its leader Eliasaph (45,650). 16The Reuben camp totals 151,450. It will move out second. 17&amp;quot;Then the Tent of Meeting will move out with the Levites in the middle of the camps. 18-19&amp;quot;On the west side of the Tabernacle, Ephraim will camp by its standard—the army of Elishama (40,500). 20-21Manasseh will camp next to him—with its leader Gamaliel (32,200). 22-23Benjamin camps next—the army of Abidan (35,400). 24The Ephraim camp totals 108,100. It will move out third. 25-26&amp;quot;On the north side of the Tabernacle, Dan will camp by its standard—the army of Ahiezer (62,700). 27-28Asher will camp next to him—with its leader Pagiel (41,500). 29-30Naphtali camps next—with its leader Ahira (53,400).  31The Dan camp totals 157,600. It will move out last.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Generations of Aaron and Moses When Yahveh Spoke to Moses on Mount Sinai Duties of Levites&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; The sons of Aaron were Nadab, the firstborn, Abihu, Eleazar, and Ithamar—3anointed and ordained as priests. 4In the Wilderness of Sinai, Nadab and Abihu died from offering before Yahveh fire different from what he&amp;rsquo;d commanded. They didn&amp;rsquo;t have any children, so Eleazar and Ithamar served as priests during Aaron&amp;rsquo;s lifetime.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses and Aaron, 2&amp;quot;Count the descendants of Kohath by families 330-50 years old who serve in the Tent of Meeting. 4This is the work of Kohath&amp;rsquo;s descendants with the most holy objects. 5When the camp sets out, Aaron and his sons will go in and take down the screen and cover the Ark of Testimony with it. 6They&amp;rsquo;ll lay a dolphin-skin covering over it, spread a pure blue cloth over it, and insert its poles. 7Over the table for the Bread of the Presence, they&amp;rsquo;ll spread a pure blue cloth and put on it the dishes, spoons, sacrificial bowls, liquid offering jars, and the continual bread that&amp;rsquo;s on it. 8They&amp;rsquo;ll spread a scarlet cloth over them, cover it with a dolphin-skin covering, and insert its poles. 9Then they&amp;rsquo;ll take a blue cloth and cover the lampstand, its lamps, snuffers, trays, and oil jars. 10They&amp;rsquo;ll put it and its utensils in a dolphin-skin covering and put it on the carrying bars. 11They&amp;rsquo;ll spread a blue cloth over the gold altar, and cover it with a dolphin-skin covering, and insert its bars. 12They&amp;rsquo;ll take the utensils for service in the sanctuary, put them in a blue cloth, cover them with a dolphin-skin covering, and put them on the carrying bars. 13Then they&amp;rsquo;ll take away the ashes from the altar and spread a purple cloth over it. 14They&amp;rsquo;ll put its utensils on it: the firepans, forks, shovels, and basins. They&amp;rsquo;ll spread a dolphin-skin covering over it and insert its poles. 15&amp;quot;After Aaron and his sons cover the holy objects and furnishings, the Kohathites will come to carry them so they won&amp;rsquo;t touch the holy objects and die. 16&amp;quot;Eleazar is responsible for the olive oil for the light, the fragrant incense, the daily grain offering, and anointing oil—the Tabernacle and everything in it, the sanctuary and its furnishings.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses, 2&amp;quot;Tell Israel to send outside the camp any leper, anybody with a discharge, anyone ceremonially unclean because of a dead person. 3Send out male or female so they won&amp;rsquo;t defile their camp where I live.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; They did that. 5-6Yahveh told Moses to say to Israel, &amp;ldquo;When a man or woman sins against Yahveh by sinning against another person, 7the offender will confess and pay restitution plus a fifth to the one that was wronged. 8If there&amp;rsquo;s no relative to receive the restitution, it goes to Yahveh for the priest in addition to the ram offered for the atonement. 9The priest will also receive every contribution associated with the holy gifts people offer. 10Everybody&amp;rsquo;s holy gifts belong to the priest. The Test for Adultery [11] 12-13&amp;quot;If a husband suspects his wife has been unfaithful, 14-15he can take her to the priest. He&amp;rsquo;s to take .11 bushel .1 ephah of barley meal as an offering for her. He won&amp;rsquo;t pour oil on it or put frankincense on it because it&amp;rsquo;s a grain offering of jealousy, a reminder of sin. 16&amp;quot;The priest will have her stand in Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s presence. 17He&amp;rsquo;ll take holy water in a clay jar, take some dust from the floor of the Tabernacle, and put it in the water. 18He&amp;rsquo;ll let her hair down loose and place the memorial grain offering in her hands. The priest will have in his hand the bitter water that brings a curse. 19He&amp;rsquo;ll have her take an oath, &amp;lsquo;If no man has had intercourse with you while under your husband&amp;rsquo;s authority, be immune to this bitter water that brings a curse. 20But if you&amp;rsquo;ve defiled yourself with another man,&amp;rsquo; [21then he&amp;rsquo;ll have her swear the oath] &amp;lsquo;may Yahveh make you a curse among your people. 22This water will make your abdomen swell and your thigh waste away.&amp;rsquo; She&amp;rsquo;ll say, &amp;lsquo;True. True.&amp;rsquo; 23&amp;quot;The priest will write these curses on a scroll and wash them off into the water. 24Then he&amp;rsquo;ll have her drink the water. 25The priest will take the grain offering of jealousy from her, wave it in front of Yahveh, and take it to the altar. 26He&amp;rsquo;ll take a handful of the memorial grain offering and offer it up in smoke on the altar. Afterward he&amp;rsquo;ll have her drink the water. 27If she&amp;rsquo;s been unfaithful, the water will cause bitterness. Her abdomen will swell, her thigh will waste away, and she&amp;rsquo;ll become a curse among her people. 28If she hasn&amp;rsquo;t defiled herself, she&amp;rsquo;ll be free and can conceive children. 29&amp;quot;That&amp;rsquo;s the law of jealousy 30when a husband suspects his wife has gone astray. 31The husband won&amp;rsquo;t be responsible, but she&amp;rsquo;ll be held guilty.&amp;rdquo; The Nazirite Vow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to say to Israel, &amp;ldquo;When men or women take a Nazarite vow to dedicate themselves to Yahveh, 3they must abstain from wine and strong drink and from vinegar made from them. They can&amp;rsquo;t drink grape juice or eat fresh grapes or raisins. 4They&amp;rsquo;re not to eat anything a grapevine produces from seeds to skin.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; During that time, they have to let their hair grow. 6-7They can&amp;rsquo;t make themselves ceremonially unclean by going near a dead body even for a parent or sibling that dies. [8] 9&amp;quot;If someone dies suddenly beside them and defiles their dedicated head, they&amp;rsquo;ll shave it the same day and on the seventh day. 10The eighth day, they&amp;rsquo;ll take two turtledoves or young pigeons to the priest at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting. 11The priest will offer one as a sin offering and the other as a burnt offering; that will purify them from their defilement. That same day they&amp;rsquo;ll reconsecrate their head, 12dedicate to Yahveh their days as a Nazirite, and take a male lamb a year old for a guilt offering. Their previous days of separation are void. 13&amp;quot;When Nazirites finish their time of separation, they&amp;rsquo;ll take an offering to the entrance to the Tent of Meeting 14and present it to Yahveh: one male lamb a year old without defect for a burnt offering, one ewe lamb a year old without defect for a sin offering, one ram without defect for a peace offering, 15and a basket of cakes of fine flour without yeast mixed with oil and wafers without yeast spread with olive oil, along with their grain offering and liquid offerings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The day Moses finished setting up the Tabernacle, he anointed and consecrated its furnishings, the altar, and its utensils. 2The leaders in Israel (besides the numbered men) made an offering 3and brought it to the Tabernacle: 6 covered carts and 12 cattle, a cart for each pair of leaders and an ox for each leader. 4Yahveh told Moses, 5&amp;quot;Accept these things for use in the Tent of Meeting. Give them to each Levite according to his service.&amp;quot; 6Moses accepted the carts and cattle and gave them to the Levites: 72 carts and 4 cattle to Gershon&amp;rsquo;s descendants to match their service, 8and 4 carts and 8 cattle to Merari&amp;rsquo;s descendants to match their service—as directed by Ithamar Ben-Aaron. 9He didn&amp;rsquo;t give any to Kohath&amp;rsquo;s descendants because their service was with the holy objects, which they carried on their shoulders. 10The leaders offered the dedication offering for the altar when it was anointed; they offered it in front of the altar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses 2to have Aaron put up the 7 lamps to shine in front of the lampstand. 3Aaron did that. 4The lampstand was hammered gold from its base to its flowers in the pattern Yahveh showed Moses. The Levites Dedicated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Again Yahveh told Moses, 6&amp;quot;Take the Levites from among the Israelites and cleanse them. 7For their cleansing, sprinkle purifying water on them, have them shave their whole bodies and wash their clothes. 8Then have them take a bull with its grain offering—fine flour mixed with olive oil. Take a second bull for a sin offering. 9Present the Levites at the Tent of Meeting and gather the community. 10Have them put their hands on the Levites. 11Then Aaron will present the Levites to Yahveh as a wave offering from the people to qualify them to perform service to Yahveh. 12The Levites will put their hands on the bulls&amp;rsquo; heads. They&amp;rsquo;ll offer one as a sin offering and the other as a burnt offering, to atone for the Levites. 13Have the Levites stand in the presence of Aaron and his sons to present them as a wave offering to Yahveh. 14&amp;quot;In that way, set the Levites apart from among the Israelites. The Levites will belong to me. 15Then they can serve in the Tent of Meeting. But you&amp;rsquo;ll cleanse them and present them as a wave offering, 16because I&amp;rsquo;ve dedicated them to myself in place of every firstborn in Israel. 17Every firstborn belongs to me among people and animals. The day I struck down the firstborn in Egypt, I sanctified them to myself. [18] 19I&amp;rsquo;ve given the Levites to Aaron and his sons to perform the service for the Israelites at the Tent of Meeting, and to atone for them so there won&amp;rsquo;t be a plague on Israel from coming near the sanctuary.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the first month, second year after the Israelites left Egypt, Yahveh told Moses in the Wilderness of Sinai, 2-3&amp;quot;Have Israel observe Passover as directed at its scheduled time: the fourteenth day of this month in the evening.&amp;quot; 4Moses told the Israelites to observe it. 5They did so in the Wilderness of Sinai the way Yahveh commanded Moses.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; Some men were ceremonially unclean because of a corpse, so they couldn&amp;rsquo;t observe it that day. They came to Moses and Aaron that day, 7&amp;quot;Although we&amp;rsquo;re unclean, why can&amp;rsquo;t we present the offering to Yahveh at the scheduled time with the rest of Israel?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses, 2&amp;quot;Make two bugles out of hammered silver. Use them to gather the community or move the camp out. 3Blow both bugles to gather the community at the Tent of Meeting. 4Blow one bugle to gather just the leaders of thousands there. 5&amp;quot;When you blow the signal, the camps pitched on the east side will set out. 6When you blow the signal again, the camps pitched on the south side will set out. 7When assembling the community, however, blow without sounding an alarm. 8By permanent statute the priestly descendants of Aaron will blow the bugles. 9When you go to war in your country against an attacker, blow the signal with the bugle, so Yahveh will remember you and save you from your enemies. 10At celebrations, at scheduled festivals, and on the first day of the month, blow the bugles over your burnt offerings and peace offerings to remind your God about you. I&amp;rsquo;m Yahveh your God.&amp;quot; Israel Leaves Sinai&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The people started complaining about their hardships. Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s anger flared. It burned among them and burned up the outskirts of the camp. 2The people cried out to Moses, and he prayed to Yahveh, and the fire died down. 3The name of that place became Taberah, because Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s fire &amp;ldquo;burned&amp;rdquo; among them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Some riffraff among them had selfish interests and cried out again, &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s going to feed us? 5We remember the fish we used to eat free in Egypt, the cucumbers, melons, leeks, onions, and garlic. 6Now our appetite&amp;rsquo;s gone. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing to look at except this manna.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Miriam and Aaron criticized Moses for the Nubian woman he&amp;rsquo;d married. 2&amp;quot;Has Yahveh indeed only spoken through you? Hasn&amp;rsquo;t he spoken through us too?&amp;quot; Yahveh heard it. (3Moses was the humblest man in the world.) 4At once, Yahveh told Moses, Aaron, and Miriam, &amp;ldquo;Come out to the Tent of Meeting.&amp;rdquo; 5He came down in a pillar of cloud and stood at the entrance to the Tent to call Aaron and Miriam. When they&amp;rsquo;d come forward, 6he said, &amp;ldquo;Listen to what I&amp;rsquo;m saying: if there&amp;rsquo;s a prophet among you, I&amp;rsquo;ll show myself to him in a vision or speak to him in a dream.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses, 2&amp;quot;Send one leader from each tribe to spy out Canaan that I&amp;rsquo;m giving to Israel.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Moses sent out these leaders from Paran:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; from Reuben, Shammua Ben-Zaccur;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; from Simeon, Shaphat Ben-Hori;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; from Judah, Caleb Ben-Jephunneh;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; from Issachar, Igal Ben-Joseph;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v8&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; from Ephraim, Hoshea Ben-Nun, (16bthat Moses called Joshua);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v9&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; from Benjamin, Palti Ben-Raphu;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v10&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; from Zebulun, Gaddiel Ben-Sodi;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v11&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt; from Joseph, tribe of Manasseh, Gaddi Ben-Susi;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The community cried out loud that night 2and complained to Moses and Aaron, &amp;ldquo;We should&amp;rsquo;ve died in Egypt! We should&amp;rsquo;ve died in the desert! 3Why is Yahveh taking us to this land to fall by the sword? Our wives and little ones will become spoils of war. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t we be better off to go back to Egypt?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; They said to one another, &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s appoint a leader and go back.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to tell Israel, &amp;ldquo;When you go into the land I&amp;rsquo;m giving you, 3make a burnt offering to meY—a sacrifice to fulfill a special vow, a free-will offering, at your scheduled times. Make a pleasing aroma from the herd or flock. 4&amp;quot;When you present your offering, present a grain offering made from .11 bushel .1 ephah of fine flour mixed with 3 pints ¼ hin of olive oil.  5Prepare wine for the liquid offering, 3 pints ¼ hin, with the burnt offering or sacrifice, for each lamb. 6&amp;quot;For a ram, prepare as a grain offering .22 bushel .2 ephah of fine flour mixed with ⅓⅓ him of olive oil. 7For a liquid offering, offer ⅓ gallon ⅓ hin of wine as an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. 8&amp;quot;When you prepare a bull as a burnt offering or sacrifice—to fulfill a special vow or for peace offerings to Yahveh—9offer it with a grain offering made from .33 bushel .3 ephah of fine flour mixed with 3 quarts ½ hin of olive oil. 10Offer as the liquid offering 3 quarts ½ hin of wine as an offering by fire, as an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. 11That&amp;rsquo;s the way it&amp;rsquo;s to be done for each ox, ram, male lamb, or goat, 12the same for each sacrifice. 13&amp;quot;Every citizen of you will do those things when you present an offering by fire, as an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. 14If foreigners staying with you—temporarily or permanently—want to make an offering by fire, they&amp;rsquo;ll do it the same way you do. 15-16There&amp;rsquo;ll be one statute, one law, one ordinance for you and for foreigners among you throughout your generations.&amp;rdquo; 17-18Yahveh told Moses to tell Israel, &amp;ldquo;When you go into the land where I&amp;rsquo;m taking you 19and you eat the food that&amp;rsquo;s there, lift up an offering to Yahveh.   20-21From the first of your dough, lift up a cake as an offering from the threshing floor. Unintentional Sins 22-23&amp;quot;When the whole community unintentionally fails to observe any commandment, 24they&amp;rsquo;ll offer 1 bull for a burnt offering (as an aroma pleasing to Yahveh, with its grain offering and liquid offering) and 1 male goat for a sin offering. 25The priest will atone for the whole community because they brought the offering to Yahveh for their error. 26He&amp;rsquo;ll forgive the community, including any foreigner among them, since it wasn&amp;rsquo;t intentional. 27&amp;quot;If one of you sins unintentionally, offer a year-old female goat for a sin offering. 28The priest will atone for you in front of Yahveh. 29For doing something unintentionally, there&amp;rsquo;ll be one law for a native and a foreigner. 30&amp;quot;But if you do something intentionally, native or foreign, you&amp;rsquo;re blaspheming Yahveh. You&amp;rsquo;ll be excluded from the community. 31Your guilt will remain because you&amp;rsquo;ve disregarded Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s message and broken his commandment.&amp;rdquo; Execution of a Sabbath Breaker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Korah Ben-Izhar Ben-Kohath Ben-Levi, along with Dathan and Abiram sons of Eliab and On Ben-Peleth (descendants of Reuben)—2together with 250 prominent chosen leaders of the community, well-known men chosen by the assembly—rebelled against Moses and some of the people. 3They gathered against Moses and Aaron, and said, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve gone far enough. The whole community is holy, every one of them, and Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s among them. Why place yourselves above Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s assembly?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-17&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh said to Moses, 2&amp;quot;Tell the Israelites to get a rod from each family leader. Write each man&amp;rsquo;s name on his rod 3and write Aaron&amp;rsquo;s name on Levi&amp;rsquo;s rod. 4Then put them in the Tent of Meeting in front of the Testimony where I meet you.  5The rod of the man I choose will sprout. I&amp;rsquo;ll stifle the criticism of your critics.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; Moses told the Israelites to give him a rod for each family leader (12 rods) with Aaron&amp;rsquo;s rod among them. 7Moses put the rods in front of Yahveh in the Tent of Testimony.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-18&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So Yahveh told Aaron, &amp;ldquo;You, your sons, and your father&amp;rsquo;s family will be responsible for the sanctuary. You and your sons will be responsible for the priesthood. 2But take your relatives from the tribe of Levi to help you while you and your sons serve in the Tent of Testimony. 3They&amp;rsquo;ll make preparations throughout the Tent, but they can&amp;rsquo;t approach the sanctuary furnishings or the altar, or they and you will die. 4An outsider can&amp;rsquo;t come near you. 5They&amp;rsquo;ll tend to preparations for the sanctuary and the altar so there won&amp;rsquo;t be any more anger on Israel. 6I&amp;rsquo;ll give your fellow Levites to you, dedicated to Yahveh, to service the Tent of Meeting. 7But you and your sons will tend to everything around the altar and inside the curtain. I&amp;rsquo;m giving you the priesthood as a service; execute any outsider that comes near.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-19&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses and Aaron, 2&amp;quot;This is a statute of Yahveh, &amp;lsquo;Tell the Israelites to bring you an unblemished red heifer that&amp;rsquo;s never worn a yoke. 3Give it to Eleazar to take outside the camp and slaughter in his presence. 4He&amp;rsquo;ll take some of its blood with his finger and sprinkle it toward the front of the Tent of Meeting seven times. 5Then the heifer will be burned in front of him—hide, meat, blood, and refuse. 6The priest will take cedar wood, hyssop, and scarlet material, and throw it onto the burning heifer. 7Then he&amp;rsquo;ll wash his clothes, take a bath, and afterward come into the camp, but he&amp;rsquo;ll be ceremonially unclean till evening. 8The one that burns it will also wash his clothes, take a bath, and be unclean till evening. 9A man that&amp;rsquo;s clean will gather the heifer&amp;rsquo;s ashes and deposit them outside the camp in a clean place, and the community will keep it as water for removing impurity from sin. 10The one that gathers the ashes will wash his clothes and be unclean till evening. A permanent statute for Israelites and foreigners living among them. 11&amp;rsquo;Anyone of you that touches a human corpse will be ceremonially unclean for a week. 12Purify yourself with the water on the third and seventh days, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be clean. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, you&amp;rsquo;re still unclean; 13you&amp;rsquo;re defiling Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s Tabernacle, and you&amp;rsquo;re excluded from Israel. 14&amp;rsquo;If someone dies in your tent, all of you in it will be ceremonially unclean for a week. 15Every open container will be unclean. 16&amp;rsquo;Anybody that touches a body out in the open, slain with a sword or dead from natural causes, will be ceremonially unclean for a week. 17Then for the unclean person they&amp;rsquo;ll take some ashes from the burnt purification from sin and add flowing water in a basin. 18A clean person will dip hyssop in the water and sprinkle it on the tent, its furnishings, the people that were there, and the one that touched the bone, the one slain, the one dead of natural causes, or the grave. 19Then the clean person will sprinkle the unclean persons on the third and seventh days. On the seventh day the clean purify the unclean. Then they&amp;rsquo;ll wash their clothes, take a bath, and be ceremonially clean by evening. 20&amp;rsquo;But those who don&amp;rsquo;t purify themselves will be excluded from the community. They&amp;rsquo;ve defiled Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s sanctuary. The water for removing impurity wasn&amp;rsquo;t sprinkled on them. 21Those who sprinkle the water will wash their clothes, and those who touch the water will be ceremonially unclean until evening. 22Anything an unclean person touches is unclean; anyone that touches it is unclean till evening.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; The Death of Miriam&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-20&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The whole community came to the Wilderness of Zin in the first month and stayed at Kadesh. Miriam died and they buried her there. Moses Strikes the Rock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; The community didn&amp;rsquo;t have water and gathered against Moses and Aaron, 3&amp;quot;If only we&amp;rsquo;d perished when our relatives perished in Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s presence! 4Why bring hisY assembly into this desert for us and our animals to die? 5Why make us come up from Egypt to this wretched place? It&amp;rsquo;s not a place with grain, figs, grapes, or pomegranates; and there&amp;rsquo;s no water.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-21&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When the Canaanite king of Arad, who lived in the Negev, heard that Israel was coming by way of Atharim, he fought Israel and took some captives. 2Israel vowed to Yahveh, &amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;ll deliver them to me, we&amp;rsquo;ll destroy their towns.&amp;rdquo; 3He delivered them, and they &amp;ldquo;destroyed&amp;rdquo; them and their towns; the name of the place became Hormah. The Bronze Snake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Then they set out from Mount Hor by taking the road to the Red Sea, to go around Edom, and the people got impatient because of the journey. 5They criticized God and Moses, &amp;ldquo;Why bring us out of Egypt to die in the desert? There&amp;rsquo;s no food or water. We hate this miserable food!&amp;rdquo; 6Yahveh sent poisonous snakes among them. They bit the people and a lot of them died. 7They came to Moses, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve sinned; we&amp;rsquo;ve criticized you and Yahveh. Intercede with him so he&amp;rsquo;ll take the snakes away.&amp;rdquo; Moses did that, 8and Yahveh told him, &amp;ldquo;Fashion a poisonous snake on a standard so everybody that looks at it will survive.&amp;rdquo; 9Moses did that.  If a snake bit anyone and they looked at the bronze serpent, they&amp;rsquo;d survive. Israel&amp;rsquo;s Journey to Moab&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-22&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Israel traveled and camped in the plains of Moab across the Jordan from Jericho. 2Balak Ben-Zippor saw what Israel did to the Amorites. 3The people of Moab were afraid of them because there were so many of them. 4The king of Moab told the elders in Midian, &amp;ldquo;This horde will eat up everything around us like an ox eats up grass in a pasture.&amp;rdquo; Balak, king of Moab at the time, 5sent messengers to Balaam Ben-Beor at Pethor, near the River Euphrates in the land of his people. He called him and said, &amp;ldquo;A people has come out of Egypt. They cover the ground; they&amp;rsquo;re living across from me. 6Come and put a curse on them; there are too many of them for me to fight. Maybe I can defeat them and drive them out. I know that whoever you bless is blessed, and whoever you curse is cursed.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-23&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 23&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Balaam told Balak, &amp;ldquo;Build seven altars for me here and prepare seven bulls and rams.&amp;rdquo; 2They offered a bull and a ram on each altar. 3Balaam told him, &amp;ldquo;Stand beside your burnt offering, and I&amp;rsquo;ll go. Maybe Yahveh will come to me, and I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what he shows me.&amp;rdquo; He went to a bare hill. 4God met him, and he said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve set up seven altars and offered a bull and a ram on each one.&amp;rdquo; 5Yahveh gave Balaam a message, &amp;ldquo;Go tell Balak such and such.&amp;rdquo; 6He went back to Balak, who was standing by his burnt offering with the leaders of Moab.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-24&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 24&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Balaam saw that it pleased Yahveh to bless Israel, he didn&amp;rsquo;t go like before to look for omens, but faced the open country. 2He saw Israel camping by tribes, and God&amp;rsquo;s Spirit came on him. 3He took up this oracle: &amp;ldquo;The oracle of Balaam Ben-Beor, the oracle of a man with his eyes wide open,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; the oracle of one that hears God&amp;rsquo;s message, that sees a vision from the Almighty, that falls down with his eyes wide open. 5&amp;quot;How fair your tents, Jacob, the places where you live, Israel!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-25&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 25&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; While Israel was camping in Shittim, the people started carrying on prostitution with the women of Moab. 2They invited the people to the sacrifices to their gods, and the people ate and bowed to their gods. 3In this way, Israel joined themselves to Baal of Peor, and Yahveh was angry. 4He told Moses, &amp;ldquo;Seize the ringleaders and execute them in broad daylight in myY presence so my fierce anger will turn away from Israel.&amp;rdquo; 5Moses told the judges, &amp;ldquo;Each of you put to death his men that have joined in worshiping Baal of Peor.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-26&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 26&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After the plague Yahveh told Moses and Eleazar, 2&amp;quot;Count by families the men 20 years old and up that can go to war.&amp;quot; 3Moses and Eleazar told them in the plains of Moab by the Jordan across from Jericho, 4&amp;quot;Count the men 20 years old and up.&amp;quot; The Israelites that came out of Egypt were as follows:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Reuben by families was Hanoch, Pallu, 6-7Hezron, and Carmi: &#x9;43,730&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 27</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-27&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 27&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The daughters of Zelophehad Ben-Hepher (Ben-Gilead Ben-Machir Ben-Manasseh) Ben-Joseph came near: Mahlah, Noah, Hoglah, Milcah, and Tirzah. 2They stood in front of Moses, Eleazar, and the leaders of the community at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting, and said, 3&amp;quot;Our father died in the wilderness, but not among those who opposed Yahveh with Korah. He died in his own sin and didn&amp;rsquo;t have any sons. 4Why should he disappear from his clan just because he didn&amp;rsquo;t have any sons? Give us a possession among our father&amp;rsquo;s brothers.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 28</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-28&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 28&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to tell Israel, &amp;ldquo;Present my offerings by fire at their scheduled times, an aroma pleasing to me, my &amp;lsquo;food.&amp;rsquo; 3Make this offering by fire to Yahveh every day: 2 male lambs a year old without defect. 4Offer one in the morning, the other in the evening. 5For a grain offering, offer .11 bushel .1 ephah of fine flour mixed with 3 pints ¼ hin of pressed olive oil. 6It&amp;rsquo;s a daily burnt offering that was ordained at Mount Sinai. 7The liquid offering that goes with it will be 3 pints ¼ hin of alcohol for each lamb, poured out in the Holy Place. 8Offer the other lamb that evening the same way with its grain offering and liquid offering. Sabbath Offerings 9&amp;quot;On the Sabbath, offer two male lambs a year old without defect, and a fifth of a measure of fine flour mixed with oil as a grain offering with its liquid offering. 10The burnt offering on each Sabbath is in addition to the daily burnt offering and its liquid offering. Monthly Offerings 11&amp;quot;At the beginning of each month, present a burnt offering to Yahveh: 2 bulls and 1 ram, 12as well as .3 measure of fine flour for a grain offering mixed with olive oil for each bull, 13and .1 of a measure of fine flour mixed with olive oil for each lamb, an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. 14Their liquid offerings will be 3 quarts ½ hin of wine for a bull, 2 quarts ⅓ hin for a ram, and 3 pints ¼ hin for a lamb. 15Offer one male goat for a sin offering with its liquid offering in addition to the daily burnt offering. Passover Offerings 16&amp;quot;The fourteenth day, first month is Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s Passover. 17On the fifteenth the festival will begin. For a week, eat bread with no yeast. 18On the first day is a holy convocation; don&amp;rsquo;t work. 19Present a burnt offering to Yahveh: 2 bulls, 1 ram, and 7 male lambs a year old without defect. 20For their grain offering, present fine flour mixed with olive oil—.3 of a measure for a bull, .2 for the ram, 21and .1 for each lamb. 22Offer 1 male goat for a sin offering, to atone for yourselves. 23Present them besides the morning&amp;rsquo;s daily burnt offering. 24Daily for 7 days, present the food of the offering by fire, an aroma pleasing to Yahveh. Present it with its liquid offering in addition to the daily burnt offering. 25The seventh day, hold a holy convocation; don&amp;rsquo;t work. Feast of Weeks Offerings 26&amp;quot;At the time of the first of the harvest, when you present a new grain offering in your Festival of Weeks, hold a holy convocation; don&amp;rsquo;t work. 27Offer a burnt offering for an aroma pleasing to Yahveh: 2 young bulls, 1 ram, 7 male lambs a year old, 28and their grain offering of fine flour mixed with olive oil—.3 of a measure for each bull, .2 for the ram, 29and .1 for each lamb. 30Offer 1 male goat to atone for yourselves. 31Besides the daily burnt offering and its grain offering, present them with their liquid offerings. They&amp;rsquo;ll be without defect. Feast of Trumpets Offerings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 29</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-29&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 29&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The first day, seventh month, hold a holy convocation; don&amp;rsquo;t work. Celebrate the Festival of Trumpets. 2Offer a burnt offering as an aroma pleasing to Yahveh: 1 bull, 1 ram, and 7 male lambs a year old without defect. 3Offer with them their grain offerings of fine flour mixed with olive oil—.3 of a measure for the bull, .2 for the ram, 4and .1 for each lamb. 5Offer 1 male goat for a sin offering to atone for yourselves. 6Offer them in addition to the burnt offering at the new moon and its grain offering, and the daily burnt offering and its grain offering. Offer their liquid offerings. Day of Atonement Offerings 7&amp;quot;The tenth day, seventh month, hold a holy convocation; fast and don&amp;rsquo;t work. 8Present a burnt offering to Yahveh as a pleasing aroma: 1 bull, 1 ram, and 7 male lambs a year old without defect. 9Offer them together with the grain offering of fine flour mixed with olive oil—.3 of a measure for the bull, .2 for the ram, 10and .1 for each lamb. 11Offer one male goat for a sin offering in addition to the sin offering of atonement and the daily burnt offering, grain offering, and liquid offering. 12&amp;quot;The fifteenth day, seventh month, hold a holy convocation; don&amp;rsquo;t work. Observe a festival to Yahveh for a week. 13Present a burnt offering as an aroma pleasing to Yahveh: 13 bulls, 2 rams, and 14 male lambs a year old without defect. 14Offer them together with their grain offerings of fine flour mixed with olive oil—.3 of a measure for each bull, .2 for each ram, 15and .1 for each lamb. 16Offer one male goat as a sin offering in addition to the daily burnt offering, grain offering, and liquid offering. 17&amp;quot;The second day, offer 12 bulls, 2 rams, and 14 male lambs a year old without defect. 18Offer them together with the grain offering and liquid offering for each bull, ram, and lamb in standard fashion. 19Offer 1 male goat as a sin offering in addition to the daily burnt offering, its grain offering, and liquid offering. 20-22&amp;quot;The third day, offer 11 bulls. Do the rest like the second day. 23-25&amp;quot;The fourth day, offer 10 bulls. Do the rest like the second day. 26-28&amp;quot;The fifth day, offer 9 bulls. Do the rest like the second day. 29-31&amp;quot;The sixth day, offer 8 bulls. Do the rest like the second day. 32-34&amp;quot;The seventh day, offer 7 bulls. Do the rest like the second day. 35&amp;quot;The eighth day, hold a solemn assembly; don&amp;rsquo;t work. 36Present a burnt offering as an aroma pleasing to Yahveh: 1 bull, 1 ram, and 7 male lambs a year old without defect. [37-38] 39&amp;quot;Present those to Yahveh at your scheduled times in addition to your offerings for fulling a vow, free will offerings, burnt offerings, and the liquid offerings for your peace offerings.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 30</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-30&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 30&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Moses told the tribal leaders, &amp;ldquo;This is what Yahveh has commanded. 2If a man makes a vow to Yahveh or takes an oath that obligates him to do something, he must keep his word. Women&amp;rsquo;s Vows&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; If a woman takes a vow to Yahveh and obligates herself to do something while in her father&amp;rsquo;s family in her youth, 4and her father hears it and doesn&amp;rsquo;t object, then her vow or pledge stands. 5But if her father forbids her, her vow and pledge don&amp;rsquo;t stand. Yahveh will release her from them because her father forbade her. 6&amp;quot;But, if she marries while under her vow or rash statement 7and her husband hears about it and doesn&amp;rsquo;t object, then her vow or pledge stands. 8But, if he forbids her, he annuls her vow or rash statement, and Yahveh will release her from it. 9&amp;quot;The vow of a widow or divorced woman stands. 10&amp;quot;However, if she vows in her husband&amp;rsquo;s house or binds herself to an obligation with an oath 11and her husband hears it, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t object, then her vow or pledge stands. 12But if her husband annuls it, it won&amp;rsquo;t stand, and Yahveh will release her from them. 13&amp;quot;A husband can annul any vow or binding oath a wife submits herself to. 14If he doesn&amp;rsquo;t say anything to her the day he hears it, then he confirms it. 15But if he tries to annul it later, he&amp;rsquo;ll bear her guilt.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 31</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-31&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 31&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses, 2&amp;quot;Take revenge for Israel on the Midianites. Afterward you&amp;rsquo;ll pass on to your people.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Moses told the people, &amp;ldquo;Arm men to attack Midian and carry out Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s revenge on it. 4Send 1,000 men from each tribe.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; They provided 12,000 men. 6Moses sent them to war with Phinehas Ben-Eleazar the priest along with the holy items from the sanctuary and bugles for signaling. 7They fought Midian and killed every male, 8including its five kings: Evi, Rekem, Zur, Hur, Reba. They also killed Balaam Ben-Beor with a sword. 9They took the women and children, their cattle, flocks, and possessions. 10They burned their towns, houses, and camps; 11and took the spoil—people and animals. 12They brought the captives, prey, and spoil to Moses, Eleazar, and the community on the plains of Moab across the Jordan from Jericho.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 32</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-32&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 32&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Reuben and Gad had lots of livestock. When they saw that Jazer and Gilead had good grazing land, 2they spoke to Moses, Eleazar the priest, and the leaders of the community, 3&amp;quot;Ataroth, Dibon, Jazer, Nimrah, Heshbon, Elealeh, Sebam, Nebo, and Beon—4land Yahveh overthrew for Israel—is suitable for our livestock. 5If we&amp;rsquo;re pleasing to you, give us this land instead of having us cross the Jordan.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; Moses said, &amp;ldquo;Will your relatives go to war, and you sit here? 7Why discourage Israel from going to the land Yahveh has given them? 8That&amp;rsquo;s what your fathers did when I sent them from Kadesh-barnea to spy out the land. 9When they went to the Valley of Eshcol and saw the land, they discouraged Israel from going in. 10Yahveh was angry that day and swore, 11&amp;rsquo;No men that came up from Egypt 20 years and older will see the land I promised Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, because they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t follow me. 12Only Caleb the Kenizzite and Joshua Ben- Nun faithfully followed me.&amp;rsquo; 13Yahveh made Israel wander in the desert for 40 years till that generation died off. 14You&amp;rsquo;re replacing your parents as sinful people to anger Yahveh toward Israel. 15If you turn aside from him, he&amp;rsquo;ll leave you in the desert. You&amp;rsquo;ll be responsible for destroying this nation.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 33</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-33&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 33&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; These are the segments of the journey Israel took when they left Egypt. 2Yahveh told Moses to write them down. 3They traveled from Rameses on the fifteenth day, first month, the day after Passover. They left right in front of the Egyptians 4while they were burying the firstborn that Yahveh struck. Yahveh also carried out judgments against their gods.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; They left from Ramses &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;to Succoth,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 34</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-34&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 34&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Yahveh told Moses to say to Israel, &amp;ldquo;When you go into Canaan, 3your south border will run from the Wilderness of Zin alongside Edom from the end of the Dead Sea eastward. 4Your border will turn from the south to the ascent of Akrabbim and go on along to Zin. It will end south of Kadesh-barnea, go out to Hazaraddar, and on along to Azmon. 5The border will turn from Azmon to where the River of Egypt empties into the Mediterranean Sea. 6&amp;quot;Your west border will be the Mediterranean Sea. 7&amp;quot;Your north border will stretch from the Mediterranean Sea to Mount Hor, 8Lebo-hamath, Zedad, 9Ziphron, and end at Hazar-enan. 10&amp;quot;Your east border will run from Hazar-enan to Shepham 11down to Riblah on the east of Ain down to the slopes east of the Sea of Chinnereth. 12It will go down to the Jordan and on down to the Dead Sea.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 35</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-35&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 35&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the plains of Moab by the Jordan across from Jericho, Yahveh said to Moses, 2&amp;quot;Tell Israel to give the Levites towns to live in, 3along with pastureland for their cattle, herds, and animals. 4The pastures will extend 1500ft out from the wall all around the city, 5a 3,000ft diameter of pastureland. 6Give the Levites 6 cities as refuge for a person to flee to that&amp;rsquo;s killed someone accidentally. 7Give them 42 other towns with their pastures to make 48 total. 8The towns you give them will be in proportion to the number of towns each tribe inherits.&amp;quot; Cities of Refuge 9-10Yahveh told Moses to say to Israel, &amp;ldquo;When you cross the Jordan into Canaan, 11identify cities of refuge a person can flee to from killing someone accidentally. 12-13The 6 cities will serve as refuges from an avenger till the slayer can stand public trial: 143 cities beyond the Jordan and three in Canaan. 15They&amp;rsquo;ll serve Israelites, foreigners, and people living temporarily in Israel. 16&amp;quot;If a slayer kills someone with an iron instrument, it&amp;rsquo;s murder; execute the slayer. 17The same applies if the weapon is stone 18or wood. 19The avenger is to execute the murderer on the spot when they meet. 20If one person pushes another in hate, throws something from an ambush, 21or hits barehanded with enmity and kills the other, it&amp;rsquo;s murder. The avenger is to execute the murderer on the spot when they meet. 22&amp;quot;One person might push someone suddenly without enmity or throw something 23like a stone and hit the other accidentally. 24The community will decide between the slayer and the avenger by these ordinances. 25They&amp;rsquo;ll protect the slayer from the avenger by returning the slayer to the city of refuge till the high priest dies. 26If the slayer ventures outside the city, 27the avenger is not considered a murderer. 28The slayer should&amp;rsquo;ve stayed in the city till the high priest died. Then the slayer could have gone home. 29&amp;quot;These are permanent statutes wherever you live. 30On the testimony of two or more witnesses, execute whoever commits murder. One witness isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. 31Don&amp;rsquo;t take a ransom in place of execution 32or for someone that flees to a city of refuge so they can go home early before the high priest dies. 33Don&amp;rsquo;t defile the land you live in; blood defiles it. Don&amp;rsquo;t atone for land defiled by blood except by the blood of the one that shed it. 34Don&amp;rsquo;t defile the land you&amp;rsquo;re living in because I&amp;rsquo;m living in it with you.&amp;rdquo; Women Heirs of Property&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numbers 36</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/numbers/chapter-36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;numbers-chapter-36&#34;&gt;Numbers Chapter 36&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The heads of clans came down from Gilead (Ben-Machir Ben-Manasseh Ben-Joseph) to Moses and Israel&amp;rsquo;s leaders. 2They said, &amp;ldquo;Yahveh told you to allot land to Israel for inheritance, and to give the inheritance of Zelophehad our relative to his daughters. 3But if they marry outside their tribe, their inheritance will move to the new tribe. 4When Israel&amp;rsquo;s Year of Jubilee comes, it will become permanent in the new tribe and lost from ours.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
