<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 Thessalonians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1 Thessalonians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Thessalonians 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-thessalonians-chapter-1&#34;&gt;1 Thessalonians Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul, Silvanus, and Timothy to the church of the Thessalonians in God the Father and the Lord Jesus ChristMessiah. Grace and peace.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; We are always grateful to God for you and include you in our prayers. We 3remember your work of faith, your labor of love, and your enduring hope that lies in our Lord Jesus Christ in the presence of our God and Father. 4Family of Christ loved by God, we know you&amp;rsquo;re chosen 5because our good news didn&amp;rsquo;t come to you just in words, but in power, in the Holy Spirit, in complete confidence, like the kind of men you know we proved to be among you on your behalf. 6You imitated us and the Lord, because you received the message with the joy of the Holy Spirit among lots of difficulties. 7As a result, you became an example for the believers in Macedonia and Achaia. 8The Lord&amp;rsquo;s message rang out from you, not only in Macedonia and Achaia, but wherever your faith in God has gone. So we don&amp;rsquo;t have to say anything. 9People acknowledge how you received us, how you turned from idols to serve the true, living God; 10how you wait for his Son from heaven—that God raised from the dead, Jesus who rescues us from the fury to come.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Thessalonians 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-thessalonians-chapter-2&#34;&gt;1 Thessalonians Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Our coming to you proved to be productive. 2As you know, after we&amp;rsquo;d suffered and been treated disgracefully, we gathered up the courage in our God to present his good news to you during our struggles. 3We didn&amp;rsquo;t pressure you with deception, impure motives, or treachery. 4But, we spoke the way we did since God approved us and entrusted us with the good news. We weren&amp;rsquo;t trying to please people, but God, who was approving our intentions. 5God is witness: we never stooped to flattery or veiled greed, 6or tried to get honor from you or anybody else. 7Though as Christ&amp;rsquo;s apostles, we could&amp;rsquo;ve expected you to support us, we were gentle among you like a nurse taking care of her kids. 8Since you became so dear to us, we enjoyed sharing with you God&amp;rsquo;s good news and our very selves. 9You remember our labor and hardship, how we worked day and night so we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t burden you while we presented his good news to you. 10Along with God, you can confirm how devoutly, uprightly, blamelessly we carried ourselves among you—11like a father with his kids. 12We urged you, encouraged you, and testified to you to live worthy of the One that was calling you to his kingdom and honor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Thessalonians 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-thessalonians-chapter-3&#34;&gt;1 Thessalonians Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When we couldn&amp;rsquo;t contain our concern about you anymore, we decided to stay behind by ourselves in Athens 2and send Timothy, our brother and fellow worker for God in the good news about Christ. He could strengthen and encourage you in your faith 3so the troubles you were facing wouldn&amp;rsquo;t disturb any of you. You know we Christians are destined for opposition. 4Even when we were there, we kept telling you we&amp;rsquo;d run into trouble; and that&amp;rsquo;s what happened. 5That&amp;rsquo;s why I couldn&amp;rsquo;t contain my concern for you anymore and sent to find out about your faith. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want your tempter to somehow make our labor be for nothing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Thessalonians 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-thessalonians-chapter-4&#34;&gt;1 Thessalonians Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Finally, we urge you by the Lord Jesus to live the way you should—like you received from us—so you improve your living even more. 2You know what commandments we gave you from the Lord Jesus. 3This is the will of God who sanctifies you: that you abstain from sexual immorality, 4that each of you know how to exercise self-control in holiness and honor (5not living in lust like Gentiles, who don&amp;rsquo;t know God), 6that you not sin and cheat on your fellow Christian in such a matter. The Lord avenges things—like we warned you. 7He didn&amp;rsquo;t call us to impurity, but to holiness. 8So whoever rejects that warning isn&amp;rsquo;t rejecting us, but God, who puts his Holy Spirit in us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Thessalonians 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-thessalonians/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-thessalonians-chapter-5&#34;&gt;1 Thessalonians Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; You also don&amp;rsquo;t need me to write about when and under what circumstances he&amp;rsquo;ll return. 2You know full well that the Lord will come like a thief at night. 3When people are saying, &amp;ldquo;Peace and safety,&amp;rdquo; destruction will come on them like birth pains on a woman; they won&amp;rsquo;t escape. 4But you aren&amp;rsquo;t in the dark, and that time won&amp;rsquo;t overtake you like a thief. 5You&amp;rsquo;re children of light and day, not of darkness and night. 6So don&amp;rsquo;t sleep like other people; stay awake and be sober. 7People sleep at night and get drunk at night, 8but you must stay awake and sober. Put on the breastplate of faith and love, and the helmet of hope for salvation. 9God didn&amp;rsquo;t destine us to his fury, but to salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ. 10He died for us; so whether we&amp;rsquo;re asleep or awake, we&amp;rsquo;ll live with him. 11Comfort one another and keep building each other up like you&amp;rsquo;re doing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
