<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cm-102 on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/categories/cm-102/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cm-102 on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/categories/cm-102/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A MINISTER’S FILING SYSTEM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-ministers-filing-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-ministers-filing-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A MINISTER’S FILING SYSTEM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will not remember! That is the bottom line when it comes to libraries and filing systems. The efficiency with which a minister discharges his responsibilities is directly proportionate to the degree of ready access he has to his materials. The quality of his work is determined by the extent to which he can organize and preserve the information that he generates and that comes to him from a wide range of sources. A person needs to organize his files because he will remember only a small percent of what he learns and needs to know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BENEDICTIONS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/benedictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/benedictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BENEDICTIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The benediction slot appears at the end of the service. In popular usage “benediction” has become a label for the closing prayer, but a benediction is really a pronouncement of blessing on those assembled for worship or on God as a final statement of praise. The biblical texts given below can serve as a word of praise to God or a word of blessing on the worshipers as they are about to leave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CALLS TO WORSHIP</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/calls-to-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/calls-to-worship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CALLS TO WORSHIP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Call to worship is a slot often used at the beginning of services designed to inspire awe, reverence, humility before God. Such services are more contemplative than celebrative, more vertically than horizontally oriented. The call to worship is a shorter scripture portion intended to focus attention of all participants and to prepare for a prayer of invocation. Other scripture readings may be longer in keeping with their purpose to inform, inspired, comfort and the like. The following texts are suggestions; there are may others that may be used for this purpose. The Book so Psalms is particularly useful as a resource for calls to worship. The texts below appear in vertical format so that notations can be made about subject matter, occasions when used, and the like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMUNION SCRIPTURES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/communion-scriptures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/communion-scriptures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMUNION SCRIPTURES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many aspects to the total meaning of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Supper, and there are many ways of applying those meanings to Christian life and worship. As a result any number of scripture passages connect naturally to the experience of coming around the Lord&amp;rsquo;s table with fellow Christians. Below are several portions of scripture that belong among those that speak of matters relevant to this worship experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psalms 23&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GROUP PRAYER PATTERNS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/group-prayer-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/group-prayer-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GROUP PRAYER PATTERNS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayers may be spontaneous or planned, vocal or silent, informal or formal depending on the setting and the desired impact. Group prayer corporately acknowledges our creaturely dependence on God and our fundamental orientation toward him. Group prayer may take various forms but any form we choose needs to evoke an I-You experience with God. Prayer should be sincere and &amp;ldquo;real,&amp;rdquo; and therefore should avoid deadness born of unnatural formalism, perfunctory language full of clichés and trite expressions, vain repetitions, and the like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IV.  PRACTICAL MINISTRY</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/iv-practical-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/iv-practical-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IV.  PRACTICAL MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;Administration&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leadership&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Church organization&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By-laws&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Filing system outline&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Records:  new-member records, non-member records, calling records, geographical records, demographic records, counseling records, legal documents, attendance records, sermon records, committee meeting minutes, talent records, library records, records for income tax, recommendations written, important correspondence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Benevolence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Education&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;History of Christian Education&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Education work&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philosophy of Christian education&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teaching methods:  team teaching&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teaching age groups:  nursery, children, youth, adults&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KEEPING CURRENT</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/keeping-current/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/keeping-current/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KEEPING CURRENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. In World Affairs&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Radio and television&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Local and national newspapers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Subscribe to Christianity Today (religious world news), Christian Century (religious world news).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D. Get on the mailing lists of missionary agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. In Practical Ministry Skills&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Subscribe to Leadership, Pulpit Helps, Discipleship, Christian Standard, and the like.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Attend seminars (National Pastors Conference), ministerial gatherings, conventions (North American Christian Convention, National Missionary Convention, preaching conventions associated with several Bible colleges)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LEADING SONG SERVICES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/leading-song-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/leading-song-services/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LEADING SONG SERVICES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ways of Structuring Song Services&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Begin with a passage of scripture, an event, a parable, etc. Hymnals normally have a scripture index that indicates the connection between hymns and scripture passages. Before each song the leader or someone in the assembly can read a passage that correlates with the overall theme or the distinctive point of the upcoming song.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pick a theme and sing songs that fit with it.  Hymnals have topical indices in the back that facilitate finding songs in that hymnal which belong to many relevant topics. If the body of the hymnal is topically arranged, you can turn to that section of the hymnal and sing one song after another. This format is useful especially if the whole service is dedicated to singing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PASSAGE USEFUL FOR BAPTISM MEDITATIONS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/passage-useful-for-baptism-meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/passage-useful-for-baptism-meditations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PASSAGE USEFUL FOR BAPTISM MEDITATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statements of the Great Commission&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 28:18-20; Mark 16:15; Luke 24:44-49; Acts 1:8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Accounts of Baptism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 8:4-8 + 12-13&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;8:26-39&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;9:10-19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10:34-48&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:12-15a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:25-34&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(19:1-7)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;22:6-16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;26:12-20&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Texts that describe John’s baptism or give accounts of Johannine baptism are not particularly appropriate for Christian baptisms. The meaning of the two baptisms is different as illustrated by the baptizing in the name of Christ those disciples of John Paul found in Ephesus (Acts 19:1-7). Reading the account of Jesus’ own baptism would not be natural for this same reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STEWARDSHIP PASSAGES</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/stewardship-passages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/stewardship-passages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STEWARDSHIP PASSAGES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Samuel 24:24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Chronicles 29:14-17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psalms 24:1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ecclesiastes 5:10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 6:2-4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6:19-21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10:8b (7-10)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;19:16-26&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark 12:41-44 (= Luke 21:1-4)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luke 3:11-12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6:27-35&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;18:28-30&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 2:44-47a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:32-35&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11:27-30&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20:35&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romans 12:3-6a, 8b&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians 4:7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6:19b-20a&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15:54-16:8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 8-9: a number of passages in these two chapters are useful for stewardship &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;thoughts. Among them are particularly 8:2-3, 5, 7-8, 14-15; 9:6-7, 10-11, &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;12-13&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 1:4-14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:28&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
