<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DOCTRINAL Summaries on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/doctrinal-summaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DOCTRINAL Summaries on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/doctrinal-summaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY OF CONVICTIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/summary-of-convictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/summary-of-convictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY OF CONVICTIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Christian worldview is interpersonal. The interpersonal “category” is the ultimate frame of reference that qualifies and limits the impersonal realities that are also part of full picture. Some major aspects of Christianity are summarized below in ways that correlate with this understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture: Special revelation is interpersonal communication from God to mankind, available to us in written form. Although God could have chosen to relate to us in some other fashion, he spoke to most people through representatives whose messages are preserved in the Old and New Testament writings. We speak of those writings as inerrant relative to the (a) intended (b) content of (c) scripture as such.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SURVEY OF CHRISTIAN DOCTRINE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/survey-of-christian-doctrine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/survey-of-christian-doctrine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SURVEY OF CHRISTIAN DOCTRINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BIBLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture is the complete word of God written and sufficiently accurate in origin and preservation to accomplish what God sent it to accomplish (Isaiah 55:11). He sent it through chosen representatives endowed with the messages he revealed to them and with the ability to correctly express it to the ones he wanted to hear it. Consequently, non-canonical writings have the status, at best, of devotional writings (Apocrypha and tradition).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE BIG PICTURE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-big-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-big-picture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE BIG PICTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest plagues in Bible study is a failure to see the “big picture.” We tend to read a verse, think about it, and discuss it. As a result, that statement gets lifted from its setting and put in the context of our interests or problems even when it may not belong there. Foreign ideas come into the picture because we do not keep context in mind. Bible study needs to cover large portions to keep in sight the flow of thought. In addition, the purpose and character of Christian understanding must provide the framework for individual doctrines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WHAT CHRISTIANS IDEALLY BELIEVE AND PRACTICE:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/what-christians-ideally-believe-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/what-christians-ideally-believe-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHAT CHRISTIANS IDEALLY BELIEVE AND PRACTICE:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A SUMMARY DESCRIPTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian churches began as an effort to foster Christian unity by returning to scripture alone for the operation of the body of Christ and by setting aside items that have crept into Christendom from outside the New Testament. The conviction has been that division arose in part from such extras. But creating unity requires more than getting rid of what causes division; it also requires what Christ’s people must stand for. Below are characteristic beliefs and practices associated with these churches generally, though certainly not with them only.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
