<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>INTERPRETATION on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/interpretation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in INTERPRETATION on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/interpretation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PRIME PASSAGES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/prime-passages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/prime-passages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRIME PASSAGES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 3:20: “He named his wife Eve because she was the mother of all living.” Evolution&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pictures descent as a group process instead of something that derives from one&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pair of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 3:22: “Man has become like one of us.” Trinity in the Old Testament.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cp. also Isaiah 6:8.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exodus 3:14: God’s self-existence (aseity). “I am because I am.” He is independent being; there&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;is no higher frame of reference than God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MISUSED BIBLICAL TEXTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/misused-biblical-texts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/misused-biblical-texts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MISUSED BIBLICAL TEXTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comments below have more to do with interpretation mistakes than with false ideas. Regardless of the correctness of the beliefs involved, many texts do not indicate them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers misuse scriptures for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) Texts get quoted incorrectly in popular usage. “Money is the root of all evil,” for example, misquotes the text, “The love of money is the root of all evil.” [incorrect quotation]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(2) The parts of a text get connected the wrong way. “By grace you are saved through faith, and that [faith] is not of yourselves; it is a gift from God.” That does not refer to faith, but to the salvation indicated in the verb—as the neuter form for “that” in the Greek text shows. [internal misconnection]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GREEK HELPS IN NEW TESTAMENT INTERPRETATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/greek-helps-in-new-testament-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/greek-helps-in-new-testament-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GREEK HELPS IN NEW TESTAMENT INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general, Greek raises possibilities of interpretation we would not think from the English wording. Sometimes the Greek eliminates ideas the English wording might suggest. The Greek helps us understand why translations differ at certain points, and alerts us to ambiguities in the original text so we do not get dogmatic about a certain idea in the passage. Greek awareness enables us to use study tools like Greek concordance, lexicons, and commentaries that discuss the original text.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VALUES OF BIBLICAL LANGUAGES FOR BIBLE STUDY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/values-of-biblical-languages-for-bible-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/values-of-biblical-languages-for-bible-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VALUES OF BIBLICAL LANGUAGES FOR BIBLE STUDY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing biblical languages does not leave you so much at the mercy of translations. One disadvantage of having to work through a translation is that (a) no two languages match up exactly. A vocabulary item in one language seldom has the same range of denotations and connotations as the closest corresponding word(s) in another. The same thing applies to phrases, sentences, word endings, and particularly idioms, a culture’s customary usages of its language’s mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8. Hindrances to interpretation 	             Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/8-hindrances-to-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/8-hindrances-to-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several situations foster misinterpretation:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) adverse consequences would come from taking a certain position (persecution, being ostracized from a fellowship, loss of a ministry or a job)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(2) competition situations (debates)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(3) hurried circumstances (deadlines)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(4) emotional situations (anger, depression, fear)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(5) the believe that the Spirit is providing the interpretation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(6) partial information (starting to work on answers before assembling&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;all the information it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. Pride (attitude)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;**John 8:37&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B. Interchange of Nature, State, and Action Terms                Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/b-interchange-of-nature-state-and-action-terms-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/b-interchange-of-nature-state-and-action-terms-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As to words, people shift categories without shifting them as to concepts, because the categories are interconnected in actual experience. Being, action, and relationship are equally present in any real event, but with the mind we can differentiate between them. So language, which reflects the subjective activity of sensory perception and mental conception, differentiates between the aspects of an event even though they are objectively interrelated. If we do not distinguish language and reality, we take a point stated about one aspect and slide it onto another. Furthermore, language itself may use a nature term to refer to an action or to state reality. If readers do not keep in mind the nature of the issue, they can make all kinds of false inferences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B. Misidentifying the genre	                 Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/b-misidentifying-the-genre-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/b-misidentifying-the-genre-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The genre issue comes into the reading of Genesis 1-11, the Book of Job, the Book of Jonah, and apocalyptic works like Revelation, Ezekiel, and Daniel. History is more replete with names, places, sequences of time; but myth, saga, novelle, and the like, may have these elements as well. Especially in myth, the place where an event happens may not be of prime importance because myth uses story form to teach timeless, universal ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>b. Presuppositions (accompanying misinformation)         Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/b-presuppositions-accompanying-misinformation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/b-presuppositions-accompanying-misinformation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Different kinds of presuppositions include (1) preliminary ideas from which further ideas derive. Presuppositions, or pre-understanding, lie ahead of the present matter. They color what we read and hear on this matter. An example of presupposition would be the idea that what works is good (pragmatism).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presuppositions can be (2) larger constructs that qualify statements about matters within them. One big issue in contemporary hermeneutics is the question about implicit cultural limitation. Revelation critiques culture and stands in prophetic relationship to it. Nevertheless, some have entertained the idea that Paul and others sought to show they were not cultural subversives. On the basis of the way they deal with slavery, table fellowship (eating with someone), salutation (speaking to someone), dress code (veil-wearing, hair length), this thinking pattern has been applied to (a) egalitarian vs. hierarchical structure of marriage and (b) homosexual behavior between consenting partners. One issue is whether such behaviors mean the same thing in our setting as they did then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIBLICAL FIGURES OF SPEECH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/biblical-figures-of-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/biblical-figures-of-speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BIBLICAL FIGURES OF SPEECH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;( ) = observations not expressly made by scripture itself&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boldface headings represent clusters of images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;means the concordance has been used to create the list&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note distinction between figures of speech and figures of thought.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note also the distinction between schemes (figures of thought) and tropes (= figures of words).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Figures of thought are represented by parables, allegories, Christ-Adam parallel, Hagar-Sarah, and so on. The words are literal, but their referent is substituted for the reality you mean. Hugh Blair, Lectures on Rhetoric and Belles Littres (Vol. 1). Carbondale, IL: SIU Press, 1965. 275 pp.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C. Confusing example and precedent 	            Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/c-confusing-example-and-precedent-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/c-confusing-example-and-precedent-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interpretation deals with what scripture teaches about doctrinal matters to be believed. It deals with what scripture teaches about practices to be done. Within “praxis” lies a further distinction between example and precedent—between what was done and what was meant to be done by other people thereafter. Establishing precedent has two steps: (1) showing that such and such was, in fact, a New Testament pattern; and (2) showing that the pattern was meant to apply universally and permanently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C. Consequent nature of appropriating scripture (illumination)      Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/c-consequent-nature-of-appropriating-scripture-illumination-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/c-consequent-nature-of-appropriating-scripture-illumination-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The meaning of “interpret”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpretation involves (1) discovering the referent, (2) connecting the referent by consistency with the rest of the big picture (integration), and (3) making application to issues the author does not address, including the modern needs of believers. The first two aspects belong to “what it meant”; the last is “what it means.” We “interpret” (exegesis) to discover “meaning” (integration) so we can “understand” and have “wisdom” (application). Until we reach a level of understanding that enables us to use what we know, we do not “understand” in a “useful” way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>c. Irrationalism (improper thinking patterns)	             Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/c-irrationalism-improper-thinking-patterns-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/c-irrationalism-improper-thinking-patterns-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(1) Irrationalism occurs when feelings become the final frame of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;reference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Viewpoints based on feelings can come from confusing feelings with the work of the Spirit. People do not consider changing beliefs because they feel that the viewpoint they have must be right. There is danger in supposing that the sense (feeling) of certainty is a reason for certainty—that the Spirit places it directly in the mind. There is no more reason to assume that happens in regard to a feeling than a thought. In either case, if people cannot differentiate between something planted by the Spirit and their own thoughts and feelings, they should not consider it divine in origin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON “FULFILL”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/comments-on-fulfill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/comments-on-fulfill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON “FULFILL”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We may wonder what definition to put on “fulfill” if it covers such a wide range of ideas as (1) a prediction’s coming to pass, (2) an event that illustrates a generalized principle (Acts 1:20?), (3) the accomplishment of something that was also the purpose of something else (the gospel’s fulfilling the Mosaic law: Matthew 5:17; cp. Romans 3:31?), (4) an obedience that accomplished what was commanded (Romans 13:8-10), (5) a necessary inference from another passage, (6) a meeting of the requirements for something (“This course fulfills the requirement”), and (7) a mere formal similarity (? Matthew 2:18, 23; perhaps 2:15).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONCEPT INVENTORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/concept-inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/concept-inventory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CONCEPT INVENTORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For interpreters to do their work properly, they must be able to bring to the text an awareness of as many linguistic and conceptual features as appear and are presupposed in the materials they are trying to understand. Jesus’ hearers in John 7:34-36 wondered whether he would go among the Gentiles or Diasporic Jews when he said, “You cannot go where I am going.” They could not understand him because in their minds they did not have the possibility of Messiah’s ascension to heaven. The same thing happened with the Sadducees when they presented Jesus with the problem about a woman married to seven brothers in succession. They did not understand the power of God to generate new possibilities beyond what they could already conceive of on the basis of past experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D.	Adopting an inappropriate model (cp. allegorizing comparisons and nature of the</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/d-adopting-an-inappropriate-model-cp-allegorizing-comparisons-and-nature-of-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/d-adopting-an-inappropriate-model-cp-allegorizing-comparisons-and-nature-of-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;D.&#x9;Adopting an inappropriate model (cp. allegorizing comparisons and nature of the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;case)&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;                     Virgil Warre, PhD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adopting an inappropriate model appears in cases that deal with analogical reasoning. It is a confusion that comes into discussions when people try to use illustrations. When the model is off, inferences made from it can be foreign to the topic at hand because the model has elements in it that are not in the thing it is called on to explain..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E. Misidentifying the Intended Reference (frame of reference)      Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/e-misidentifying-the-intended-reference-frame-of-reference-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/e-misidentifying-the-intended-reference-frame-of-reference-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A word, phrase, or general presentation does not mean whatever the expressions could mean; it means what fits the immediate flow of thought, the distant context, and the nature of the case. Readers need to look for the relevant contrast over against which the writer is speaking. They need to properly identify the topic an author is speaking about. They must transcend their existential situation and personality bent lest they put biblical statements in a foreign framework; otherwise, the dogmatic and practical principles get ahead of the exegetical one (see entries above). Readers have to read the biblical writer “on his own terms”; they have to “get inside the writer’s mind.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F. Confusing language and reality	                Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/f-confusing-language-and-reality-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/f-confusing-language-and-reality-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since language is based on perception, it expresses a person’s subjective viewpoint. Consequently, (a) statements can be made from the way things look more than from the way they really are (phenomenological language). In a related matter, (b) language does not reproduce the whole of the reality it refers to, but only enough to let the hearer know what the speaker is talking about. From previous experience or explanation, a hearer fills in the rest of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>G.	Reading restrictive for nonrestrictive (or positive)	               Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/g-reading-restrictive-for-nonrestrictive-or-positive-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/g-reading-restrictive-for-nonrestrictive-or-positive-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Restrictive means limited to some portion less than all: “They are good people” (their relatives are not good). Nonrestrictive means all the group—at least generally—is characterized that way: “They are good people (I am not talking about anybody else here, and, yes, I am aware of the rotter that abandoned his family years ago).” Both statements indicate what the speaker means, not what is true or what else he knows about other people or about any exceptions to his point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GETTING THE POINT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/getting-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/getting-the-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GETTING THE POINT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION: The Nature of Language Communication&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. An allegory: parallels between working a puzzle and interpreting the Bible&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not everything is all there together; we have to put it together. The Bible has a historical organization and a practical application to specific situations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are tempted to start putting pieces together before we get all the pieces turned over and sorted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We begin by turning the pieces over and sorting them by color and perhaps shape, a procedure comparable to getting the data together before beginning to work on a conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H. Technicalizing terminology		 Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/h-technicalizing-terminology-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/h-technicalizing-terminology-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Assuming technical usage in the scripture is a way of trying to get something more specific out of a text than the author meant. Technicalizing is a kind of restrictive reading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technical contrasts with positive, general, or descriptive usage. Technicalizing shows up in taking words as appellative names rather than as descriptive ones: church of Christ, church of God, disciples become Church of Christ, Church of God, Disciples. Technicalizing leads to expectancy for uniform usage. It specifies a smaller group within those who could be described by the word picture. In church offices, elder means more than “older”; it ‎means a(n older) man who oversees a group of believers as when qualifications are listed and a process of selection takes place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HERMENEUTICS: GETTING THE POINT:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-getting-the-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-getting-the-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HERMENEUTICS: GETTING THE POINT:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AN OUTLINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTION: Nature of Language Communication&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Parallels between working a puzzle and interpreting the Bible&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Nature of language&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Language is always from the subjective viewpoint.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;Literal language can occur even though language comes from the subjective side.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.&#x9;Figurative language is a possibility because language comes from the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;subjective side.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c.&#x9;Phenomenological language arises from the fact that language comes from the subjective side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I. Setting the conclusion and then working toward it	             Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/i-setting-the-conclusion-and-then-working-toward-it-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/i-setting-the-conclusion-and-then-working-toward-it-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ways of referring to the problem&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. It is a “foregone conclusion.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b. Prooftexting&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c. Getting the dogmatic principle ahead of the exegetical one&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d. Getting the practical problem ahead of the exegetical one&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e. Not reading the Bible “on its own terms”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pattern of the procedure (the reason it has apparent validity)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People may “work backwards” from what works or what they have experienced to what they believe. At each step in the process, they choose what hooks up with other points that lead toward the desired conclusion. Setting the conclusion and working to it, yields firm interpretations in ambiguous cases, and twists statements in the direction of the foregone conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>II. 	SELECTED LINGUISTIC PHENOMENA (Note Dr. Warren’s Ph.D. dissertation The Implication of Divine Self-Consistency for the Doctrine of Natural Depravity, pp. 152-70.)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/ii-selected-linguistic-phenomena-note-dr-warrens-phd-dissertation-the-implication-of-divine-self-consistency-for-the-doctrine-of-natural-depravity-pp-152-70/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/ii-selected-linguistic-phenomena-note-dr-warrens-phd-dissertation-the-implication-of-divine-self-consistency-for-the-doctrine-of-natural-depravity-pp-152-70/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;II. &#x9;SELECTED LINGUISTIC PHENOMENA (Note Dr. Warren’s Ph.D. dissertation The Implication of Divine Self-Consistency for the Doctrine of Natural Depravity, pp. 152-70.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Streamlining Causal Distinctions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Streamlining causal distinctions is a shorthand way of speaking about causal relationships. It occurs especially when the exact manner of connection is unimportant for present purposes. It can create ambiguity because the (1) mode of causality and (2) the directness of causation get blurred. All languages streamline causality and interchange modality, but Hebrew does so more than English and other modern languages do in cultures impacted by scientific precision. Much of the “God talk” in scripture comes to mean something different when English speakers use it; they bring the verbiage into their language without adjusting its import. By allowing variation within the mode, Semitic thought tends to be general and holistic in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>III. GENERAL MECHANICS BEHIND INTERPRETATION         Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/iii-general-mechanics-behind-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/iii-general-mechanics-behind-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The “big three” in interpretation are (1) the law of harmony, (2) the law of contrast, and (3) the nature of the case. All three amount to one thing—the law of harmony, but we sort them out to stress the peculiar contribution each aspect makes to the whole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Law of harmony (analogy)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two things or two ideas can have varying degrees and kinds of relationship. From one extreme to the other is (1) what is positively determined by something else,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPRETATION, HERMENEUTICS, THEOLOGICAL METHOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/interpretation-hermeneutics-theological-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/interpretation-hermeneutics-theological-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPRETATION, HERMENEUTICS, THEOLOGICAL METHOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In dealing with controversial passages, interpreters make their choice by their understanding of the big picture, the general understanding, the conceptual context. They follow this procedure even with passages that at first glance would call for a more likely-sounding interpretation. The readers may choose a less likely sounding meaning because of the general understanding they bring to the text. In such cases, where more than one reading is possible, the text doesn’t prove either idea that the readers are bringing to it; that text rises no higher than confirmatory evidence in contrast to primary proof. The passage falls out of the process of arriving at the general understanding. That general understanding must come from someplace else or from other places taken together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTRODUCTORY CONSIDERATIONS ON JONAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/introductory-considerations-on-jonah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/introductory-considerations-on-jonah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTORY CONSIDERATIONS ON JONAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Observations against Jonah as history&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Overabundance of extreme miracle (12 miracles in 48 verses)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. The storm that arose (1:4)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b. The lot that fell on Jonah (1:7)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c. The stilling of the storm (1:15)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d. The preparation of a “great fish” (1:17)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e. The fish’s swallowing Jonah (1:17)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;f. The fish’s vomiting him on dry land (2:10)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;g. Jonah’s living through the experience (2:1-9)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IV. INTERPRETING VARIOUS CLASSES OF LITERATURE      Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/iv-interpreting-various-classes-of-literature-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/iv-interpreting-various-classes-of-literature-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Examples of biblical literary genres: apocalyptic, benedictions, covenant, diatribe, didactic, drama, epistles, fable, history, lament, law, myth, parables, poetry, prophecy (predictive), proverbs, psalms, riddles, speeches (sermons, prayer, dialog), wisdom literature&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Prime concerns&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The degree of figurativeness expected in various genres&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Figurativeness and literalness are matters of degree. The degree of figurativeness depends on the purpose of communication. If the purpose is to inform, the writing less figurative; if it is to motivate, it may be more figurative. Poetry and prophecy foster figurative expression; history and law have less figurativeness. Didactic material lies between the extremes. High levels of figurativeness do not occur so often in passages that seek to inform, because figurativeness works against clarity. Figurative language is used more for confirming truths already understood, exhortation, and impression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. Confusing advice and commandment	                Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/j-confusing-advice-and-commandment-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/j-confusing-advice-and-commandment-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Commandment means something that excludes alternative behaviors. It applies to (a) moral law, which goes back to first principles for determining right action. Moral law comes from divine purpose and the nature of the case. It distinguishes between natural and unnatural. Since moral commandments reflect purpose and the nature of things based on purpose, people obey moral commandments to bring about a more satisfying life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commandment applies to (b) positive commandment. Although other possibilities exist, this one is specified—perhaps for “good order.” Positive commandment rests more on authority because it addresses appropriate and more appropriate. (The purpose of positive commandment is nicely put by C. S. Lewis in Perelandra, p. 118.) It is a commandment obeyed out of love and deference more than from necessity, fear, or duty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JEWISH EXPECTATIONS OF THE KINGDOM OF GOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/jewish-expectations-of-the-kingdom-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/jewish-expectations-of-the-kingdom-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JEWISH EXPECTATIONS OF THE KINGDOM OF GOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AND SOME IMPLICATIONS FOR NEW TESTAMENT INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines for biblical interpretation include the “big three”: (1) the principle of harmony, (2) the principle of contrast, and (3) the nature of the case. The first derives from the nature of scripture, which as a matter of principle we accept as true throughout and therefore harmonious. The second principle derives from the nature of language, which conveys ideas relative to a framework of thought. The last principle derives from experience, a prime resource for knowing the way things are. All three principles interrelate and impact the interpretation of human language in general and scripture in particular.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NEW TESTAMENT INTERPRETATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/new-testament-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/new-testament-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NEW TESTAMENT INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF OLD TESTAMENT TEXTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several hermeneutical questions arise about the New Testament writers’ use of Old Testament texts. In cases like Matthew’s use of Hosea 11:1, we may broaden the definitions of prophecy and fulfillment as a way of legitimizing his use of the prophet’s comment. Making this move reflects a prior commitment to the principle that inspiration makes New Testament authors “forever correct.” People’s prior commitment to “inerrancy” causes them to take a positive view on a text that they might not otherwise have chosen or would otherwise consider a matter of opinion. That does not weaken its validity; it merely demonstrates consistency. We cannot with finality settle some questions directly. We take views on derivative issues that harmonize with primary views. On the other hand, the possibility of other imaginable reasons for a writer’s use of an earlier text does not invalidate one affirmed because of assumed inerrancy. We are involved here in the distinction between a presuppositional and phenomenological approach to the view of scripture. Without the assumption that divine inspiration kept writers from error, we would have less justification for using insights from one writer to clarify ambiguous words of another writer, for harmonizing two authors who could otherwise mean incompatible things, for interpreting biblical statements so as not to conflict with information we learn from science, for choosing this interpretation from among two or more otherwise equally plausible views, given only the text itself, or even for taking a less likely sounding interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMPLICATION OF DIVINE SELF-CONSISTENCY FOR THE DOCTRINE OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-implication-of-divine-self-consistency-for-the-doctrine-of-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-implication-of-divine-self-consistency-for-the-doctrine-of-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMPLICATION OF DIVINE SELF-CONSISTENCY FOR THE DOCTRINE OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A BIBLICAL-SYSTEMATIC APPROACH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EXEGETICAL IMPASSE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A standoff has persisted in exegesis between Calvinistic and non-Calvinistic thought on the nature of human kind largely because no necessary resolution can come at the level of individual passages that have implications for anthropology. A few examples illustrate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) Psalm 51:10 says, “Create in me a clean heart, O God; and renew a right spirit within me” (cp. 36:26); Ezekiel 18:31 shows another emphasis: “Make for yourselves a new heart and a new spirit.” The difficulty is whether Psalm 51:10 interprets Ezekiel 18:31 or vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V. PITFALLS IN INTERPRETATION  	               Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/v-pitfalls-in-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/v-pitfalls-in-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Allegorizing the comparison&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The allegorizing problem applies to all expressions that make comparisons: similes, metaphors, parables, illustrations (vs. examples). Comparison does not mean likeness in every respect, but in the respects the speaker indicates. All comparisons relate figure and fact as overlapping circles. Some things about the figure do not apply to the fact. When hearers press the comparison to aspects outside the purpose of the illustration,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;they abandon the speaker’s authority for claiming those likeness. They commit the equivalent of what in logic is called “the fallacy of four terms”; that is, the middle term does not refer to the same thing in both statements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VI. TESTING OTHER PEOPLE’S INTERPRETATION                   Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/vi-testing-other-peoples-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/vi-testing-other-peoples-interpretation-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interpretation is a community effort. In practice, Christians do not just individually interact with the scripture; they interact with each other as well. For biblical interpretation purposes, we need to understand how language works both in studying scripture and in teaching and hearing the way of the Lord more perfectly. Theology as a community effort includes studying the history of Christian thought; it provides another resource for biblical understanding. It identifies the appropriate role of tradition as teacher rather than authority. Christians are church theologians, never professional theologians; they do something with what they learn (education for use), and they do it in community with other people inside and outside the body of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VII. HERMENEUTICS AND LIFE 	                Virgil Warren, PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/vii-hermeneutics-and-life-virgil-warren-phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/vii-hermeneutics-and-life-virgil-warren-phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A. The process of hermeneutics and life [understanding the biblical message]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Goal: to find out what the scripture means by experiencing what it says; do it to understand it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Passages take on a liveliness and relevance because of experiences we face. Meaning is not just objective significance, but subjective impact. The two correspond as to content, but the impact comes from the doing. Understanding through interpretation (validity) leads to belief (truth) and obedience (commitment), which turns around and clarifies the understanding. As reciprocation occurs between parts and whole in biblical-systematic interpretation, so also reciprocation occurs between text and experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WISDOM AND LAW: DIVORCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/wisdom-and-law-divorce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/wisdom-and-law-divorce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WISDOM AND LAW: DIVORCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The difference between law and wisdom as well as the relationship between them showed up in an article on the adult offspring of divorce by Irene Sege published in the Boston Globe (see The Manhattan Mercury for Friday, December 20, 1995, D1). Generalizations about these young people show that their parents’ divorce measurably affects a sizable portion of their children when they grow up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a matter of wisdom, then, not to enter marriage without the most earnest intentions of maintaining the future marriage for the children’s sake—among other things. And, it is likewise a matter of wisdom to go together into marriage with a set of values that increases the likelihood of the marriage’s permanence. This kind of observation is built on reality as based on human nature (vs. purpose or relationship) and has the pattern of tendency (vs. uniformity).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADULTERY, DIVORCE, AND REMARRIAGE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/adultery-divorce-and-remarriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/adultery-divorce-and-remarriage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADULTERY, DIVORCE, AND REMARRIAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;The elements of the issue diagrammed&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God’s Intentional Will                               God’s Conditional Will&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(law) (ideal) (righteousness)                           (law) (real)  (redemption)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;divorce                           permanent singleness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;marriage       &#x9; &#x9;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;____________________________ I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;remarriage possibility&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;New Testament teachings about divorce and remarriage: Matthew 5:31-32; 19:3-12; Mark 10:2-12; Luke 16:8; Romans 7:2-3; 1 Corinthians 7:1-17, 25-40&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt  Mt  Mk  Lk  Ro 1Cor&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5   19   10   16   7    7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Man is not to divide what God has united in marriage.   &#x9;             x   x      x     x   x   10-11&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BLESSINGS AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE KINGDOM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/blessings-and-responsibilities-of-the-kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/blessings-and-responsibilities-of-the-kingdom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BLESSINGS AND RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE KINGDOM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first portion of Matthew 5-7 has to do with the first “petal on our daisy”: Blessings and Responsibilities (5:3-16). Before looking at the meaning of the verses individually, we must see how the structure of the sermon may affect its interpretation. Since it is wisdom literature, it is loosely structured. The significance of this point can be appreciated by looking at Luke’s Sermon on the Plain (6:20-49), which has several close parallels with the Sermon on the Mount. Despite similarities many interpreters consider them different presentations, partly because they may fall at different points in Jesus’ ministry. Regardless of whether they are two accounts of the same sermon or different accounts of two sermons, Luke’s rearrangement of similar material shows that we should be cautious about making too much out of connectors between blocks of material. In other words, context connections in wisdom literature are less helpful in interpretation, because the writer tends to connect his paragraphs more loosely. They are self-contained units more than interdependent ones. In yet other places Luke has bits and pieces that appear in Matthew 5-7. Luke 13:22-24ff. compares with Matthew 7:21-23 on the judgment scene and the narrow gate. Luke 16:17-18 parallels Matthew 5:18 and 32, which includes the “jot and tittle” statement and the ethics of marriage. The connections we see between portions of the sermon may not have been as strong in Jesus’ mind as they might look to us. The structure of Matthew’s account may be more apparent than real. Observations based on sequence and association may be well to make, but their validity probably rests more on the nature of adjacent subjects than on their placement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BUILDING LIFE ON A FIRM FOUNDATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/building-life-on-a-firm-foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/building-life-on-a-firm-foundation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BUILDING LIFE ON A FIRM FOUNDATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HATE, ADULTERY, AND DIVORCE:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hate-adultery-and-divorce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hate-adultery-and-divorce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HATE, ADULTERY, AND DIVORCE:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5:21-32&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5:21-6:18 may be regarded as an outgrowth of the comment in 5:20 that people’s righteousness should exceed the righteousness of the scribes and Pharisees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Murder, adultery, divorce, and the lesser sins of anger (5:22a), hate, name calling (5:22b), revenge (5:38-42), and capricious oath taking (5:33-37) are all of the same sort: they depersonalize other people. Depersonalizing relationships can be done by&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a)&#x9;legalizing them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HYPOCRISY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hypocrisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hypocrisy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HYPOCRISY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though the Sermon on the Mount is wisdom literature and therefore less structured, it has pattern and carries a unifying theme. The initial set of beatitudes introduces statements of responsibility for being God’s light and salt in the world. To accomplish that purpose, Jesus’ disciples must correct their thinking at points like the ones he mentions. We should not misconstrue this correcting as discarding previous revelation, but as fulfilling it by proper understanding. In 5:20 Jesus tells his followers that their righteousness needs to exceed that of contemporary religious leaders, a comment clarified by six illustrations. Under the contrast formula “You have heard that it was said by them of old time . . . but I tell you     . . .” Jesus discusses murder, adultery and divorce, oath taking, revenge, and love. Chapter 6:1-18 is a further unit about hypocrisy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JESUS AND THE LAW</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/jesus-and-the-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/jesus-and-the-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JESUS AND THE LAW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our study of the Sermon on the Mount brings us to Matthew 5:17-20, the second “petal” on the daisy. We have entitled it “Jesus and the Law” because it shows how his ministry and teaching relate to God’s earlier revelation. This paragraph introduces Jesus’ objection to the Pharisees. He contrasts his teaching more with theirs than with the Old Testament Law itself. The verses deal with his concern that people not misunderstand what he is teaching.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OATHS AND ADVERSARIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/oaths-and-adversaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/oaths-and-adversaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OATHS AND ADVERSARIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This chapter looks at Matthew 5:33-48, dealing first with verses 33-37 on taking oaths. Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You have heard that it was said to them of old time, “You shall not swear falsely, but shall perform to the Lord your oaths.” But I tell you not to swear at all, neither by heaven, for it is the throne of God, nor by earth, for it is the footstool of his feet, neither by Jerusalem, for it is the city of the great King. Neither shall you swear by your head, because you cannot make one hair white or black. But let your conversation be yes, yes and no, no. Whatever is more than these comes from the evil one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OVERCOMING THE CRITICAL MIND SET</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/overcoming-the-critical-mind-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/overcoming-the-critical-mind-set/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OVERCOMING THE CRITICAL MIND SET&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Jesus says, “Do not judge,” he raises four questions: (1) What does judge mean? (2) Why do we do it? (3) Why should we stop it? (4) How can we stop it? We can study Matthew 7:1-6 by asking these questions about the text.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. What does judge mean?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Judge means more than “evaluate.” In 7:6 Jesus warns his listeners not to cast pearls before swine or give holy things to dogs. To take that advice, we have to make a judgment as to who is, so to speak, a “dog” or “pig.” We must always discern the difference between right and wrong or effective and ineffective, and we are called on to warn fellowmen about such things. Nevertheless, on occasion Matthew 7:1 is quoted in self-defense by people appropriately confronted with some characteristic sin. But, since fellow Christians have mutual responsibility to lead each other to repentance, Jesus does not forbid reaching a verdict on the morality of someone’s behavior and approaching him about it respectfully.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STRENGTH FOR TODAY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/strength-for-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/strength-for-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STRENGTH FOR TODAY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 6:19-34 gives us an opportunity to use a simple method of Bible study. It consists of asking a question and reading scripture with an eye for answers. We may be surprised at how often scripture addresses such questions. Familiar scriptures take on a fresh light because new experiences establish a new context for seeing new applications. The answers were not noticed before because we were not prepared for them. Matthew 6 offers insights into matters we never thought the Bible even addressed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TALKING TO THE FATHER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/talking-to-the-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/talking-to-the-father/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TALKING TO THE FATHER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our study of Matthew 5-7 has progressed around the daisy outline to the model prayer. We discussed 6:1-18 under the heading of hypocrisy. The accompanying diagram shows how the model prayer fits inside that larger portion. Jesus’ comments about giving, prayer, and fasting follow a pattern that includes “they have their reward,” doing their alms, praying and fasting “in secret,” and “your Father will reward you openly.” His statements about prayer lead into the “model prayer,” a subset in this format for 6:1-18.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE MEANING OF THE GOLDEN RULE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-meaning-of-the-golden-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-meaning-of-the-golden-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MEANING OF THE GOLDEN RULE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isaiah 35:8 prophesied that there would be “a highway of holiness” that only the redeemed would pass over. A wayfaring man, though a fool, would not err in it. Life gets complicated sometimes, but scripture teaches one principle that simplifies it for everyone regardless of capacity or station.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On two occasions the Jewish religious leaders asked Jesus what the most important commandment was. Matthew 22:34 records one of the incidents:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE SERMON AS A WHOLE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-sermon-as-a-whole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-sermon-as-a-whole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE SERMON AS A WHOLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 5-7 records the Sermon on the Mount. This study presents thirteen lessons on that material. First, we look at the structure of the whole presentation. It is “wisdom literature,” an especially appropriate expression in this case because Jesus closes with an illustration about a wise man who built his house on ledge rock. “Wisdom” lies not only in knowing what to do, but in doing it. It is application in addition to information. Wisdom is living life among men according to the will of God. It means more than avoiding evil and doing good; it means aiming at doing best. That is always the wise way to live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE VALUE OF THE GOLDEN RULE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-value-of-the-golden-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-value-of-the-golden-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE VALUE OF THE GOLDEN RULE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The previous study on Matthew 7:12 dealt with the meaning of the Golden Rule. This study looks at the impact of the Golden Rule on individuals and on their relationships. In the parallel between “[Do] [to others] [as you would have others do to you]” and “[Love] [your neighbor] [as yourself],” we made two primary observations. (1) Do replaces love; so love is an action that can be commanded. That doing is a giving of ourselves for the joy of others. Often love means giving of ourselves for the needs of others, but we can also love God, who “is not served by men’s hands as though he needed anything” (Acts 17:25). It is better, then, to define love broadly enough to include loving him. When we meet people’s needs, we are increasing their happiness; so love becomes self-giving for the joy of others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIBLICAL BRAIN TEASERS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/biblical-brain-teasers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/biblical-brain-teasers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BIBLICAL BRAIN TEASERS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of the examples below raise issues that are not in themselves very important. We offer them, however, as (1) “exercises” in hermeneutical creativity on matters where frankly it does not hurt to be wrong. Besides, it is not healthy to get in the habit of “dodging” critical issues because they impact (2) evaluating biblical accuracy. Though the points themselves are often not significant, their existence in a religious text does raise a point that is significant—whether people can trust the biblical accounts. Distrusting them for unnecessary reasons should be avoided, and we cannot legitimately trust them without correct exegetical work as a means of properly avoiding unnecessary criticism of scripture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BRAIN TEASERS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/brain-teasers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/brain-teasers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BRAIN TEASERS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following examples provide occasions for working through paradoxes, apparent contradictions, hard sayings, and ambiguous comments. A summary of ways to resolve difficulties accompanies the course description and agenda sheets: “Resolving Apparent Contradictions in Scripture.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) Indicate the class, the assignment number, and your name at the top of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(b) Repeat the text of the brain teaser at the outset of the paper; otherwise, your answers will not be readily retrievable for future use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HARDENING PHARAOH’S HEART</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hardening-pharaohs-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hardening-pharaohs-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HARDENING PHARAOH’S HEART&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mode    Text                            Wording&#x9;sign             Pharaoh’s&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;offer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c&#x9;Ex 4:21&#x9;I will harden Pharaoh’s heart&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c         7:3&#x9;&amp;quot;   &amp;quot;        &amp;quot;             &amp;quot;           &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a         &#x9;      7:13&#x9;heart was hardened&#x9;(staff to snake)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a                7:22&#x9;    &amp;quot;      &amp;quot;         &amp;quot;&#x9;water to blood&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b  &#x9;      8:15&#x9;Pharaoh hardened his heart&#x9;frogs&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a&#x9;      8:19&#x9;heart was hardened&#x9;lice&#x9;go inside the country&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b&#x9;      8:32&#x9;Pharaoh hardened his heart&#x9;flies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a&#x9;      9:7&#x9;heart was stubborn&#x9;livestock plague&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hermeneutics A</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hermeneutics A&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpretation of texts often comes in terms of the assumed overall viewpoints, more than by the requirements of the text under discussion. Hence, we can’t solve the problem itself because we are not dealing with the whole viewpoint that gives credence to the idea on this text.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One approach to an unacceptable view is to show that each text used to support it can be handled in a way that fits with another view. When all the texts so used have been addressed in this way, no basis remains for the questionable idea. So, it is not a matter of disproving, but of showing that the other view cannot shoulder its positive burden of proof; so the view is at best a matter of opinion because it is a viewpoint based on inadequate evidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LOVE AND HATE IN SEMITIC PARLANCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/love-and-hate-in-semitic-parlance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/love-and-hate-in-semitic-parlance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LOVE AND HATE IN SEMITIC PARLANCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several well-known scriptures combine love and hate. They appear first as worded in the New American Standard Bible followed by the wording in the Conversational Version. The manner of expression in the latter represents what gets at the Hebrew idioms that impact this set of words. After the examples, there are notations about the rationale for the translation in the Conversional Version.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 29:31-30&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOME IMPLICATIONS OF LEGAL PROCESS FOR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/some-implications-of-legal-process-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/some-implications-of-legal-process-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOME IMPLICATIONS OF LEGAL PROCESS FOR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HERMENEUTICS, FAITH, AND PRACTICE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN THE CHRISTIAN SYSTEM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basic claim: law is artificial to interpersonal process and detrimental to Christianity; law impacts interpretation, faith, and practice. We are calling the Christian worldview “interpersonal” because persons in relationship are the most original, eternal, supreme, basic, pervasive, universal, and complex aspect of the system. Christianity’s prominent vocabulary deals with persons relating positively to one another: love, faith, grace, mercy, promise, truth (in communication), conscience, heart, mind, blessing, righteousness, reconciliation, joy (vs. happiness), humility, peace (vs. national tranquility), spirit (vs. physical circumcision for naturalization into a physical nation). All the features of interpersonalism contrast with their opposites. The first and second great commandments (cp. Golden Rule) deal with love, the summarizing, most important, outward-directed pattern of interpersonal action, which produces the other interpersonal actions. As Micah 6:8 said of old, “What does the Lord require of you but to do justly, love kindness, and walk humbly with your God” (cp. Deuteronomy 10:12-13; Isaiah 66:2).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STUDY METHODS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/study-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/study-methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STUDY METHODS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This write-up describes methods of study applied to the Book of Hebrews. It follows the examples in Merrill C. Tenney’s commentary on Galatians: The Charter of Christian Liberty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;The synthetic method&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read the Book of Hebrews in one siting to discover the author’s overall purpose in writing the book. In two or three pages, show how each section of the book (as you perceive it to be divided) relates to its purpose as determined above. Is there any one argument that pervades all the author’s individual arguments? Remember that the purpose of writing is not necessarily the same thing as some prominent theme of the book. Themes may be used to fulfill the purpose of writing. (Note Tenney, Galatians, pp. 25-35)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SYSTEMATIC INTERPRETATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/systematic-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/systematic-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SYSTEMATIC INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there a verse or set of verses in scripture that supports the hermeneutical principle (biblical/systematic) that specific passages are to be understood within the overall context of scripture itself, or is this a logical principle of interpretation put together from experience?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The question about systematic interpretation of the Bible can be asked about the interpretation of any body of communication. Systematic harmonization is the natural thing to do in interpretation; there is nothing surprising about it. We always take an individual comment in light of the whole conversation because we know enough about language to know that a person cannot say everything in every sentence. The same principle applies to a book or an author’s set of books. For the time being, we assume the author is speaking consistently between the parts of a conversation, between articles, or between books spread out even over several years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
