<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 Timothy on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 Timothy on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2 Timothy 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-timothy-chapter-1&#34;&gt;2 Timothy Chapter &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;Paul, apostle of Christ&lt;sup&gt;Messiah&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus by God’s will in regard to the life he promised in Christ Jesus, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;to Timothy, my dear son. Grace, mercy, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; peace from God the Father and Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&#34;section-ref&#34;&gt;2 Tim 1:1-2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;stirring-up-timothys-gift&#34;&gt;Stirring up Timothy’s Gift&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;As I remember you in my prayers day and night, I thank my ancestors’ God that I serve with a good conscience. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I really want to see you again because I’ve been remembering your tears. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I remember your sincere faith, &lt;em&gt;a faith&lt;/em&gt; your grandmother Lois and your mother Eunice had first. I’m sure it’s been in you, too, ever since. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;That’s why I’m reminding you to stir up the spiritual gift you have from the laying on of my hands. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;God hasn’t given us a timid mentality, but power, love, and self-discipline. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;So don’t be ashamed of the Lord’s mystery or of me his prisoner; suffer with me for the good news as God gives you strength. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;He has saved us and called us with a holy calling. What we can do ourselves doesn’t define &lt;em&gt;that calling&lt;/em&gt;. His purpose and grace define it, which he gave us in Christ Jesus before time began. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The coming of our Savior Christ Jesus now has revealed that purpose and grace. He destroyed death and brought life and immortality to light through the good news. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;He’s appointed me as a preacher, apostle, and teacher &lt;em&gt;of that good news&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;That’s why I’m suffering what &lt;em&gt;I am&lt;/em&gt;. But I’m not ashamed; I know who I’ve trusted, and I’m confident that he can keep what I entrusted to him till that day. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Hold onto the sound form of the message you’ve heard from me about the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;By the Holy Spirit who lives in us, keep what he’s entrusted &lt;em&gt;to you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#x9; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Timothy 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-timothy-chapter-2&#34;&gt;2 Timothy Chapter &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;So, my son, &lt;u&gt;you&lt;/u&gt; be strong in the grace that Christ Jesus &lt;em&gt;gives&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;What you’ve heard from me among many witnesses entrust to faithful men that can teach others. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Endure hardship with &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; like a good soldier of Christ Jesus. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;A soldier doesn’t get mixed up in the affairs of daily life while he’s a soldier. That way he can please his recruiter. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;An athlete doesn’t win the garland unless he competes by the rules. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;A laboring farmer should be first to share in his crops. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Think about what I’m saying; the Lord will help you understand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Timothy 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-timothy-chapter-3&#34;&gt;2 Timothy Chapter &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;Be aware that difficult times will come later on. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;People will be selfish, money-loving, proud and arrogant, slanderous, disobedient to parents, ungrateful, unholy, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;without natural affection, heartless, slanderous gossips, without self-control, vicious, not loving what’s good, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;treacherous, reckless, conceited, loving pleasure more than God. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;They’ll have the trappings of religion but deny its power. Avoid people like that. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;They’re the kind that sneak into families and seduce morally weak women that are weighed down with sins and&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;lured on by various desires, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;mas&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; are&lt;/em&gt; always learning but never able to find the truth. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Those who oppose the truth are like Jannes and Jambres, who opposed Moses. They’re corrupt in mind; they’re rejected as far as the faith is concerned. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;They won’t get anywhere because their foolishness will be obvious to everybody just like the foolishness of those &lt;em&gt;men&lt;/em&gt; was&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Timothy 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/2-timothy/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-timothy-chapter-4&#34;&gt;2 Timothy Chapter &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;I solemnly charge &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; in front of God and Christ Jesus—who will judge the living and the dead—and by his appearing and kingdom: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;proclaim the message. Be ready in normal or unusual times. Refute, reprimand, encourage patiently with teaching. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The time will come when &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; won’t pay attention to sound teaching. They’ll draw teachers to themselves that reinforce their own desires and say what they want to hear. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;They’ll wander off from the true message and turn to myths. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;You&lt;/u&gt; be self-controlled, suffer hardship, do the work of an evangelist, fulfill your ministry.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
