<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TIMOTHY TITUS Pastoral Epistles on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/categories/timothy-titus-pastoral-epistles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TIMOTHY TITUS Pastoral Epistles on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/categories/timothy-titus-pastoral-epistles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A CLUSTER OF POSITIONS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-cluster-of-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/a-cluster-of-positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A CLUSTER OF POSITIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Un)conscious desire to avoid the demand made on a person’s life if these materials are&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;true&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anti-supernatural bias (note distinctions between atheistic, agnostic, deistic, neo-&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;orthodox)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deistic impulse of a Newtonian universe shows itself in theological liberalism (the “older modernism”) that is akin to ancient Sadduceeism. This impulse correlates with (a) the stress on “scientific” method, taken to mean something that eliminates anything supernatural. There is a confusion between what a method can address and the idea that only those things exist which that method can address. The deistic impulse tries to foster an aura of philosophical legitimacy by claiming that (b) miracle would be a contradiction of natural law. The claim confuses contrary and contradictory, and different from opposite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>METHOD IN LITERARY CRITICISM</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/method-in-literary-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/method-in-literary-criticism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;METHOD IN LITERARY CRITICISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scholars look at a number of phenomena in Pauline literature to assess whether Paul actually wrote the piece: (a) words (new words not in Paul, Pauline words not in this writing, Pauline words used in non-Pauline ways), (b) syntax (complex vs. simple sentence structure, Hebraisms and other solecisms), (c) topics addressed, and (d) mood of the writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What control questions need to be asked on literary bases for verdicts on authorship?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PASTORALS: DATE, DESTINATION, SEQUENCE, PURPOSE</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/pastorals-date-destination-sequence-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/pastorals-date-destination-sequence-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PASTORALS: DATE, DESTINATION, SEQUENCE, PURPOSE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Date:&#x9;Fluctuates according to the dating of Paul’s first imprisonment in Rome; not&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;later than A.D. 67&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Order:&#x9;1 Timothy,        Titus,         2 Timothy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Destination:&#x9;Ephesus,            Crete,         Ephesus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purpose:&#x9;To reinforce Timothy’s and Titus’s leadership as to legitimacy and pattern&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To prepare for the time after Paul’s soon departure (cp. 2 Peter 1:13-15)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Timothy 3:14: “I am writing these things to you . . . that you may know&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOURCES OF THE PAULINE MATERIAL</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/sources-of-the-pauline-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/sources-of-the-pauline-material/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOURCES OF THE PAULINE MATERIAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introductory Guidelines&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kinds of sources found in Pauline material are not only those that appear in literature generally, but those that fit the nature of scripture. This observation is not meant to prejudice research but to point out a consistency Christians expect to find in this study. So the first guideline is that (a) scripture is like what God himself would exhale. Presumably 2 Timothy 3:16 teaches that scripture as such is God-breathed as to its intended content. Sources and processes of origination for Pauline material correlate with the nature of scripture that issues from them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PROBLEM OF THE PASTORALS</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-problem-of-the-pastorals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/essays/the-problem-of-the-pastorals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PROBLEM OF THE PASTORALS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Historical Problem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those who  reject  the  Pauline  authorship  of  the  pastoral  epistles  (1  Timoty,  2&#xA;Timothy, Titus ) contend that there is no time in Paul’s life as recorded in Acts when he could have written these epistles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We cannot show, however, that the end of The Acts account is also the end of Paul’s life. Arguments for a release from Paul’s Roman imprisonment in the closing chapter of Acts are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
