<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cm-105 on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/categories/cm-105/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cm-105 on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/categories/cm-105/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A MINISTER AND HIS FAMILY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/a-minister-and-his-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/a-minister-and-his-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A MINISTER AND HIS FAMILY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New Testament qualifications for leadership deal not only with the person himself, but also with his domestic situation. Being qualified for ministry includes, then, how your wife and kids act and how you all relate to one another. The ongoing relationship within your family follows the reciprocal pattern characteristic of all social relationships. How you treat them affects how they treat you, and how they treat you affects how you treat them. Consequently, the burden does not fall just on the minister in the family. The emphasis here is, however, is on your side of the interaction. It stresses the fact that your relationship toward them is preliminary to how they subsequently enhance or detract from your ministry. Their actions do not wholly reflect how you have first loved them and their actions reflect other influences in their past and present lives, but there is a correlation between the quality of how you treat them and how they conduct themselves as a result.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ARRANGING A MINISTER&#39;S SCHEDULE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/arranging-a-ministers-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/arranging-a-ministers-schedule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ARRANGING A MINISTER&amp;rsquo;S SCHEDULE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The Nature and Purpose of a Schedule&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A minister&amp;rsquo;s schedule is not structured so automatically as most people&amp;rsquo;s schedules are. Larger congregations with multiple staffs may foster developing a schedule pattern more like that of a business, but most churches do not lend themselves naturally to such an arrangement. Ministry is highly open-ended with many different kinds of activities. Furthermore, it varies so much from day to day and week to week and can involve all hours of the day and night. The “work-week hours” do not form so definite a block of time. For this last reason a minister should deliberately schedule his professional and non-professional activities. If he does not scheduling deliberately, before long the professional side of his work can take over the non-professional (or conceivably vice versa) and become overwhelming, or the professional part can get lopsided in favor of certain things–things wherein skills are best and interests are greatest or things in which “the tyranny of the urgent/immediate” takes over. Under these conditions laying out a minister’s schedule is both difficult and essential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHURCH POLICIES ON WEDDINGS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/church-policies-on-weddings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/church-policies-on-weddings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHURCH POLICIES ON WEDDINGS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this church’s facilities what officiating personnel may be used? May weddings be performed by persons other than a paid staff member? Is there a church receptionist in charge of scheduling, planning, and supervising rehearsals and ceremonies?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May musicians other than the congregation’s regular organist(s) or pianist(s) play for a wedding? May the couple bring in outside soloists and musicians who have their own instruments? Are there any limitations on what kinds of instrumentation or music styles may be used for the wedding ceremony and reception time?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HANDLING CRITICISM IN THE MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/handling-criticism-in-the-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/handling-criticism-in-the-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HANDLING CRITICISM IN THE MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We reserve the word criticism for illegitimate fault-finding. It means something negative because it has negative cause, result, or both. Criticism is evil because it does not edify of others but aggrandizes self. A critic’s conscious motive may be to hurt or offend, and the person criticized feels that hurt. Criticism does not build up anyone or improve the situation. It is not done the same way constructive efforts are done. Many times critics do not go to the person himself, but air their complaints to third parties or in public situations. They make their statements in condemnatory tone of voice and in ways which imply their doubt that the other person to be willing or able to make adjustments that correct. Their aim is to evaluate rather than ameliorate–to condemn rather than to help&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISSUES THAT UNDERLIE MARRIAGE POLICIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/issues-that-underlie-marriage-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/issues-that-underlie-marriage-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ISSUES THAT UNDERLIE MARRIAGE POLICIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is marriage a Christian institution or a social/racial/human one?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deciding that marriage is a racial institution means that a minister may conceive of himself as serving primarily an agent of the state rather than the church. In that case he feels freer to perform weddings for non-Christians or even for mixed couples. A minister may still want to consider whether a “minister’s” performing the wedding has the appearance of religious approval of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEMPTATIONS IN THE MINISTRY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/temptations-in-the-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/temptations-in-the-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TEMPTATIONS IN THE MINISTRY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Temptations appeal to two basic aspects of our nature–physical and social. Temptation addresses legitimate physical drives in an effort to get us to fulfill them in illegitimate ways either in excess or in the wrong way. In the social dimension, temptations come through evil example, social pressure, social reinforcement, even misunderstood good example. Temptations also play on our ignorance, taking advantage of what we do not know, misreading God&amp;rsquo;s invisibility of God as absence so as to remove that curb our impulses, and turning our viewpoint of consciousness into selfishness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE MINISTER’S PERSONAL POLICIES ON WEDDINGS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/the-ministers-personal-policies-on-weddings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/the-ministers-personal-policies-on-weddings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MINISTER’S PERSONAL POLICIES ON WEDDINGS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Specific Questions About Policies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Will you perform ceremonies only for members of the congregation where you serve?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your congregation has an especially fine facility, you will have more requests from people outside the church to have their weddings there. Many larger churches have more than one sanctuary. Besides the main auditorium they may have a chapel that seats a hundred or so and maybe even a prayer chapel that will accommodate a dozen or so. Consequently, the church is ideally equipped to handle private weddings, moderate-sized ceremonies, as well as large gatherings. Under those conditions the facility meets the needs of practically all possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YOUTH MINISTER SEARCH COMMITTEE: SUMMARY REPORT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/youth-minister-search-committee-summary-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/youth-minister-search-committee-summary-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YOUTH MINISTER SEARCH COMMITTEE: SUMMARY REPORT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;______________ ____________ Church&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April 28, ____&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Principles of the Search&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The numbered items below came into the candidate’s description either from the committee that developed the job description, from the elders as a group before the search committee was appointed, from the search committee itself, or from informal comments made by other people and passed along to the search committee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These factors go beyond the assumed traits expected for youth ministers: good character, good social skills, able to establish rapport with young people, biblically sound, intelligent in ways that pertain to ministry work and doctrinal understanding, balanced in being an activist and a learner, articulate; willing to listen to peers, parents, teens, and other church workers; spiritually mature, a finisher, a planner who does not try to “work out of his hip pocket,” flexible, self-motivated, a team player, someone who can balance fun with seriousness and knows when and how much of each is appropriate, someone that does not have large ego needs, someone who can trust without being gullible, a natural leader who can let other people do things, a person with a sense of propriety in talk and dress as well as personal associations particularly with those of the opposite sex, someone who can keep confidentialities. Many of these traits are degree matters, which means they strengthen over time. Some of them are difficult to assess before the fact; for now, they can be addressed by comments from references, inferred from basic behavior, and assumed in mutual trust until experience can give verification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
