<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>INTERPERSONALISM on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/interpersonalism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in INTERPERSONALISM on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/interpersonalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>“FRIENDS OF GOD”: THE STARTING PLACE FOR ALL THINGS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/friends-of-god-the-starting-place-for-all-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/friends-of-god-the-starting-place-for-all-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“FRIENDS OF GOD”: THE STARTING PLACE FOR ALL THINGS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THEOLOGICAL AND PRACTICAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“He is a friend of God.” That is about the best thing a person can say about someone. In the mouth of God himself, Isaiah says, “Abraham my friend” (Isaiah 41:8; cp. James 2:23; 2 Chronicles 20:7). In scripture, friendship implies several things about relationship to God. Jesus tells us what he is doing: revelation (John 15:15); so friends better describes us than slaves or servants does. Besides, he cares about us—a lot, enough even to die voluntarily an excruciating death for us (John 15:13-15; Romans 5:6-8, etc.). That implies doing for us whatever else we really need and cannot do for ourselves; that is what a friend does (Romans 8:32; 1 John 3:17). Friendship with God separates us from people that are at cross purposes with him: “Friendship with the world is enmity with God” (James 4:4; 1 John 2:15); so we have the same values and purposes that he does. Experience tells us what ideal friendship is like and how it operates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APOLOGETICS AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/apologetics-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/apologetics-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APOLOGETICS AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Promoting and Defending the Faith)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism characterizes the defense of the Christian faith in three ways. First is its need-answer-use that persons have for what Christianity offers. Apologetics—the defense of the faith—takes place in a reciprocating pattern around three poles: (1) a person’s present sense of need, (2) the conceptual and past historical basis for answering that need, and (3) the present verification through experience of the behavioral and existential correlates in that answer. The verification by experience can come back around to qualify present perception of need and to assist in the awareness of what scripture means by what it says. The process incorporates a need-answer-use triangular format that can move back and forth as well as begin at any one of the three poles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ATTITUDE TOWARD THE BODY AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/attitude-toward-the-body-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/attitude-toward-the-body-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ATTITUDE TOWARD THE BODY AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The material realm does not stand in opposition to the spiritual realm but in subordination to it. That arrangement can be the case because the material realm derived by creation from the spiritual, or personal, one. Our bodies, then, stand in a subordinate relation to ourselves/spirits/personhood as the creation does to God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So the body is not to be depreciated as in Gnostic thought, deprived as in asceticism, glorified as in humanism, or satiated as in Epicureanism. It is not to be made the whole picture as in materialism. It is to be subordinated in Christianity. This arrangement Paul calls “possessing the vessel” (1 Thessalonians 4:3-4; cp. 2 Corinthians 4:7; 1 Peter 3:7; 1 Corinthians 9:27; Romans 8:13; 12:1, 2). The body is the instrument by which people express themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BAPTISM AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/baptism-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/baptism-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BAPTISM AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a matter of standard procedure, baptism is an act of personal identification with Jesus Christ, which means commitment to his lordship, values, and purposes. In consequence of that identity with Christ, God forgives sin, gives his Spirit, and adds us to the body of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nature of Baptism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The primary fact about Christian baptism is that it is an (1) interpersonal act. It is done by a person in a relationship with another person for personal purposes. In personal conversion and reconciliation before God, we have the same kind of process that goes on in overcoming estrangement with people. There is no exact time when “friendshiping” occurs, but what is in fact a process performatively reduces to a point in, say, a handshake or a hug. No one supposes that shaking hands creates friendships; yet it does not merely reflect the friendship either since that friendship is in fact what has not existed before. It is a commitment to friendship and helps establish the friendship. It may testify to the friendship if anyone is watching, and it gives the participants a specific point in time to look back to in defining their status with each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BASES FOR INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/bases-for-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/bases-for-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BASES FOR INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. What Is Most Original (the [inter]personal character of ultimate reality)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;God created the universe out of nothing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God’s creatorship means that the material, inorganic, impersonal universe is secondary to the (inter)personal creator. God spoke the universe into existence (Genesis 1:3, 6, 9, 11, 14, 20, 24, 26, 29; Hebrews 11:3; 2 Peter 3:5). Its origin came from an act of the will (Acts 17:22-31), not from determinism through physical cause-effect. It was created (John 1:1-3; Colossians 1:14-20), not out of God, but by him from nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Central to Less Central: An Interpersonal Format</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/central-to-less-central-an-interpersonal-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/central-to-less-central-an-interpersonal-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Central to Less Central: An Interpersonal Format&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;for Prioritizing Issues in Christian Unity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation proposes a way to help fulfill two responsibilities that we tend to put in tension with one another: our responsibility for representing Christian truth and our responsibility for facilitating Christian unity. The proposal stems from believing that interpersonalism prioritizes what naturally occupies central place in Christianity. We can draw on that observation to help us in the quest for unity in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS OF INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-of-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-of-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHARACTERISTICS OF INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Interpersonalism” refers to interaction between persons, mutual relations, compenetration, mutuality, transaction. Interpersonal unity is the kind of thing John expresses with his a-in-b-in-a formula (e.g., John 10:38; 14:10, 11, 15-16, 20, 23, 38; 15:4-9; 17:21-24; 1 John 2:24-28; see also Colossians 1:27-28). Paul speaks about being “members of one another” (Ephesians 4:25). Interpersonalism contrasts with law, ritual (sacramentalism), nature (materialism), idea (rationalism), and mysticism. The ordinances are performative; they are acts by which we “say something” more than “means of grace’ that we get from them. By them we say something by what we do (cp. Titus 1:16).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIAN ATTITUDE AND CHRISTIAN UNITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christian-attitude-and-christian-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christian-attitude-and-christian-unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIAN ATTITUDE AND CHRISTIAN UNITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article encourages using interpersonal principles in the quest for Christian unity.1 We are reflecting on the role of attitude in creating an atmosphere for conflict resolution in the body of Christ today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first observation is simply that (a) proper attitude increases other people’s willingness to listen to our viewpoint. The Golden Rule works because we tend to respond in kind. The pattern operates negatively and positively: disrespect usually evokes disrespect, and respect evokes respect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIAN UNITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christian-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christian-unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIAN UNITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The Importance of Christian Unity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism highlights the importance of Christian unity because (a) unifying mankind is the very purpose of the church. In Christ, God is creating “a new united mankind” (Ephesians 2:14-16). What has come together in him must exemplify the purpose of him. The importance of unity also lies in its (b) apologetic value. Division in Christ belies the call to unity in Christ. The credibility of the Christian calling and claim is weakened or destroyed otherwise (John 17: 21, 23; Luke 11:18). The richness of the (c) Christian experience lies specifically in the “peace” that comes from Christians living together in harmony (1 Corinthians 7:15; cp. Romans 14:19).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIANITY BY CONTRAST: SKETCHES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christianity-by-contrast-sketches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christianity-by-contrast-sketches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIANITY BY CONTRAST: SKETCHES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prolegomena&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Law of Contrast/Law of Opposition. Ideas are clearest in contrast to their parallel alternatives. The principle applies to clear thinking and proper interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The whole provides the context for its parts. The character of the whole sets the character of its constituents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Continuity of kind between cause and effect, purpose and result, problem and solution: Matthew 7:16-20; 12:33-35; Luke 6:43-45, James 3:12.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good and bad are always figured relative to purpose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMUNION AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/communion-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/communion-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMUNION AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As with any ritual or formal act, the Lord’s Supper means for us only what we mean into it. The bread and the grape juice are transformed in our minds into the body and the blood of the Lord. The elements represent rather than are. “This is my body” uses “is” in the way a new grandfather does when he pulls a snapshot out of his wallet and says, “This is my grandson.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONFLICT RESOLUTION BY INTERPERSONAL MEANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/conflict-resolution-by-interpersonal-means/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/conflict-resolution-by-interpersonal-means/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CONFLICT RESOLUTION BY INTERPERSONAL MEANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism shows how people can befriend people they disagree with without feeling that they are compromising convictions in doing so. Accepting persons transcends approving of their ideas or even their deeds in some cases. Presence is not approval. So, interpersonal considerations provide a format for conflict resolution. We have to relate to people to have any influence on them, and we can do that on the basis of their potential for change. This approach underlies God’s effort at the reconciliation process (salvation).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CONNECTIONS BETWEEN INTERPERSONALISM AND CHRISTOLOGY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/connections-between-interpersonalism-and-christology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/connections-between-interpersonalism-and-christology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CONNECTIONS BETWEEN INTERPERSONALISM AND CHRISTOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture makes clear that Jesus the Messiah possessed deity in the distinctive, ontological sense. From the standpoint of theory, it may not contradict the salvation enterprise for us not to understand that fact fully or with complete accuracy. His sinlessness relative to God’s will for him in the flesh appears to be the essential element for salvation purposes. It would be best, then, not to regard as “enemies of Christ” those who misperceive him as the first created being (who created everything else, Colossians 1:15-16) yet affirm his sinlessness and everything scripture says about him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CREATION IN INTERPERSONAL CONTEXT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/creation-in-interpersonal-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/creation-in-interpersonal-context/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CREATION IN INTERPERSONAL CONTEXT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism puts the personal ahead of the impersonal. Person and personal aspects like mind, will, emotion, and conscience do not arise epiphenomenally from the impersonal, but by virtue of mind operating through will, the personal creates the impersonal (Genesis 1:1-5ff) and orders it (Genesis 1:26-31; 2:7-15). The personal is eternal, but the impersonal has beginning and end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism puts the personal God ahead of the created universe. Not only is the created universe not the ultimate frame of reference; it is not abstracted from its ultimate personal creator. None of God’s works are to be regarded apart from him or considered discretely in and of themselves whether creation, revelation, providence, or redemption. The universe has not always been here; it had a beginning from the transcendent personal creator, who had no beginning. It will also have an end, but he is eternal. The doctrine of creation from nothing is unique in ancient religions. And Judaeo-Christianity is unique in having a relational God of principle as the highest frame of reference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EPISTEMOLOGY AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/epistemology-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/epistemology-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EPISTEMOLOGY AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(How We Know)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We walk by faith, not by sight (2 Corinthians 5:7). Faith and sight are two ways to know. Sight means knowledge by direct perception; faith is knowledge through the testimony of other people. We know about the past, the future, the distant, and the invisible only by testimony, if at all. In short, most knowledge comes from revelation either by God or some other person. In either case, it is interpersonal—by faith.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESCHATOLOGY AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/eschatology-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/eschatology-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ESCHATOLOGY AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Last Things)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Under the (inter)personal worldview, there is eschatology because the future is going somewhere intentional. Predestination guarantees the meaningfulness of history by providing destiny. The possibility of making all things new contrasts with the myth of eternal returns, the cyclical view of history. A creating God who originates by willing can bring about the truly new. The future is not limited to the possibilities of the past, nor is the future sheer eventuation; the future is foreordained by a Person who chooses destinies. There is more to tomorrow than one experience leading to the next.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETHICS AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ethics-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ethics-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETHICS AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Ethics, morality, and goodness pertain to behavior in personal relationships.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ethics does not deal with being (ontology), substance (hypostasis), the material realm. Augustine set aside that concept of ethics in his costly error of identifying evil as loss (privation) of form in substance relative to its pristine condition. That starting point generated natural depravity for explaining universal, all-pervasive sin and the impossibility of self-salvation. According to his thinking, sin was a function of inheritable mis-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVANGELISM AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/evangelism-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/evangelism-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVANGELISM AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Objects of Evangelism (See also comments on the scope of salvation under interpersonalism essay “Salvation.”)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One important ramification of the interpersonal nature of the gospel is that it applies to every person. The only qualification for receiving it is being a person, someone with the interpersonal capacity. The gospel does not have to do with birds and animals (contra Francis of Assisi). Christianity is not an elitist religion for a particular caste or nation, for heads of state, intellectuals (as in Gnosticism), the rich, the educated, the freeman, the adult, the righteous, or the married, but for every person. “I did not come so much to call the righteous, but sinners to repentance” (Luke 5:32). It is for as many as have sinned, experienced alienation (lost), and stand in need of reconciliation (saved).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVENTS AND STATEMENTS RE INTERPERSONAL PRIORITIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/events-and-statements-re-interpersonal-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/events-and-statements-re-interpersonal-priorities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVENTS AND STATEMENTS RE INTERPERSONAL PRIORITIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Priority of Interpersonal over Formal Matters&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Sabbath was made for man, not man for the Sabbath (Mark 2:27; cp. Exodus 23:12d; Deuteronomy 5:14c)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Today you will be with me in paradise” (Luke 23:43).  No gift for cleansing offered.  In fact, there was no provision at all in the Law for the forgiveness of murder or any capital crime.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David and his men ate the showbread that was legally available only for the priests (Matthew 12:1-8; Mark 2:23-28; Luke 6:1-5; 1 Samuel 21:6).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAITH AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/faith-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/faith-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FAITH AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Faith belongs to the interpersonal circumstance because it is something one person puts in another person. Faith trusts in another. Scripture applies the faith principle to two areas: salvation (consequences) and knowledge (information). In both applications a second person stands in the gap (a) between the doer and the result and (b) between the learner and what’s learned. Habakkuk 2:4 serves as the gateway into the whole Christian system: “The just will live by faith/trust.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FREEDOM AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/freedom-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/freedom-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FREEDOM AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Freedom means moving in accordance with reality. Freedom is not detachment from everything; that would be lostness. It means moving in conformity with what is there. The interpersonal connection lies in acknowledging the presence of God and other persons and in living with them instead of striving after an unreal individualism. Fulfillment comes from association; people must live in conformity with the fact that they are persons designed for relationship with persons. A certain amount of individual limitation is necessary to be free because other reality exists. Proper relationship to God sets the stage for proper relationship to everything else. Divine fellowship sets the stage for objective freedom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOD AND INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/god-and-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/god-and-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GOD AND INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism applies to the ultimate frame of reference in that deity forms a three-person unity. In philosophy, “God” refers to ultimate reality. In scripture, this reality is personal because he is counselor who has no counselor (Psalm 11:3-4), his pleasure is what measures all doing, and his glory is the effect of everything that happens (Ephesians 1:11; Psalm 19:1). Interpersonalism represents the most complex form of existence. It stands to reason that if it exists in the created realm, it should be present in what originated everything in the created realm. The stream, we say, cannot rise above its source. The most inclusive understanding of God is at the “corporate,” or triune, level. The traditional doctrine of trinity combines into one concept unity, diversity, equality, and order and puts it before all other reality. Note the title The Eternal We, by Harold J. Green (Chicago, Ill.: Loyola University Press, 1987). Trinity is not just any kind of threeness-in-oneness; it is an interpersonal threeness-in-oneness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUIDANCE AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/guidance-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/guidance-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GUIDANCE AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Divine guidance takes place with people; hence, it includes choices, thinking, feelings, and other personal factors with both God and people. God does not make all our choices for us; he treats us like friends more than like slaves. Pushing the idea that God has a special plan for each person may be nothing more than (1) the old self-centeredness in religious garb; self-centeredness is not interpersonal. (2) It may be a kind of laziness, because people do not want to put out significant effort in deciding or taking responsibility for their decisions. Submitting to God does not mean being submissive. “Super-spirituality” is not interpersonal spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HERMENEUTICS AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/hermeneutics-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HERMENEUTICS AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(How to Interpret to Bible)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism establishes a theological method. Interpersonalism impacts hermeneutics by establishing a programmatic for interpreting the Bible. What does not deduce from interpersonalism must be firmly established by primary proof. Primary proof is the kind of proof that requires one conclusion, while secondary evidence confirms what comes from primary. Primary proof that does not arise from the nature of the case (interpersonalism ultimately) must rest on positive commandment rather than moral law, because moral law refers to what comes from the nature of the case. Interpersonalism establishes what is to be regarded a priori as central. It becomes a way of shouldering appropriately the positive burden of proof on many issues. Interpersonalism calls for doing theology in the interpersonal mode because it goes on in an interpersonal context.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOLY SPIRIT AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/holy-spirit-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/holy-spirit-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HOLY SPIRIT AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The gift of the Spirit is first of all an interpersonal relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Holy Spirit is a person, not a force, a power, a feeling, an atmosphere, idea, principle, or attitude. He is not God’s energy. Since the Spirit is a person and people are persons, “having the Spirit” means relating to deity in the person of the Spirit. Consequently, his guidance and empowerment come first through interpersonal means—influence before miracle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPERSONALISM AND ORDINANCES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpersonalism-and-ordinances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpersonalism-and-ordinances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPERSONALISM AND ORDINANCES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Baptism and the Lord’s Supper are performative acts, acts by which the performer “says something.” Their meaning comes from what we mean into them; otherwise, they have no meaning. That indicates that they are not rituals done to us by which grace comes to us automatically by virtue of the ritual itself somehow or by virtue of the legitimized authority of the administrator. There is value that comes on us, but it comes on us from God on the prior condition of our commitment to him as communicated by the performative act.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPERSONALISM AND THE MYSTERY OF GOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpersonalism-and-the-mystery-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpersonalism-and-the-mystery-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPERSONALISM AND THE MYSTERY OF GOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism integrates with the “mystery of God” because (a) the mystery factor is highest in the interpersonal categories. That is so because the other categories—nature, law, and logic—are deterministic; but persons, especially persons in relationship, are not fully predictable since they have rationality, creativity, and free will on both sides of the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mystery of God comes also from (b) the fact that God is supernatural, but we can regard him only with our finite minds.  That reduces our ability to “figure him out” or predict his next move. He will not be inconsistent with his nature, values, and purposes; but those three factors leave a lot of room for variability. They allow his freedom and supernatural abilities to operate in ways we cannot know or understand or anticipate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPERSONALISM AS A CRITERION FOR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpersonalism-as-a-criterion-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpersonalism-as-a-criterion-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPERSONALISM AS A CRITERION FOR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FELLOWSHIP, ORTHODOXY, AND RELATIVE CENTRALITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism serves as a general criterion for deciding what is part of the faith. It is the touchstone for distinguishing “gospel from culture” and truth from preference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism serves as a criterion for arranging things from central to less central within what is actually true about the Christian faith. The value of this observation lies in helping us decide what to emphasize in introducing someone to Christ (evangelism) and in arranging the sequence of virtues and duties in the process of sanctification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPERSONALISM: THE INTEGRATING REALITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpersonalism-the-integrating-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpersonalism-the-integrating-reality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPERSONALISM: THE INTEGRATING REALITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOR CHRISTIAN TRUTH&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KNOWLEDGE IN INTERPERSONAL CONTEXT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/knowledge-in-interpersonal-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/knowledge-in-interpersonal-context/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KNOWLEDGE IN INTERPERSONAL CONTEXT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Peace that passes understanding: Philippians 4:7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am the way, the truth, and the life [truth is personal]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(note: “You will know the truth, and the truth will make you free.”)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowledge puffs up; love builds up. [It does so by stressing relationships, whereas knowledge fosters distinctions between us.]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If anyone among you thinks he knows anything, let him know that he does not yet know what he should know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LANGUAGE IN INTERPERSONAL CONTEXT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/language-in-interpersonal-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/language-in-interpersonal-context/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LANGUAGE IN INTERPERSONAL CONTEXT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Language often develops its vocabulary relative to the personal-impersonal distinction. We see that in English, although it may be difficult to get a feel for how widespread or universal it is in languages generally. One example is “educate,” a word that would not likely be used for training an animal to do tricks; “train” would be the more likely word..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The capacity for speech enhances the social experience. Thomas Mann was willing even to say, “Speech is civilization.” Language helps define humanness and personhood. Our conversation reveals to other persons what we are, connects us with other people, and sets the direction for our future together. It behooves each Christian to avoid the vulgarisms that dehumanize, depersonalize, and assault other people. Instead, this interpersonal capacity should compliment, thank, and ennoble. What has so much potential for good becomes all the more devastating for evil when misused. No wonder we are justified or condemned by our words (Matthew 12:37).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAW AND GOSPEL IN CONTRAST (IP)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/law-and-gospel-in-contrast-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/law-and-gospel-in-contrast-ip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LAW AND GOSPEL IN CONTRAST (IP)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2 Corinthians 3:6 Paul declares that the “letter” kills, but the spirit gives life. His point appears to be that the absoluteness and inflexibility of law stifles and destroys persons in operation, especially in relation with each other. It drives people away even as the Israelites turned away from the glow on Moses’ face. The “spirit,” or purpose, of the Law corresponds with the Person who gave it. “Cutting someone a little slack” is a liberating experience. On this usage of “spirit,” compare John 1:17; 4:23; Romans 7:6; Galatians 3-4. Spirit appears to mean personal and interpersonal in contrast to letter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAW AND INTERPERSONALISM IN CONTRAST</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/law-and-interpersonalism-in-contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/law-and-interpersonalism-in-contrast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LAW AND INTERPERSONALISM IN CONTRAST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Law and personal relationship do not have a (1) part-to-whole relationship. Legal process does not represent a secondary operation inside of interpersonal operation. Grace-faith does not function inside of law, and law does not provide mechanisms inside of interpersonalism. In Pauline terms, works are not part of the grace-faith-promise-spirit system. Likewise, legality and interpersonalism are not (2) parts of a common larger operation.1 Legal works do not supplement or combine with interpersonal actions in bringing about the interpersonal consequences needed by estranged persons. Legal operations are foreign to interpersonal process. The two systems are parallel, alternative, and mutually exclusive.2 If something is of law, it is no longer of faith (Galatians 2:12); if it is legal, it is not interpersonal. If it is of grace, it is no more of works (Romans 11:6). If inheritance is of law, faith is void and promise is of no effect (Romans 4:14). Grace, faith, and promise are aspects of interpersonal operation in contrast to works and debt, which belong to legal process (Romans 4:13-16; cp. Galatians 3:18). God has not established procedures for persons to go through to get salvation; he has given them a Person to identify with and commit to in order to receive it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LEADERSHIP AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/leadership-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/leadership-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LEADERSHIP AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leading takes place in the interpersonal circumstance and has the purpose of helping people grow in their social skills necessary for getting the job done. Leadership is gained and exercised by interpersonal means. In the church, leadership does not come by heredity, force, being “pushy,” or by shortcutting, “riding in on another person’s shirt tail,” or bypassing lesser roles through formal education. People do not become leaders because they refuse to be involved otherwise—the “won’t-work-so-let-lead” syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LOVE AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/love-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/love-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LOVE AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both vertical and horizontal relationships have the same interpersonal character. Experiencing the horizontal helps us understand the vertical; understanding the vertical motivates us to do the horizontal. In both directions, love is the characterizing feature. It includes most aspects of interpersonal associations and originates so many of the virtues involved in them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Love is accomplished by the mechanism implicit in the Golden Rule (Matthew 7:12), which restates the Second Great Commandment (Leviticus 19:18). “Doing / for others / as you would have others do for you” parallels “Love / your neighbor / as yourself.” That means love is something we “do” rather than something we feel or say. Love is a pattern of doing—self-giving for the joy of “others” without qualification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MANAGING EMOTIONS (IP)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/managing-emotions-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/managing-emotions-ip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANAGING EMOTIONS (IP)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Among the several things we can do to manage our emotions, we can tap into vertical interpersonal resources through prayer and Bible reading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. Secondly, we can put ourselves around positive people who affirm us as persons. Talking about the problem to other people gets feelings into words and concepts, so they feel more objective, more manageable, and clearer. We get them “off our chest.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christsir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MANKIND AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/mankind-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/mankind-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANKIND AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Interpersonalism applies first to mankind as an explanation of God’s purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Humankind is “for the praise of the glory of God’s grace” (Ephesians 1:6; cp. 12, 14). Both “praise” and “grace” apply to social activity. Praise is response to grace. What God first gave from his grace we praise him for in our response. Both God and people give and receive. God gives to people in his grace and receives praise and honor. We get from grace and give in praise. Since the phenomenon consists of two-directional action between persons, from an (a) existential standpoint the purpose of people itself is interpersonal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MARRIAGE AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/marriage-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/marriage-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MARRIAGE AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marriage is a specialized interpersonal relationship. Whatever we know about personal associations in general applies most crucially to matrimony. The products of love and the ways of expressing and developing it apply to marriage more than anywhere else because of the intensity and all-inclusiveness of that relationship. Marriage is primarily interpersonal with added distinctives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marriage involves complementary relationship. The ultimate concept in marriage is oneness, not sameness. Husband and wife have complementary capacities in the full range of human personhood and complementary roles in their operation as a socio-physical unit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MEANING AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/meaning-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/meaning-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MEANING AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meaning addresses the connection between things. The meaning of a word refers to its connection with its referent—what it refers to. The meaning of a part in a system refers to the purpose it fulfills in connection with the rest of the parts that form the whole. Connectivity is the essence of the theory of meaning. Now to apply it to persons in relationship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meaning relates to ethics. As ethical considerations stem from relationship and purpose so meaningfulness stems from those same two existential and eschatological components. Significance comes from the combined interaction of lateral and longitudinal activity. Meaning differs from ethics because it covers more than moral matters, but its interpersonal character applies to ethics because we choose to purpose what others help us accomplish and because we relate through love. The fulfillment of purpose, the experience of living, and being loved give us a sense of worth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MISAPPLYING THE CHRISTIAN SYSTEM (IP)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/misapplying-the-christian-system-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/misapplying-the-christian-system-ip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MISAPPLYING THE CHRISTIAN SYSTEM (IP)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If interpersonalism characterizes the Christian worldview, it follows that any deviation in its formulation is likely some departure from personal relationship as its most basic, central, decisive feature. It is instructive to survey the history of the church to see how it has departed. The departures have been into one of the other major categories or some combination of them, a prioritizing of something else over interpersonalism, or a reduction from the full set of factors in interpersonalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PARENTING AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/parenting-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/parenting-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PARENTING AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parenting takes place first by interpersonal means. It is on top of interpersonal process that any authority comes, and that authority is bounded in its application by the distinctive purposes at work in this special setting for interpersonal process. The interpersonal circumstance sets the attitude parents take toward their children. Children are smaller but not less. If love is the medium of interpersonal relationships, love becomes the medium for parenting. The means and manner of parenting are primarily interpersonal influence instead of physical force, intimidation, authoritative control, manipulation, and the like. One of the main means of interpersonal influence is modeling what we want to teach, commend, command, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PERSEVERANCE AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/perseverance-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/perseverance-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PERSEVERANCE AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian growth (sanctification) relates to perseverance in Christ because continued growth safeguards against apostasy. The writer of Hebrews suggests interpersonal activity as a way to persevere. He speaks of fellowship with the faithful, imitation of the faithful, and service to all mankind (chs. 10-13).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Personal relationships also connect with perseverance in that how we relate is equally relevant all along the way—at life’s end as much as at any previous time. Not only is how we relate relevant, it is determinative at each point along the way. Present relationships are good or bad in terms of present good or bad motives, attitudes, and behaviors. It is not good now because it was good before—as if past acts could override present behavior. Like any social relationship, fellowship with God in the end is not an average figured across the whole life span; it consists of how things are in the end. It is not determined by making judgment at some point in the past; it is determined by judgment at the end (the final “now”). For the same reasons, previous “salvation” relationship does not preclude present alienation any more than bad past behavior destroys present reconciliation (Ezekiel 18:21-24). There is no thought of forming a social bond that somehow remains permanent despite subsequently departing from those behaviors that were required for establishing it. The state at the end is not the result of permanent miraculous change of substantive nature (condition); neither is it a permanent legal status irreversible by decree. It is an interpersonal relationship made permanent by perseverant repentance and faithful forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRAYER AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/prayer-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/prayer-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRAYER AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Prayer as interpersonal activity establishes the elements of prayer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayer is talking to God, so it is verbal communication from one person to another, silent or oral. Talking to God includes whatever occurs in conversation: praise, thanksgiving, intercession, request, confession, promise, or just talking through thoughts and experiences. The interpersonal character of the act helps explain how our Lord could pray all night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. Prayer as interpersonal activity contrasts with practices that get confused with it or substituted for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PREACHING AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/preaching-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/preaching-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PREACHING AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much of what applies to evangelism applies to preaching. Evangelism addresses the gospel to non-believers. Preaching addresses the gospel to believers by and large since most often the term describes teaching and exhortation in the gathered community of Christians. Evangelism tends to think of itself as cross-cultural; preaching usually addresses people in the same culture. Interpersonalism calls us to remember that preaching is communication to people; so it is not oratory, which emphasizes the form of delivery. It is also not recitation, which highlights the verbalizing of information and gives the impression that it does not come from the heart, that a person is saying words into the air rather than speaking into the listeners. It is not “heart to heart” talk. Reciters are performers; they are “saying their piece.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSYCHOLOGICAL STRENGTH FROM INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/psychological-strength-from-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/psychological-strength-from-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PSYCHOLOGICAL STRENGTH FROM INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psychological strength comes from friendship. We often reference psychological strength to inner factors because it contrasts with outer flux; we can experience “inner peace” even during unstable circumstances. But psychological strength is not so much inner peace amidst outer chaos as it is “inter” strength from other persons. Our inner stability came from someone else. Furthermore, psychological strength ties to personhood in our commitment to an ever-present, immutable God and to others in relationship with us through him&amp;ndash;fellowship. Strength persists in the face of destruction because of one person’s concern to help others by doing what may relieve them, save them, and give them peace, power, and joy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REVELATION AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/revelation-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/revelation-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;REVELATION AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Revelation is interpersonal in that it is from one Person to another.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That point applies both to general and revelation. Not abstracting general revelation from the One that speaks in it amounts to the same thing as not abstracting creation from the creator. Personalizing general revelation equals personalizing creation. Nature has the character of revelation inasmuch as it is secondary, derivative, dependent reality. From the characteristics of nature, we can “read” something of the nature of its origin and originator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SALVATION AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/salvation-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/salvation-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SALVATION AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Problem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christianity analyzes the human predicament as stemming from faulty personal relationship, which in turn stems from improper personal behavior. A great amount of suffering in the world comes from inappropriate social activity. So we cannot expect the answer to our condition to be a chemical, scientific, materialistic, or miraculous solution. As a result, Christianity does not attempt to solve the problem of our human predicament in the same realm, through the same means, or by the same method the world tries to use. It is not primarily by science or scientific technology that we raise the quality of life. It is not primarily through political, military, or legal processes that we achieve peace and happiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SANCTIFICATION AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sanctification-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sanctification-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SANCTIFICATION AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The possibility of spiritual growth (sanctification) comes from the nature of interpersonal process. Under the perfection demand of law, becoming perfect cannot occur after perfection is broken. But salvation before God deals with restoring a personal relationship, which means that development toward maturity can substitute for having already achieved it and always having to keep it. We can deal with each other directionally (growth) rather than positionally (perfection) because repentance-forgiveness can make up the difference between performance and perfection. That fact is part of Paul’s contrast between faith vs. works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELF-IMAGE AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/self-image-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/self-image-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SELF-IMAGE AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christians sometimes object to good self-image and feeling good about ourselves as somehow bad. The problem comes from an overreaction. To get people to see their need for salvation, Christians sometimes overdo how evil unsaved people are. Furthermore, they seem to think that feeling good about themselves makes God’s salvation unnecessary or it makes them feel them can save themselves. Interpersonalism keeps the balance between responsibility and dependence. We are responsible for responding on our side of the relationship, but our responses on our side of the relationship do not establish the relationship. We depend on the other Person to establish it from the other side—to accept us—because he is the offended party.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOME EFFECTS OF CENTRALIZING THE INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/some-effects-of-centralizing-the-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/some-effects-of-centralizing-the-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOME EFFECTS OF CENTRALIZING THE INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CATEGORY IN BIBLICAL-SYSTEMATIC THEOLOGY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AN OUTLINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Centralize&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. Interpersonal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C. Biblical-systematic theology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D. Alternatives transcended&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Bases for the Interpersonal Center&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. The (inter)personal character of ultimate reality&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God’s creatorship: Genesis 1:1; Acts 17:22-31; John 1:1-3; Colossians&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:14-20, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trinitarian considerations: Matthew 3:16; John 14:16, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. Statements about the gospel in personalized terms&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preaching Christ: 8:35; 11:20; 17:18; Romans 16:25; Philippians 1:15-18&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(cp. Acts 5:42)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOME INTERPERSONAL IMPLICATIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/some-interpersonal-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/some-interpersonal-implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOME INTERPERSONAL IMPLICATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOR ONENESS IN CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Efforts at Christian unity have variously stressed one or more bases: organizational union, common experience, or essential doctrine. Roman Catholicism exemplifies the concern for unity through the church as an institution, which is particularly fitting because Catholic theology conceives of grace as flowing through the church by way of duly ordained clergy: “where the bishop is, there is the church.” Because of the emphasis on tongue speaking, pentecostalism can illustrate the common-experience approach. Erasmus among others advocated a minimum set of essential doctrines as foundational for Christian unity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPIRITUAL FRUIT AND INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/spiritual-fruit-and-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/spiritual-fruit-and-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SPIRITUAL FRUIT AND INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In scripture, “spirit” vs. “flesh” stands for the interpersonal center of life in distinction to an egocentric or ethnocentric one. It is the transcendent vs. the imminent. The terminology evidently came about because flesh takes something into itself to find fulfillment. Persons, however, must give of themselves to find fulfillment. “Flesh” stands for an individualism that fosters a competitive mentality. “Spirit” stands for an interpersonalism that fosters unifying love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STEWARDSHIP AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/stewardship-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/stewardship-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STEWARDSHIP AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christian stewardship belongs to the interpersonal system. In relationships, people do not live to themselves or die by themselves even as in marriage the right over one’s body does not lie in the one alone but in the other also (1 Corinthians 7:4). In social relationships, each gives of self for the joy of the others. In that same fashion, God has given of himself in creating, sustaining, and redeeming us. We are not our own; we have been bought for a price, so to speak, so life itself is ours as a stewardship to glorify God with. We give ourselves to the Lord, who first gave himself for us (2 Corinthians 8:5).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STRENGTHENING THE WILL AND INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/strengthening-the-will-and-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/strengthening-the-will-and-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STRENGTHENING THE WILL AND INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Will is an aspect of people that links mind, emotion, and action to create what we call “person.” In addition to other factors, personal relationships impact the will, the mind, and the emotions to produce action. Will contrasts from stimulus-response; so we are more than a set of complicated electro-chemical processes. We can decide; we do not have to respond to the strongest environmental stimulus. Since we can decide, we find ourselves living by values more than by drives and stimuli. We are not the determined creatures depicted by Skinnerian behaviorism, but persons created in the image of God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUFFERING AND INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/suffering-and-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/suffering-and-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUFFERING AND INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture treats the problem of pain like being disciplined by a parent (Hebrews 12:5-11 &amp;lt; Proverbs 3:5). Since a personal, all-powerful, all-knowing God controls the universe, everything that happens here he either initiates or allows. Everything that occurs passes through his omniscience, his will, and his power. We can be confident that the experience will not be more than we can handle (1 Corinthians 10:13).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God’s motive for allowing suffering as far up as we can handle serves for our development much as a parent’s discipline serves for a child’s maturity. Negative experiences impress us with our dependence; they help us develop virtues like humility, patience, respect, and gratitude (Romans 5:2-4; 1 Corinthians 12:7-10). They toughen us up and cause us to seek refuge in inner security (or more precisely “inter-security”) because we cannot depend on external, natural circumstances. Suffering helps us get priorities straight and rise above our present circumstance. Hard times draw us closer together with those of like faith and like difficulty, and enable us to empathize with others who suffer (2 Corinthians 1:3-4; Hebrews 2:18). They give us opportunity to glorify God by allowing us to show that we are not fair-weather friends (1 Peter 1:6-7).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEMPTATION AND INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/temptation-and-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/temptation-and-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TEMPTATION AND INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Temptation tries to get us to exchange the welfare of everyone for the welfare of self. In so doing, it attempts to call us from an interpersonal to an individualistic frame of reference. Temptation tries to get us to exchange the intangible (personal) for the tangible (material) framework. It tries to get us to exchange the eternal for the temporary and the immediate for the delayed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We can counteract these temptations through interpersonal means by fellowship with good people and by recognizing our responsibility to help them. We can consolidate our problems by doing everything as to the Lord. That way we deal with them collectively under one solution and through a personal one. We can remember who we are and whom we represent. We also trust God not to allow us to be tempted above what we can handle (1 Corinthians 10:13). The interpersonal spiritual exercises, regularly practiced, strengthen us ahead of time for confronting problems when they appear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE CHURCH AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-church-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-church-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE CHURCH AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Theologically the church is an interpersonal system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The church as the kingdom of heaven now does not share identity with any political entity. Civil religion and state church, while characteristic of Mosaism, are foreign to Christ’s kingdom. In the Messiah there is neither Jew nor Gentile. It is comparable to spiritual Israel, being a Jew inwardly. The kingdom of “heaven” is transpolitical, transnational, transcultural, interpersonal. The kingdom of God “suffers violence” when people try to turn it into something political-militaristic-geographical (Luke 16:16-17).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PROBLEM-SOLVING POWER OF INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-problem-solving-power-of-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-problem-solving-power-of-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PROBLEM-SOLVING POWER OF INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What makes things the way they ought to be and what helps things improve to even better levels is also what corrects what is not the way it should be. The characteristics of interpersonalism give it a problem-solving power for personal problems. Inasmuch as interpersonalism has the full range of characteristics existent in persons and associations between persons, it has the potential for solving all the problems that persons in relationship can have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE RELATIONSHIP OF INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE RELATIONSHIP OF INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TO NON-INTERPERSONAL MATTERS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism refers to the fundamental character of reality. As such, it is a claim about worldview. Interpersonal refers to the presence of the interpersonal element, but the addition of ism describes the pervasive nature of things. The same goes for legal vs. legalism, for determined vs. determinism, for scientism, and so on. In the latter instance, the word no longer describes an aspect, but characterizes the whole. It becomes that by which a person integrates as much as possible of what belongs to the whole. Only after that exercise does he bring in secondary matters to account for exceptional or practical matters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE RELATIONSHIP OF INTERPERSONALISM AND DOCTRINE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-interpersonalism-and-doctrine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-interpersonalism-and-doctrine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE RELATIONSHIP OF INTERPERSONALISM AND DOCTRINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sets the character of doctrines&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism sets the context that establishes the character of individual doctrines and the practices that grow out of them within the living whole.  Interpersonalism adjusts the sense in which some doctrine like the trinity is to be understood. It is not simply a formal threeness-in-oneness, but an interpersonal threeness-in-oneness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Doctrinal teaching includes the nature of the One and the ones we relate to. It establishes the values and purposes that govern our relationship to Him and them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE UNEVANGELIZED AND INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-unevangelized-and-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-unevangelized-and-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE UNEVANGELIZED AND INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The unevangelized have a frame of reference by which they can approximate God’s intentions for human behavior. They experience relationships with other persons (ethics) and can read from that how broken friendship is overcome (salvation). The “noble pagan” can practice the Golden Rule (The Second Great Commandment) and “grope” after God to find him (Acts 17:27) since deity must be superior and personal (The First Great Commandment). So the unevangelized can be accountable and judged in relation to their limited perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THEOLOGY FROM BELOW</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/theology-from-below/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/theology-from-below/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THEOLOGY FROM BELOW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isaiah declares that a wayfaring fool need not err in the way of the Lord (35:8). We, being evil, know how to give good gifts to our children (Matthew 7:11 = Luke 11:13). Jesus’ comment is a cue and clue that the way of the Lord is not that hard. At least the basics of revelation we ought to catch onto from personal experience as we “feel after God to find him” because “he is not far from every one of us” (Acts 17:27).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WEAKER CHRISTIANS AND INTERPERSONALISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/weaker-christians-and-interpersonalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/weaker-christians-and-interpersonalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WEAKER CHRISTIANS AND INTERPERSONALISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weaker brother situations come up with people who differ from us. Weaker brother matters deal with issues not wrong in themselves: eating shamble meat (Romans 14; 1 Corinthians 8), practicing vegetarianism, observing holidays (Romans 14:5), drinking wine (Romans 14:21). They are wrong depending on how we look at them and how we do them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weaker brothers are people whose viewpoint and feelings we cannot easily share on practical matters. They may be led into sin by seeing us indulge in what we do with a clear conscience. Their danger lies in following our example with a different meaning and motivation from ours. They do so because they cannot easily know our thoughts and motives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WORSHIP AS INTERPERSONAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/worship-as-interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/worship-as-interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WORSHIP AS INTERPERSONAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Worship is an interpersonal act in the vertical direction. It requires awareness, imagination, and concentration in contrast to habit or a stimulus-response elicited by form, place, or atmosphere. There is no required posture of the body, just a posture of the heart and mind. There is no necessary location such as one mountain or city (John 4:21). Instead, God wants people to worship him in spirit and truth because he is spirit and truth. Spirit lies inside interpersonalism. It does not require a temple, church building, or prayer room. It does not call for quietness or loudness, stillness or movement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Agape in 1 John</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/agape-in-1-john/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/agape-in-1-john/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Greek term &lt;em&gt;agape&lt;/em&gt; (ἀγάπη) appears with remarkable frequency in 1 John, forming the theological backbone of John&amp;rsquo;s understanding of God&amp;rsquo;s nature and Christian community life. This study examines the semantic range and theological significance of &lt;em&gt;agape&lt;/em&gt; in the Johannine corpus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lexical-background&#34;&gt;Lexical Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;classical-usage&#34;&gt;Classical Usage&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In classical Greek, &lt;em&gt;agape&lt;/em&gt; was a relatively rare term, overshadowed by &lt;em&gt;eros&lt;/em&gt; (romantic love) and &lt;em&gt;philia&lt;/em&gt; (friendship). The LXX translators&amp;rsquo; choice of &lt;em&gt;agape&lt;/em&gt; to render Hebrew &lt;em&gt;ahavah&lt;/em&gt; (אַהֲבָה) began the process of filling this term with rich theological content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
