<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ezra on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ezra on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the first year of Cyrus, king of Persia, to fulfill his message through Jeremiah, Yahveh stirred up Cyrus. He sent a written proclamation everywhere in his kingdom: 2&amp;quot;Cyrus, king of Persia, says, &amp;lsquo;Yahveh God of heaven has given me the kingdoms of the world and appointed me to build him a temple in Jerusalem, in Judah. 3Whoever is from his people, your God be with you! Go up and rebuild the Temple of Yahveh God of Israel, the God in Jerusalem. 4Wherever there&amp;rsquo;s a survivor, support him with silver and gold, supplies and livestock, plus freewill offerings.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;           &#x9;&#x9;Ezra 1:1-4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The People in the Province Who Went Up from the Exiles Nebuchadnezzar Took Away They went to Jerusalem and their towns in Judah 2with Zerubbabel, Jeshua, Nehemiah, Seraiah, Reelaiah, Mordecai, Bilshan, Mispar, Bigvai, Rehum, and Baanah: from the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; famly of Parosh &#x9;2,172&#x9;4family of Shephatiah &#x9;      372&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; family of Arah &#x9;775&#x9;6family of Pahath-moab (descended from Jeshua and Joab)  &#x9;   2,812&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; family of Elam &#x9;1,254&#x9;8family of Zattu &#x9;&#x9;      945&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When the seventh month came and the Israelites were in the towns, they came together in Jerusalem. 2Jeshua Ben-Jozadak, his brothers the priests, Zerubbabel Ben-Shealtiel, and his brothers built God&amp;rsquo;s altar for offering burnt offerings as written in the Law of Moses, the man of God. 3They set up the altar on its original site despite their fear of the people around them. They offered burnt offerings to Yahveh morning and evening. 4They celebrated the Festival of Booths as written and offered the set number of burnt offerings daily as required by the Law. 5From then on, there was continual burnt offering for new moons and the annual festivals Yahveh had consecrated. Everyone offered a freewill offering to Yahveh. 6From the first day, seventh month, they offered burnt offerings, but the foundation of the Temple hadn&amp;rsquo;t been laid. 7Then they donated money to the masons and carpenters as well as food, drink, and olive oil to the Sidonians and Tyrians to bring cedar from Lebanon by sea to Joppa with permission from Cyrus.&#x9;    Ezra 3:1-7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When the enemies of Judah and Benjamin heard that the exiles were rebuilding a temple to Yahveh God of Israel, 2they approached Zerubbabel and the other leaders, &amp;ldquo;Let us build with you. We worship your God too. We&amp;rsquo;ve been sacrificing to him since Esarhaddon, king of Assyria, sent us here.&amp;rdquo; 3But Zerubbabel, Jeshua, and the other leaders said, &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t have anything in common with us building a temple to our God. We&amp;rsquo;ll build it like King Cyrus decreed.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The prophets Haggai and Zechariah Ben-Iddo served as prophets to the Jews in Judah and Jerusalem in the name of the God of Israel. 2Then Zerubbabel and Jeshua started again to rebuild God&amp;rsquo;s Temple. His prophets supported them. 3At that time, Tattenai, governor of the province Beyond the River, and Shethar-bozenai, and their colleagues came and asked, &amp;ldquo;Who issued a decree for you to rebuild this Temple and restore this structure?&amp;rdquo; 4We told them the names of the men that were reconstructing it. 5But God kept an eye on the elders of the Jews. They didn&amp;rsquo;t stop them till a report could go to Darius and a written reply could come back.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; King Darius issued an order to search the Babylonian archives, which were housed in the treasury. 2But in the fortress in Ecbatana, in the province of Media, they found a scroll with the following written in it: &amp;ldquo;Record:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; In the first year of King Cyrus, he issued a decree: &amp;lsquo;As to God&amp;rsquo;s Temple in Jerusalem, rebuild it, where sacrifices are offered. Keep its foundations the same. Its height and width are 90ft 4with three courses of large stones alternating with one course of timbers. Pay for it out of the royal treasury. 5Take back to God&amp;rsquo;s temple the gold and silver articles Nebuchadnezzar took from it.&amp;rsquo;&#x9;   &#x9;Ezra 6:1-5 6&amp;quot;Now then, Tattenai, governor of Beyond the River, Shethar-bozenai, and your associates, officials in the provinces Beyond the River, don&amp;rsquo;t interfere. 7Let the governor and elders of the Jews rebuild God&amp;rsquo;s Temple on its site. 8And, I decree what you&amp;rsquo;re to do for those elders in rebuilding this Temple: without delay pay them the full cost out of the royal treasury from taxes in the provinces Beyond the River. 9As the priests in Jerusalem request, give daily whatever they need: young bulls, rams, and lambs for burnt offerings, wheat, salt, wine, and anointing oil. 10Then they can offer acceptable sacrifices to the God of heaven and pray for the life of the king and his sons. 11For anybody who violates this edict, I decree that a timber be pulled out of his house, he be impaled on it, and his house be made a garbage pile. 12May the God that has put his name there overthrow any king or people that tries to violate this decree and destroy that Temple of God. I, Darius, have made this decree. Carry it out diligently.&amp;rdquo;&#x9;Ezra 6:6-12 Completion and Dedication of the Temple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, in the reign of Artaxerxes, king of Persia, came Ezra Ben-Seraiah (Ben-Azariah Ben-Hilkiah 2Ben-Shallum Ben-Zadok Ben-Ahitub 3Ben-Amariah Ben-Azariah Ben-Meraioth 4Ben-Zerahiah Ben-Uzzi Ben-Bukki 5Ben-Abishua Ben-Phinehas Ben-Eleazar) Ben-Aaron the chief priest. 6Ezra, a scribe, an expert in the Law of Moses, came up from Babylon. The king granted him everything he requested because Yahveh&amp;rsquo;s hand was on him. 7Some Israelites, priests, Levites, singers, gatekeepers, and Temple servants came up to Jerusalem in the seventh year of King Artaxerxes. [8] 9On the first day, first month, Ezra started out from Babylon. On the first day, fifth month he arrived at Jerusalem because God&amp;rsquo;s good hand was on him. 10He had set his heart on studying the Law of Yahveh, practicing it, and teaching its statutes and ordinances in Israel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Heads of Families and the Genealogies of Men Who Went Up from Babylon During the Reign of King Artaxerxes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; from the family of Phinehas, Gershom; from the family of Ithamar, Daniel; from the family of David, Hattush,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; a descendant of Shecaniah; from the family of Parosh—Zechariah, plus 150 men in the genealogy;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; from the family of Pahath-moab, Eliehoenai Ben-Zerahiah plus 200 men;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When these things had been completed, the officials approached me, &amp;ldquo;The people of Israel, the priests, and the Levites haven&amp;rsquo;t separated from the foreigners and the disgusting things of the Canaanites, Hittites, Perizzites, Jebusites, Ammonites, Moabites, Egyptians, and Amorites. 2They&amp;rsquo;ve taken some of their daughters as wives for themselves and their sons. The holy race has intermingled with foreigners. The officials and rulers have been the most prominent in this unfaithfulness.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ezra 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/cyv/ezra/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ezra-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Ezra Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; While Ezra was praying and confessing, crying and prostrating himself in front of God&amp;rsquo;s Temple, a big crowd of men, women, and children gathered around him, sobbing with him. 2Shecaniah Ben-Jehiel, one of Elam&amp;rsquo;s sons, told him, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve been unfaithful to our God and married foreign women from the land. But there&amp;rsquo;s still hope for Israel. 3Let&amp;rsquo;s make a covenant with God to put away the wives and their children as you&amp;rsquo;ve advised and do it according to the Law. 4Get up! This is your responsibility. We&amp;rsquo;ll be with you. Have the courage to do it.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
