<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Women&#39;s Studies S 1TIM 2 on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/womens-studies-s-1tim-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Women&#39;s Studies S 1TIM 2 on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/womens-studies-s-1tim-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 TIMOTHY 2:8-15: SITUATIONAL OR GENERAL?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-28-15-situational-or-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-28-15-situational-or-general/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 TIMOTHY 2:8-15: SITUATIONAL OR GENERAL?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpreters have proposed several ways for removing from present observance of New Testament directives about male-female role relationship in the church and the home: 1 Timothy 2:8-15; 1 Corinthians 11:2-16; 14:33b-36; Colossians 3:18-19; and 1 Peter 3:1-7.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One way has been to (1) consider female deference a fallen condition (Genesis 3:16). Now that Christ has removed the curse, the principle no longer obtains. But the New Testament injunctions appear after Christ would have removed this supposed “curse.” Besides, “rule” (מָשַׁל, mashal) in Genesis 3:16 does not mean “rule” in some unwholesome sense as in a “cursed” estate; elders are to “rule well” in the church (1 Timothy 5:17; Hebrews 13:7, 17) and in the home (1 Timothy 3:4; cp. deacons in 3:11). Paul argues for female deference because the man was created first and the woman was deceived. In 1 Corinthians 11:7-9 the apostle adds that she was created from man and for man, and that Adam was created in the image of God (in some sense, degree, directness, or manner that Eve was not (cp. Genesis 2:21-23, 18).1 The five observations pertain to events that occurred before any fallen condition existed.2 Moreover, the other elements of the “fallen situation” in Genesis 3:14-21 have not been removed. Lastly, it is not a fallen condition that God is the head of Christ and that Christ is the head of every man, observations that Paul lays parallel to the man as the head of the woman (1 Corinthians 11:3; cp. Ephesians 5:23-24).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 TIMOTHY 2:9-15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-29-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-29-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 TIMOTHY 2:9-15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Paul’s Intended Connection Between Genesis 2-3 and Women’s Roles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul appeals to the sequence of creation and the manner of the fall for his not allowing women to teach or to exercise authority over men. One inference is that (1) Paul appeals to Genesis to confirm, rather than to prove, the propriety of his custom; it is a post facto appeal rather than an a priori one. He says what he says by his own authority rather than because of a historical divine reason. His authoritative conclusion rests on some practical consideration rather than a theological one. Then cultural propriety can be the basis; so outside the first-century circumstance, it does not necessarily apply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NOTATIONS ON 1 TIMOTHY 2:11-12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/notations-on-1-timothy-211-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/notations-on-1-timothy-211-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTATIONS ON 1 TIMOTHY 2:11-12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does αὐθεντεῖν mean “exercise authority” or “domineer”?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) The law of contrast implies that αὐθεντεῖν does not mean “dominate” since it is a correlative term with ὑποταγή in the previous verse. Ἐν πάσῃ ὑποταγῇ and αὐθεντεῖν seem to be correlative expressions like learn and teach, with which they appear. Correlative terms stand in a common larger category as natural contrasts: lost-saved, father-son, prophecy-fulfillment, faith-works, and the like. Within the same context the sense in which one is meant is the sense in which the other is used. If father means physical father, then son means physical son, not spiritual son. If prophesy means to state a significant principle, then fulfill means to be an example of that principle, not the occurrence of a prediction. Correlative terms obey the law of contrast/opposition/negation inside the law of harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN’S STUDIES AND “STANDARD SITUATION”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-and-standard-situation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-and-standard-situation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN’S STUDIES AND “STANDARD SITUATION”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One point in 1 Timothy 2 has to do with husband-wife vs. man-woman as Paul’s intended reference. Connecting the statements of 1 Timothy with (a) a husband-wife contrast rather than (b) a man-woman contrast represents a crucial variable between instruction on marriage roles vs. gender roles. A third approach to the text has something of the same effect but seems to be more straightforward and therefore less cumbersome: (c) Paul is addressing “standard situation,” that is, married with children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN’S STUDIES IN 1 TIMOTHY 2:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-in-1-timothy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-in-1-timothy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN’S STUDIES IN 1 TIMOTHY 2:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FACTORS IN INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nature of the New Testament: body of law or book of wisdom (See essays on “Imperatival Intent” and “Law and Wisdom.”)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nature of the pastoral epistles: contain mandates on morality all the way through exhortations and cultural sensitivities down to bylaw material&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; The nature of 2 Timothy materials: directed to a local situation (Ephesus) or applicable to all the churches of the Gentile territories (note 2:7)?&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; The lack of homogeneity in lists: lifting up holy hands and dress code items need not be of the same sort as female subjection manifested in not teaching or exercising authority over men&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Quietness” (ἡσυχία, hēsychia, 2:11, 12) as a manifestation of the female deference principle (distinction between the principle itself and the cultural manner of manifesting it):  note the cognate term ἡσύχάζω (hēsychazō), meaning “to rest”; in Luke 23:56b, where it is used of “resting” on the Sabbath day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ΑΥΘΕΝΤΗΣ  (AUTHENTĒS)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/%CE%B1%CF%85%CE%B8%CE%B5%CE%BD%CF%84%CE%B7%CF%82-authent%C4%93s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/%CE%B1%CF%85%CE%B8%CE%B5%CE%BD%CF%84%CE%B7%CF%82-authent%C4%93s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ΑΥΘΕΝΤΗΣ  (AUTHENTĒS)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An important item in 1 Timothy 2 is a case of αὐθεντέω (authenteō) that Al Wolters pointed out at the November meeting of the Evangelical Theological Society in Lisle, Illinois.  It appears in Origen’s Commentary on 1 Corinthians, which, I believe, is one of Origen’s as-yet untranslated works. The full Greek text of the commentary is in Journal of Theological Studies, X (1909), 29-51. The reference appears in 74:20 of Origen’s Commentary. The text is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
