<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philippians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philippians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Philippians 1</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;philippians-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Philippians Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul and Timothy, servants of ChristMessiah Jesus, to the saints in Philippi and their bishops and deacons. 2Grace and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for the memories I have of you. 4I gladly mention you in my prayers 5because of your fellowship in the gospel since day one. 6I&amp;rsquo;m confident that the good work God began in you he&amp;rsquo;ll keep perfecting till Christ comes. 7It&amp;rsquo;s right for me to regard you that way because in my imprisonment and defense of the gospel, you&amp;rsquo;ve shared your grace with me. 8God is witness, I long for you with the affections Jesus has. 9I pray that your love will keep growing along with knowledge and insight 10so you&amp;rsquo;ll approve what&amp;rsquo;s excellent, be sincere, and keep your conscience clear till Christ comes. 11That way the fruit that comes from goodness will fill you, the fruit that comes through Jesus Christ to God&amp;rsquo;s glory and praise.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippians 2</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;philippians-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Philippians Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So, if there&amp;rsquo;s any encouragement in Christ, any comfort from love, any fellowship with the Spirit, any affection and compassion, 2fill me with happiness. That way you&amp;rsquo;ll have the same attitude, love, purpose, and unity of spirit. 3Don&amp;rsquo;t do anything selfish out of empty conceit, but in humility consider each other more important than yourself. 4Don&amp;rsquo;t just look at your own interests, but at the interests of other people too. 5Take the attitude Christ Jesus took.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippians 3</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;philippians-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Philippians Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So, family of Christ, be happy in the Lord. Writing things like these is not hard for me to do, and it reinforces you. 2Watch out for dogs, evil doers, the &amp;lsquo;false Circumcision.&amp;rsquo; 3We are the &amp;lsquo;Circumcision,&amp;rsquo; who serve by God&amp;rsquo;s spirit, who take pride in Christ Jesus, who don&amp;rsquo;t put confidence in what&amp;rsquo;s physical. 4If anybody could put confidence in that, I sure could: 5I was circumcised on the eighth day, from the nation of Israel, tribe of Benjamin, the truest of Hebrews. As to the Law, I was a Pharisee. 6As to zeal, I persecuted the church. As to legal goodness, I was blameless. 7Butms what were gains to me I consider losses for Christ. 8Everything&amp;rsquo;s a loss compared to knowing Christ Jesus my Lord. I lost everything on account of him and considered it rubbish so I could gain him. 9I don&amp;rsquo;t have a goodness of my own—from keeping the Law; I have a goodness that comes from trusting Christ, a goodness that God gives conditioned on trust. 10I want to know him, the power his resurrection has, and fellowship with his sufferings. I want to live in conformity with his death 11so I can attain resurrection from the dead, whatever it takes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippians 4</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/philippians/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;philippians-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Philippians Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So, fellow Christians loved and longed for, my joy and crown, stand firm in the Lord.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; I urge Euodia and Syntyche to work in harmony in the Lord. 3Yes, and I ask you, loyal yoke fellow, help them. They struggled together with me in the gospel, with Clement and the rest of my fellow workers, whose names are in the Book of Life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Always bepl happy in the Lord; I&amp;rsquo;ll say it again, be happy. 5Let everybody see yourpl gentle spirit. The Lord is near. 6Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, but in prayer and supplication make your requests to God accompanied by gratitude. 7God&amp;rsquo;s peace, which goes beyond understanding, will keep watch over your hearts and minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
