<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WOMEN&#39;S STUDIES on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/womens-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WOMEN&#39;S STUDIES on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/womens-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 TIMOTHY 2:8-15: SITUATIONAL OR GENERAL?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-28-15-situational-or-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-28-15-situational-or-general/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 TIMOTHY 2:8-15: SITUATIONAL OR GENERAL?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpreters have proposed several ways for removing from present observance of New Testament directives about male-female role relationship in the church and the home: 1 Timothy 2:8-15; 1 Corinthians 11:2-16; 14:33b-36; Colossians 3:18-19; and 1 Peter 3:1-7.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One way has been to (1) consider female deference a fallen condition (Genesis 3:16). Now that Christ has removed the curse, the principle no longer obtains. But the New Testament injunctions appear after Christ would have removed this supposed “curse.” Besides, “rule” (מָשַׁל, mashal) in Genesis 3:16 does not mean “rule” in some unwholesome sense as in a “cursed” estate; elders are to “rule well” in the church (1 Timothy 5:17; Hebrews 13:7, 17) and in the home (1 Timothy 3:4; cp. deacons in 3:11). Paul argues for female deference because the man was created first and the woman was deceived. In 1 Corinthians 11:7-9 the apostle adds that she was created from man and for man, and that Adam was created in the image of God (in some sense, degree, directness, or manner that Eve was not (cp. Genesis 2:21-23, 18).1 The five observations pertain to events that occurred before any fallen condition existed.2 Moreover, the other elements of the “fallen situation” in Genesis 3:14-21 have not been removed. Lastly, it is not a fallen condition that God is the head of Christ and that Christ is the head of every man, observations that Paul lays parallel to the man as the head of the woman (1 Corinthians 11:3; cp. Ephesians 5:23-24).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 TIMOTHY 2:9-15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-29-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/1-timothy-29-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 TIMOTHY 2:9-15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Paul’s Intended Connection Between Genesis 2-3 and Women’s Roles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul appeals to the sequence of creation and the manner of the fall for his not allowing women to teach or to exercise authority over men. One inference is that (1) Paul appeals to Genesis to confirm, rather than to prove, the propriety of his custom; it is a post facto appeal rather than an a priori one. He says what he says by his own authority rather than because of a historical divine reason. His authoritative conclusion rests on some practical consideration rather than a theological one. Then cultural propriety can be the basis; so outside the first-century circumstance, it does not necessarily apply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABSTRACT OF CONCEPTS RELEVANT TO WOMEN’S STUDIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/abstract-of-concepts-relevant-to-womens-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/abstract-of-concepts-relevant-to-womens-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT OF CONCEPTS RELEVANT TO WOMEN’S STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Something must explain why equally committed Christians come out on different sides of the same issue from the same Bible. It is either because of (1) unconscious presuppositions, (2) faulty reasoning, (3) misunderstanding of how language works, or (4) inadequate concept inventory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following notations attempt to (a) map out the issues, (b) isolate the relevant interpretation principles, (c) define the exegetical task, and (d) identify the biblical texts most involved. They also try to (e) narrow down the point at issue so that irrelevant matters are set aside so that what we are sure of can lessen the practical problem in the church.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADDENDUM: “MALE AND FEMALE”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/addendum-male-and-female/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/addendum-male-and-female/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADDENDUM: “MALE AND FEMALE”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Old Testament Occurrences&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Man/&#x9;&#x9;      &#x9;Septuagint Readings: Ralphs’ &amp;amp; Brenton’s Editions Combined&#x9;      MT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Animal Gender &#x9;          (ἄρσην/θῆλυς)                                                                    נְקֵבָה/זָכָר&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M&#x9;&#x9;n&#x9;Gen. 1:27&#x9;ἄρσεν καὶ θῆλυ &#x9;(“[God] made them male and female”)      Gen. 1:27&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M&#x9;  &#x9;n&#x9;        5:2&#x9;             &amp;quot;        &#x9;(“[God] made them male and female”)&#x9;        5:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A&#x9;   &#x9;n&#x9;        6:19&#x9;             &amp;quot;        &#x9;(&amp;ldquo;They will be male and female&amp;rdquo;)*      &#x9;        6:19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A&#x9;    &#x9;n&#x9;        6:20&#x9;             &amp;quot;&#x9;(“They . . . male and female”)*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A2&#x9;    &#x9;n&#x9;        7:22&#x9;             &amp;quot;&#x9;(“seven and seven, male and female”)&#x9;&#x9;  7:22&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADDITIONAL THOUGHT ON WOMEN’S STUDIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/additional-thought-on-womens-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/additional-thought-on-womens-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADDITIONAL THOUGHT ON WOMEN’S STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Ministry Before Consensus”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some additional questions arise from previous presentations on women’s studies. For one thing, I have used “ministry” in the title of a paper that centered on leadership in relation to women&amp;rsquo;s roles. “Ministry” is broader than leadership, but leadership is the area in which disagreement about women&amp;rsquo;s roles has arisen. One way to help resolve controversial issues is to appeal to the larger category in which they stand. A title about “ministry” is useful on this subject because women are clearly free to make significant contributions to kingdom work; the question is whether they are free to make contributions in formal leadership ministry over men. Ministry as the larger category sets the context for leadership ministry. Any distinctive elements in the latter must be added in such a way as not to contradict the larger framework. The thesis in “Ministry Before Consensus” has been that we can carry forward the kingdom&amp;rsquo;s work significantly and with minimal negatives even before we resolve the problem. We can do that if we keep the problem clearly defined, if we keep it from spilling over into foreign issues, and if we maintain a proper understanding of Christian leadership. Women&amp;rsquo;s formal and informal Christian leadership ministry needs to conform to Christian leadership ministry generally, Christian leadership ministry needs to take place in a way that harmonizes with Christian ministry, and Christian ministry of every sort must retain the characteristics of interpersonal process. Since it is ministry that we want to get done, ministry is the subject area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>APPLYING NEW TESTAMENT TEACHING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/applying-new-testament-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/applying-new-testament-teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;APPLYING NEW TESTAMENT TEACHING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ON MARRIAGE, FAMILY, AND PUBLIC DECORUM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CONCEPT 1:  Family is the basic unit of society, more than the individual.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CONCEPT 2:  When order is added to personal relationship, the qualities of person relationship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;are not set aside.  Structure retains the interpersonal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CONCEPT 3:  Worth and the sense of worth come from behavior compared to responsibility, not&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;person compared to person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Worth comes from accomplished responsibility, not “success” in competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVANGELICAL PERSPECTIVES ON MEN-WOMEN RELATIONSHIP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/evangelical-perspectives-on-men-women-relationship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/evangelical-perspectives-on-men-women-relationship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVANGELICAL PERSPECTIVES ON MEN-WOMEN RELATIONSHIP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introductory Observations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general, women’s studies relate to the genetic nature of men and women and cultural expectancy regarding their interaction. Discussing evangelical perspectives on men and women in relationship adds biblical interpretation to the inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On this subject what makes a viewpoint evangelical is not so much the viewpoint itself as the accompanying attitude toward scripture and the consequent method of interpretation which that attitude involves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FEMALE METAPHORS FOR GOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/female-metaphors-for-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/female-metaphors-for-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FEMALE METAPHORS FOR GOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:27 Women and Men created in God’s image&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Humankind was created as God’s reflection: in the divine image God created them; female and male, God made them.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hosea 11:3-4 God described as a mother&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God: “Yet it was I who taught Ephraim to walk, I who took them up in my arms; but they did not know that I healed them. I led them with cords of human kindness, with bands of love. I was to them like those who lift infants to their cheeks. I bent down to them and fed them.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GALATIANS 3:28: A TEST CASE FOR SOUND HERMENEUTICS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/galatians-328-a-test-case-for-sound-hermeneutics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/galatians-328-a-test-case-for-sound-hermeneutics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GALATIANS 3:28: A TEST CASE FOR SOUND HERMENEUTICS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“There is no male and female because you are all one in Christ Jesus” (Galatians 3:28). The wording of that part-verse has become a popular way for Christians to express the egalitarian principle that (a) in the home and in the church, there are no necessary role distinctions between the sexes. A man or a woman has the same theoretical “right” to lead. In its healthiest form, egalitarianism calls for “a fair field and no favors” in all parts of the social arena.1 A more extreme alternative to male headship is the belief that (b) in the home and in the church, there is only interpersonal leadership. Not only is there is no designated final responsibility in marriage and ministry referenced to sex; there is no hierarchical arrangement at all; there is only natural vs. formal leadership.2 Cooperation rather than structure is the ideal modus operandi. At least the first of these viewpoints is a proposed meaning of Paul’s statement to the Galatians. This study evaluates that reading in light of the evident exegetical and theological import of the passage, and addresses various ways by which women’s roles come or might come into its sphere of meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GREEK ELEMENTS IN THE INTERPRETATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/greek-elements-in-the-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/greek-elements-in-the-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GREEK ELEMENTS IN THE INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF EPHESIANS 5:21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;editorial question&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Ephesians 5:21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does “defer to one another in the fear of Christ” belong with the preceding or succeeding context?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The United Bible Society’s text of the Greek New Testament puts the injunction with the preceding material in the third edition, but with the succeeding context in the third edition (corrected). Grammatically the participle “submitting” parallels participles in the preceding two verses—participles that grammatically modify the subject of the finite verb in 5:18. A free-standing participle can be a command; but clear cases of that usage are infrequent in the New Testament (Mark 5:23; Romans 12:92, 10?, 11?, 123?, 132? 163?, 172?, 18, 19; 13:11; 1 Corinthians 8:24; Ephesians 5:21?; Titus 2:7; 1 Peter 2:18; 3:1). Moreover, nothing grammatical calls for invoking that usage in Ephesians 5:21 because of the parallel between “deferring” and the preceding participles of 5:19-20: “. . . speaking to one another . . . singing and making melody . . . giving thanks . . . deferring to one another . . .” Grammatically, “deferring” ties with the preceding flow of thought by being parallel to the three preceding participles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMPERATIVAL INTENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/imperatival-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/imperatival-intent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IMPERATIVAL INTENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Description of Imperatival Intent&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imperative forms can convey a range of meanings; they have (1) varied quality. In language, authorial intent does not bear a one-to-one relationship with linguistic forms. In assessing a writer’s use of the imperative mood, we look beyond the form itself and infer its force from the near and distant literary context, the historical context, and the nature of the case.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) Imperatives may entreat, where one wants a benefit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISSUES IN WOMEN’S STUDIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/issues-in-womens-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/issues-in-womens-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ISSUES IN WOMEN’S STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Guided Study&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below are six items for thought and research on women’s studies. Some points may be referred to in Hermeneutics: Getting the Point; check the scripture index for locations. As much as possible, consciously integrate into your write-up the principles studied in the course.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some items involve work with the original languages and may not seem fully understandable to those who have not studied Greek. There is no expertise in biblical languages required, however, since the exercises are vocabulary items that can be looked at through Englishman’s Greek Concordance to the New Testament. On some questions students may want to consult Dr. Warren’s “Preliminary Essays on Women’s Studies.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>James B. Torrance. Worship, Community &amp; the Triune God of Grace. Downers Grove, Illinois: InterVarsity Press, 1997. 130pp. Reviewed by Virgil Warren, Manhattan, Kansas.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/james-b-torrance-worship-community-the-triune-god-of-grace-downers-grove-illinois-intervarsity-press-1997-130pp-reviewed-by-virgil-warren-manhattan-kansas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/james-b-torrance-worship-community-the-triune-god-of-grace-downers-grove-illinois-intervarsity-press-1997-130pp-reviewed-by-virgil-warren-manhattan-kansas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November 1994, James Torrance, professor emeritus of systematic theology at the University of Aberdeen, presented the Didsbury Lectures in the Nazarene Theological College, Manchester. InterVarsity Press offers these lectures in written form with a preface and appendix added by the author.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Worship is the central concern of the volume, which brings the author to emphasize the nature of God particularly as trinitarian and gracious. Worship is described as “our participation through the Spirit in the Son’s communion with the Father” (p. 15; cp. 21). We “worship the Father through the Son in the Spirit” (p. 22). We “participate through the Spirit in the incarnate Son’s communion with the Father” (p. 59). “The real agent in all true worship is Jesus.” Granted the ambiguities in such phraseology as “participation through the Spirit” and “Jesus as the only true agent,” we nevertheless see that Christ’s “priesthood” is not simply in regard to something completed; it is the sole ongoing basis for perpetual relationship to God, in life generally and in worship especially.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man &amp; Woman in Christian Perspective, by Werner Neuer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/man-woman-in-christian-perspective-by-werner-neuer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/man-woman-in-christian-perspective-by-werner-neuer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Man &amp;amp; Woman in Christian Perspective, by Werner Neuer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Werner Neuer. Man &amp;amp; Woman in Christian Perspective. Trans. from the 2nd German edition by Gordon J. Wenham. Wheaton, IL: Crossway Books, 1991 [1981]. 224 pp. pr&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neuer begins by placing the relevance of his topic in the contemporary challenge of secular feminism, an important point because the church, in being biblical, should not be needlessly countercultural. Subsequent chapters on male-female differences reflect the natural assumption that in the family and in the church God has assigned role emphases correlated with sex in keeping with the way he has gifted males and females. Five chapters deal with the view of man and woman found in the Old Testament, the gospels, the epistles of Paul, the rest of the New Testament, and in church history. Two chapters address the continuing validity of the biblical viewpoint and the urgency of practicing it. The volume concludes with a summary of main points. Along the way, five excursi expand on texts and issues that call for more extended treatment than the ongoing presentation itself allows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAN AND WOMAN IN ADAM AND IN CHRIST</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/man-and-woman-in-adam-and-in-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/man-and-woman-in-adam-and-in-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MAN AND WOMAN IN ADAM AND IN CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One major argument for egalitarianism in marriage and the church pictures female deference as a fallen condition that has been reversed in Christ. “Your husband will rule over you” (Genesis 3:16) has changed to “In Christ there is no male and female” (Galatians 3:28). New Testament comments about male headship merely temporalize the Christian ideal in the interests of Christian mission. The following comments attempt to show that this scenario artificially combines unrelated ideas and overextends the cultural variable. Genesis 3:16 does not indicate a result of the curse, Galatians 3:28 is not an absolute principle, and statements elsewhere about headship are not necessarily pragmatic concessions to cultural norms that no longer apply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MINISTRY BEFORE CONSENSUS ON WOMEN’S ROLES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ministry-before-consensus-on-womens-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ministry-before-consensus-on-womens-roles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MINISTRY BEFORE CONSENSUS ON WOMEN’S ROLES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN THE CHURCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Practical situations have a way of forcing us to “get on with it” despite unresolved questions. While pragmatics fosters “caving in” to illegitimate pressures, it also keeps us from letting theoretical matters make the system dysfunctional and pushes us to put things in perspective. Current differences of understanding about the range of women’s roles in the church and the home offer one more example of the qualifying effect of practical need on doctrinal theory. The need to fulfill the mission mandate suggests that we adopt an interim approach that does justice to everything we are sure about in connection with this issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NOTATIONS ON 1 TIMOTHY 2:11-12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/notations-on-1-timothy-211-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/notations-on-1-timothy-211-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTATIONS ON 1 TIMOTHY 2:11-12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does αὐθεντεῖν mean “exercise authority” or “domineer”?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) The law of contrast implies that αὐθεντεῖν does not mean “dominate” since it is a correlative term with ὑποταγή in the previous verse. Ἐν πάσῃ ὑποταγῇ and αὐθεντεῖν seem to be correlative expressions like learn and teach, with which they appear. Correlative terms stand in a common larger category as natural contrasts: lost-saved, father-son, prophecy-fulfillment, faith-works, and the like. Within the same context the sense in which one is meant is the sense in which the other is used. If father means physical father, then son means physical son, not spiritual son. If prophesy means to state a significant principle, then fulfill means to be an example of that principle, not the occurrence of a prediction. Correlative terms obey the law of contrast/opposition/negation inside the law of harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PARAMETERS IN WOMEN’S STUDIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/parameters-in-womens-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/parameters-in-womens-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PARAMETERS IN WOMEN’S STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Biblical Passages Relevant to Women’s Studies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exodus 15:20-21: Miriam and the women of Israel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Judges 4:4-5:31: judgeship of Deborah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Kings 22:14-20: Huldah the prophetess&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proverbs 31:10-31: description of a worthy woman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luke 2:9: Anna prophesied&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 2:18 &amp;lt; Joel 2:28-29: “Your sons and daughters will prophesy”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 21:9: Philip’s four daughters tht prophesied&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romans 16:1-3: Phoebe, a servant in the church at Cenchrea that Paul sent to Rome&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROLEGOMENA FOR MEN AND WOMEN IN CHRIST</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/prolegomena-for-men-and-women-in-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/prolegomena-for-men-and-women-in-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROLEGOMENA FOR MEN AND WOMEN IN CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Précis   Neglected or misunderstood factors complicate any endeavor, including the interaction between men and women in the home, the church, and society. An unnecessary “edge” gets into discussions on this matter because of unconscious preconceptions about (a) the bases for self-esteem, (b) the nature of leaders and led and their interaction, and (c) the impact that love has on all interpersonal processes formal or natural.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STRUCTURING THE HERMENEUTICAL TASK IN WOMEN’S STUDIES: WISDOM OR LAW?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/structuring-the-hermeneutical-task-in-womens-studies-wisdom-or-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/structuring-the-hermeneutical-task-in-womens-studies-wisdom-or-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STRUCTURING THE HERMENEUTICAL TASK IN WOMEN’S STUDIES: WISDOM OR LAW?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are inclined to think that some reasonable explanation lies behind the variant understandings of gender roles by equally sincere and capable Christian interpreters. Something must be happening in the minds of some that is not happening in others who likewise take a proper view of scripture. We suspect that part of the difficulty lies at (a) the linguistic level. People do not remember that the imperative mood can have more than one quality, hence, our essay elsewhere on “Imperatival Intent,” which assembles the different values that imperatives and their equivalents may have. Another part of the difficulty lies at (b) the corpus level. People make different assumptions about the nature of the New Testament as a body of normative literature, hence, this essay on “wisdom” vs. “law” and the accompanying excerpt on “Confusing Advice and Commandment.” What we have to say here comes in association with the accompanying diagram.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUBMITTING TO ONE ANOTHER:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/submitting-to-one-another/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/submitting-to-one-another/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUBMITTING TO ONE ANOTHER:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 5:21-6:9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This portion of Ephesians deals with “household teaching” on the relationship of husbands and wives, parents and children, masters and slaves. Other comparable texts are Colossians 3:18-4:1 and 1 Peter 2:(13-)18-3:7.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In regard to each relationship, Paul appeals to interpersonal principles to set the tone for it. In other places, he does the same thing to solve problems that impact practical relationships in the body (languages, 1 Corinthians 12-14; leadership, 2 Corinthians 10-13; etc.). He can do that because personal relationship is always the context in which further considerations exist and must exist in a way that does not interfere with that context. Paul implies that interpersonalism should carry the process as much as possible. Only when influence for practical reasons is inadequate is there a need to invoke the principle of authority (much less force).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE MEANING OF “SUBMISSION”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-meaning-of-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-meaning-of-submission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MEANING OF “SUBMISSION”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As with other controversial matters, the biblical view of marriage and the family gets lost in the throes of pendulum thinking. Truth tends to lie between extremes, but on this issue unnecessary rigidness creates an extreme opposite and equal reaction. After a while,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;discussions on headship and submission get lost in a battle between those extremes and lose sight of the proper orientation for the subject. Emotions take over on one side, which wants to defend the accuracy of scripture in all matters whereof it speaks. The other side wants to breathe some fresh air of freedom for women and their service in the kingdom. Whenever something comes up that seems to foster one extreme, people on the other extreme react. As a result, discussion does not resolve the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN MENTIONED IN THE BIBLE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/women-mentioned-in-the-bible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/women-mentioned-in-the-bible/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN MENTIONED IN THE BIBLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To maintain a balanced approach in the current women’s studies debate, we should keep in mind what women did with divine approval in both Testaments. The following is a suggestive list.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anna: a “prophetess” in Jerusalem at the time of Jesus’ presentation in the temple. She “gave thanks to God and spoke of him to all that were looking for redemption in Israel” (Luke 2:36-38).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN’S STUDIES AND “STANDARD SITUATION”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-and-standard-situation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-and-standard-situation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN’S STUDIES AND “STANDARD SITUATION”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One point in 1 Timothy 2 has to do with husband-wife vs. man-woman as Paul’s intended reference. Connecting the statements of 1 Timothy with (a) a husband-wife contrast rather than (b) a man-woman contrast represents a crucial variable between instruction on marriage roles vs. gender roles. A third approach to the text has something of the same effect but seems to be more straightforward and therefore less cumbersome: (c) Paul is addressing “standard situation,” that is, married with children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN’S STUDIES IN 1 TIMOTHY 2:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-in-1-timothy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-in-1-timothy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN’S STUDIES IN 1 TIMOTHY 2:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FACTORS IN INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nature of the New Testament: body of law or book of wisdom (See essays on “Imperatival Intent” and “Law and Wisdom.”)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nature of the pastoral epistles: contain mandates on morality all the way through exhortations and cultural sensitivities down to bylaw material&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; The nature of 2 Timothy materials: directed to a local situation (Ephesus) or applicable to all the churches of the Gentile territories (note 2:7)?&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; The lack of homogeneity in lists: lifting up holy hands and dress code items need not be of the same sort as female subjection manifested in not teaching or exercising authority over men&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Quietness” (ἡσυχία, hēsychia, 2:11, 12) as a manifestation of the female deference principle (distinction between the principle itself and the cultural manner of manifesting it):  note the cognate term ἡσύχάζω (hēsychazō), meaning “to rest”; in Luke 23:56b, where it is used of “resting” on the Sabbath day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WOMEN’S STUDIES NOTATIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-notations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/womens-studies-notations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WOMEN’S STUDIES NOTATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In women’s studies, something is causing equally committed, intelligent, educated, hard-working, well-known Christians to come to incompatible conclusions, which leads to disagreement and division. Since this topic has behavioral correlates, we cannot treat it as we do the millennial question and go on about our work; this topic affects how we go on with our work. Since it is a broad-to-narrow issue, people with different persuasions find it hard to be equally tolerant; it is usually easier for a broader view to be accepting of a more restricted one than vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ΑΥΘΕΝΤΗΣ  (AUTHENTĒS)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/%CE%B1%CF%85%CE%B8%CE%B5%CE%BD%CF%84%CE%B7%CF%82-authent%C4%93s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/%CE%B1%CF%85%CE%B8%CE%B5%CE%BD%CF%84%CE%B7%CF%82-authent%C4%93s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ΑΥΘΕΝΤΗΣ  (AUTHENTĒS)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An important item in 1 Timothy 2 is a case of αὐθεντέω (authenteō) that Al Wolters pointed out at the November meeting of the Evangelical Theological Society in Lisle, Illinois.  It appears in Origen’s Commentary on 1 Corinthians, which, I believe, is one of Origen’s as-yet untranslated works. The full Greek text of the commentary is in Journal of Theological Studies, X (1909), 29-51. The reference appears in 74:20 of Origen’s Commentary. The text is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
