<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Romans on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Romans on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Romans 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul, servant of ChristMessiah Jesus, called to be an apostle, and set apart to deliver the good news 2God promised through his prophets in the scriptures. 3-5That news is about his Son, David&amp;rsquo;s son by descent—physically, and God&amp;rsquo;s Son by designation—spiritually as to holiness. God powerfully designated him such by raising him from the dead. Through Jesus Christ our Lord we&amp;rsquo;ve received grace and apostleship for making obedient faith available to Gentiles. 6Among them you, too, are the called people of Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So yousg that condemn don&amp;rsquo;t have any excuse. When you condemn someone else, you condemn yourself, because you&amp;rsquo;re doing the same things. 2You know it&amp;rsquo;s right for God to condemn people that do things like that. 3Do you suppose—condemner of another while doing the same things yourself—that you are going to escape his condemnation? 4Do you disregard his rich kindness, tolerance, and patience, and not understand that his kindness is for leading you to repentance? 5Because of your stubborn, unrepentant heart, you&amp;rsquo;re storing up displeasure for yourself when God reveals his just condemnation. 6He&amp;rsquo;ll pay back every person for what they&amp;rsquo;ve done. 7That will mean eternal life for people who strive for glory, honor, and immortality by carrying through in good works. 8It&amp;rsquo;ll mean displeasure and anger for people that chase after injustice. 9There&amp;rsquo;ll be trouble and distress for everybody that does evil, for Jews first and for Greeks. 10But there&amp;rsquo;ll be honor and peace for everybody that does good, for Jews first and for Greeks. 11God doesn&amp;rsquo;t play favorites: 12as many as have sinned without having the Law will perish without having it; as many as have sinned under it will be condemned by it. 13It&amp;rsquo;s not who hears the Law that&amp;rsquo;s good, as far as God&amp;rsquo;s concerned; it&amp;rsquo;s who does the Law. 14When Gentiles that don&amp;rsquo;t have the Law, naturally do what&amp;rsquo;s in it, they are governing themselves. 15They show that the Law is written on their hearts. Their conscience testifies, and their thoughts defend or accuse one another. 16That&amp;rsquo;s the basis for judgment when God by Christ Jesus judges people&amp;rsquo;s secrets by the good news I&amp;rsquo;m presenting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So, what advantage does a Jew have? What&amp;rsquo;s the benefit of circumcision? 2A lot, in a lot of ways. The first advantage is that God entrusted the Jews with his messages. 3So what if some Jews were unfaithful? Their unfaithfulness doesn&amp;rsquo;t do away with God&amp;rsquo;s faithfulness, does it? 4Goodness, no! Let God be true and everyone else a liar, like the scripture says,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; If our unrighteousness highlights God&amp;rsquo;s righteousness, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say, would we, that God&amp;rsquo;s not fair in inflicting his displeasure? (I&amp;rsquo;m speaking here for the sake of argument.) 6Goodness, no! How would he judge the world? 7We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say, would we, that since our lie highlights God&amp;rsquo;s truth, he shouldn&amp;rsquo;t consider us sinners? 8We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say, would we—as some accuse us of saying, &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s do evil to bring about good&amp;rdquo;? (They deserve condemnation!)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; What can we say, then, our ancestor Abraham discovered? 2If what he did, justified him, he had something to feel good about, but not toward God. 3What does the scripture say? &amp;ldquo;Abraham trusted God, and God considered him righteous&amp;rdquo; [Gen 15:6] because of it. 4In the case of people that are producing righteousness, the consequence—being considered righteous—doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from God or his grace; he would owe it to them to consider them righteous. 5But for those who are not producing righteousness but are trusting the One that considers the ungodly as righteous, their trusting God to do that is considered righteousness. 6David speaks about the &amp;ldquo;good fortune&amp;rdquo; of people God considers righteous aside from law,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ve been justified by trusting, and we express trusting God by trusting our Lord Jesus Christ. 2The Christ gives us access to this grace that we stand in. Because of it, we rejoice in the hope that comes from our glorious God. 3Not only that, but we can even rejoice in hardships because we know they produce endurance, 4which produces character, which produces a hope 5that doesn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint because God keeps pouring out his love into our hearts through the Holy Spirit he gave us. 6When we were still weak, at the right time ChristMessiah died for the ungodly. 7Hardly anybody is willing to die even for somebody that&amp;rsquo;s good. Somebody might, 8but God has shown us how much he cares about us by having ChristMessiah die for us while we were still sinners. 9More than that, if his blood has justified us, we&amp;rsquo;re safe from God&amp;rsquo;s displeasure. 10If the death of his Son reconciled us to God while we were estranged, now that he&amp;rsquo;s reconciled us, his life will save us. 11All the while, we take pride in God through his Son who reconciled us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So should we say, &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s keep sinning so there&amp;rsquo;ll be more grace&amp;rdquo;? 2Goodness, no! How can we who died to sin keep living in it? 3Don&amp;rsquo;t you know that we who were baptized into Christ Jesus, were baptized into his death? 4Baptism buried us with him into death. As the Father gloriously raised Christ from the dead, we too can live in a new life. 5If we&amp;rsquo;ve participated in what&amp;rsquo;s like his death, we&amp;rsquo;ll participate in what&amp;rsquo;s like his resurrection. 6Know this: our old self was crucified with him to destroy the sinful body so we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t serve sin anymore. 7Whoever dies is justified from sin. 8If we&amp;rsquo;ve died with Christ, we believe we&amp;rsquo;ll live with him. 9We know that since Christ arose from the dead, he won&amp;rsquo;t die again, and death doesn&amp;rsquo;t have control over him. 10The death he died, he died to sin once and for all; the life he lives now, he keeps living to God. 11We consider ourselves dead to sin too, but alive to God in Christ Jesus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t you know, you that know the Law, that it applies to someone as long as the person&amp;rsquo;s alive? 2The Law ties a woman to her husband as long as he&amp;rsquo;s alive. If he dies, she&amp;rsquo;s free from the law about husbands. 3So while he&amp;rsquo;s alive, she&amp;rsquo;d be an adulteress if she joined herself to another man. But if her husband dies, she&amp;rsquo;s free from the law, and she&amp;rsquo;s not an adulteress if she joins herself to another man. 4So, through the Christ&amp;rsquo;s body you also died to the Law and united with someone else—who resurrected—so you could bear fruit to God. 5When you were in the flesh, its sinful desires that were through the Law worked in your members to bear fruit that led to death. 6Now you&amp;rsquo;re released from the Law because you&amp;rsquo;ve died to what imprisoned you. As a result, you&amp;rsquo;re serving in the new spirit, not in the old letter.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So there&amp;rsquo;s no condemnation in Christ Jesus. 2The life-producing spirit that operates in him has freed you from law that produces sin and death. 3What the Law couldn&amp;rsquo;t do because it operated through weak flesh, God did by sending his Son in the form of sin-oriented flesh to deal with sin in the flesh and put it in its place. 4So the goodness the Law called for, you can fulfill by living according to the spirit instead of the flesh. 5People that live in a flesh-oriented way focus on material things; people that live in a spirit-oriented way focus on things that are not material. 6The fleshly mentality leads to a dead end; the spiritual mentality leads to life and peace. 7So the flesh-oriented mentality opposes God because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t—and can&amp;rsquo;t—be in submission to his Law. 8People that live in a flesh-oriented way can&amp;rsquo;t be pleasing God. 9But, we&amp;rsquo;re not flesh-oriented, but spirit-oriented if God&amp;rsquo;s Spirit lives in us. If we don&amp;rsquo;t have Christ&amp;rsquo;s spirit, we don&amp;rsquo;t belong to him. 10If Christ is in us, the body is dead because of sin, but the spirit is alive because of goodness. 11If the Spirit of the one that resurrected Jesus is living in us, the One that resurrected Christ will make our mortal bodies alive by the Spirit that is living in us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Truth is, in Christ I have constant sorrow in my heart. I&amp;rsquo;m not lying; my conscience confirms it in the Holy Spirit: 3I&amp;rsquo;d be willing to be cut off from the ChristMessiah for my fellow Jews, my physical relatives, 4Israelites, who have the adoption as children, the honor, the covenants, the Law, the divine service and worship, the promises. 5They&amp;rsquo;re the ones that descended from the ancestors, and from them physically came the ChristMessiah, who&amp;rsquo;s over all, God blessed forever! Amen!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; My heart&amp;rsquo;s desire and prayer to God is for their salvation. 2I admit they have a zeal for God, but they don&amp;rsquo;t know what they&amp;rsquo;re doing. 3They don&amp;rsquo;t understand the righteousness that comes from God, and they try to establish their righteousness by themselves. They haven&amp;rsquo;t submitted to the righteousness God gives. 4For everybody that trusts, Christ puts an end to law as a way to achieve righteousness.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So God hasn&amp;rsquo;t set his people aside, has he? Goodness, no! I&amp;rsquo;m an Israelite too, a descendant of Abraham from the tribe of Benjamin. 2God hasn&amp;rsquo;t set aside the people he chose ahead of time. Don&amp;rsquo;t you know what the scripture says in the passage about Elijah? He pleads with God against Israel,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; How does God answer him?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s the same way now. By God&amp;rsquo;s grace there&amp;rsquo;s a remnant. 6If it&amp;rsquo;s by God&amp;rsquo;s grace, it&amp;rsquo;s not from what the remnant does. Otherwise, grace wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be grace. 7So what&amp;rsquo;s the point? What Israel&amp;rsquo;s looking for, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t found, but the Chosen have found it. The rest became stubborn. 8Like the scripture says,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So I urge you by God&amp;rsquo;s mercies to present your bodies as living sacrifices, holy and pleasing to God; that&amp;rsquo;s your spiritual service. 2Don&amp;rsquo;t conform yourselves to this world; transform yourselves by renewing your mind so you can discern what God&amp;rsquo;s will is—what&amp;rsquo;s good, pleasing, and perfect.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; By the grace God gave me, I say to everyone among you not to think more of yourselves than you should. Think properly as measured by the faith God has allotted to each of you. 4There are many parts to one body, and they don&amp;rsquo;t all serve the same purpose. 5That&amp;rsquo;s how it is with the many of us that are in Christ. Individually we&amp;rsquo;re interdependent parts with one another. 6We have different gifts according to God&amp;rsquo;s grace. If our gift is prophecy, let&amp;rsquo;s prophesy in accordance with our faith. 7If it&amp;rsquo;s service, let&amp;rsquo;s carry out our commitment to him in our service. If it&amp;rsquo;s teaching, let&amp;rsquo;s do it in teaching. 8If it&amp;rsquo;s encouraging, let&amp;rsquo;s do it in encouragement. If it&amp;rsquo;s sharing, let&amp;rsquo;s do it liberally. If it&amp;rsquo;s leading, let&amp;rsquo;s do it diligently. If it&amp;rsquo;s showing mercy, let&amp;rsquo;s do it cheerfully.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Every person needs to submit to higher authorities, because there&amp;rsquo;s no authority except by God&amp;rsquo;s approval. God has established the authorities that exist. 2So if a person resists them, he&amp;rsquo;s resisting what God has established, and he&amp;rsquo;ll be condemned for it. 3Rulers don&amp;rsquo;t bring fear for good behavior, but for bad. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of authority. Do what&amp;rsquo;s right, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be praised for it. 4They&amp;rsquo;re God&amp;rsquo;s ministers to you for good. If you do what&amp;rsquo;s wrong, be afraid; they don&amp;rsquo;t carry a sword for nothing. They punish people for doing bad things. 5So you need to submit, not only to avoid punishment, but for conscience sake. 6For the same reason, pay your taxes, because they&amp;rsquo;re God&amp;rsquo;s ministers, who dedicate themselves to those very things. 7Pay everybody what&amp;rsquo;s due to them—taxes, customs, respect, honor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Accept people that are weak in faith, and don&amp;rsquo;t pass judgment on the way they think. 2One person believes he can eat anything, but a weak person just eats vegetables. 3The one that eats must not look down on the one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t; the one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t eat must not criticize the one that does. 4What right do you have to criticize somebody else&amp;rsquo;s household servant? He stands or falls to his own Lord. And, he will stand because the Lord can make him stand. 5One person considers one day more important than another; another person considers every day alike. Each one should be fully confident in his own mind. 6The one that observes a day observes it to the Lord; the one that eats, eats to the Lord because he thanks God. The one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t eat, doesn&amp;rsquo;t eat to the Lord, and thanks God. 7None of us live to ourselves or die to ourselves. 8If we live, we live to the Lord; if we die, we die to the Lord. So whether we live or die, we&amp;rsquo;re the Lord&amp;rsquo;s.  9That&amp;rsquo;s why Christ died and came to life so he could serve as Lord of the living and the dead. 10And why criticizesg your fellow Christians or look down on them? We&amp;rsquo;ll all stand at God&amp;rsquo;s judgment seat. 11The scripture says,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; We that are strong need to bear with people&amp;rsquo;s weaknesses, instead of pleasing ourselves. 2Let&amp;rsquo;s make every effort to be pleasing to our neighbors for their good, so we can build them up. 3Christ didn&amp;rsquo;t please himself; like the scripture says,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; What was written earlier was written to instruct us so that by patience and the scriptures&amp;rsquo; encouragement we could have hope. 5May God, who is patient and encouraging, influence you to take the attitude toward one another that Jesus Christ takes toward us. 6That way with united voice you can praise the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I commend to you our sister Phoebe, a servant in the church in Cenchrea. 2Welcome her in the Lord in a way appropriate to saints. Help her with whatever she needs. She&amp;rsquo;s helped lots of people, including me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Greet Prisca and Aquila, my fellow workers in Christ Jesus. 4They&amp;rsquo;ve risked their necks to save my life. Not only am I grateful to them; so are all the Gentile churches. 5Greet the church that meets in their house. Hello to Epaenetus, my dear friend, the first convert to Christ in Asia; 6and to Mary, who has worked hard for youpl. 7Greet Andronicus and Junia, my kin and fellow prisoners. They&amp;rsquo;re well-known among the apostles and have been Christians longer than I have. 8Give our regards to Ampliatus, my friend in the Lord; 9to Urbanus, our fellow worker in Christ; and to my close friend Stachys. 10Greet Apellesmas, approved in Christ, those in the family of Aristobulus, 11and Herodion, my compatriot. Greet the family of Narcissus, who are in the Lord; 12as well as Tryphaena and Tryphosa, laborers in the Lord. Greet 13Rufus, chosen in the Lord, and his mother and mine. 14Say hello to Asyncritus, Phlegon, Hermes, Patrobas, Hermas, and the disciples that are with him; 15as well as Philologus and Julia; Nereus and his sister Olympas; and the saints that are with them. 16Greet one another with a holy kiss. All the churches of Christ send their greetings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Romans 65</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-65/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/romans/chapter-65/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;romans-chapter-65&#34;&gt;Romans Chapter 65&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; LXX].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
