<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luke on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Luke on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Luke 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Many have undertaken to put together an account of what&amp;rsquo;s been fulfilled among us. 2Eyewitnesses from the beginning and ministers of the message have handed down accounts of those events to us. 3It seemed appropriate to me, as well, to trace these things from the start and write you an orderly account, most excellent Theophilus, 4so you can know for certain that your oral instruction was accurate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At that time Caesar Augustus issued a decree to take a census of the Roman Empire. 2That was the first census, when Quirinius was governing Syria. 3Everyone went to his ancestral city to register. 4Joseph went up from Nazareth in Galilee to Judaea, to Bethlehem, David&amp;rsquo;s city because he&amp;rsquo;d descended from David. 5He went up to register with Mary, who was engaged to him and pregnant. 6While they were there, she came due 7and had her firstborn son. She wrapped him in cloths and laid him in a manger because there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any room for them in the inn.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the fifteenth year of Tiberias Caesar, Pontius Pilate was governing Judaea, Herod was tetraarch of Galilee, his brother Philip was tetraarch of Iturea and Trachonitis, Lysanius was tetraarch of Abilene, 2Annas and Caiaphas were high priests. That&amp;rsquo;s when a message came from God to John son of Zachariah in the desert. 3He went to the area around the Jordan River and started presenting a baptism of repentance to forgive sins. 4Scripture says in Isaiah the prophet,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus went away from the Jordan filled with the Holy Spirit. The Spirit was leading him to the desert 2while the devil tempted him during 40 days. He didn&amp;rsquo;t eat anything during that time. Afterwards, he was hungry, 3and the devil said, &amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re God&amp;rsquo;s Son, tell this stone to become a loaf of bread.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus answered, &amp;ldquo;Scripture says,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; The devil took him up to show him the kingdoms of the world in an instant, 6&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;ll give you all this authority and their splendor. It&amp;rsquo;s been given to me, and I can give it to whoever I want to. 7If you bow down to me, it&amp;rsquo;ll all be yours.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; While a crowd was pressing on him and listening to God&amp;rsquo;s message, he was standing by Lake Gennesaret 2and saw two boats at the edge of the lake. The fishermen had gotten out of them and were washing their nets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; He got in one of the boats—Simon&amp;rsquo;s—and asked him to shove it out a little from the shore. Then he sat down and started teaching the crowd from the boat. 4When he finished, he told Simon to put out into the deep water and let down his nets for a catch.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus was passing along between grain fields on a Sabbath, and his disciples were picking off heads, rubbing them in their hands, and eating the seeds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Some Pharisees said, &amp;ldquo;Why are you doing what&amp;rsquo;s against the Law on Sabbath?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus answered, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve read, haven&amp;rsquo;t you, what David and the ones with him did when they were famished? 4He went into God&amp;rsquo;s house and took the consecrated loaves, ate them, and gave them to the ones that were with him. They&amp;rsquo;re against the Law for anybody but priests to eat. 5Person takes precedence over Sabbath.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After he finished, he went to Capernaum. 2A centurion&amp;rsquo;s valued servant was sick, close to death. 3The centurion heard about Jesus and sent elders of the Jews to ask him to come get the servant through it. 4When they got to Jesus, they urged him earnestly, &amp;ldquo;He deserves doing that for him. 5He loves our nation and built us a synagogue.&amp;rdquo; 6Jesus went with them. &amp;ldquo;Sir, don&amp;rsquo;t bother coming under my roof. I don&amp;rsquo;t deserve that. 7I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel worthy of coming to you personally. Just say the word, and let my servant be healed. 8I&amp;rsquo;m directed by the authority of superior officers myself with soldiers under me. I tell one to go, and he goes; another to come, and he comes; a servant to do something, and he does it.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Soon afterward he started traveling from one town and village to another, announcing the coming of God&amp;rsquo;s kingdom. The Twelve were with him 2as well as some women he healed from illnesses and evil spirits: Mary, called the Magdalene, that seven demons had come out of; 3Joanna wife of Chuza, Herod&amp;rsquo;s business manager; Susanna, and quite a few that were contributing to them out of their own resources.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He called the Twelve together and gave them power and authority to cast out demons and heal sicknesses. 2He sent them out to announce the coming of God&amp;rsquo;s kingdom and to heal the sick. 3&amp;quot;Don&amp;rsquo;t take anything with you—no staff, sack for extra clothes, bread, money, or two shirts apiece. 4Stay in whatever house you enter till you leave the area. 5Whoever doesn&amp;rsquo;t welcome you, go outside of town and shake the dust off your feet as a gesture to them.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, the Lord appointed 72 other men to go ahead of him in pairs to every town and place where he intended to go.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; He told them, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a huge harvest and there aren&amp;rsquo;t many workmen, so ask the crew chief to put more help in his harvest. 3I&amp;rsquo;m sending you out like lambs among wolves. 4Don&amp;rsquo;t carry a money bag, knapsack, or shoes. Don&amp;rsquo;t visit with anybody along the road. 5Whatever house you go in, first say, &amp;lsquo;Peace to this house.&amp;rsquo; 6If peace-loving people live there, your blessing will rest on them. If not, it will come back to you. 7Stay in the same house and eat what they provide. A worker is worth his wages. Don&amp;rsquo;t move around from house to house. 8Whatever town you go in and they welcome you, eat what they put in front of you. 9Heal the sick in it and say, &amp;lsquo;God&amp;rsquo;s kingdom has come close to you.&amp;rsquo; 10Whatever town doesn&amp;rsquo;t welcome you, go out in the main streets and say, 11&amp;rsquo;Even the dust of your town that sticks to our feet we wipe off against you. But know this: God&amp;rsquo;s kingdom has come close to you.&amp;rsquo; 12At the judgment it&amp;rsquo;ll be more bearable for Sodom than for that town. 13&amp;quot;Woe to you, Chorazin! Woe to you, Bethsaida! If the miracles done in you had been done in Tyre and Sidon, they would&amp;rsquo;ve repented long ago in burlap and ashes. 14At the judgment it&amp;rsquo;ll be more bearable for those cities than for you. 15And you, Capernaum! You won&amp;rsquo;t be exalted to heaven, will you? You&amp;rsquo;ll be taken down to hell. 16&amp;quot;Whoever listens to you is listening to me; whoever rejects you is rejecting me; and whoever rejects me is rejecting the One that sent me.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He was praying in a place. When he finished, one of his disciples said, &amp;ldquo;Teach us how to pray like John used to teach his disciples.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; He said,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Give us our food each day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Forgive us of our sins 5&amp;quot;Which of you would go to a friend in the middle of the night and say, &amp;lsquo;Lend me three loaves of bread. 6A friend of mine has come, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to feed him.&amp;rsquo; 7&amp;quot;From inside, the friend would answer, &amp;lsquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t bother me. The door&amp;rsquo;s already shut; the kids are in bed with me. I can&amp;rsquo;t get up to give you anything.&amp;rsquo; 8Though he didn&amp;rsquo;t want to, he got up and gave him what he needed because he was his friend and persisted. 9Ask and you&amp;rsquo;ll receive, seek and you&amp;rsquo;ll find, knock and it&amp;rsquo;ll open for you. 10The one that asks receives, the one that seeks finds, the one that knocks it&amp;rsquo;ll open for. 11&amp;quot;If your son asks for a fish, would you give him a snake instead? 12If he asks for an egg, would you give him a scorpion? 13If you, being sinful, know how to give good things to your kids, how much more will the heavenly Father give the Holy Spirit to people that ask him.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Meantime, the thousands in the crowd that had been following him were so packed together they were stepping on each other. Jesus started saying to his disciples first, &amp;ldquo;Watch out for the yeast from the Pharisees, which is hypocrisy. 2Everything covered up will be uncovered; everything hidden will be discovered. 3What youpl say in the dark will be heard in the light; what youpl whisper in the storerooms will be shouted from the housetops. 4&amp;quot;Friends, don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of people that can kill the body and that&amp;rsquo;s all they can do. 5I&amp;rsquo;ll show you who to be afraid of: the One with the right to kill you and throw you into hell. Yes, be afraid of him. 6Don&amp;rsquo;t 5 sparrows cost 2 assarions? And God doesn&amp;rsquo;t forget about a one of them. 7The very hairs on your head are numbered. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid; you&amp;rsquo;re worth more than lots of sparrows. 8&amp;quot;Everyone that acknowledges me to other people, I&amp;rsquo;ll acknowledge to God&amp;rsquo;s angels. 9Whoever denies who I am in front of other people I&amp;rsquo;ll deny in front of God&amp;rsquo;s angels. 10Everyone that slanders me can be forgiven, but whoever blasphemes the Holy Spirit won&amp;rsquo;t be forgiven. 11&amp;quot;When they take you in front of synagogues, rulers, and authorities, don&amp;rsquo;t worry about what to say to defend yourselves. 12The Holy Spirit will teach you at the time what to say.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-13&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At that time, some people told Jesus about the Galileans whose blood Pilate had mixed with their sacrifices. 2He said, &amp;ldquo;Do you think those Galileans were more sinful than other Galileans because they suffered this? 3No, but unless you repent, you&amp;rsquo;ll die too. 4Do you think the 18 that the tower of Siloam fell on and killed were the most sinful people in Jerusalem? 5No, but unless you repent, you&amp;rsquo;ll die too.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-14&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; On a Sabbath, when he went into the house of a ruling Pharisee to eat, the leaders were watching him closely. 2In front of him was a man with extreme swelling. 3Jesus said to the lawyers and Pharisees, &amp;ldquo;Is it lawful to heal on a Sabbath?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; They didn&amp;rsquo;t say anything. He took hold of him and healed him and let him go. 5He said, &amp;ldquo;If a son or ox falls into a well, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you pullf him out right away on a Sabbath day?&amp;rdquo; 6They couldn&amp;rsquo;t answer him.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-15&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Tax collectors and sinners were coming to listen to him. 2The Pharisees and scribes started grumbling, &amp;ldquo;This fellow welcomes sinners and eats with them.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; He told them this parable. 4&amp;quot;What man that has a 100 sheep and loses one, doesn&amp;rsquo;t leave the 99 in the open country and go looking for the one that&amp;rsquo;s lost? 5 When he finds it, he puts it on his shoulders happy. 6When he gets home, he calls his friends and neighbors, &amp;lsquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s celebrate; I&amp;rsquo;ve found the sheep I lost.&amp;rsquo; 7There&amp;rsquo;ll be more celebration in heaven over one sinner that repents than over 99 good people that don&amp;rsquo;t need to repent.&amp;rdquo; 8&amp;quot;What woman that has 10 coins and loses one, doesn&amp;rsquo;t light a lamp, sweep the house, and keep looking till she finds it? 9When she does, she calls her friends and neighbors, &amp;lsquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s celebrate; I found the coin I lost.&amp;rsquo; 10In the same way, God&amp;rsquo;s angels celebrate over one sinner that repents. 11&amp;quot;A man had two sons. 12The younger one said to his father, &amp;lsquo;Give me my share of the assets.&amp;rsquo; He divided his assets between the two sons. 13&amp;quot;A few days later the younger son got everything together and left home for a distant country, and wasted his assets there, living immorally. 14When he&amp;rsquo;d spent everything, a severe famine arose in that country, and he was out of money. 15He went to work for a citizen in that country, who sent him into his fields to feed pigs. 16He was so hungry he wanted to eat the carob pods the pigs were eating, but nobody would give him anything. 17&amp;quot;He came to himself, &amp;lsquo;How many of my father&amp;rsquo;s hired hands have more than enough to eat, and I&amp;rsquo;m starving here. 18I&amp;rsquo;ll go to my father and say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve sinned against Heaven and you. 19I don&amp;rsquo;t deserve to be your son anymore. Make me one of your hired hands.&amp;rdquo; 20&amp;quot;He went to his father. While he was still a long way off, his father saw him, felt sorry for him, and he ran and hugged him and kissed him. 21The son said, &amp;lsquo;Dad, I&amp;rsquo;ve sinned against Heaven and you. I don&amp;rsquo;t deserve to be your son anymore.&amp;rsquo; 22&amp;quot;But his dad told the servants, &amp;lsquo;Quick, bring a robe—the best one—and put it on him. Put a ring on his finger and sandals on his feet. 23Get the grain-fed calf and butcher it; let&amp;rsquo;s eat and celebrate. 24This son of mine was dead and has come back to life; he was lost and is found.&amp;rsquo; They started celebrating. 25&amp;quot;His older son was out in the field. When he got close to the house, he heard music and dancing. 26He called one of the servants over and asked him what was going on. 27&amp;quot;&amp;lsquo;Your brother came back, and your father has butchered the grain-fed calf because he received him back in good health.&amp;rsquo; 29&amp;quot;But he answered, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve slavedp for you all these years and never neglected a thing you told me to do, and you&amp;rsquo;ve never given me a kid to celebrate with my friends. 30But when that son of yours comes who wasted your living with prostitutes, you butcher the grain-fed calf!&amp;rsquo; 31&amp;quot;He said, &amp;lsquo;Son, you&amp;rsquo;re always here, and everything I have is yours. 32But we needed to be happy and celebrate because this brother of yours was dead and is alive; he was lost and is found.&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-16&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He also told his disciples, &amp;ldquo;A rich man had a property manager that was reportedly wasting the rich man&amp;rsquo;s holdings. 2He called him in, &amp;lsquo;What&amp;rsquo;s this I hear about you? Give me your record books for your work; you can&amp;rsquo;t continue being manager.&amp;rsquo; 3The fellow thought to himself, &amp;lsquo;What am I going to do? My boss is firing me. I&amp;rsquo;m not strong enough for hard work; I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed to beg. 4I know what I&amp;rsquo;ll do, so when I&amp;rsquo;ve been let go, people will welcome me into their homes.&amp;rsquo; 5&amp;quot;He called in each debtor and said to the first, &amp;lsquo;How much do you owe my employer?&amp;rsquo; 8&amp;quot;The employer had to admire the conniving fellow. The children of this world are smarter among their own kind than the children of light are. 9Make friends with your material wealth so when it runs out, they&amp;rsquo;ll welcome you into permanent shelters.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-17&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He said to his disciples, &amp;ldquo;Inevitably offenses will come, but woe to the ones that bring them. 2It&amp;rsquo;d be better to have a big millstone put around their necks and be thrown into the sea than to make one of these little ones sin. 3Be careful. If your friend sins, reprimand him; if he repents, forgive him. 4If he sins against you seven times in a day and comes back seven times and says, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry,&amp;rsquo; forgive him.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-18&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He told a parable to the effect that people should always pray, and not give up. 2&amp;quot;There was a judge in a town who didn&amp;rsquo;t fear God or respect people. 3A widow in that town kept coming to him to defend her against her accuser. 4At first he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help her, but after a while he said to himself, &amp;lsquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t fear God or respect people, 5but this widow keeps hounding me. I&amp;rsquo;ll see that she gets justice so she won&amp;rsquo;t wear me out, coming to me all the time.&amp;rsquo; 6&amp;quot;Listen to what the unjust judge illustrates. 7Won&amp;rsquo;t God provide justice for his chosen ones that call to him for help day and night, and be patient with them? 8I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, he&amp;rsquo;ll provide it right away. But, when the Son of Man comes, will he find people with faith on the earth?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-19&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus was passing through Jericho, 2and a wealthy tax collector named Zacchaeus 3wanted to see what he looked like, but he couldn&amp;rsquo;t because of the crowd; he was too short. 4So he ran ahead and climbed up in a sycamore tree that Jesus was heading toward. 5When Jesus got there, he looked up, &amp;ldquo;Zacchaeus, hurry and climb down. I need to stay at your place today.&amp;rdquo; 6He hurried and climbed down and welcomed him happily.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-20&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; One day he was teaching the people in the Temple and delivering good news. The chief priests, scribes, and elders confronted him: 2&amp;quot;What right do you have to do this? Who gave you that right?&amp;quot; 3&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;ll ask you something too. Tell me, 4Was John&amp;rsquo;s baptism from heaven or humans?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; They talked it over, 6&amp;quot;If we say, &amp;lsquo;From heaven,&amp;rsquo; he&amp;rsquo;ll say, &amp;lsquo;Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you believe him?&amp;rsquo; If we say, &amp;lsquo;From humans,&amp;rsquo; the people will stone us; they&amp;rsquo;re convinced John was a prophet.&amp;quot; 7They said they didn&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-21&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He looked up and saw wealthy people putting contributions in the Treasury 2and a poor widow putting in two leptons*. 3&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, that poor widow put in more than anybody. 4They contributed from their abundance, but she put in everything she had to live on.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Some were talking about the Temple, because it was decorated with beautiful stones and memorial gifts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; He said, &amp;ldquo;The time&amp;rsquo;s coming when what you see here won&amp;rsquo;t be left stone on stone.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-22&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Festival of Unleavened Bread (called Passover) was coming up. 2The chief priests and scribes were looking for some way to destroy him because they were afraid of the people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Satan got into Judas, called Iscariot, one of the Twelve. 4He went to talk to the chief priests and soldiers about delivering Jesus to them. 5They were elated and offered him money. 6He agreed and started looking for a chance to turn him over away from a crowd.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-23&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 23&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The whole assembly got up and took him to Pilate. 2They started accusing him, &amp;ldquo;This man&amp;rsquo;s misleading our nation, forbidding people to pay tribute to Caesar, and claiming to be the Messiah, a king.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Pilate asked him, &amp;ldquo;Are you king of the Jews?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Pilate said to the chief priests and the crowd, &amp;ldquo;This man&amp;rsquo;s not guilty of anything!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; They kept insisting, &amp;ldquo;He stirs up the people, teaching everywhere from Galilee to here.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luke 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/luke/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;luke-chapter-24&#34;&gt;Luke Chapter 24&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; But early in the morning on the first day of the week, the women went to the tomb, carrying the spices they&amp;rsquo;d prepared. 2They found the stone rolled away from the tomb, 3but when they went in, didn&amp;rsquo;t find the body of the Lord Jesus. 4While they were wondering what happened, two men stood by them in dazzling clothes. 5The women were scared and lowered their faces toward the ground. The men said, &amp;ldquo;Why look for the living among the dead? 6He&amp;rsquo;s not here; he resurrected. Remember how he told you back in Galilee 7that he had to be betrayed to sinners, be crucified, and resurrect the third day.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
