<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Esther on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Esther on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Esther 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Ahasuerus/Xerxes ruled from India to Nubia over 127 provinces [486-65 B.C.]. 2In his third year on his throne in Susa the capital, 3he held a banquet for his nobles and officials, the army chiefs of Persia and Media, and the nobles and governors of the provinces. 4For 180 days he showed the wealth of his royal glory and the splendor and pomp of his majesty. 5After that, he gave everybody there—least and greatest—a banquet that lasted a week in the court of his palace garden. 6There were white cotton curtains and blue hangings held up by cords of fine purple linen on silver rings and marble pillars. There were gold and silver couches on a mosaic pavement made out of porphyry, marble, mother-of-pearl, and precious stones. 7Drinks were served in gold cups of different kinds, and the royal wine was plentiful according to the king&amp;rsquo;s bounty. 8The drinking was done by law: attendees were not compelled, because the king had ordered each official of his household to follow each person&amp;rsquo;s wishes. 9Queen Vashti also gave a banquet for the women in the king&amp;rsquo;s palace.&#x9;&#x9;Esther 1:1-9 Queen Vashti Deposed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, when King Ahasuerus calmed down, he remembered what Vashti had done and what he&amp;rsquo;d decreed against her. 2Then the king&amp;rsquo;s advisors that attended him said, &amp;ldquo;Have beautiful young virgins be sought for you. 3Appoint officers in all the provinces to gather them to the harem in Susa under the custody of Hegai, the king&amp;rsquo;s eunuch in charge of the women. Give them ointments, 4and have the young woman that pleases you replace Vashti as queen.&amp;rdquo; He liked that; so that&amp;rsquo;s what he did.&#x9;&#x9;Esther 2:1-4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, King Ahasuerus promoted Haman Ben-Hammedatha the Agagite, and made his authority secure over his fellow officials. 2The king&amp;rsquo;s aides at the king&amp;rsquo;s gate bowed in homage to Haman because that&amp;rsquo;s what the king commanded. But Mordecai didn&amp;rsquo;t bow. 3The king&amp;rsquo;s aides at the king&amp;rsquo;s gate said, &amp;ldquo;Why aren&amp;rsquo;t you obeying the king?&amp;rdquo; 4When they&amp;rsquo;d spoken every day to him and he ignored them they told Haman to see if he would tolerate Mordecai&amp;rsquo;s reason for not bowing to him: he&amp;rsquo;d told them he was a Jew. 5When Haman saw that Mordecai didn&amp;rsquo;t bow in homage, it made him mad. 6But he thought it was beneath his station to arrest only Mordecai. Since they&amp;rsquo;d told him who Mordecai&amp;rsquo;s nationality was, he made an effort to destroy all the Jews in the kingdom.&#x9;      &#x9;Esther 3:1-6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Mordecai found out what had happened, he tore his clothes, put on burlap and ashes, and went out into the city, wailing loudly and bitterly. 2He went as far as the king&amp;rsquo;s gate, because nobody was supposed to enter the king&amp;rsquo;s gate dressed in burlap. 3In every province where the decree had gone, the Jews were mourning greatly with fasting, crying, wailing. Many were lying on burlap and ashes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; On the third day, Esther put on her royal robes and stood in the inner court of the king&amp;rsquo;s palace by his rooms. He was sitting on his throne across from the entrance to the palace. 2When he saw her, he was pleased and extended the gold scepter that was in his hand. She came and touched the top of it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; He asked her, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s troubling you, Queen Esther? What&amp;rsquo;s your request? I&amp;rsquo;ll give it to you up to half the kingdom.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; That night the king couldn&amp;rsquo;t get to sleep, so he had them bring the record book and read it to him. 2The Chronicles wrote that Mordecai had reported about Bigthana and Teresh, two of the king&amp;rsquo;s eunuchs, the doorkeepers that had tried to lay hands on King Ahasuerus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; The king asked, &amp;ldquo;What honor&amp;rsquo;s been given to him for that?&amp;rdquo; His attendants said, &amp;ldquo;Nothing.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; The king said, &amp;ldquo;Who&amp;rsquo;s in the court?&amp;rdquo; Haman had just come into the outer court of the king&amp;rsquo;s palace to speak to him about hanging Mordecai on the gallows he&amp;rsquo;d built.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The king and Haman came to drink wine with Queen Esther. 2The king asked her that second day as they drank their wine, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s your petition, Queen Esther; I&amp;rsquo;ll grant it. What&amp;rsquo;s your request? Up to half the kingdom I&amp;rsquo;ll do it.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; She answered, &amp;ldquo;If I&amp;rsquo;m pleasing to you, my king, if it pleases you, have my life given to me as my petition, and my people as my request.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; That day King Ahasuerus gave Queen Esther the house of Haman, enemy of the Jews. Mordecai came into the king&amp;rsquo;s presence because she revealed how he was related to her. 2The king took off the signet ring he&amp;rsquo;d taken away from Haman and gave it to Mordecai. Esther put Mordecai over Haman&amp;rsquo;s house.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; She spoke again to the king, fell at his feet, cried, and implored him to overturn the plot Haman had devised against the Jews. 4He extended the gold scepter to her. She got up and stood in front of him, 5&amp;quot;If it pleases you, if I&amp;rsquo;ve found favor with you, if the matter seems proper to you, if I&amp;rsquo;m pleasing to you, have it written to revoke the letters Haman wrote in his plot to destroy the Jews in your provinces. 6How can I endure to see the misfortune that will fall on my people and the destruction of my kin?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The thirteenth day, twelfth month, when the king&amp;rsquo;s edict was about to be carried out and the Jews&amp;rsquo; enemies hoped to gain mastery over them, fortunes reversed. The Jews gained mastery over those who hated them. 2They gathered in their towns throughout the provinces to seize the ones that tried to harm them. Nobody could stand up against them, because the dread of the Jews had fallen on the people. 3Even the rulers of the provinces, the satraps, the governors, and the ones that were doing the king&amp;rsquo;s business helped the Jews, because the dread of Mordecai had fallen on them. 4He became greater and greater in the king&amp;rsquo;s palace, and his fame spread throughout the provinces. 5The Jews struck their enemies with the sword, killing and destroying, and doing what they pleased to the ones that hated them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Esther 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cyv/esther/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;esther-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Esther Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; King Ahasuerus put under tribute the territory and lands by the Sea. 2His accomplishments by his authority and strength—as well as the full account of Mordecai&amp;rsquo;s status that the king advanced him to—are recorded in The Chronicles of the Kings of Media and Persia. 3Mordecai the Jew was second to King Ahasuerus, great among the Jews and favored by his host of relatives. He sought the good of his people and spoke for the welfare of his whole nation.&#x9;   Esther 10:1-3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
