<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philippians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philippians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Philippians 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;philippians-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Philippians Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul and Timothy, servants of-Christ Jesus, to-all the saints in Christ Jesus the-ones being in Philippi with elders and deacons. 2Grace to-you and peace from God (the) Father of us and (the) Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; I-thank the God of-me at every [the] remembrance of-you, 4always making [the] prayer with joy in every prayer of-me for all of-you, 5over the fellowship of-you in the gospel from the first day until the now, 6confident with-respect-to-this- very-thing that the One having begun in you (a) good work will-keep-perfecting (it) until (the) day of-Christ Jesus, 7even-as it-is right for-me to-think on-behalf-of you all on-account-of [the] me to-have you in the heart, and in the bonds of-me and in the defense and confirmation of-the gospel, you all being sharers-with me of-[the]-grace. 8For [the] God (is) witness of-me, as I-long-for you all in (the) affections of-Christ Jesus. 9And this I-pray, in-order-that the love of-you still more and more may-increase in knowledge and all insight, 10unto [the] your approving the excellent things, in-order-that you-may-be sincere and of clear conscience unto (the) day of-Christ, 11filled-with (the) fruit of-righteousness, the-one through Jesus Christ unto (the) glory and praise of-God.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippians 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;philippians-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Philippians Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So if (there is) any encouragement in Christ, if any comfort of-love, if any fellowship of-(the)-Spirit, if any affection and compassion, 2make┘the joy of-me└full in-order-that you-may-have-in-mind the same thing, having the same love, united-in-spirit, intending the one purpose, 3(doing) nothing according-to selfishness, nothing according-to empty-conceit, but with-[the] humility considering one-another more-important than-yourselves, 4each-one not looking-at the-things of yourselves, but [also]ms everyone the-things of-others. 5Have┘this└attitude in you that (was) also in Christ Jesus, 6who, being in (the) form of-deity, did┘not└consider [the] being equal to-God (a) clung-to-thing, 7but emptied himself, having-taken (the) form of-(a)-servant, having-been in (the) likeness of-man, and having-been-found in-form like (a) man, 8he-humbled himself, becoming obedient unto death, even (the) death of-(a)-cross. 9Wherefore also [the] God exalted him and gave to-him the name [the] above every name, 10in-order-that at the name of-Jesus every knee would-bend of-heavenly-ones and earthly-ones and subterranean-ones, 11and every tongue would-confess that Jesus Christ (is) Lord to (the) glory of-God (the) Father.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippians 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;philippians-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Philippians Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Finally/As-a-result2, my brothers, rejoice in (the) Lord. To-write the same-things to-you (is) not troublesome to me, but/and (is is) safe for you. 2Watch-out-for the dogs; watch-out-for the evil doers; watch-out-for the mutilation/false-circumcision. 3We are the circumcision, the-ones serving (the) Spirit of-God and taking-pride in Christ Jesus and not putting-confidence in (the) flesh, 4although I having confidence even in (the) flesh if anybody else seems to-put-confidence in (the) flesh, I more. 5With-respect-to circumcision (the) eighth-day, of (the) nation of-Israel, of-(the) tribe of-Benjamin, (a) Hebrew of Hebrews, according-to (the) Law (a) Pharisee, 6according-to zeal persecuting the church, according-to (the) righteousness the-one in (the) Law being blameless. 7[But]ms whatever-things were to-me gains—these I-consider loss on-account-of [the] Christ. 8But more-than-that I┘also└consider all-things to-be loss on-account-of the surpassing-thing of-the knowledge of-Christ Jesus the Lord of-me, on-account-of whom I-lost [the] all-things, and consider (them) garbage in-order-that I-might-gain Christ 9and be-found in him, not having my-own righteousness, the-one from law, but the-one through trust of-Christ, the righteousness from God on-the-basis-of [the] trust, 10[the] to-know him and the power of-the resurrection of-him and the fellowship of-the sufferings of-him, being conformed to-the death of-him, 11if somehow I-might-attain to the resurrection [the] of-(the() dead.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philippians 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/philippians/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;philippians-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Philippians Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So, my beloved and longed-for brothers, (the) joy and crown of-me, stand-firm thus in (the) Lord, beloved. 2I-urge Euodia and I-urge Syntyche to-have┘the same└attitude in (the) Lord. 3Yes, I-ask you also, genuine yokefellow, help them, who struggle-together-with me in the gospel and with Clement and the rest of-(the) fellow-workers of-me, the names of-whom (are) in (the) book of-life. 4Rejoice in (the) Lord always. I-will-say (it) again, rejoice. 5Let┘the gentle-demeanor of-you└be-known to-all men. The Lord (is) near. 6Worry in-respect-to-nothing, but in every [the] prayer and [the] supplication with thanksgiving make┘└know to [the] God. 7And the peace of-[the] God the-one surpassing all knowledge-will-guard the hearts of-you and the minds of-you in Christ Jesus.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
