<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Image of God on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/image-of-god/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Image of God on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/image-of-god/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE “IMAGE OF GOD”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-image-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-image-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE “IMAGE OF GOD”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much of my creative energies lately have been directed toward tracing through the implications of interpersonal relationship as the organizing reality for Christian truth. Nowhere has this observation appeared more relevant than in the study of the nature of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the centuries extensive thought has gone into the interpretation of Genesis 1:26-27 and related materials: “Let’s make mankind in our image after our likeness.” There have been four proposed aspects of the “image of God” together with their effects. Reason heads the list. The ability to think abstractly relates to the capacity for language communication, creativity, responsibility (dominion), conscience, even humor, self-transcendence, and the ability to project consciousness over behind the eyes of another person. People can penetrate a situation in thought and imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGO DEI AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-imago-dei-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-imago-dei-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGO DEI AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BASES AND INTEGRATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study proposes that the image of God in us is the interpersonal capacity. It does not necessarily say something new, but endeavors to assemble relevant factors, to clarify a viewpoint that best incorporates them, and to show its consonance with the Christian worldview. In method, the approach sets aside a reductionism that strives after identifying our “essence” and “risks” reification, faculty psychology, depersonalization, and individualism, which are tendencies that derive from non-revelatory origins. It opts instead for a combinationalism that accounts for all the features of nature, function, and relationship that’s special revelation pictures us as having and called to have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
