<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Women&#39;s Studies Eph 5 21 on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/womens-studies-eph-5-21/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Women&#39;s Studies Eph 5 21 on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/womens-studies-eph-5-21/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GREEK ELEMENTS IN THE INTERPRETATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/greek-elements-in-the-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/greek-elements-in-the-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GREEK ELEMENTS IN THE INTERPRETATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF EPHESIANS 5:21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;editorial question&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Ephesians 5:21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does “defer to one another in the fear of Christ” belong with the preceding or succeeding context?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The United Bible Society’s text of the Greek New Testament puts the injunction with the preceding material in the third edition, but with the succeeding context in the third edition (corrected). Grammatically the participle “submitting” parallels participles in the preceding two verses—participles that grammatically modify the subject of the finite verb in 5:18. A free-standing participle can be a command; but clear cases of that usage are infrequent in the New Testament (Mark 5:23; Romans 12:92, 10?, 11?, 123?, 132? 163?, 172?, 18, 19; 13:11; 1 Corinthians 8:24; Ephesians 5:21?; Titus 2:7; 1 Peter 2:18; 3:1). Moreover, nothing grammatical calls for invoking that usage in Ephesians 5:21 because of the parallel between “deferring” and the preceding participles of 5:19-20: “. . . speaking to one another . . . singing and making melody . . . giving thanks . . . deferring to one another . . .” Grammatically, “deferring” ties with the preceding flow of thought by being parallel to the three preceding participles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUBMITTING TO ONE ANOTHER:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/submitting-to-one-another/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/submitting-to-one-another/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUBMITTING TO ONE ANOTHER:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians 5:21-6:9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This portion of Ephesians deals with “household teaching” on the relationship of husbands and wives, parents and children, masters and slaves. Other comparable texts are Colossians 3:18-4:1 and 1 Peter 2:(13-)18-3:7.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In regard to each relationship, Paul appeals to interpersonal principles to set the tone for it. In other places, he does the same thing to solve problems that impact practical relationships in the body (languages, 1 Corinthians 12-14; leadership, 2 Corinthians 10-13; etc.). He can do that because personal relationship is always the context in which further considerations exist and must exist in a way that does not interfere with that context. Paul implies that interpersonalism should carry the process as much as possible. Only when influence for practical reasons is inadequate is there a need to invoke the principle of authority (much less force).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
