<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MANKIND (Anthropology) on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/mankind-anthropology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MANKIND (Anthropology) on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/mankind-anthropology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MANKIND</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/mankind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MANKIND&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;&#x9;The Purpose of Mankind&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II.&#x9;&#x9;The Image of God in Mankind&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;III.&#x9;&#x9;The Effects of Sin on Mankind (See What the Bible Says About Salvation, pp. 38-45.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;&#x9;Section I: Consequences of sin: personal perversion and meaninglessness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;&#x9;Section II: Consequences of sin: guilt, alienation, and destruction of the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;environment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;&#x9;Section III: Perpetuating sin: ignorance&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once sin entered the human race, it moved from person to person, from generation to generation down to our own day. We get it started it on our own and keep it moving “unassisted”; we get a lot of help from other people! In this section we are thinking about the ways our ignorance can get sin started and keep it moving without the input other people often give.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PURPOSE OF MANKIND:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-purpose-of-mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-purpose-of-mankind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PURPOSE OF MANKIND:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;QUESTIONS AND ANSWERS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Section I: God’s Delight&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given his nature, God decided on certain purposes. In light of those purposes, he made the creation, including humankind. So God made the nature of man the way he did because of the purposes he had for us in his creation and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God made mankind simply because he delighted in doing so. Aside from any further considerations, persons experience fulfillment in being creative. The same holds for our personal God. Because of sheer delight, God expressed himself creatively and “saw that it was good.” That recurring statement in Genesis 1 expresses his sense of satisfaction in doing so (Genesis 1:31; cp. 1:4, 10, 12, 18, 21, 25). In that respect, God created us for something of the same reason he made the rest of creation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNITY AND DIVERSITY IN THE UNIVERSAL BODY OF CHRIST</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/unity-and-diversity-in-the-universal-body-of-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/unity-and-diversity-in-the-universal-body-of-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UNITY AND DIVERSITY IN THE UNIVERSAL BODY OF CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By creation, all human persons have the image of God, which means they have the interpersonal capacity and equal inherent worth. Since the image exists at the individual level, we must view the created variants as “modes of the image.” Sex, race, size, intelligence, athletic ability, physique, age, and the like do not affect inherent worth and can therefore have no place in our attitude toward ourselves or other people. We do not have to be married to participate in the image, we do not have to become Jews to be a favored people, we do not have to speak English to be part of the kingdom, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ANALYSIS OF AUGUSTINE’S DOCTRINE OF EVIL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/analysis-of-augustines-doctrine-of-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/analysis-of-augustines-doctrine-of-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ANALYSIS OF AUGUSTINE’S DOCTRINE OF EVIL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The view of mankind common in evangelicalism descends from Augustine of Hippo. His early efforts in philosophy centered on the problem of evil. Although he spent his earliest years under the influence of Catholic Christianity, he left that background to become an Auditor for nine years in a Gnostic-like sect that followed the teachings of Mani. At first, Manichaeism seemed to him to explain the problem by teaching that evil and good are two kinds of substances. They have become intermingled in mankind so that “salvation” consists of separating good from its mixture with evil. Because of internal inconsistencies that Augustine came to see in this dualistic philosophy, he eventually left it and returned to Christianity. The problem of evil stood at the beginning of his development as a philosopher-theologian; its solution stood near the center of the theological system he formulated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BEHAVIORAL AND PSYCHOLOGICAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/behavioral-and-psychological-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/behavioral-and-psychological-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BEHAVIORAL AND PSYCHOLOGICAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God created us to have fellowship with him, so he made us in his image by giving us the interpersonal capacity. But in practice there has always been a breakdown in the realization of that potential in every individual, a breakdown we may call depravity.1 Like Satan and the fallen angels earlier, every one of us has failed to express our capacity adequately or correctly. In different ways and to varying extents we fail to function interpersonally, in conformity to our own created nature, and in accordance with divine purpose. With the exception of Jesus Christ, each of us has misused the specific abilities that comprise interpersonal capacity and its derivatives, and thereby has affected all aspects of ourselves, our relations, and our destiny; so we say that everyone has total depravity. It turns out that in varying degrees, depravity has been universal since the beginning and all-pervasive in every person that ever lived. Depravity means that although everyone has the real creatable image, no one fully has the ideal ethical image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITERIA FOR A BIBLICAL VIEW OF HUMAN ABILITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/criteria-for-a-biblical-view-of-human-ability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/criteria-for-a-biblical-view-of-human-ability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITERIA FOR A BIBLICAL VIEW OF HUMAN ABILITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prevenient grace and natural depravity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In place of the natural depravity of traditional theology, we prefer to speak of psychological depravity. In doing so, we acknowledge the power of sin without considering ourselves subject to a determinism that results in lostness. In the construct of depravity plus prevenient grace, psychological depravity functions on the analogy of habit. Prevenient grace consequently omits natural regeneration from God’s acts of grace that precede salvation. A view of human ability is developed below under five criteria listed according to the sequence in which they apply to the process of restoration to fellowship with God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITIQUE OF AUGUSTINE’S VIEW OF EVIL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/critique-of-augustines-view-of-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/critique-of-augustines-view-of-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITIQUE OF AUGUSTINE’S VIEW OF EVIL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Augustine’s treatment of the problem of evil falls short for two related reasons. (1) He did not properly distinguish natural and moral evil, suffering and sin, pain and guilt. In his thought, they amounted to the same problem. (2) He attempted to examine even moral evil primarily in reference to the category of nature. In so doing, he glossed over the distinction between impersonal and interpersonal reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETHICAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE AS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/ethical-observations-on-the-image-as/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/ethical-observations-on-the-image-as/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETHICAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE AS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ethical Use of Imago dei&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) The image as interpersonal capacity connects the natural and the ethical usages of the expression image of God. One pervasive concern of biblical content is wholeness, the big picture, the synthetic emphasis in contrast to a dichotomistic, analytical, reductionist approach. That concern carries over into the terminology. The penchant for integration accounts for the rather facile shifting back and forth between natural, behavioral, and relational usages of terms like image, life, sin, flesh, create, knowledge, and wisdom associated with the creation narrative. Integration accounts for places where such expressions may combine these rather different, though related, concepts when dealing with subjects in broad scope.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EXTREMELY SINFUL: Psalm 51</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/extremely-sinful-psalm-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/extremely-sinful-psalm-51/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EXTREMELY SINFUL: Psalm 51&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psalm 51 records David’s response to his sin with Bathsheba:  heading of the Psalm, “When Nathan the prophet came to him after he had gone into Bathsheba” (2 Samuel 11-12).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David’s redeeming quality was admission of his sin, his willingness to repent, and his concern to reach out to God for forgiveness: Psalm 51:1-4, 7-17, which is the bulk of the Psalm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David felt totally characterized by sin as when we say someone is a “born liar.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HERMENEUTICS AND NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/hermeneutics-and-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/hermeneutics-and-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HERMENEUTICS AND NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exegetical Impasse&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A standoff has persisted in exegesis between Calvinistic and non-Calvinistic interpreters largely because no resolution can come at the level of individual passages that have implications for anthropology. A few examples illustrate the problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) Psalm 51:10 says, “Create in me a clean heart, O God; and renew a right spirit within me.” Ezekiel 18:31 shows another emphasis, “Make for yourselves a new heart and a new spirit.” The difficulty is whether Psalm 51:10 interprets Ezekiel 18:31 or vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HUMAN DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/human-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/human-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HUMAN DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overview of Natural Depravity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late fourth century Augustine, bishop of Hippo in North Africa, gave classical expression to natural depravity as part of his understanding of the nature of evil. In his thought, evil is a lack (privation) in the form of substance relative to its original form. That relatively deformed condition produces evil action. The nature of evil is lack, the cause of evil is lack in form, and the criterion of evil is lack in form compared to pristine form&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMAGE AND LIKENESS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/image-and-likeness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/image-and-likeness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IMAGE AND LIKENESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have not made a distinction between “image” and “likeness,” even though Genesis 1:26 uses two words to compare mankind and God. (a) Nothing in the context distinguishes them. Furthermore, (b) in most other passages only one term occurs, image in Genesis 9:6-7; 1 Corinthians 11:7; James 3:9 and likeness in Genesis 5:2 in an otherwise word-for-word parallel to 1:26. Like in Genesis 3:5, 22 translates a different item than in 1:26.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INDWELLING SIN: ROMANS 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/indwelling-sin-romans-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/indwelling-sin-romans-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INDWELLING SIN: ROMANS 7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Paul speaks of sin resident within him (or indwelling sin), perhaps he means it phenomenologically; that is, the experience of sin feels like something inside him. His point is that sin is not just something outside us (environment, influence) trying to tempt us into misaction; it is something inside us as well. There is a subjective as well as objective component in the sin phenomenon. The implication is personal responsibility for subjective response to objective influence and stimulus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ITEMS AFFECTED BY THE DOCTRINE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/items-affected-by-the-doctrine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/items-affected-by-the-doctrine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ITEMS AFFECTED BY THE DOCTRINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the nature of mankind is a central consideration in Christian theology, the doctrine of natural depravity in mankind affects a variety of issues and impacts them in significant ways. The following enumeration of consequences may not be necessary in every case, but historically this concept has triggered them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anthropology itself is significantly different because mankind is understood as born without the full spiritual capacity that Adam and Eve had before they sinned. Beyond the consequences of their sin that Genesis 3 and elsewhere indicate, natural depravity adds to the silence of scripture by saying that in some way—either by built-in natural result or direct divine penalty—their sin led to a defective genetic nature that everybody has biologically inherited. Because we all have descended from the same pair, we are all infected with this defect in every aspect of our being. The will is weakened so that we cannot resist temptation even when we want to. The affections are so disoriented that often we do not even want to resist. We do not love what we should. Even emotional disorders may integrate with natural depravity. Bodily drives are perverted, which accounts for unwholesome sexual desires, homosexuality, bestiality, gluttony, drunkenness, as well as inhibitive and compulsive behaviors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intellect is skewed at least relative to spiritual matters, so that we are blind to what should be “as clear as the nose on our face.” Some have integrated the concept more broadly by connecting it with the idea that supposedly people use only 5-8% of the brain’s capacity. That somehow represents the difference between the IQ of fallen and unfallen man. Unfallen Adam could use 100% of his brain power and was more intelligent than afterward. He supposedly had great intuitive knowledge as well as greater intellectual power than anyone has now. Some have claimed that he had such a grasp of natural science as is unattainable today (John Laidlaw, The Bible Doctrine of Man, 1895; see Gordon Clark, pp. 20-21).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NATURAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/natural-observations-on-the-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/natural-observations-on-the-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NATURAL OBSERVATIONS ON THE IMAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous chapter we offered restrictive guidelines for identifying the image of God—boundaries within which the understanding of image must fall. The image must be a creatable likeness that applies to the whole individual even after the Fall. Then we offered two sets of positive evidence for the image as interpersonal capacity to build the view “from zero.” There were two deductive arguments: (1) the interpersonal purposes of mankind predict interpersonal nature of man as the image; (2) being in the image of an interpersonal God implies that mankind is interpersonal. Finally, we made inductive observations: human peculiarities observed in connection with image terminology end up being aspects of interpersonal capacity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PREVENIENT GRACE AND NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/prevenient-grace-and-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/prevenient-grace-and-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PREVENIENT GRACE AND NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have set aside the doctrine of natural depravity because (a) natural depravity lacks adequate primary biblical evidence for it. (b) Natural depravity creates contradictions. One set of propositions summarizes an argument against natural depravity. Since God is self-consistent, the variable that explains the Great Dilemma must lie outside God. Since only God and we figure in salvation, that variable must lie in us. We must be capable of responding to God; otherwise, God would be choosing who is saved by choosing whom he enables to respond to him unto salvation while saying that he does not want anyone to perish (2 Peter 3:9). As natural depravity in effect means divine self-contradiction, natural ability maintains divine self-consistency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIMARY EVIDENCE FOR THE IMAGE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/primary-evidence-for-the-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/primary-evidence-for-the-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRIMARY EVIDENCE FOR THE IMAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From evidence presented in the next three chapters, we conclude that having the image of God means having interpersonal capacity. At the outset we want to make explicit three notable ideas in the designation “interpersonal capacity.” (a) Interpersonal means that the image of God has to do with persons instead of things, forces, animals, or ideas. (b) Interpersonal relates the image to the social setting. The image involves more than the individual because it pertains to marriage, community, church, society, humankind as well as God’s purposes for persons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSYCHOLOGICAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/psychological-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/psychological-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PSYCHOLOGICAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary/Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proposition counter to natural depravity is as follows: there is no (1) clear (2) biblical basis for saying that Adam’s ability in regard to (3) spiritual things after the fall was any different from what it was (4) before the fall in a (5) biologically inheritable sense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By “clear” biblical base we mean that some passages could be understood the way natural depravity takes them, but no passage requires such an understanding. In fact, many texts offered in support of that concept cannot have that meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY STATEMENT AGAINST NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/summary-statement-against-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/summary-statement-against-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY STATEMENT AGAINST NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proposition counter to natural depravity is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;there is no (1) clear (2) biblical basis for saying that Adam’s ability in (3) spiritual matters after the Fall was different from what it was (4) before the Fall in a (5) biologically inheritable sense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By “clear” biblical base we mean that certain passages might be understood in the way natural depravity assumes, but no passage requires such a reconstruction; many texts proposed in support of that concept cannot have that meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY STATEMENT ON NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/summary-statement-on-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/summary-statement-on-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY STATEMENT ON NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proposition counter to natural depravity is as follows: there is no (1) clear (2) biblical basis for saying that Adam’s ability regarding (3) spiritual things after the fall was different from what it was (4) before the fall in a (5) biologically inheritable sense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By “clear” biblical base we mean that there are passages that we could interpret the way natural depravity takes them. But, no passage requires such an understanding. Many texts offered in support of that concept cannot have that meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUMMARY STATEMENT REGARDING NATURAL DEPRAVITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/summary-statement-regarding-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/summary-statement-regarding-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUMMARY STATEMENT REGARDING NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proposition counter to natural depravity is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no (1) clear (2) biblical basis for saying that Adam’s ability in regard to (3) spiritual things after the fall was any different from what it was (4) before the fall in a (5) biologically inheritable sense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By “clear” biblical base we mean that there are some passages that could be understood the way natural depravity takes them. However, no passage requires such an understanding. In fact, many texts offered in support of that concept cannot have that meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE “IMAGE OF GOD”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-image-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-image-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE “IMAGE OF GOD”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much of my creative energies lately have been directed toward tracing through the implications of interpersonal relationship as the organizing reality for Christian truth. Nowhere has this observation appeared more relevant than in the study of the nature of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the centuries extensive thought has gone into the interpretation of Genesis 1:26-27 and related materials: “Let’s make mankind in our image after our likeness.” There have been four proposed aspects of the “image of God” together with their effects. Reason heads the list. The ability to think abstractly relates to the capacity for language communication, creativity, responsibility (dominion), conscience, even humor, self-transcendence, and the ability to project consciousness over behind the eyes of another person. People can penetrate a situation in thought and imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DENIAL OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-denial-of-natural-depravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-denial-of-natural-depravity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DENIAL OF NATURAL DEPRAVITY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A DISTINCTIVE OF “THE RESTORATION MOVEMENT”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One distinctive of the Churches of Christ/Christian Churches has been their relatively high view of human nature. They have stood virtually alone in denying the traditional doctrine of natural depravity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late fourth century, Augustine, bishop of Hippo in North Africa, gave classical expression to this concept as part of his understanding of the nature of evil generally. In his thought, evil is a lack (privation) in the form of substance relative to its original form. This relatively de-formed condition produces evil action. Thus, the nature of evil is lack, the cause of evil is lack in form, and the criterion of evil is lack in form compared to original form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGE AND ETHICS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-image-and-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-image-and-ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGE AND ETHICS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theory of meaning, the basis for self-image, and the theory of ethics all three reference the same factors: being, action, and relationship. The previous chapter discussed meaning and self-image as the objective and subjective sides of the same thing. This chapter notes that ethics belongs to action in the interpersonal sphere. Since we have identified the image of God with the interpersonal capacity, it remains for us to explicate the principles for ethical theory that grow out of the construct established by God’s creating us in his (a) interpersonal image for (b) fellowship and (c) purpose. Action connects the first item with each of the last two. Image defines human nature/being, which behavior ties to relationship and purpose. Relationship and purpose are relational since action relates persons to others in fellowship and relates them to the results of their deeds. Action connects being to relations (ethics) even as action connected objective and subjective in the previous chapter (meaning).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGE AND THE BODY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-image-and-the-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-image-and-the-body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGE AND THE BODY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Including the Body in the Image&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter we address more deliberately the issue noted before. A long-standing debate about the image concerns whether to include the body in it. There are three ways to relate the image and the body. The body might be (a) part of the image, (b) involved with the image, or (c) analogous to the image. Several considerations go into deciding whether the body is in, with, or like the image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGE OF GOD AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-image-of-god-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-image-of-god-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGE OF GOD AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Interpersonal capacity” includes three notable ideas about the image. (a) Interpersonal stresses the fact that the image of God has to do with characteristics of persons rather than that of things, forces, ideas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(b) Interpersonal relates the image to the social setting so that it involves more than the individual by addressing marriage, community, church, society, mankind as well as the purposes of God for us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE IMAGO DEI AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-imago-dei-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-imago-dei-as-the-interpersonal-capacity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE IMAGO DEI AS THE INTERPERSONAL CAPACITY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BASES AND INTEGRATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study proposes that the image of God in us is the interpersonal capacity. It does not necessarily say something new, but endeavors to assemble relevant factors, to clarify a viewpoint that best incorporates them, and to show its consonance with the Christian worldview. In method, the approach sets aside a reductionism that strives after identifying our “essence” and “risks” reification, faculty psychology, depersonalization, and individualism, which are tendencies that derive from non-revelatory origins. It opts instead for a combinationalism that accounts for all the features of nature, function, and relationship that’s special revelation pictures us as having and called to have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NATURE OF MANKIND</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-nature-of-mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-nature-of-mankind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NATURE OF MANKIND&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preface&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The present volume was a project during a year’s sabbatical at Manhattan Christian College in Manhattan, Kansas. I am grateful to fellow faculty members, administration, and trustees for approving the sabbatical proposal. To my colleagues—especially Steve Isom, Dr. Franklin Karns, and Dr. Scott Caulley—I owe a debt of thanks for shouldering increased teaching loads so the necessary courses for the l989-1990 academic year could be maintained. Students and family have been encouragements as well during the completion of this and other commitments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRADITIONAL REASONS FOR GOD’S CREATING US</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/traditional-reasons-for-gods-creating-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/traditional-reasons-for-gods-creating-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRADITIONAL REASONS FOR GOD’S CREATING US&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Issues can be relatively simple in themselves; and so the question seems about God’s reason for creating us. Issues get complicated when we try to distinguish our own understanding from other ones and when we have to give reasons against such alternatives, especially if they overlap our own.1 As in our positive presentation so also in evaluating other positions, interpersonalism serves as the criterion for what is foreign and contradictory to what scripture says about the nature and purpose of God and man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRIMMING BACK THEOLOGY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/trimming-back-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/trimming-back-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRIMMING BACK THEOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BY SHEDDING NATURAL DEPRAVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Contribution of “Restorationism”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A less emphasized contribution of the Restoration Movement has been its dispensing with the centuries-old concept of natural depravity. The idea originated with Augustine of Hippo (354-430), who was emerging from the Greek philosophical tradition that did philosophy in the ontic category, in particular, Manichaeism. His seminal notion was that evil was a privation of form in being relative to its pristine condition, with perverted function arising from the deformation. That explanation of theodicy applied to the human condition and its behavioral outworking called sin. The Reformation and contemporary evangelicalism as well have incorporated that concept into their systematics. A student of historical theology has to go from the Stone-Campbell movement all the way into liberalism to find an absence of the natural depravity concept.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
