<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Acts on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/acts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Acts on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/acts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF ACTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-acts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-acts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF ACTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Along with Luke, Acts has short paragraphs that summarize periods of time the author&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;does not handle in detail: 1:12-14; 2:43-47; 4:32-35; 6:7; 8:1-3, 25, 40; 12:24-25; 15:33-35, 41; 19:21-22; 28:30-31. They serve as links between the high points the author has highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On some occasions the author introduces a brief note about someone that will play a major role later in the account: Saul at the stoning of Stephen (7:58; 8:1), Barnabas as among those who sold land to support for the needy (4:36-37), John Mark as the one whose mother owned the upper room where the disciples awaited Peter’s fate (12:12).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERNAL EVIDENCE ON THE AUTHORSHIP OF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/internal-evidence-on-the-authorship-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/internal-evidence-on-the-authorship-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERNAL EVIDENCE ON THE AUTHORSHIP OF&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACTS OF APOSTLES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “we passages” in Acts provide the best indication of its authorship. They occur in a series of sections as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:10-17&#x9;(10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20:5-15 &#x9;(5, 6, 7, 8, 13, 14, 15)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;21:1-18 &#x9;(1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;27:1-28:16&#x9;(27:1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 15, 16, 18, 20, 27, 29, 37;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LUKE-ACTS AS INTERPRETED HISTORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/luke-acts-as-interpreted-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/luke-acts-as-interpreted-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LUKE-ACTS AS INTERPRETED HISTORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.  Selectivity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fact that the book does not recount all the events means that selection has occurred. If selection has occurred, the writer does not just tell about a bunch of things that happened (“stream of consciousness”). Rather, he is a historian that makes a judgment about what events are epitomes and direction-setting events. Seeing the big picture, a historian chooses events that—from the vantage point of God above or of later perspective—prove to be more important because of their impact on subsequent events or prove more useful to any distinctive purpose the author may have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PLACE OF ACTS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/place-of-acts-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/place-of-acts-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PLACE OF ACTS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basic proposition: Place leads to purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Traces the spread of the gospel from Jerusalem to Rome&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note  Acts 1:8 pattern:             &#x9;Jerusalem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Judaea&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samaria&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ends of the earth (Rome)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(HISTORICAL)     &#x9;&#x9;Provides a framework for Paul’s epistles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. Covers the intercalary period between the beginning of the church and the end of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Israel (middle third of the first century)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covers to within three years of the time when&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE “SPEECHES” IN ACTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-speeches-in-acts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-speeches-in-acts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE “SPEECHES” IN ACTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides historical narrative in The Acts, Luke includes significant verbal presentation from conversations, prayers, letters, and sermons. Below in order of appearance are the major examples of spoken material.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Selection of Matthias&#x9;1:16-22&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sermon on Pentecost&#x9;2:14-26, 38-39&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sermon at Gate Beautiful&#x9;3:12-26&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First Defense to the Sanhedrin&#x9;4:8-12, 19-20&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayer &#x9;4:24-30&#x9;Jerusalem Christians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Ananias and Sapphira)&#x9;(5:3-4, 8-9)&#x9;(Peter)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Second Defense to the Sanhedrin&#x9;5:29-32&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PURPOSE OF ACTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-purpose-of-acts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-purpose-of-acts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PURPOSE OF ACTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In working out the purpose of Acts, we consider three items:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) the purpose would best applies to Luke-Acts taken together.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(b) the purpose ought specifically to relate in some way to Theophilus (1:1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(c) the purpose can be a combination of purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among the suggestions offered for the purpose of Luke-Acts are the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) Luke-Acts was prepared as a trial brief for Paul’s first appearance before the judgment seat of Caesar. It explained the forerunner and founding personality of Christianity and showed its general relationship to Judaism, and then proceeded to outline the pattern of its spread from Judaea throughout the rest of the Roman Empire. The fact that Acts portrays the relationship between Christians and Roman rulers in a good light could corroborate this suggestion. Theophilus could have been Paul’s trial lawyer. “Most excellent” (Luke 1:3) could be a title of address for such a dignitary (Acts 23:26; 24:3; 26:25).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE WITNESS OF ACTS TO THE KERYGMA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-witness-of-acts-to-the-kerygma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-witness-of-acts-to-the-kerygma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE WITNESS OF ACTS TO THE KERYGMA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Theories about an evolutionary origin for the Christian religion present a fundamental line of inquiry. The body of literature called the “New Testament” supposedly shows stages that process passed through. If the New Testament does not actually represent the original Christian preaching, what really did comprise their message, and how can we recover that primitive gospel?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts of Apostles, written after the life of Jesus of Nazareth, presupposes incidents in his ministry. It purports to be a history of men divinely appointed to establish a religion based on these incidents. The record of their “acts” includes accounts of what they said as well. Such a record should prove valuable in discovering the content of the earliest “preaching,” the kerygma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
