<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ATONEMENT on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/atonement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ATONEMENT on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/atonement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON JOHN CALVIN’S PENAL SUBSTITUTION THEORY OF THE ATONEMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/comments-on-john-calvins-penal-substitution-theory-of-the-atonement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/comments-on-john-calvins-penal-substitution-theory-of-the-atonement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON JOHN CALVIN’S PENAL SUBSTITUTION THEORY OF THE ATONEMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the Reformation, a common understanding of Christ’s atonement work considers his righteousness as a substitute for ours and his death as a substitute for our death as punishment for our sin. The comments below shoulder a negative burden of proof to show that John Calvin’s penal substitution understanding is foreign to atonement theory unless we adopt the rest of his legal theological method, where penal substitution would make sense. The thesis here is that substitutionary atonement theory does not belong in non-Calvinistic theology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REASONS FOR THE INCARNATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/reasons-for-the-incarnation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/reasons-for-the-incarnation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;REASONS FOR THE INCARNATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing what heaven was like, why did Jesus ever leave it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing what earth was like, why did he ever come here?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing what Golgatha was going to be like, why did Jesus ever become a man?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Communication: Hebrews 1:1-2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Means of communication: “son” vs. angels/prophets&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. Manner of communication: demonstration and description&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;holistic      vs.   in many parts/progressive&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“son-wise”         in many ways&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;personal            verbal&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SACRIFICE AND SALVATION: ANCIENT NEAR EASTERN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/sacrifice-and-salvation-ancient-near-eastern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/sacrifice-and-salvation-ancient-near-eastern/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SACRIFICE AND SALVATION: ANCIENT NEAR EASTERN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ANTECEDENTS TO REDEMPTION THROUGH CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Sacrifice is as old as religion, and religion is as old as man.” The antiquity of sacrifice relates to its universality. Virtually every ancient culture offered sacrifices to supernatural entities; some cultures still do. In the Bible, sacrifice begins in the second generation (Genesis 4:2-8) and appears throughout the patriarchal and Mosaic periods, culminating in Christ’s “sacrifice.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite the abundance of biblical material on sacrifice, the origin of sacrifice is ambiguous. Did it arise from people’s natural religious instincts or from unrecorded divine appointment?1 The same uncertainty applies to the rationale for sacrifice; it is not explicitly stated anywhere in the Old Testament.2 After summarizing some particulars about sacrifice and noting some relevant archaeological remains, the following presentation offers a rationale for sacrifice that connects it with salvation as related to the life and death of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SIX NOTATIONS ON IDENTIFICATION ATONEMENT THEORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/six-notations-on-identification-atonement-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/six-notations-on-identification-atonement-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SIX NOTATIONS ON IDENTIFICATION ATONEMENT THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Identification as the Whole Basis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In identification atonement theory, “identification” means more than identifying with Christ from our own side so God will count Christ’s atoning death as a substitute for our own death. That leaves substitution—or whatever—as the operative mechanism. Identification likewise is not just God’s viewing us from his side as connected with Christ. Identification in these senses fits with any theory of the atonement. Identification would merely connect the sinner with Christ—in the sinner’s mind and God’s mind—in anticipation of whatever mechanism then removed the penalty: ransom, substitute, or conquest. Identification would not replace or obviate some additional operation after the subjective and objective connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STRICTURES ON CALVIN’S PENAL SUBSTITUTIONARY ATONEMENT  THEORY:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/strictures-on-calvins-penal-substitutionary-atonement-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/strictures-on-calvins-penal-substitutionary-atonement-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STRICTURES ON CALVIN’S PENAL SUBSTITUTIONARY ATONEMENT  THEORY:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IDENTIFICATION AS AN ALTERNATIVE PROPOSAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Salvation through Jesus Christ is the most distinctive feature of Christianity. Herein lies its primary difference from previous divine economies, other religions, and human agendas. In Christ, God is concerned with more than letting us know about him, about his moral standards, and about our responsibilities within his purposes. Salvation is not from ignorance, as by revelation; it is not deliverance from material existence as in Gnosticism and eastern dualism; it is not deliverance from individuality as in Hinduism. It is deliverance from alienation and all the negatives that grow out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE MEANING OF “IDENTIFICATION WITH CHRIST”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-meaning-of-identification-with-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-meaning-of-identification-with-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE MEANING OF “IDENTIFICATION WITH CHRIST”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Identification with Christ” refers to a complex of factors within the reality of personal relationship, which we are calling interpersonalism. Interpersonalism is a worldview that considers persons in relationship as the highest frame of reference. That reality includes aspects like the following.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Faith in Christ as the object of identification in place of all others. We not only understand and believe intellectually, but trust actively that Christ is an “extension of,” and the human “manifestation of,” the other side of the divine-human relationship. We believe that identification with him leads to identification with the Father because that is the Father’s condition for identification with himself. We believe what Christ believes; we accept what he teaches about all things whereof he speaks. We put our trust in him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE RATIONALE FOR ATONEMENT THROUGH CHRIST</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-rationale-for-atonement-through-christ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/essays/the-rationale-for-atonement-through-christ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE RATIONALE FOR ATONEMENT THROUGH CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary statement: “Christ alone has achieved perfect goodness as a man in the flesh by obeying the Father in everything even to the point of yielding to an agonizing death. When we commit ourselves to Christ as Lord together with the values and purposes he shares with the Father, God considers us righteous like him, forgiving our sin, reckoning aspiration for achievement, reconciling us to himself.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
