<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 Corinthians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1 Corinthians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-1&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul, called (to be an) apostle of-Christ Jesus by (the) will of-God, and Sosthenes our brother, 2to-the church of-[the] God [the] being in Corinth, to-the sanctified ones-ones in Christ Jesus, called (to be) saints with all the-ones calling-on the name of-the Lord of-us Jesus Christ in every place, theirs and ours. 3Grace to-you and peace from God (the) Father of-us and (the) Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-2&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; And-I, having-come to you, brothers, I-did┘not└come according-to superiority of-word or wisdom, proclaiming to-you the mystery of-[the] God. 2For I-did┘not└determine to-know anything among you except2 Jesus Christ and this-one crucified. 3And-I in weakness and in fear and in much trembling was with you, 4and the word of-me and the proclamation of-me (were) not in persuasive words, but in demonstration of-spirit and power, 5in-order-that the faith of-you might┘not└be in (the) wisdom of-men, but in (the) power of-God.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-3&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; And-I, brothers, was┘not└able to-speak to-you as spiritual but as physical, as infants in Christ. 2I-gave┘you milk└to-drink, not solid-food. For you-are still physical, for where jealousy and strife (are) among you, are not you fleshly and walk according-to man? 4For when anybody (of you) says, &amp;ldquo;I am of-Paul,&amp;rdquo; and another (says), &amp;ldquo;I (am) of-Apollos,&amp;rdquo; are-you not men? 5What then is Apollos? And what is Paul? Ministers by whom you-came-to-believe, and to-each as the Lord gave. 6I-planted, Apollos watered, but God made-(it)-grow. 7So neither is the-one planting anything, nor the-one watering, but God the-One making-(it)-grow. 8Now the-one planting and the-one watering are one, but each will-receive [the] his-own pay according-to [the] his-own work. 9For we-are fellow-workers of-God; you are God&amp;rsquo;s field, God&amp;rsquo;s building.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-4&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In-this-way let┘(a) man└consider us: as ministers of-Christ and stewards of-(the)-mysteries of-God. 2Here beyond-that it-is-required in [the] stewards that (a) person be-found reliable. 3But to-me it-is (a) very-small-thing that I-should-be-examined by you or by (a) human court; indeed I-do┘not-even└judge myself. I-am-aware-of┘nothing└against myself, but I-do┘not└stand-justified by this; but the-One examining me is (the) Lord. 5So-that do┘not└judge anything ahead-of time until the Lord comes, who also will-bring-to-light hidden-things of-[the] darkness and will-disclose the plans of-the hearts, and then [the] praise will-be to-each from [the] God.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-5&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Sexual-immorality is┘actually└reported among you, and such immorality that (is) not -even among the Gentiles, that somebody would-be-living-with (the) wife of-the/his father. 2And are you proud and not mourning instead in-order-that the-one having-done this [the] deed should-be-removed from (the) midst of-you? 3For I, being-absent with-the body but present in-the spirit, have┘already└judged, as-if being-present, the-one having-committed this thus. 4In the name of-the Lord [of-us]ms Jesus, you having-been-assembled and [the] my spirit with the power of-the Lord of-us Jesus, 5deliver such-(a person) to-[the] Satan for (the) destruction of-the flesh, in-order-that the spirit may-be-saved in the day of-the Lord. 6The pride of-you (is) not good. Do-you┘not└know that (a) little yeast leavens the whole lump? 7Clean-out the old yeast in-order-0that you-may-be (a) new lump, even-as you-are unleavened, for also Christ the Passover of-us was sacrificed. 8So let-us celebrate-the-festival, not with old yeast nor with yeast of-evil and wickedness, but with unleavened (bread) of-sincerity and truth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-6&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Does┘anybody of-you having (a) matter against the other└dare to-go-to-law before the unrighteous and not before the saints? 2Or do-you┘not└know that the saints will-judge the world? And if the world is-judged by you, are-you unable (to be judges) of-(the)-least (matters)? 3Do-you┘not└know that we-will-judge angels, much-less matters-of-everyday-life? 4So if you-have matters-of-this life, do-you-appoint these (as judges) the-ones to (your shame: 5I-speak to-you to (your) humiliation: (is it) so (that) there-is nobody among you wise, who will be-able to-decide in-the-midst2 of the brother of-him? 6But brother goes-to court with brother and this before unbelievers? 7Already [then]ms it-is (a) defect to-you actually that you-have lawsuits with each-other. On-account-of what rather not be wronged? 8But you wrong and defraud, and this brothers. 9Or do-you┘not└know that unjust-ones will┘not└inherit (the) kingdom of-God? do┘not└deceive-yourselves. Neither immoral-people nor idolaters nor adulterers nor effeminate nor homosexuals 10not thieves nor covetous-people, not drunkards, not revilers, not swindlers will-inherit (the) kingdom of-God. 11And some-of you-were these, but you-were-made-righteous in the name of-the Lord Jesus Christ and in the Spirit of-the God of-us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-7&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now about what-things you-wrote. (It is) good for (a) man not to-touch (a) woman. 2But on-account-of [the] sexual-immorality, each man should-have [the] his-own wife, and each woman should-have [the] her-own husband. 3The husband needs-to-give to-the wife the/her due; and likewise also the wife (needs-to-give) to-the husband the/his due. 4The wife does┘not└have-authority-over [the] her body, but the husband (does). And likewise the husband also does┘not└have-authority-over [the] his body, but the wife (does). 5Do┘not└deprive one-another, except2 for (a) time by agreement in-order-that youpl-may-devote-yourselves to-[the] prayer and be together3 again, in-order-that [the] Satan may┘not└tempt youpl on-account-of the self-control of-you. 6But I-say this according-to concession, not according-to commandment. 7But I-want all men to-be also as myself, but each has his-own gracious-gift from God, the–one thus, on-the-one-hand, and the-other thus, on-the-other-hand.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-8&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now about [the]-things offered to idols. We┘all└have knowledge. [The] knowledge puffs up; [the] love builds up. 2If anybody thinks (himself) to-know something, he-did┘not-yet└come-to-know as it-is-necessary to-know. 3And if anybody loves [the] God, this-one has-been-known by him. 4About [the] eating things-offered-to-idols. We know (there is) no idol in (the) world and that nobody (is) God but2 one. 5For even if there-are so-called gods either in heaven or on earth, as there-are many gods and many lords, 6 [but] for-us (there is) one God the Father, from whom (are) [the] all-things and we (exist) for him, and one Lord Jesus Christ through whom (are) [the] all-things and we (exist) through him.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-9&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Am-I not free? Am-I not (an) apostle? Have-I┘not└seen Jesus the Lord of-us? Are you not the work of-me in (the) Lord? 2If I-am not (an) apostle to-others, [but] I-am to-you. For you are the seal of-the apostleship of-me in (the) Lord. 3[The] my defense to-the-ones sitting-in-judgment-on me is this. 4I-do┘not not┘┘└have (a) right to-eat and drink, do-I? 5I-do┘not not┘┘└have (a) right to-lead-around (a) sister as-(a)-wife, └└ do-I, like the also other apostles and the brothers of—the Lord and Cephas? 6Or do┘I only and Barnabas not└have (a) right not to-work? 7Who at-any-time serves-as-(a)-soldier at┘his-own└expense? Who plants (a) vineyard and does┘not└eat the fruit of-it? Or who shepherds sheep and does┘not└eat [of] the milk of-the flock? 8I-am┘not┘┘└speaking according-to man, └└am-I, or does┘the Law not also└say these-things? 9For in [the] Law of-Moses it-has-been-written, &amp;ldquo;You-shall┘not└muzzle (an) ox while-threshing.&amp;rdquo; It-is┘not┘┘└(a) concern to-[the] God of-[the] oxen, └└is-it? 10Or does-he-speak altogether on-account-of us? For on-account-of us he-wrote that the-one plowing ought to-plow in hope and the-one threshing (ought) to-thresh in hop of-[the]-sharing. 11If we sowed to-you [the] spiritual-things, (it is a) great-thing if we harvest [the] physical-things of-you? 12If others are-sharers-of the right from-you, not more we? But we-did┘not└use this [the] right. But we-put-up with all-things in-order-that we-might┘not└give any hindrance to-the gospel of-[the] Christ. 13Do-you┘not└know that the-ones performing the sacred (services) [the]ms eat of-the temple; the-ones waiting-on the altar have-(a)-share-with the altar? 14Thus also the Lord gave-directions to-the-ones proclaiming the gospel to-live from the gospel. 15But I have┘not└used any of-these. And I-did┘not└write these-things in-order-that it-may-be thus in my (case). For to-die (would be) good to-me rather than anybody should empty the boast of-me. 16For if I-preach-the-gospel, (a) boast is not to-me; for necessity lies-on me—for woe is to-me if I-do┘not└preach-the-gospel. 17For if I-do this willingly, I-have┘(a) stewardship└entrusted (to me). 18What then is the reward of-me? That preaching-the-gospel I-present the gospel without-charge to the not making-full-use-of the right of-me in the gospel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-10&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I-do┘not└want you to-be-unaware, brothers, that the fathers of-us were all under the cloud and passed–through the sea, 2and all were-baptized to [the] Moses in the cloud and in the sea, 3and all ate the same spiritual food, 4and all drank the same spiritual drink; for they drank from (a) spiritual rock following (them), and the rock was [the] Messiah. 5But not with [the] most of-them was┘[the] God└pleased, for they-were-struck-down in the wilderness. 6But these-things became examples for-us unto our [the] not being coveters of-evil-things even-as they-also coved (them). 7Nor be idolaters even-as some of-them, as it-has-been-written,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-11&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Be-imitators of-me even-as I-also (am) of-Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Now I-praise you, because you-have-remembered all-things of-me, and hold-firmly-to the traditions, even-as I-delivered (them) to-you. 3Now I-want you to-know that [the] Christ is the head of-every husband, and the/a husband (is the head) of-(a)-wife, and [the] God is (the) head of-[the] Christ. 4Every man praying or prophesying having (something) on (his) head disgraces the head of-him. 5And every woman praying or prophesying uncovered with-respect-to-the head disgraces the head of-her. For it-is one and the same-thing (for it to be) [the] shaved. 6For if (a) woman is-uncovered, let-her-cut-her-hair-off; and if (it is) shameful for-(a)-woman to-cut-her-hair-off or shave-(it)-off, let-her-be-covered. 7For (a) man ought not cover the/his head, being (the) image and glory of-God. And the woman is (the) glory of-(the)-man. 8For (a) man is not of-(the)-woman, but (the) woman on-account-of the man. 10On-account-of this, the woman ought to-have authority on the/her head on-account-of the angels. 11However, in (the) Lord the woman (is) neither without (the) man nor (the) man without (the) woman. 12For as the woman (is) out-of the man, so also the man (is) through the woman, and [the] all-things (are) out-of [the] God. 13Judge in you yourselves: is-it proper for-(a)-woman to-pray to-[the] God uncovered? 14Does┘not [the] nature itself└teach you that if (a) man lets-his-hair-grow-long it-is (a) dishonor to-him, 15but if (a) woman lets-her-hair-grow-long, it-is (an) honor to-her? 16Now if anybody wants to-be contentious, we do┘not└have such (a) custom nor the churches of-[the] God.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-12&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now concerning [the] spiritual gifts, brothers, I-do┘not└want you to-be-unaware. 2You-know that when you-were Gentiles, you-were led-astray to [the] dumb [the] idols. 3Wherefore I-make-known to-you that nobody speaking by (the) Spirit of-God, says, &amp;ldquo;Jesus (is) accursed&amp;rdquo;; and nobody is-able to-say, &amp;ldquo;Jesus (is) Lord,&amp;rdquo; except2 by the Holy Spirit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Now there-are varieties of-spiritual gifts, but the same Spirit, 5and there-are varieties of-ministries, and the same Lord, 6and there-are varieties of-activities, but the same God the-one working [the] all-things in all (people). 7But to-each the manifestation of-the Spirit is-given for the common-good. 8For to-one (the) word of-wisdom is-given by the Spirit, but to-another (the) word of-knowledge according-to the same Spirit. 9To-another, faith by the same Spirit, but to-another spiritual-gifts of healings by the one Spirit. 10But to-another workings of-miracles, but to-another prophecy, and to-another varieties of-spirits, to-another kinds of-languages, but to-another translation of-languages. 11And all these-things the One and the same Spirit works, distributing to-each individually even-as he-desires.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-13&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; If I-speak in the languages of-[the] men and [the] angels, but do┘not└have love, I-have-become (a) noisy gong or crashing cymbal. 2And if I-have prophecy and know-all [the] mysteries and all [the] knowledge and if I-have all [the] faith so-as to-remove mountains, and do┘not└have love, I-am nothing. 3And-if I-give-away┘all the belongings of-me└to-feed (the poor), and if I-deliver-over the body of-me in-order-that I-may-be-burned-up, and I-do┘not└have love, I-am-profited nothing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-14&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Pursue [the] love, and earnestly-desire [the] spiritual (gifts), but specifically in-order-that you-may-be-prophesying. 2Ffor the-one speaking in (a) language is┘not└speaking to-men but to-God, because nobody is-understanding; but by-(the)-Spirit he-speaks mysteries. 3But the-one prophesying speaks to-men edification and exhortation and consolation. 4The-one speaking in-(a)-language builds┘himself└up, but the-one prophesying builds┘(the) church└up. 5Now I-am-willing for you all to-speak in-languages, but specifically in-order-that you-may-be-prophesying. And the-one prophesying (is) greater than the-one speaking in-languages unless3 he-translates in-order-that the church may-receive edification.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-15&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now I-make-known to-you, brothers, the gospel that I-preached to-you, that you also received, and in which you┘also└stand, 2and by which you-are-being-saved if you-hold-on-firmly to which word I-preached to-you—unless2 you-believed in vain. 3For I-delivered to-you among first-things, what also I-received, that Christ died for the sins of-us according-to the scriptures, 4and that he-was-buried and that he-has-been-raised on-the third [the] day according-to the scriptures, 5and that he-appeared to-Cephas, then to-the twelve, 6and that he-appeared to-over five-hundred brothers at-the-same-time, of whom the more remain till now, but some fell-asleep. 7Then he-appeared to-James, then to-all the apostles. 8And last of-all he-appeared also-to-me, as-it-were, to-one born-at-and-unusual-time-of-year. 9For I am the least of-the apostles, who am not worthy to-be-called (an) apostle, because I-persecuted the church of-[the] God. 10But by-(the)-grace of-God I-am what I-am, and the grace of-him [the] to me was not in vain, but I-labored more than they all, but not I, but the grace of-[the] God [the] with me. 11So whether I or those, thus we-preach and thus you-believed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Corinthians 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/1-corinthians/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-corinthians-chapter-16&#34;&gt;1 Corinthians Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now about the collection [the] for the saints. Even-as I-directed the churches of-[the] Galatia, so you-do also. 2Every first (day) of-(the)-week, let┘each of-you└lay by him storing-up whatever2 things-go-well, in-order-that when I-come, collections will┘not└take place. 3And when I-arrive, whomever2 you approve—I-will-sent these through letters to-carry the gift of-you to Jerusalem. 4And if it-is fitting for-[the] me-also to-go, they-will-go with me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Now I-will-come to you when I-pass-through Macedonia, for I-do-pass-through Macedonia. 6And perhaps I-will-stay with you or even winter (with you), in-order-that you-may-send┘me└forward whenever2 I-come. 7For I-do┘not└want to-see you now in passing, for I-hope to-remain with you for (a) certain time, if the Lord allows. 8But I-will-stay in Ephesus until [the] Pentecost. 9For (a) door opened to-me, wide and effective, and (there are) many opponents.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
