<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EVIDENCES on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/evidences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EVIDENCES on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/evidences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CANON CRITICISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/canon-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/canon-criticism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CANON CRITICISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Definition of Canonicity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Canonicity constitutes normative literature. It sets the doctrinal “norms” by which we consider issues and measure viewpoints. In Christianity, canonicity correlates with inspiration. The canon consists of writings that came from “inspired” men, men whose writings were as correct and authoritative as they would have been if God himself had “exhaled them” (2 Timothy 3:16).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. Principles for Canonicity (See separate document “The Determining Principles for&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DATES AND ORIGIN OF NEW TESTAMENT WRITINGS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/dates-and-origin-of-new-testament-writings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/dates-and-origin-of-new-testament-writings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DATES AND ORIGIN OF NEW TESTAMENT WRITINGS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Four Scholars Compared&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Book&#x9;Guthrie&#x9;Harrison&#x9;Thiessen&#x9;Hiebert&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew&#x9;80-100&#x9;70-80&#x9;45-50&#x9;66&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jerusalem&#x9;Palestine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark&#x9;60-70&#x9;65-70&#x9;67-68&#x9;64-65&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jerusalem&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Rome&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luke&#x9;75-85&#x9;70&#x9;58&#x9;66-67&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Achaia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John&#x9;90-110&#x9;80-100&#x9;85-90&#x9;80-98&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts&#x9;64&#x9;55-60&#x9;61&#x9;67-68&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romans&#x9;57-59&#x9;56-57&#x9;56&#x9;58&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Macedonia&#x9;Corinth&#x9;Corinth&#x9;Corinth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians&#x9;spring 57&#x9;55-56&#x9;spring 54, 55&#x9;spring 57&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEG DATES FOR NEW TESTAMENT STUDIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peg-dates-for-new-testament-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peg-dates-for-new-testament-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PEG DATES FOR NEW TESTAMENT STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.D.&#x9;34 (perhaps 37)&#x9;Accession of Aretas&#x9;Paul’s   conversion   had   to   follow   this &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;date (Gal. 1:17-18; 2 Cor. 11:32).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;36&#x9;Pontius Pilate deposed&#x9;Does   the   absence   of   a   procurator   in &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Palestine  account  for  the  possibility  of&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;executing      Stephen     and     of     Paul’s &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;putting   others   to  death?   (Acts  7:1-8:3; &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;9:1-2; 26:9-11)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;40&#x9;Death of Aretas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;44&#x9;Death of Herod Agrippa I&#x9;Paul’s  first   missionary   journey   had   to &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;follow  this  date. (Acts 12:20-23 recounts&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;his death + 13:1-14:28 records the tour.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIMARY QUESTIONS IN THE COLLECTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/primary-questions-in-the-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/primary-questions-in-the-collection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRIMARY QUESTIONS IN THE COLLECTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF THE NEW TESTAMENT CANON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some scholars suppose the apostles did not consider their work as something for the subsequent ages of the church. They were writing for the then and there. They had supposed that Christ would return within the lifetime of some first-generation Christians. Writing for posterity did not enter their minds. If their literary activity took place under these conditions, collecting their writings to establish a permanent canon would not have been a concerted effort either. Only when it became evident that Christ would not immediately return did the early Christians begin to locate and assemble apostolic writings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DETERMINING PRINCIPLES FOR CANONICITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-determining-principles-for-canonicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-determining-principles-for-canonicity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DETERMINING PRINCIPLES FOR CANONICITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In keeping with the structure of apologetics, the following sketch deals with the principles for determining whether a writing belongs in the Judaeo-Christian canon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The historical principle comes logically first because canonicity has first to do with (5) where the book came from, which means who wrote it and where he got his information. Behind this step lies the concern about (4) how people recognized divine spokesmen and distinguished them from false claimants. The question rests on the observation that God’s breaking into the world through special revelation always, by definition and the nature of the case, involves (3) miracle. Even the prophets themselves must be able to distinguish divine revelation from their own thoughts. The next step is (2) the distinction between divine miracle that confirms revelation and other phenomena like demonic miracle, deception, parapsychological phenomena, misidentified natural occurrences. This distinction is most decisively made by (1) the triumph of the divine in confrontation with alternatives: the “resurrection” of Israel from Egypt (and attendant events) for the Old Testament and the resurrection of Messiah from the grave in the New Testament serve as prime examples. These are historical considerations because biblical revelation is a historical (vs. metaphysical) construct. The historical principle determines canonicity by giving us the right books in the first place; it is positive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TYPICAL ISSUES IN CRITICAL INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/typical-issues-in-critical-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/typical-issues-in-critical-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TYPICAL ISSUES IN CRITICAL INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Critical introduction addresses several issues related to the study of documents. In this setting, “introduction” does not mean getting acquainted with a book’s contents for the first time. “Critical” introduction does not “criticize” the book as if to degrade it. Critical introduction evaluates the nature of a book and matters surrounding its origin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two classifications of information critics draw on in this endeavor are internal evidence and external evidence. Internal evidence refers to data in the writing; external evidence refers to information from elsewhere. In critical introduction to the New Testament, (a) extant early Christian literature provides most of the external evidence. (b) Other resources related to the origins of Christianity help evaluate the records of early Christianity. They have been assembled in writings like F. F. Bruce’s Jesus and Christian Origins Outside the New Testament (Grand Rapids, MI: Wm. B. Eerdmans Publishing Co., 1974) or Gary R. Habermas’ Ancient Evidence for the Life of Jesus: Historical Records of His Death and Resurrection (Nashville, TN: Thomas Nelson Publishers, 1984). A final, more distant source of introductory information comes from extra-biblical records that preserve (c) the historical background in the contemporary biblical world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE GOSPELS IN GENERAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-gospels-in-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-gospels-in-general/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE GOSPELS IN GENERAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Form&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Large portions cover the triumphal entry to the ascension: Matthew 21-28, Mark&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11-16, Luke 19:29-24:53, John 12-21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. Principle of selectivity: materials that show him as Messiah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C. Emphasis on the resurrection: note Acts 4:33; Romans 1:1-7; 1 Corinthians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;15:1-11&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;History in general, much less a “gospel” in particular, is neither a stream of consciousness nor a complete record. It is a selective account that operates like a dot-to-dot, moving from one direction-setting event to the next.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE RELATIONSHIP OF THE SYNOPTICS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-the-synoptics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-relationship-of-the-synoptics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE RELATIONSHIP OF THE SYNOPTICS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PERICOPES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;___       =  Peculiar to Matthew        &#x9;=   5&#x9;(42%) of Matthew&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IIII&#x9; = Peculiar to Mark                 &#x9;=   2&#x9;(7%)   of Mark&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;////&#x9; = Peculiar to Luke                  &#x9;=   9&#x9;(59%) of Luke&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark and Luke                        =   5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew and Mark               &#x9;= 12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew and Mark and Luke &#x9;= 42&#x9;(92%) of John is new&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew and Luke                 &#x9;= 14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;89 sections&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*The diagram above comes from class notes taken under Dr. Lewis A. Foster, former Dean of the Graduate School at The Cincinnati Christian Seminary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE SYNOPTIC GOSPELS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-synoptic-gospels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-synoptic-gospels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE SYNOPTIC GOSPELS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scholars speculate about synoptic origins in an effort to create a scenario for the features of the first three gospels as a set. We do not have to settle on what actually explains the phenomena; we need only develop credible possibilities for explaining those features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Introducing the Synoptic Problem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “synoptic problem” addresses the relationship between Matthew, Mark, and Luke. The degree of their similarity calls for explanation beyond what happened. Their unusual similarity is then complicated by the differences between them. Evangelical perspective calls for minimizing appeal to contradiction to solve the question. The synoptic phenomenon is part of the “gospel problem” as a whole. In addition to the characteristics of all four gospels, the synoptic problem focuses on features shared by the first three. The following considerations highlight how alike they are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PECULIARITIES OF MATTHEW</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peculiarities-of-matthew/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peculiarities-of-matthew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PECULIARITIES OF MATTHEW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Among the gospels, greatest number of Old Testament citations of prophecies fulfilled in&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the life of Jesus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only gospel to use the term church (ἐκκλησία, ekklēsia): 16:18; 18:172&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Only gospel that uses the expression kingdom of heaven (in the same places where other&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;gospels say kingdom of God). Uses “kingdom of God” also: 6:33; 12:28; 19:24; 21:31, 43.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; With the exception of the Cry of Dereliction (27:46), there are no explanations of Jewish customs or terms, as there are in the other gospels.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Not presented wholly in chronological order as measured by the other synoptics&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; The infancy narrative is written from Joseph’s viewpoint.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only synoptic (or gospel) to use outer darkness as a figure for condemnation/hell (8:12; 22:13; 25:30; 27:45)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PECULIARITIES OF MARK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peculiarities-of-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peculiarities-of-mark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PECULIARITIES OF MARK&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Most characterized by the expression εὐθύς (euthys, “immediately”: 42 times vs. 4 times in Matthew and once in Luke). Does καὶ εὐθύς [kai euthys] amount to “and by and by,” “and at another time”?&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most pronounced emphasis on deeds of Jesus and the least teaching material (λογία, logia)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most characteristically uses the historic present&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Most characteristically uses the ingressive imperfect tense&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Shortest gospel (but has some individual blocks that are longer than the corresponding treatments in the other synoptics)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Stress on the “Messianic secret”&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contains a few Latinisms&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PECULIARITIES OF LUKE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peculiarities-of-luke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peculiarities-of-luke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PECULIARITIES OF LUKE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indicates most noticeably the prayer life of Jesus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; More attention given to women involved in the life and ministry of Jesus, which could fit&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;with writing from Mary’s viewpoint&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; The infancy narrative and some other materials are written from Mary’s viewpoint.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Contains a section of “new material” in 10:1-18:14&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Speaks of two angels rather than one:  Luke 24:4 ( = Matthew 28:2; Mark 16:5)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERNAL EVIDENCE FOR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/internal-evidence-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/internal-evidence-for/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERNAL EVIDENCE FOR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE AUTHORSHIP OF JOHN’S GOSPEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Determining from internal evidence the authorship of John’s gospel requires establishing the identity of “the disciple whom Jesus loved”: “This [disciple that Jesus loved] is the disciple that bears witness of these things and wrote them, and we know his testimony is true” (21:24 + 20). A similar comment appears in the account of the spear thrust: “He that has seen has borne witness, and his witness is true; and he knows he says true things that you may believe” (19:35; cp. 20:30-31). The characteristic description appears five times in the gospel beginning with the night before Christ’s death: 13:23; 19:26; 20:2; 21:7, and 21:20.1 Other more vague references to unnamed men include the second of “two disciples” of John that heard Jesus speak (1:35-39), the first being Andrew (1:40); and “another disciple,” known by the high priest (18:15).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PECULIARITIES OF JOHN’S GOSPEL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peculiarities-of-johns-gospel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/peculiarities-of-johns-gospel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PECULIARITIES OF JOHN’S GOSPEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Emphasizes the corporeality of the resurrected Christ as well as the fleshliness of Jesus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;incarnate&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Has the largest percentage of the gospel devoted to the triumphal entry to the ascension;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;chapters 14-17 record just record what happened from the upper room to the arrest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Written around the synoptics’ account; so written subsequent to them&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much higher percentage of teaching-preaching, or discourse, material proportionately&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(known as a “spiritual gospel”)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF ACTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-acts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-acts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF ACTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Along with Luke, Acts has short paragraphs that summarize periods of time the author&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;does not handle in detail: 1:12-14; 2:43-47; 4:32-35; 6:7; 8:1-3, 25, 40; 12:24-25; 15:33-35, 41; 19:21-22; 28:30-31. They serve as links between the high points the author has highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On some occasions the author introduces a brief note about someone that will play a major role later in the account: Saul at the stoning of Stephen (7:58; 8:1), Barnabas as among those who sold land to support for the needy (4:36-37), John Mark as the one whose mother owned the upper room where the disciples awaited Peter’s fate (12:12).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERNAL EVIDENCE ON THE AUTHORSHIP OF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/internal-evidence-on-the-authorship-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/internal-evidence-on-the-authorship-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERNAL EVIDENCE ON THE AUTHORSHIP OF&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACTS OF APOSTLES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “we passages” in Acts provide the best indication of its authorship. They occur in a series of sections as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:10-17&#x9;(10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20:5-15 &#x9;(5, 6, 7, 8, 13, 14, 15)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;21:1-18 &#x9;(1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;27:1-28:16&#x9;(27:1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 15, 16, 18, 20, 27, 29, 37;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LUKE-ACTS AS INTERPRETED HISTORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/luke-acts-as-interpreted-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/luke-acts-as-interpreted-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LUKE-ACTS AS INTERPRETED HISTORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.  Selectivity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fact that the book does not recount all the events means that selection has occurred. If selection has occurred, the writer does not just tell about a bunch of things that happened (“stream of consciousness”). Rather, he is a historian that makes a judgment about what events are epitomes and direction-setting events. Seeing the big picture, a historian chooses events that—from the vantage point of God above or of later perspective—prove to be more important because of their impact on subsequent events or prove more useful to any distinctive purpose the author may have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PLACE OF ACTS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/place-of-acts-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/place-of-acts-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PLACE OF ACTS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basic proposition: Place leads to purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Traces the spread of the gospel from Jerusalem to Rome&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note  Acts 1:8 pattern:             &#x9;Jerusalem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Judaea&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samaria&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ends of the earth (Rome)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(HISTORICAL)     &#x9;&#x9;Provides a framework for Paul’s epistles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. Covers the intercalary period between the beginning of the church and the end of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Israel (middle third of the first century)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covers to within three years of the time when&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE “SPEECHES” IN ACTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-speeches-in-acts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-speeches-in-acts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE “SPEECHES” IN ACTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides historical narrative in The Acts, Luke includes significant verbal presentation from conversations, prayers, letters, and sermons. Below in order of appearance are the major examples of spoken material.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Selection of Matthias&#x9;1:16-22&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sermon on Pentecost&#x9;2:14-26, 38-39&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sermon at Gate Beautiful&#x9;3:12-26&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First Defense to the Sanhedrin&#x9;4:8-12, 19-20&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayer &#x9;4:24-30&#x9;Jerusalem Christians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Ananias and Sapphira)&#x9;(5:3-4, 8-9)&#x9;(Peter)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Second Defense to the Sanhedrin&#x9;5:29-32&#x9;Peter&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PURPOSE OF ACTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-purpose-of-acts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-purpose-of-acts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PURPOSE OF ACTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In working out the purpose of Acts, we consider three items:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(a) the purpose would best applies to Luke-Acts taken together.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(b) the purpose ought specifically to relate in some way to Theophilus (1:1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(c) the purpose can be a combination of purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among the suggestions offered for the purpose of Luke-Acts are the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) Luke-Acts was prepared as a trial brief for Paul’s first appearance before the judgment seat of Caesar. It explained the forerunner and founding personality of Christianity and showed its general relationship to Judaism, and then proceeded to outline the pattern of its spread from Judaea throughout the rest of the Roman Empire. The fact that Acts portrays the relationship between Christians and Roman rulers in a good light could corroborate this suggestion. Theophilus could have been Paul’s trial lawyer. “Most excellent” (Luke 1:3) could be a title of address for such a dignitary (Acts 23:26; 24:3; 26:25).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE WITNESS OF ACTS TO THE KERYGMA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-witness-of-acts-to-the-kerygma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-witness-of-acts-to-the-kerygma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE WITNESS OF ACTS TO THE KERYGMA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Theories about an evolutionary origin for the Christian religion present a fundamental line of inquiry. The body of literature called the “New Testament” supposedly shows stages that process passed through. If the New Testament does not actually represent the original Christian preaching, what really did comprise their message, and how can we recover that primitive gospel?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts of Apostles, written after the life of Jesus of Nazareth, presupposes incidents in his ministry. It purports to be a history of men divinely appointed to establish a religion based on these incidents. The record of their “acts” includes accounts of what they said as well. Such a record should prove valuable in discovering the content of the earliest “preaching,” the kerygma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF ROMANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-romans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF ROMANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;With the exception of Luke 20:16, Romans is the book that most uses the Pauline expression God forbid (μὴ γένοιτο, mē genoito): 3:4, 6, 31; 6:2, 15; 7:7, 13; 9:14; 11:1, 11. It appears also in 1 Corinthians 6:15; Galatians 2:17; 3:21; cp. 6:14.*&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The longest list of individuals saluted (16:3-16). In Colossians the long list of names&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;consists of saluters (4:7-14, five; while Romans contains seven—eight including Tertius).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRONOLOGY OF THE LIFE OF PAUL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chronology-of-the-life-of-paul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/chronology-of-the-life-of-paul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRONOLOGY OF THE LIFE OF PAUL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Third missionary tour&#x9;                                 2¼ +&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Caesarean imprisonment                                                 2 years&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Roman imprisonment                                                      2 years (Acts 28:30)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Death&#x9;67&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: A.D. 34-49 = 17 years by including the years at the ends of the period.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORIGIN OF THE ROMAN CHURCH(ES)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/origin-of-the-roman-churches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/origin-of-the-roman-churches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ORIGIN OF THE ROMAN CHURCH(ES)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At least three household churches existed in Rome by the time Paul wrote to the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;imperial city: Romans 16:5, 14, 15.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early churches outside Palestine had varying proportions of the following groups:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jews, proselytes, God-fearers (σεβόμενοι, sebomenoi), Gentiles/Greeks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Converts from Pentecost: Acts 2:10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. Jews returning after the relaxation of Claudius’ edict of expulsion in A.D. 49&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Claudius died in A.D. 54): Romans 16:3-5a and Acts 18:2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RECENSIONS OF ROMANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/recensions-of-romans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/recensions-of-romans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RECENSIONS OF ROMANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Placements of the doxology (16:25-27 in the standard English text)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;At end&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.&#x9;After 15:33&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c.&#x9;After 14:23 (some also at end); see Greek apparatus for the New Testament in loco.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d.&#x9;Omitted altogether&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Placements of the benediction (16:20b in the standard English text)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;At 16:20; then Tertius adds a note and Paul closes the letter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.&#x9;At 16:24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c.&#x9;In both places&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d. &#x9;After 16:27&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROMANS: ORIGIN, DATE, AND DESTINATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/romans-origin-date-and-destination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/romans-origin-date-and-destination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ROMANS: ORIGIN, DATE, AND DESTINATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Origin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul wrote Romans after the acquaintances previously known from elsewhere had moved to the imperial city (16:3-16), after he had preached from Jerusalem to Illyricum (Romans 15:19, cp. 23), while he was in route to Jerusalem with the offering for the saints (Romans 15:25-28, 31), and at a time when he anticipated preaching the gospel in Spain (15:24, 28-29). According to Acts 19:21-22, while Paul was still in Ephesus on the third tour, he planned to go to Jerusalem and then to Rome. On this third tour, Paul organized the collection for the poor Christians in Jerusalem (cp. Acts 20:4; 21:15; 1 Corinthians 16:1-9;     2 Corinthians 8-9). Having left Ephesus after the riot, Paul journeyed north through Troas, across through Macedonia, and down to Greece (20:1-6) before returning through Macedonia and down the east coast of the Aegean Sea to Miletus and on to Palestine. He had not planned to minister again in Asia (Acts 20:25, 38). His three-month stay in Corinth during this trip would have given him time to compose Romans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EXTRA NAMES IN THE HEADINGS OF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/extra-names-in-the-headings-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/extra-names-in-the-headings-of/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EXTRA NAMES IN THE HEADINGS OF&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE PAULINE EPISTLES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Possible significances of added names in Paul’s salutations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bearer of the letter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amanuensis (*)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prominent people with Paul at the time of writing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assistants present with Paul at the founding of the church he is writing to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Co-authors&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Basic Data&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Book&#x9;Names in Heading&#x9;Relevant Notations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romans                                                      &#x9;Phoebe = bearer ? (16:1-2)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*Tertius = scribe (16:22)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians&#x9;Sosthenes&#x9;*a scribe used (16:21);&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IMPLICATIONS OF THE UNITY OF BIBLICAL MATERIALS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/implications-of-the-unity-of-biblical-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/implications-of-the-unity-of-biblical-materials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IMPLICATIONS OF THE UNITY OF BIBLICAL MATERIALS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Jeremiah as a test case&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. New Testament books where the unity issue has been raised&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.   Matthew&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.   Mark&#x9;&#x9;Source theories&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.   Luke&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D.   Acts&#x9;1-12,   13-28&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;E.   Romans&#x9;1-14,   15-16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*F.   2 Corinthians&#x9;1-9,   10-13   (See “Reconstruction of the Fourfold Corinthians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Correspondence Theory”)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;G.   Philippians&#x9;1-2,   3:1-3:19/4:1/4:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;H.   1 Peter&#x9;1-3,   4-5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.     Revelation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REASONS FOR THE “MOOD SHIFT” BETWEEN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/reasons-for-the-mood-shift-between/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/reasons-for-the-mood-shift-between/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;REASONS FOR THE “MOOD SHIFT” BETWEEN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 CORINTHIANS 9 AND 10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change of situation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the process of writing, Paul received word that the situation in Corinth had taken a turn for the worse again. As a result, the rest of the letter has more of a stern character.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Different letter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 1-9 represents a substantial part of the fourth Corinthian correspondence, while 10-13 represents part of a lost “severe letter” written between what we know as 1 and 2 Corinthians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RECONSTRUCTION OF THE FOURFOLD CORINTHIAN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/reconstruction-of-the-fourfold-corinthian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/reconstruction-of-the-fourfold-corinthian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RECONSTRUCTION OF THE FOURFOLD CORINTHIAN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CORRESPONDENCE THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians 6:14-7:1 does not form the whole of the “previous letter.” It is not a unit that can stand on its own, so its beginning and end have been removed and then inserted where it does not fit very well. The reasons for considering these verses an interpolation are (1) that they do not tie closely to the surrounding context and (2) that if they are omitted, the flow of thought is smooth enough that a reader would not notice anything was missing. In relation to the first reason, we wonder why a redactor would put it in at this point if it does not fit with the context very well, especially after he had excised it from its original setting in a fashion that does not form a unit. If a redactor could insert a paragraph that was loosely connected, an author himself could do the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE “PREVIOUS LETTER” TO THE CORINTHIANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-previous-letter-to-the-corinthians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-previous-letter-to-the-corinthians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE “PREVIOUS LETTER” TO THE CORINTHIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;List of Views&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. There was no previous letter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. There was a previous letter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now lost&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Partially included in 2 Corinthians 6:14-7:1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. There was a Previous Letter: 1 Corinthians 5:9-13.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;Ἔγραψα [egrapsa, “I wrote”] is a normal past-tense aorist in 5:9.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;&amp;ldquo;My letter&amp;rdquo; (5:9) sounds like a more distant reference (literally “I-have-written/I-wrote to you in the[my] letter”; ἔγραψα ὑμῖν ἐν τῇ ἐπιστολῇ [egrapsa hymīn en tēi epistolēi]).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DESTINATION AND DATE OF GALATIANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/destination-and-date-of-galatians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/destination-and-date-of-galatians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DESTINATION AND DATE OF GALATIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main introductory problems associated with Galatians are its destination and date. Determining the destination affects the time frame for the date. Since the readers are called “Galatians” (3:1; cp. 1:2), the question is whether Paul uses the term to mean (1) the ethnic group of Gauls, who gave their name to the ancient Hellenistic kingdom, or (2) the citizens of the Roman province of Galatia. The “northern Galatia” theory refers to the first option; the “southern Galatia” theory indicates the second. By that time the Roman province extended farther south to include Lystra, Derbe, and Iconium, cities Paul and Barnabas evangelized on the first missionary tour. Northern Galatia was a less extensive territory in the mountainous inland area around Pessinus and Ancyra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HISTORICAL BACKGROUND BEHIND GALATIANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/historical-background-behind-galatians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/historical-background-behind-galatians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HISTORICAL BACKGROUND BEHIND GALATIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts&#x9;Secular Sources&#x9;                     Galatians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pilate deposed?  A.D. 36&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;death of Stephen (Acts 7)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul leads a generalized persecution of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the church (9:1-2; 26:9-12).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pilate deposed?  A.D. 36&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;is converted at Damascus&#x9;&#x9;conversion of Paul (1:15-17)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(9:3-25; 22:3-16; 26:13-20a)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pilate deposed?  A.D. 36&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 years in Arabia (1:18)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;goes to Jerusalem by way of Damascus,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul travels to Jerusalem, feared by &#x9;     &#x9;     stays with Peter 15 days, sees no&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PAUL’S VISITS TO JERUSALEM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/pauls-visits-to-jerusalem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/pauls-visits-to-jerusalem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PAUL’S VISITS TO JERUSALEM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Events in Galatians&#x9;Events in Acts&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:16-17&#x9;Paul is converted, goes to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arabia, then back to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Damascus (3 years)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:18-19&#x9;Paul goes to Jerusalem, sees&#x9;9:26-30&#x9;Visits Jerusalem, where Barnabas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cephas, stays 15 days, but&#x9;&#x9;    brings him to the Christians—&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sees no other apostle except&#x9;&#x9;    to the apostles. Paul disputes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;James.&#x9;&#x9;    with Grecian Jews. His life is&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;threatened and he goes to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tarsus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:21&#x9;Paul goes to Syria and Cilicia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACCEPTING THE PAULINE CORPUS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/accepting-the-pauline-corpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/accepting-the-pauline-corpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ACCEPTING THE PAULINE CORPUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hebrews&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Titus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Timothy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;modern order of&#x9;&#x9;2 Thessalonians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;being questioned&#x9;3&#x9;1 Thessalonians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philemon&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Colossians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philippians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Galatians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romans&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a distinction between progressivism and evolution, the one being forward movement while the latter is simply modification. Progressivism in the 1800s expressed itself in post-millennialism and in biblical criticism in the Tübingen school, which denied to Paul all his letters except four: Romans, 1 Corinthians, 2 Corinthians, and Galatians. German rationalism postulated a long upward development pattern that brought about the Christian literary canon as late as A.D. 180. In the 1900s, this extreme gave way to a more reasonable approach that did not see a need for 150 years to develop the New Testament documents. Some, like John A. T. Robinson went to the opposite extreme by saying that all the New Testament books could have existed by A.D. 70. World War I smashed the onward-and-upward hopefulness about humankind, and led to pre-millennialism eschatologically and a turn toward less extreme critical viewpoints in New Testament studies. The evolutionary framework is still presupposed, but Paul is usually allowed to have at least nine of the letters that ancient Christian writers assigned to him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF EPHESIANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-ephesians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-ephesians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF EPHESIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;distinctive expressions include&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“in the heavenlies [ἐν τοῖς οὐρανοῖς]”: 1:3, 20; 2:6; 3:10; 6:12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“to the praise of the/his glory (of his grace)”: 1:6, 12, 14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“the new man [ὁ καινὸς ἄνθρωπος]”: 2:15; 4:25 (cp. ὁ νεὸς ἄνθρωπος in Colossians 3:10)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Along with Colossians (1:26-27; 2:2; 4:3) and Romans (16:25), Ephesians uses mystery (μυστήριον, mystērion) to refer to the previously unrevealed fact that Gentiles as Gentiles have access to fellowship with God through faith: 1:9; 3:3-9; 6:19. (See notations on Colossians.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COLOSSIANS, PHILEMON, AND EPHESIANS SENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/colossians-philemon-and-ephesians-sent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/colossians-philemon-and-ephesians-sent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COLOSSIANS, PHILEMON, AND EPHESIANS SENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SIMULTANEOUSLY  (plus the letter to the Laodecians?)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All come from an imprisonment: Ephesians 3:1; 4:1; Colossians 4:3, 18; Philemon 1, 9-10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The subject matter and style of language in Colossians and Ephesians are closer than any other two epistles of Paul.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.  Household teaching: Ephesians 5:21-6:9; Colossians 3:18-4:1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.  Putting the members to death&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The bearers are connected.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6:21  Ephesians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tychicus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:7  Colossians  4:9&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Onesimus&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOODSPEED’S ARGUMENTS AGAINST THE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/goodspeeds-arguments-against-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/goodspeeds-arguments-against-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GOODSPEED’S ARGUMENTS AGAINST THE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PAULINE AUTHORSHIP OF EPHESIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians reflects no definite, localized, historical situation which it is intended to meet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians does represent a historical situation. Tychicus is the bearer, who will tell a definite readership about the affairs of Paul. The lack of detailed historical and geographical data is offset by its probable encyclical destination and its hortatory-doctrinal purpose. Furthermore, since Ephesians was published contemporary with Colossians and borne by the same messengers, historical details were not of such importance, being available from the bearers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MATTERS THAT AFFECT STYLE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/matters-that-affect-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/matters-that-affect-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MATTERS THAT AFFECT STYLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Higher critics do not allow a wide enough range of style variance in New Testament authors. The items below have implication for greater variety in style.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Subject matter&#x9;&#x9;Complex problems tend to cause complex presentations. Certain (topic)&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;subjects call for special vocabulary. What we are trying to combat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;determines terminology: “faith and works” (Judaism), “fullness” (Gnosticism), priesthood (new subject). For the sake of meeting the minds of the ones we want to address, we use the vocabulary of the other in reference to our own subject so there can be a correlation of parts of thought systems, or functional equivalents. Becoming/being a Christian we might call a natural “high” because of the modern drug scene. Vocabulary generated by such circumstances will be peculiar to the circumstance (cp. “circumcision of the heart,” “fullness of the godhead,” “armor of salvation”).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NEW TESTAMENT STUDIES AND THE USE OF AMANUENSES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/new-testament-studies-and-the-use-of-amanuenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/new-testament-studies-and-the-use-of-amanuenses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NEW TESTAMENT STUDIES AND THE USE OF AMANUENSES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The majority of New Testament writings are letters, so we expect them to reflect practices in first-century letter writing. One custom was using an amanuensis, a stenographer who wrote down the contents. Biblical studies do not give this factor much attention even though New Testament writers used amanuenses. The oversight seems unusual to us today since most of us in the Western world write our own correspondence. If we do employ a secretary, it is primarily for computer skills. We are accustomed to reproducing by typeset, copiers, or computer printers. But ancient writers had to use different methods. If the work of an amanuensis can impact New Testament studies, we should allow that to affect our thinking where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PLACE OF WRITING THE PRISON EPISTLES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/place-of-writing-the-prison-epistles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/place-of-writing-the-prison-epistles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PLACE OF WRITING THE PRISON EPISTLES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The criteria for the prison-epistles imprisonment are (1) a lengthy imprisonment with (2) an expected release (3) where Onesimus would have access to Paul.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pro                                &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Con&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ROME&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul  was  under  house  arrest  and &#x9; Paul requests housing to be prepared in&#x9;could receive  guests like Onesimus.&#x9;Colossae   (but   Paul    will    soon    be&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;released   from  the   Roman   imprison-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ment).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A known imprisonment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was  there a  Colossae after A.D.  60?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USE OF AMANUENSES IN THE NEW TESTAMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/use-of-amanuenses-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/use-of-amanuenses-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;USE OF AMANUENSES IN THE NEW TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Overview)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Basic Data Regarding Amanuenses&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul used amanuenses                                    Paragraphs explained as Pauline&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;postscripts&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Romans 16:22&#x9;16:25-27 after 15:33; 16:20 (21-23)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;1 Corinthians 16:21&#x9;16:21-23* after 16:19-20&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;2 Corinthians&#x9;13:(13-)14 after 13:12 (-13)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D.&#x9;Galatians (6:11-18?)&#x9;6:11-18?*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;E.&#x9;Ephesians&#x9;6:23-24?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;F.&#x9;Philippians&#x9;4:21-23&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;G.&#x9;Colossians 4:18&#x9;4:18*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;H.&#x9;1 Thessalonians&#x9;5:28&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;2 Thessalonians 3:17&#x9;3:17-18* after 3:16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J.&#x9;1 Timothy&#x9;6:21b&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FRAGMENTING PHILIPPIANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/fragmenting-philippians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/fragmenting-philippians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FRAGMENTING PHILIPPIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Mood shift between 3:1 and 3:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.  Basic questions: if a segment does not fit its context, why would an interpolator put it there; if it does fit its context, why regard it as an interpolation?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.  The interpolation in this case (as well as the cases of 2 Corinthians 6:14-7:1 and        2 Corinthians 10-13) does not form a unit. It is difficult to tell where such a document would end (3:19?; 4:1?; 4:3?).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PHILIPPIANS: THE TIME OF WRITING</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/philippians-the-time-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/philippians-the-time-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PHILIPPIANS: THE TIME OF WRITING&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WITHIN THE ROMAN IMPRISONMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:12-14: Enough time for Paul to influence the praetorian guard and others because of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;their exposure to him while he was in prison&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:22-26; 2:24: Near the end of the imprisonment because Paul anticipates release from the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;present circumstance&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;christir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF COLOSSIANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-colossians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-colossians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF COLOSSIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Has the greatest number who send salutations of any New Testament writing. Philemon has a goodly number as well. Romans has by far the greatest number of saluted people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only book to refer to a Christian writing that is probably no longer (evidently) extant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only book where a New Testament writer adopts the Gnostics’ pleroma, etc., as an image for understanding the role of Christ&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNOSTICISM AND THE BOOK OF COLOSSIANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/gnosticism-and-the-book-of-colossians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/gnosticism-and-the-book-of-colossians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GNOSTICISM AND THE BOOK OF COLOSSIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;spirit = good&#x9;Evil/sin was defined as a kind of being/&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dualism&#x9;“stuff” rather than a way of acting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;matter = evil&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mankind is a mixture of spirit and matter and&#x9;Two attitudes toward  the  flesh  were  then&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;therefore of good and evil.&#x9;adopted:  asceticism,  which  deprived   the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;flesh;  and   hedonism,  which   satiated  the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;flesh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salvation became the  task  of  “unmixing”  the&#x9;In   Christianity   the   task   is    overcoming&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the evil and good in man by unmixing the spirit&#x9;separation    between    persons    and   other&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORTHODOX CHRISTIANITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/orthodox-christianity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/orthodox-christianity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ORTHODOX CHRISTIANITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A prevalent idea in current religious studies is that Christianity as we know it became associated by way of historical process with the Roman government. The line of descent from Jesus that history preserved was that line of development, both as to its viewpoints and its literature. Petrine Christianity as represented by the Judaizers was the main contrast to Pauline Christianity and its international universalism. Government influence suppressed and destroyed the writings of “heretics” as measured by the preserved standard, and generally disenfranchised its people. So, the understanding of Jesus as well as the canonical literature that has descended to us results from historical processes and no more represent a “legitimate,” or true, understanding of Jesus than other traditions did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE COLOSSIAN HERESY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-colossian-heresy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-colossian-heresy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE COLOSSIAN HERESY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. A combination of doctrines in one group, rather than two or three doctrines held by&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;different groups in the Colossian church&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;The epistle itself contains no hint that the author writes to more than one group.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Historical criticism depreciates needless multiplication of persons or events. The simpler explanation more likely holds true (law of parsimony).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;The apostle moves back and forth from the elements of one teaching to the elements of the other, which he would presumably not do if writing to separate groups. Note especially the connecting particles between verses that appear to refer to separate heresies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE ORIGIN OF GNOSTICISM AND ITS BEARING ON THE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-origin-of-gnosticism-and-its-bearing-on-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-origin-of-gnosticism-and-its-bearing-on-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE ORIGIN OF GNOSTICISM AND ITS BEARING ON THE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;DATE OF COLOSSIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do know about a highly developed form of Gnosticism in the second century, but that fact has no bearing on the date and content of Colossians as a Pauline production in the first century.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gnosticism involved a largely secret-knowledge form of religion. It may have taken a while before Gnosticism was openly known to have certain features in its written or otherwise available representations. A secret society might not be inclined to write its doctrine early.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SEQUENCE OF THE THESSALONIAN CORRESPONDENCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sequence-of-the-thessalonian-correspondence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sequence-of-the-thessalonian-correspondence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SEQUENCE OF THE THESSALONIAN CORRESPONDENCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. 2 Thessalonians follows 1 Thessalonians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;So listed in all the ancient canons (even Marcion’s)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The New Testament letters, however, are always arranged by length from longest to shortest per author. Curious that second (and third) epistles to the same destination should always be shorter than the first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;References in 2 Thessalonians apparently to a previous letter: 2:2, 15; 3:17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The references could be to a lost letter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THESSALONIANS TIME LINE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/thessalonians-time-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/thessalonians-time-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THESSALONIANS TIME LINE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;spring 51 (or 50)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul’s arrival in Corinth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;summer 51 (or 50)&#x9;&#x9;1 Thessalonians is written soon after Paul&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;comes to Corinth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June 52 (or 51)&#x9;&#x9;Gallio becomes proconsul in Corinth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gallio refers questions to the emperor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul’s many days (Acts 18:18)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul before Gallio (Acts 18:12-17—&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;shortly   after   Gallio’s   proconsulship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;begins and near the end of 18 months)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August 53&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Claudius’ 12th year of tribunicial power&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRACING PAUL’S MOVEMENTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/tracing-pauls-movements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/tracing-pauls-movements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRACING PAUL’S MOVEMENTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BEHIND THE THESSALONIAN CORRESPONDENCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 17:1&#x9;Paul comes to Thessalonica.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;17:2&#x9;Paul spends three Sabbaths there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;17:10&#x9;After a disturbance created by unbelieving Jews, the believers send Paul and&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Silas on to Berea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;17:13&#x9;After another uproar at Berea led  by the same unbelieving Jews in&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thessalonica, they send Paul toward the sea while Timothy and Silas remain &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;in Berea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;17:15&#x9;Paul, having been conducted to Athens, sends word back with his escorts to&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CLUSTER OF POSITIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/a-cluster-of-positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/a-cluster-of-positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A CLUSTER OF POSITIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Un)conscious desire to avoid the demand made on a person’s life if these materials are&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;true&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anti-supernatural bias (note distinctions between atheistic, agnostic, deistic, neo-&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;orthodox)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deistic impulse of a Newtonian universe shows itself in theological liberalism (the “older modernism”) that is akin to ancient Sadduceeism. This impulse correlates with (a) the stress on “scientific” method, taken to mean something that eliminates anything supernatural. There is a confusion between what a method can address and the idea that only those things exist which that method can address. The deistic impulse tries to foster an aura of philosophical legitimacy by claiming that (b) miracle would be a contradiction of natural law. The claim confuses contrary and contradictory, and different from opposite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>METHOD IN LITERARY CRITICISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/method-in-literary-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/method-in-literary-criticism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;METHOD IN LITERARY CRITICISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scholars look at a number of phenomena in Pauline literature to assess whether Paul actually wrote the piece: (a) words (new words not in Paul, Pauline words not in this writing, Pauline words used in non-Pauline ways), (b) syntax (complex vs. simple sentence structure, Hebraisms and other solecisms), (c) topics addressed, and (d) mood of the writing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What control questions need to be asked on literary bases for verdicts on authorship?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PASTORALS: DATE, DESTINATION, SEQUENCE, PURPOSE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/pastorals-date-destination-sequence-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/pastorals-date-destination-sequence-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PASTORALS: DATE, DESTINATION, SEQUENCE, PURPOSE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Date:&#x9;Fluctuates according to the dating of Paul’s first imprisonment in Rome; not&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;later than A.D. 67&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Order:&#x9;1 Timothy,        Titus,         2 Timothy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Destination:&#x9;Ephesus,            Crete,         Ephesus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purpose:&#x9;To reinforce Timothy’s and Titus’s leadership as to legitimacy and pattern&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To prepare for the time after Paul’s soon departure (cp. 2 Peter 1:13-15)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Timothy 3:14: “I am writing these things to you . . . that you may know&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOURCES OF THE PAULINE MATERIAL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sources-of-the-pauline-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sources-of-the-pauline-material/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOURCES OF THE PAULINE MATERIAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introductory Guidelines&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kinds of sources found in Pauline material are not only those that appear in literature generally, but those that fit the nature of scripture. This observation is not meant to prejudice research but to point out a consistency Christians expect to find in this study. So the first guideline is that (a) scripture is like what God himself would exhale. Presumably 2 Timothy 3:16 teaches that scripture as such is God-breathed as to its intended content. Sources and processes of origination for Pauline material correlate with the nature of scripture that issues from them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PROBLEM OF THE PASTORALS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-problem-of-the-pastorals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-problem-of-the-pastorals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PROBLEM OF THE PASTORALS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Historical Problem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those who  reject  the  Pauline  authorship  of  the  pastoral  epistles  (1  Timoty,  2&#xA;Timothy, Titus ) contend that there is no time in Paul’s life as recorded in Acts when he could have written these epistles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We cannot show, however, that the end of The Acts account is also the end of Paul’s life. Arguments for a release from Paul’s Roman imprisonment in the closing chapter of Acts are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF HEBREWS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-hebrews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-hebrews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF HEBREWS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the only canonical New Testament epistle without any statement of authorship (John’s three epistles do not very clearly identify their author either.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;has the most extensive use of the Old Testament numerically and proportionately of any New Testament book. Every major point in the book is based on an Old Testament reference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the only New Testament book to develop the priesthood theme in connection with Jesus&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EXTERNAL TESTIMONY TO THE AUTHORSHIP OF HEBREWS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/external-testimony-to-the-authorship-of-hebrews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/external-testimony-to-the-authorship-of-hebrews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EXTERNAL TESTIMONY TO THE AUTHORSHIP OF HEBREWS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Presentation of Evidence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Early Christian writers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eastern tradition&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;Direct statement regarding authorship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1)&#x9;Pantaenus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order of time, Pantaenus is the earliest witness to the Eastern Tradition about the authorship of Hebrews. He flourished about A.D. 180 as president of the catechetical school in Alexandria, Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Photius says that Pantaenus heard men who had seen the apostles.   Eusebius tells us that Julian, bishop of Alexandria, sent Pantaenus eastward as far as India as a missionary because of his piety and scholarship (Ecclesiastical History 5:10). Alexander, bishop of Alexandria about A.D. 212, highly commended him. (See Eusebius’ Ecclesiastical History 6:14.) Eusebius himself and Jerome also speak of him as a learned, influential Christian leader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HEBREWS AND THE ALEXANDRIAN ORIGIN OR DESTINY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/hebrews-and-the-alexandrian-origin-or-destiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/hebrews-and-the-alexandrian-origin-or-destiny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HEBREWS AND THE ALEXANDRIAN ORIGIN OR DESTINY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The only reasons for associating Hebrews with Alexandria are that (1) the earliest favorable attestation comes from there and that (2) it supposedly uses the allegorical method of interpretation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philo joined Greek philosophy and Jewish revelation by allegorical method. He stood at&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the head of a line of scholars who did the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hebrew writer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allegorical interpretation is like using the Acts 27 trip to Rome as an allegory about life with its rough seas, throwing sins overboard, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HEBREWS’ RHETORICAL STYLE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/hebrews-rhetorical-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/hebrews-rhetorical-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HEBREWS’ RHETORICAL STYLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hebrews uses the Old Testament text more than any other New Testament book does. (Matthew is next.) It has the longest Old Testament quotation of any book in the New Testament: 8:8-12 &amp;gt; Jeremiah 31:31-34.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author makes every major point from an Old Testament quotation. There is a deliberate exegetical pattern (especially Psalm 110:4). This pattern represents profound insight in exegesis rather than allegorical method of interpretation, as some suppose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERNAL EVIDENCE ON CRITICAL MATTERS: HEBREWS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/internal-evidence-on-critical-matters-hebrews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/internal-evidence-on-critical-matters-hebrews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERNAL EVIDENCE ON CRITICAL MATTERS: HEBREWS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Authorship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hebrews makes no claim to authorship. Certain points about the book may have&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;relevance to the authorship question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;2:3-4: “How will we escape if we neglect such a great salvation, which having at the first been spoken through the Lord, was confirmed to us by them that heard, God also bearing witness with them both by signs and wonders and by many powers and by gifts of the Holy Spirit according to his own will.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTERPRETATION IN HEBREWS CONTRASTED TO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpretation-in-hebrews-contrasted-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/interpretation-in-hebrews-contrasted-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTERPRETATION IN HEBREWS CONTRASTED TO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE ALLEGORICAL METHOD OF PHILO&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Historical backgrounds are important because they illuminate scripture. They often confirm the biblical record and may help prove its trustworthiness on things that can be tested. So we view historical backgrounds as a valuable resource. This presentation, however, stresses another observation. Like all sources of information, historical backgrounds misused can harm rather than help biblical studies. It can detract from hermeneutical and apologetic concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SKETCH OF PROPOSITIONS AND PRESUPPOSITIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sketch-of-propositions-and-presuppositions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sketch-of-propositions-and-presuppositions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SKETCH OF PROPOSITIONS AND PRESUPPOSITIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;on the use of 2 Samuel 7:14 in Hebrews 1:5b&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;While 2 Samuel 7:14 must refer to Solomon because Solomon so understood it (1 Kings 6:11-13; 8:17-21), it cannot refer exclusively to him since the context speaks of an eternal seed (2 Samuel 7:16).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II.&#x9;By the nature of the case, there can be only one universal eternal kingdom.  So Daniel 2:(35) 44; Psalm 89:27 + 4, 36; and therefore the universal kingdom of Psalm 2 (first quotation) and the eternal kingdom of Psalm 110 (last quotation) must all refer to the same thing as the eternal kingdom of 2 Samuel 7 (as well as Psalm 89; Isaiah 9; etc.).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO JAMES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-james/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-james/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO JAMES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. External Citation and Authorship Evidence (see Salmon, pp. 473ff.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Origen is the earliest writer to refer to its words by name and to cite it as scripture (Commentary on John 7:1).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Eusebius puts it among the disputed books but accepted it for himself (comm. in Psalm 56—work of an apostle—and Psalm 100 as scripture), referring to it as the first of the catholic epistles. Eusebius notes that jew ancients quoted it, but (Salmon) Eusebius may have overlooked less direct allusions to it: Salmon notes Shepherd of Hermas; Clement of Rome.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WISDOM LITERATURE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/wisdom-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/wisdom-literature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WISDOM LITERATURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The New Testament contains several literary genres:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;gospels (Matthew, Mark, Luke, John)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;history (Acts)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;epistles (Romans-Hebrews, 1 Peter-3 John)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;apocalyptic (Revelation)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;wisdom literature (Sermon on the Mount, James, Jude).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Content&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wisdom literature has some affinities with law. They both deal with human behavior and so use the imperative mood extensively. Wisdom, however, is a larger category than law even as advice is larger than commandment. The accompanying diagram shows their relationship. Advice vs. commandment, opinion vs. faith and fact, procedure vs. fundamental morality represent distinctions between the two types of material. Advice and commandment differ as to intent and scope. The advice in wisdom literature is not interested just in what&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 1 PETER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-1-peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-1-peter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 1 PETER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.&#x9;Destination Geographical&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;The whole of Asia Minor except in Cilicia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 Peter 1:1 addresses all the geographical names of Roman provinces in Asia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Minor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Provincial Galatia included Lycaonia and thoe parts of Phrygia and Pisidia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;that did not belong to Asia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Not addressed to Cilicia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;not because overlooked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cilicia was associated with Syrian Antioch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Lycia and Pamphylia are not mentioned. They were two small districts whose early church history is vague (Acts 24:25), especially since they were not organized into an independent province until A.D. 74. Biggs says that they were still, in a sense, part of Galatia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 PETER AND JUDE IN PARALLEL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/2-peter-and-jude-in-parallel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/2-peter-and-jude-in-parallel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 PETER AND JUDE IN PARALLEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:10 &#x9;Ταῦτα γὰρ ποιοῦντες οὐ μὴ πταίσητέ ποτε.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:12&#x9;Διὸ μελλήσω ἀεὶ ὑμᾶς ὑπομιμνῄ-σκειν περὶ τούτων, καίπερ εἰδότας&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2:1&#x9;. . . ἐν ὑμῖν ἔσονται ψευδοδιδάσκα-λοι, οἵτινες παρεισάξουσιν αἰρέσεις ἀπωλείας,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;καὶ τὸν ἀγοράσαντο αὐτοὺς δεσπό-την ἀρνούμενοι, . . .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2:2&#x9;καὶ πολλοὶ ἐξακολουθήσουσιν αὐ-τῶν ταῖς ἀσελγείαις, . . .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2:3&#x9;καὶ ἐν πλεονεξίᾳ πλαστοῖς λόγοις ὑμᾶς ἐμπορεύσονται,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;οἷς τὸ κρίμα ἔκπαλαι οὐκ ἀργεῖ, . . .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2:4&#x9;Εἰ γὰρ ὁ θεός ἀγγέλων ἁμαρτησάν-των οὐκ ἐφείσατο, ἀλλὰ σειραῖς ζόφου ταρταρώσας παρέδωκεν εἰς κρίσιν τηρουμένους, (cp. 2:9; 3:7)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 2 PETER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-2-peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-2-peter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 2 PETER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No epistle of the New Testament (Thiessen) “has earlier or stronger attestation than 1 Peter,” while (Moorehead) “the Second Epistle of Peter comes to us with less historical support of its genuineness than any other book of the New Testament.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Attestations to the Existence of 2 Peter by Points of Resemblance and Quotation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;Shepherd of Hermas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. &#x9;1 Clement&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;2 Clement&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D. &#x9;Didache&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 1 JOHN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-1-john/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-1-john/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 1 JOHN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Authorship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.  External&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Earliest allusion in Polycarp (Ad Phil. 7)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Perhaps Papias (Eusebius’ Ecclesiastical History 3:39:3, 17)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Coincidences of language in Justin, Barnabas, Hermas, Clement of Rome&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Clement of Alexandria, Origen, and Tertullian cite it as John’s.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.  Internal evidence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; 1 John, 2 John, 3 John, and Hebrews are the four anonymous New Testament epistles.  The opening of I John, like the close of Hebrews, tells something of the author.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; An eyewitness: “What we have seen with our own eyes” (1:1)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Authoritative condemnation of error&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 2 JOHN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-2-john/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-2-john/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 2 JOHN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Authorship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.  External&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The external attestation to 2 John is not so strong as that for 1 John. Absence of citations from the book may have been due to its subject matter. It is significant that the objections to apostolic authorship come from the later Christian writers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.  Internal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The term “the Elder” (v. 1) is appropriate for any older man of any office, especially since by the time of its writing, the apostle John was probably the only living apostle. “Elder” among the Jews was applied to leaders at (1) the synagogue level, but also at (2) the city level and (3) the national level. By analogy it appears that “elder” could have been applied to local units but also to the whole “nation” (1 Peter 5:1; 2 John 1; cp. Philemon 9?). So it could designate the ultimate leadership within any level (John, Peter, Paul?). The expression “apostles and elders” (Acts 15:2) is significant in this respect. Could it mean elders in general with the apostles as specially marked among them? A slightly different arrangement terminologically would have the apostles as “apostles” of the universal church and at the same time (some of) the “elders” of the Jerusalem church. The passage in Eusebius that contains Papias’ statement (Ecclesiastical History 3:39:4) introduces all the apostles as “elders.” So a distinction between the apostle John and an elder John is not necessary in view of Papias’ use of the words. Note also 1 Peter 5:1.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 3 JOHN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-3-john/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/critical-introduction-to-3-john/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRITICAL INTRODUCTION TO 3 JOHN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Authorship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is uncertain whether there is any evidence for 3 John ‘s being cited before the third century, if the Muratorian Canon speaks only of two epistles of John. This lack of citation and mention is understandable because of its brevity and the character of its contents. What was said of “the Elder” in connection with 1 John applies here also.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. Destination&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OBSERVATIONS ON REVELATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/observations-on-revelation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/observations-on-revelation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OBSERVATIONS ON REVELATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Literary Form&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9; Large number of doxological passages: 1:5-6; 4:8, 11; 5:9-10, 12, 13; 7:10, 12;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11:15, 17-18; 12:10-12; 15:3-4; 19:1-2, 5, 6-8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Simple vocabulary&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Numerological interest&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Threes: three measures of barley (6:6); three woes of three angels (8:13) = three plagues? (9:18); three unclean spirits (16:13); three gates on each side of the new Jerusalem (21:13); a third of the trees, sea, creatures, ships (8:8-9); a third of the rivers (8:10-11); a third of the sun, moon, stars not shining for a third of the day (8:12); a third of men (9:15); a third of the stars (12:4)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE SEVEN CHURCHES OF ASIA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-seven-churches-of-asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-seven-churches-of-asia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE SEVEN CHURCHES OF ASIA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;Literary Analysis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Length: the letters are approximately the same.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Unity with chapter 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2:1b = 1:16  &#x9;holds the seven stars in his right hand&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:12b-13a &#x9;walks in the midst of the seven golden candlesticks&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2:8b = 1:17b &#x9;the first and the last&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:18a &#x9;who was dead and lives again&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2:12b = 1:16b &#x9;the sword of my mouth (out of his mouth came a sharp two-&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;edged sword)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE SEVEN DAYS OF CONSUMMATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-seven-days-of-consummation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-seven-days-of-consummation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE SEVEN DAYS OF CONSUMMATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Part I: Recurring Elements&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recurring elements give clues to the common identity of elements that appear separately in the Book of Revelation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Earthquake (seven references)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.  Passages&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;6:12 (seal 6)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.&#x9;The sun became as black as burlap made out of hair.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.&#x9;The whole moon became blood.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c.&#x9;The stars in the sky fell to the earth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d.&#x9;The sky was removed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;e.&#x9;Every mountain and island moved out of their place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“BEYOND THE JORDAN”:  A PHRASE IN QUESTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/beyond-the-jordan-a-phrase-in-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/beyond-the-jordan-a-phrase-in-question/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“BEYOND THE JORDAN”:  A PHRASE IN QUESTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Beyond the Jordan” is a recurring biblical phrase that requires detailed study. It has relevance to locating unknown places like “the threshing floor of Atad” in Genesis 50:10, 11. In this reference “beyond the Jordan” occurs twice as an explanatory note for the position of the threshing floor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Questions arise as to whether the geographical note carries a consistent meaning, what that usage is, whether more than one consistency may be involved, and whether there are sufficient clear usages to determine its significance in ambiguous cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABBREVIATED TIME</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/abbreviated-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/abbreviated-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABBREVIATED TIME&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture does not readily adapt itself to the eons of time projected for accomplishing what evolutionary theory postulates, particularly in the biosphere. With varying degrees of likelihood, certain possibilities might push the date A.M. beyond the 4000 + B.C. minimum reading of scripture as in fiat creationism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;Possibilities for Elongation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;Time prior to Genesis 1:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Proposed relationships between Genesis 1:1 and 1:2ff&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. &#x9;Genesis 1:1 as a caption for the subsequent creation account&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BASIC CONCEPTS IN CREATIONIST-EVOLUTIONARY THOUGHT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/basic-concepts-in-creationist-evolutionary-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/basic-concepts-in-creationist-evolutionary-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BASIC CONCEPTS IN CREATIONIST-EVOLUTIONARY THOUGHT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Can we put in sequence the origin of reciprocating parts that are necessary for the viability of the organism and the parts themselves? If we can put their origin in sequence, they are not reciprocal. But the parts of plants and animals are in fact reciprocally interdependent unto viability. All parts have to be present and functional at all times. Disorganization destroys functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reciprocation is related to the concept of irreducible minimums, but it adds to it the origin of complexity and change between levels of complexity; hence, the mechanisms of change plus hoistic harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON EXTREME EVIL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-extreme-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-extreme-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON EXTREME EVIL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the problem of evil is not “easy” to answer, we can understand some things about how a degree of evil could occur in a holy God’s universe. But why an all-powerful God allows extreme evil to happen is more difficult. Scripture itself does not explain why he lets evil operate to the degree it does. Nevertheless, some observations make the issue more understandable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, whatever the reason(s), God does not place himself above the horrors of human suffering. It is beyond us how he can stand by and let atrocities take place before his very eyes when he could do something to stop them. We must remember, however, that the Father has not only stood by and let evil people mistreat other evil people and even abuse good people; he stood by and let sinful men crucify his own Son. No wonder Jesus cried out, “Why have you forsaken me?” (Matthew 27:46; etc., cp. Psalm 22:1). The human perspective of the dying divine Son is graphically evident in that “cry of dereliction.” That situation is even more difficult when he lets good men do evil, thinking they were doing him service (John 16:2). The crucifixion of Messiah involves both the Father standing by and the Son standing in the pain (John 18:6, etc.)—even though Jesus could have called twelve legions of angels to deliver him (Matthew 26:53). Whatever the reason, it is significant enough that deity went through it himself, not asking us to endure anything he was unwilling to suffer. Deity does not play favorites with his own, not even with his own Son, not even with himself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMPARING THEISM AND NATURALISM IN ORIGINS THEORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comparing-theism-and-naturalism-in-origins-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comparing-theism-and-naturalism-in-origins-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMPARING THEISM AND NATURALISM IN ORIGINS THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A formal similarity could be seen between “emergent evolution” and progressive creationism. The “emergent points” of emergent evolution might appear to correlate with the “intervention points” of progressive revelation. From a scientist’s viewpoint, we could consider the possibility that a connector in a progression is a natural one rather than a supernatural one, as previously supposed. We may not already know that a natural “force” exists for accomplishing this complexification. There is a difference, however, between keeping the natural category potential for explanation in such cases and making it the necessary category for explanation by disallowing the supernatural category in principle. The latter is what methodological naturalism does by assuming that its method, good in itself, somehow becomes the only legitimate method. Creationists, however, want to keep the supernatural category open after the initial creation of mass-energy. The formal similarity is limited because of the internal-external variable in the respective formats at their correlating junction points.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVIL IN THE WORLD: IS GOD HOLY?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/evil-in-the-world-is-god-holy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/evil-in-the-world-is-god-holy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EVIL IN THE WORLD: IS GOD HOLY?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction:  The Antilogism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.  &#x9;The origin of evil in the free will (intellect) of secondary agencies maintains the holiness of God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.  Persons involved&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Satan: John 8:44&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adam and Eve&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a.  Origin of sin among people: Romans 15:12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b.  Universality among people&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.  Why allow evil in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evil is a necessary potentiality of free will. God is not limited by the option, but&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FAITH AND SIGHT/SCIENCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/faith-and-sightscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/faith-and-sightscience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FAITH AND SIGHT/SCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Science deals with the experience of recurrent natural processes in the present. The technology science uses enhances the degree and kinds of sense perception in the natural realm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Limitations of Science&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Science cannot deal with universals or absolutes. It is subject to “the plague of particularity.” Science must take an inductive approach although it can form hypotheses, which are proposed universals suggested by observed particulars. The scientific method cannot deal with the absolutes of universal space or eternal time; hence, strictly speaking, it cannot see the big picture and cannot produce a worldview, because it is based on human experience, which is limited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GAMALIEL’S ARGUMENT FOR THE RESURRECTION OF JESUS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/gamaliels-argument-for-the-resurrection-of-jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/gamaliels-argument-for-the-resurrection-of-jesus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GAMALIEL’S ARGUMENT FOR THE RESURRECTION OF JESUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The resurrection of Jesus provides a plausible explanation for his followers’ continued and growing zeal for claiming him as the Messiah although he had been killed. Messiah indeed “abides forever” as per the Old Testament witness, but killing him does not necessarily eliminate him from that role if he resurrected, especially if he arose and ascended to God with the understanding that he was to return and pick up the Messianic work in whatever fashion that proves to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GENERAL SCHEMATIC FOR CHRISTIAN APOLOGETICS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/general-schematic-for-christian-apologetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/general-schematic-for-christian-apologetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GENERAL SCHEMATIC FOR CHRISTIAN APOLOGETICS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To locate the study of critical introduction to the Old Testament within the total picture of apologetics, we give here an abstract of the flow of apologetics. Instead of beginning with objective Christian evidences, as traditionally done, we include a prior step so that evangelism and apologetics become much the same kind of thing. Coming to conviction begins in the present with (1) our sense of need to be loved, to feel innocent and meaningful, and to have something to depend on. (2) The answer in Christianity comes as a cluster of historical events surrounding the person of Jesus the Messiah, especially his resurrection and the meaning of his life, death, and resurrection for human need in any age. (3) When we begin to carry out the principles of living that Christ taught and to receive in experience Christ’s love, the purposefulness of life, the freedom from guilt, and the confidence of living under One we can trust, we confirm subjectively that the truth is also the truth for us. Living in the new condition helps us identify more clearly the real needs among, and plus, perceived needs. This stage helps us understand the message itself more clearly, and so on. The process forms an ongoing dynamic of reciprocal causations between the three “poles.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOOD AND EVIL IN ETERNAL PERSPECTIVE:</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/good-and-evil-in-eternal-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/good-and-evil-in-eternal-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GOOD AND EVIL IN ETERNAL PERSPECTIVE:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HELP FROM REVELATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good triumphs over evil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good and evil are not equal opposites in power or legitimacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good and evil are not equally eternal. Evil has a beginning and an end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evil is allowed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evil does not simply take over and “bully” people around undeterred.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evil is temporary (limited in length).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In comparison to good, individual evils are short-lived along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Death removes it from the scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTELLIGENTLY DISCUSSING CREATION AND EVOLUTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/intelligently-discussing-creation-and-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/intelligently-discussing-creation-and-evolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTELLIGENTLY DISCUSSING CREATION AND EVOLUTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presentation here is not for solving the creation-evolution problem, but for clarifying the issue and correcting inappropriate thinking patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Identifying the Issue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creationism as such vs. the Christian formulations of it. There is a difference between creation as a concept and the Judaeo-Christian—or even Islamic—formulation of it. The Christian formulation gets into additional matters, which vary according to the manner interpreters handle the relevant biblical materials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INTRODUCTORY CONSIDERATIONS ON JONAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/introductory-considerations-on-jonah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/introductory-considerations-on-jonah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;INTRODUCTORY CONSIDERATIONS ON JONAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two views have been taken of the Book of Jonah: (1) the historical and (2) the literary. Under the former, Jonah gives an account of actual events. In the latter, the work is a short story written to express more general truths about God and man in the world. The significance of the matter along with the procedure for determining the genre is dealt with below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>METHODOLOGY FOR CRITICAL INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/methodology-for-critical-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/methodology-for-critical-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;METHODOLOGY FOR CRITICAL INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TO THE OLD TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Christians, critical introduction to the Old Testament has the advantage of inspired external evidence to confirm and complement the internal evidence for authorship, date, and character of the earlier literary works. That approach represents logical order, not necessarily chronological order. The Christian method (1) begins with the New Testament verdict of Christ and the apostles insofar as they speak on critical Old Testament issues and (2) examines the data in those books to see whether they fit the verdict. Lastly, the method (3) crosschecks each book with information available from archaeology and ancient Near Eastern literature. The New Testament sets the framework for any view of the character and manner of origin for the Jewish canon. Tshe procedure could begin with the claims in the Old Testament books and measure the contents against the claims. In fact, that is what critics do with any book, but they would not be doing it as Christians. Critics do not have to do it necessarily as Christians, but Christians can take advantage of a factor already in place for clarifying and confirming matters where it can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NOTATIONS ON THE DOCUMENTARY THEORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/notations-on-the-documentary-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/notations-on-the-documentary-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NOTATIONS ON THE DOCUMENTARY THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOR ORIGINS OF THE PENTATEUCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Criteria for Source Identification&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Structure. A brief statement of the literary basis for source documents here anticipates objections raised against the approach. The theory appeals to parallel accounts as a phenomenon that betrays variant origins for the story they tell. Important doublets are the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creation Accounts&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Genesis 1 (PE); 2 (J)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Flood Narrative&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Genesis 6-8 intermixed&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Naming of Isaac&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Genesis 17:17 (P); 18:12 (J); 21:6&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PART FOUR: THE PHILOSOPHICAL METHOD IN SKETCH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/part-four-the-philosophical-method-in-sketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/part-four-the-philosophical-method-in-sketch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PART FOUR: THE PHILOSOPHICAL METHOD IN SKETCH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Ways of Defining Religion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The subjective side (perceived meaning)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Transcendent viewpoint&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Worldview: ultimate frame of reference, big picture, the whole&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Christianity and Other Religions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;Method of selection&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Other alternatives fall out by default, not by direct disproof.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That procedure works because to do otherwise would require shouldering the negative burden of proof. It offers a positive rather than confrontational pattern for “feeling after God and finding him” (Acts 17:27).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PART III: THE SCIENTIFIC METHOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/part-iii-the-scientific-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/part-iii-the-scientific-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PART III: THE SCIENTIFIC METHOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.   &#x9;Description of General Evolution and Special Creationism&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.   General evolution&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;History of the evolutionary model&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of evolution originated at least as early as the fifth century B.C. in the person of Greek philosopher Empedocles and may be traced in various forms through Aristotle, Augustine, and others until modern times. Charles Darwin gave classical expression to this much older idea when he published his Origin of the Species in 1859. He highlighted the principle of “natural selection,” which was supplemented by Lamarck’s notion of “the inheritance of acquired characteristics” and de Vries’ “theory of mutations.”   Others influential in refining the evolutionary model and background factors include Maupertius, Erasmus, Robert Chambers, Herbert Spencer, Charles Lyell, Thomas Huxley, and Mivart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RECIPROCAL CAUSATIONʹ, THE BIOSPHERE,</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/reciprocal-causation%CA%B9-the-biosphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/reciprocal-causation%CA%B9-the-biosphere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RECIPROCAL CAUSATIONʹ, THE BIOSPHERE,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AND THEISTIC PROOF&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following observations evaluate the possibility of general evolution in the organic realm, particularly in the animal kingdom. They address features of living reality that highlight reciprocal causation, its necessary accompanying features, and its implications in contrast to all forms of straight-line causal series.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PART I&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Question #1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Can nature unaided put in sequence the origin of reciprocating parts that each together produce all the effects that are necessary for the viability of the whole and of each other? [system level per kind]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESOLVING APPARENT CONTRADICTIONS IN SCRIPTURE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/resolving-apparent-contradictions-in-scripture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/resolving-apparent-contradictions-in-scripture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RESOLVING APPARENT CONTRADICTIONS IN SCRIPTURE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Resolving apparent contradictions in scripture calls for methods of interpretation. The approach assumes the inerrancy of scripture; brain teasers often become paradoxes in wording rather than contradictions in reality. The approach also assumes that scripture is divine in such a way that makes it harmonious throughout. The mechanisms available for harmonizing scriptures with each other and with experience amount to the same things as the mechanisms used for properly interpreting human language. The same things we do to clear up ambiguities we do to resolve difficulties. Apparent difficulties normally arise because either or both sides of the dilemma are unclear, but people do not realize that at the time they sense a problem with the text. The following list is a summary of mechanisms for resolving discrepancies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELAH IN THE PSALMS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/selah-in-the-psalms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/selah-in-the-psalms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SELAH IN THE PSALMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Derivation of סֶלָה&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;From the root סלה, “to rest” or “be silent.” סֶלָה (penult accent) is taken as a pausal form of סֶלָה (ultima accent), directing the leader to pause or be silent presumably for an instrumental interlude (Gesenius).It always has the same form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.  From סלה, “to lift up” (Sampey, Leupold, and “most modern scholars”). It is thus a direction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;to the orchestra “to raise” the volume of the accompaniment momentarily—like a fortissimo or sforzando.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUFFERING IN THE WORLD: DOES GOD LOVE US?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/suffering-in-the-world-does-god-love-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/suffering-in-the-world-does-god-love-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUFFERING IN THE WORLD: DOES GOD LOVE US?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;Need to Get Rid of Parochial Self-Centeredness&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;If God were holy, there would be no evil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. &#x9;If God were loving, he would not confine people to hell forever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obviously, if there is a final overthrow of evil, it must be forever.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. &#x9;People fuss at God on the one hand because there is evil.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. &#x9;People desire on the other hand to practice freedom of the will.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE ANTIQUITY AND CHARACTER OF RITUAL SACRIFICE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-antiquity-and-character-of-ritual-sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-antiquity-and-character-of-ritual-sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE ANTIQUITY AND CHARACTER OF RITUAL SACRIFICE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the higher critical reconstruction of Hebrew history, ritual sacrifice developed later than the time of Moses. The prophetic movement, beginning with Amos, opposed blood sacrifice as an appropriate way to draw near to God. The reconstruction takes certain statements as reminiscent of this earlier attitude in Israel and call for examination in light of the Wellhausen claim.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Amos 5:21-26&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contrary to higher critical opinion, Amos’ opposition to feasts, solemn assemblies, burnt offerings, peace offerings, meal offerings, and songs in Israel’s contemporary worship was due to (a) their syncretistic nature, (b) their superficial manner, or (c) the polytheistic character of Israel’s worship. Amos’ objection was not to sacrifice as such, but to sacrifices invalidated by contextual considerations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DATE OF THE EVENTS IN JOB</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-date-of-the-events-in-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-date-of-the-events-in-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DATE OF THE EVENTS IN JOB&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Attempting to determine the date of the events in Job proceeds assumes that the book is more than a piece of literary art. The poetic form of most of the book has led some to regard it as less than historical, but form does not speak to historicity. Writers use poetry to tell the events at the Red Sea (Exodus 15) and the story of Sisera’s defeat (Judges 5). Prose fiction, on the other hand, appears constantly in modern authors. Whereas skillful writers of contemporary literature do produce remarkable works about fictitious people and happenings, it is doubtful whether that happened among the ancients. Their literature appears to have been at least a development of some kernel of historical truth, including the sophisticated poetry extant from the later Greek tragedians. Furthermore, Job is both poetry and prose, so the idea that poetry points to fiction and prose to non-fiction does not apply consistently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NOACHIAN FLOOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-noachian-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-noachian-flood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NOACHIAN FLOOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Views of the Flood&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Local flood theory: anthropologically universal, but not global&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Tranquil flood theory: perhaps universal, but not catastrophic with geological&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;upheavals, volcanic activity, or cosmic disturbances&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;Catastrophic universal flood theory designed to account for the fossil-bearing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;geological column&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. The Universality of the Flood&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;The purpose of the flood for destroying “every living thing that I have made”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 7:4)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE STRUCTURE OF JOB</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-structure-of-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-structure-of-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE STRUCTURE OF JOB&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Set-Up: Behind the Scenes: 1-2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eliphaz 4-5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 6-7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bildad 8&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 9-10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zophar 11&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 12-14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eliphaz 15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 16-17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bildad 18&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 19&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zophar 20&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eliphaz 22&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 23-24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bildad 25&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 26-31&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elihu 32-37&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God 38-39&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 40:1-5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God 40:6-41&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Job 42:1-6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Resolution 42:7-17&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;      christir.org&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE THIRD REASON</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-third-reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-third-reason/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE THIRD REASON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introductory Comment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Belief in the resurrection does not wholly depend on the evidence for one unique event. That event ties into other matters that anticipated it in prophecy and issued from it in history. To a significant extent, accepting Jesus as Messiah depended on the Jews’ proper understanding of Old Testament anticipations for the Messiah. This web of evidence increases exponentially the power of the data. A different understanding of Messiah and his kingdom, however, predisposed most patriotic Jews to reject him on doctrinal grounds. Nevertheless, as Gamaliel’s presentation shows in Acts 5, the argument from the very existence of the church tended to short-circuit that doctrinal objection sufficiently to force a re-evaluation of prophetic interpretation and current policy toward Jesus’ disciples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/untitled/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
