<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 Chronicles on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 Chronicles on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-1&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Solomon secured himself in his kingdom; the LORD God was with him and made him great. 2He called together all Israel&amp;ndash;the commanders of thousands and hundreds, the judges and every leader, the heads of families. 3He led the whole assembly went to the high place at Gibeon; God&amp;rsquo;s Tent of Meeting was there that Moses had made in the countryside. 4But David had brought the Ark up from Kiriath-jearim to the tent he&amp;rsquo;d made for it in Jerusalem. 5The bronze altar that Bezalel son of Uri son of Hur had made, was there in front of the Tabernacle. Solomon and the assembly went to it, 6and he offered 1,000 burnt offerings on it.  &#x9;2 Ch 1:1-6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-2&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Solomon decided to build a temple for the LORD&amp;rsquo;s name and a royal palace for himself. 2He assigned 70,000 to transport materials, 80,000 to quarry stone in the mountains, and 3,600 to supervise them. 3He sent word to Hiram, king of Tyre, &amp;ldquo;As you sent my father David cedars for his palace, do for me. 4I&amp;rsquo;m getting ready to build a temple for the LORD my God and dedicate it to him for burning fragrant incense and offering burnt offerings morning and evening on Sabbaths, new moons, and the LORD&amp;rsquo;s appointed festivals—items of worship required permanently in Israel. 5The temple I&amp;rsquo;m going to build will be great, because our God is greater than all other gods. 6But who can build him a temple? The sky, the highest heavens, can&amp;rsquo;t contain him; who am I to build him a temple, except for burning incense to him? 7Send me a man skilled at working in gold, silver, brass, and iron; in purple, crimson, and violet fabrics; a man that knows how to engrave and work with the skilled men I have in Judah and Jerusalem that my father provided. 8Send me cedar, cypress, and algum wood from Lebanon; your woodsmen know how to cut timber in Lebanon. My men will work with yours 9to prepare an abundance of it for the great, wonderful temple I&amp;rsquo;m going to build. 10I&amp;rsquo;ll give your woodsmen that cut the logs 220,000 bushels 20,000 kors of crushed wheat, 220,000 bushels 20,000 kors of barley, 189,000 gallons 20,000 baths of wine, and 189,000 gallons 20,000 baths of oil.&amp;rdquo;&#x9; 2 Ch 2:1-10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-3&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Solomon started building the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple on Mount Moriah, where the Lord had appeared to David, the place David prepared on the threshing floor of Ornan/Araunah the Jebusite. 2He began construction on the second day, second month, fourth year of his reign.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Ch 3:10-17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; The foundation for God&amp;rsquo;s Temple was 30 x 90ft.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; The porch in front of it was 30ft wide and 180ft tall, overlaid with pure gold inside.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-4&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; He made&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Ch 4:11-22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Figures of gourds were under it, entirely circling the sea (45ft). The oxen were in 2 rows cast in one piece with the Sea. 4It stood on 12 oxen, 3 facing out in each direction with their hindquarters inward. 5It was 4ins thick, with a brim like a cup—like a lily blossom. It could hold 27,000 gallons 3,000 baths.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-5&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Solomon finished the work on the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple, he brought in the silver, gold, and utensils David had dedicated, and put them in the treasuries in God&amp;rsquo;s Temple.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Then he gathered to Jerusalem the elders in Israel, the leaders of tribes and families, in preparation for bringing up the Ark from The City of David (Zion). 3The men of Israel gathered to him at the festival in the seventh month. 4The elders came, and the Levites picked up the Ark 5and brought it up. They brought up the Tent of Meeting and the holy utensils that were in it. 6King Solomon and the community were sacrificing so many sheep and oxen they couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep count of them. 7The priests brought the Ark to its place in the inner sanctuary, the Holy of Holies, under the cherubs. 8They spread their wings over it and covered it and its poles. 9The poles were long enough to be visible in front of the inner sanctuary, but not outside; they&amp;rsquo;re still there. 10The only things in the Ark were the two tablets Moses put there at Horeb/Sinai, where the LORD made a covenant with the Israelites after they came out of Egypt. &#x9;2 Ch 5:1-10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-6&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Solomon said,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Ch 6:36-42&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Then he faced the people and blessed the assembly standing there, 4&amp;quot;Bless the LORD God of Israel, who said to my father David, 5&amp;rsquo;From the time I brought my people out of Egypt, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t chosen a city to build a temple in for my name. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t chosen any man as a leader over Israel. 6But I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen Jerusalem as the place to identify with and David as leader over Israel. 7My father wanted to build him a temple, 8but the LORD said, &amp;lsquo;You meant well, 9but you won&amp;rsquo;t build me a temple; your son will.&amp;rsquo; 10He has fulfilled that promise; I&amp;rsquo;ve risen to the throne and built the temple for his name. 11That&amp;rsquo;s where I&amp;rsquo;ve set the Ark that holds the covenant he made with Israel.&amp;quot; 12-13Solomon had built a bronze platform 7½ x 7½ x 4½ft high beside the altar in the middle of the court. He stood on it, knelt, and spread out his hands toward heaven.                   &#x9;2 Ch 6:1-13 14&amp;quot;LORD God of Israel, there&amp;rsquo;s no God like you in heaven or on earth. You keep covenant and show enduring love to everyone that follows you with all their heart. 15You&amp;rsquo;ve kept your promise to David. You&amp;rsquo;ve said it with your mouth and fulfilled it with your hand. 16Keep this promise too, &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll always have a descendant on Israel&amp;rsquo;s throne if they follow my Law like you have.&amp;rsquo; 17Confirm that promise now. 18&amp;quot;But will you live with people on earth? The sky and highest heaven can&amp;rsquo;t contain you, much less this Temple I&amp;rsquo;ve built. 19Yet attend to my petition. Listen to my call 20so you&amp;rsquo;ll be looking toward this Temple day and night where you&amp;rsquo;ve said you&amp;rsquo;d put your name. 21Listen when your people and I pray toward this place. Listen from heaven and forgive. 22&amp;quot;When someone sins against another and comes here to take an oath at your altar, 23then listen from heaven and judge them. Punish the sinful by bringing their way on their own head and justify the good by rewarding them according to their goodness. &#x9;2 Ch 6:14-23 24&amp;quot;When an enemy defeats your people because they&amp;rsquo;ve sinned, if they repent, confess your name, and petition you in this Temple, 25then listen from heaven, forgive them, and bring them back to the country you&amp;rsquo;ve given them and their ancestors. 26&amp;quot;When there&amp;rsquo;s no rain because they&amp;rsquo;ve sinned against you and they pray toward this place, confess your name, and turn from their sin when you punish them, 27then listen from heaven and forgive your people. Teach them the good way to live and send rain on the land you&amp;rsquo;ve given them to inherit.&#x9;2 Ch 6:24-27 28&amp;quot;When there&amp;rsquo;s a famine in the country; disease, blight or mildew; locust or grasshopper; a sickness, or an enemy laying siege to our towns—29whatever petition your people make, each knowing their own suffering and pain and spreading their hands toward this Temple, 30then listen from where you live, forgive, and render to each as they&amp;rsquo;ve done—only you know everyone&amp;rsquo;s heart—31so they&amp;rsquo;ll respect you and follow your ways as long as they live in the country you&amp;rsquo;ve given their ancestors. 32&amp;quot;When foreigners come from a distant country because of your great name, your powerful hand and outstretched arm, and pray toward this Temple, 33then listen from where you live, and do everything they call to you for, so every nation will know you and respect you like your people do, and so they&amp;rsquo;ll know that the Temple I&amp;rsquo;ve built wears your name. 34&amp;quot;When your people go out to battle by whatever way you send them and they pray to you toward this city you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen and the Temple I&amp;rsquo;ve built, 35then listen from heaven and support them. &#x9;2 Ch 6:28-35 36&amp;quot;When they sin against you (everybody sins), you&amp;rsquo;re angry with them, and deliver them to an enemy that takes them captive near or far, 37if they take it to heart, repent, and petition you, &amp;lsquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve sinned, we&amp;rsquo;ve committed iniquity, we&amp;rsquo;ve acted wickedly&amp;rsquo;; 38if they come back to you with all their heart and soul, and pray toward the land you&amp;rsquo;ve given their ancestors, the city you&amp;rsquo;ve chosen, the Temple I&amp;rsquo;ve built, 39then listen from where you live, support them, and forgive them. 40&amp;quot;Open your eyes and ears to answer the prayer I&amp;rsquo;ve offered here. 41Rise, LORD God, to your resting place, you and your powerful Ark. Cover your priests with salvation; may your holy people celebrate what&amp;rsquo;s good. 42Don&amp;rsquo;t turn away from your anointed one. Remember your enduring love for your servant David.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-7&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Solomon finished praying, fire came down from the sky and consumed the burnt offering and sacrifices, and the LORD&amp;rsquo;s glory filled the Temple. 2The priests couldn&amp;rsquo;t go in because of it. 3When the Israelites saw the fire and the LORD&amp;rsquo;s glory come down on the Temple, they bowed down on the pavement with their faces to the ground in worship and praised him, &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s truly good; his love endures forever.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-8&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At the end of the 20 years it took Solomon to build the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple and his own palace, 2he rebuilt the towns Hiram had given him and settled Israelites in them. 3Then he captured Hamath-zobah 4and built Tadmor in the open country and storage cities in Hamath. 5He built Upper and Lower Beth-horon, fortified towns with walls, gates, and bars. 6He built Baalath, the storage cities he had, towns for his chariots and cavalry, and everything he delighted to build in Jerusalem, Lebanon, and the rest of the territory he ruled.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 9</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-9&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When the queen of Sheba heard about Solomon, she came to Jerusalem to test him with hard questions. She brought a large contingent of camels carrying spices, and lots of gold and precious stones. When she got there, she talked to him about everything on her mind. 2He answered her questions; there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything he couldn&amp;rsquo;t explain to her. 3When she&amp;rsquo;d seen his wisdom, the palace he&amp;rsquo;d built, 4the food at his table, the seating of his officials, the attendance by his servers and their attire, his cupbearers and their attire, the stairway he used to go up to the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple, she was breathless, 5&amp;quot;The report was true that I heard in my country about your words and wisdom. 6But I didn&amp;rsquo;t believe it till I saw it. They didn&amp;rsquo;t tell me half of it. 7How fortunate your officers must feel, being around you continually and listening to your wisdom. 8Bless the LORD your God that delighted in you and set you on his throne. He loved Israel and established the nation permanently; that&amp;rsquo;s why he made you their king—to do justice and goodness.&amp;quot; &#x9;2 Ch 9:1-8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-10&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Rehoboam went to Shechem, because Israel had come to Shechem to make him king. 2When Jeroboam heard about it, he came back. (He was in Egypt where he&amp;rsquo;d fled from Solomon.) 3They sent for him. When Jeroboam and all Israel came, they said to Rehoboam, 4&amp;quot;Your father made our yoke heavy. Lighten his hard service and the heavy yoke he put on us, and we&amp;rsquo;ll serve you.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-11&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Rehoboam got to Jerusalem, he gathered 180,000 soldiers from Judah and Benjamin to fight Israel to restore the kingdom to himself. 2But a message from the LORD came to Shemaiah, the man of God, 3&amp;quot;Tell Rehoboam and all Israel in Judah and Benjamin, 4&amp;rsquo;The LORD says, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t fight your kin. Go back home. I&amp;rsquo;m going to let this happen.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot; 5-10Rehoboam lived in Jerusalem and built fortified towns for defense in Judah and Benjamin: Bethlehem, Etam, Tekoa, Beth-zur, Soco, Adullam, Gath, Mareshah, Ziph, 9Adoraim, Lachish, Azekah, 10Zorah, Aijalon, and Hebron. 11He reinforced the fortresses and put officers in them along with stores of food, olive oil, and wine. 12He put shields and spears in every city and reinforced them greatly. He held onto Judah and Benjamin. &#x9;2 Ch 11:1-12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 12</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-12&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Rehoboam&amp;rsquo;s kingdom got secure and strong, he and Israel turned away from the Law of the LORD. 2In his fifth year, because they weren&amp;rsquo;t faithful to the LORD, Shishak, king of Egypt, came up against Jerusalem 3with 1,200 chariots and 60,000 cavalry. The Lybians, Sukkites, and Nubians came with him without number. 4He captured the fortified towns in Judah and advanced to Jerusalem. 5Then Shemaiah the prophet came to Rehoboam and Judah&amp;rsquo;s officials that had fled to Jerusalem to escape Shishak, &amp;ldquo;The LORD says you&amp;rsquo;ve left him, so he&amp;rsquo;s left you to Shishak.&amp;rdquo; 6The officials of Israel and the king humbled themselves, &amp;ldquo;The LORD is good.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 13</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-13&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 13&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the eighteenth year of King Jeroboam, Abijah became king in Judah. 2He ruled for 3 years in Jerusalem. His mother was Micaiah, daughter of Uriel of Gibeah. War arose between Abijah and Jeroboam. 3Abijah entered the battle with 400,000 trained soldiers; Jeroboam drew up in battle formation against him with 800,000 trained soldiers.&#x9; 2 Ch 13:1-3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Abijah stood on Mount Zemaraim in the hill country of Ephraim and shouted, &amp;ldquo;Jeroboam and all Israel, 5don&amp;rsquo;t you know that the LORD God of Israel gave the rule over Israel permanently to David and his descendants by a covenant of salt? 6Yet Jeroboam rebelled against him. 7Worthless men gathered around him, scoundrels that proved to be too strong for the son of Solomon when he was young and timid and couldn&amp;rsquo;t hold his own against them. 8So now you intend to resist the kingdom of the LORD by the descendants of David because you have a big army and the golden calves Jeroboam made as your gods. 9Haven&amp;rsquo;t you driven out the LORD&amp;rsquo;s priests, the descendants of Aaron and the Levites, and made your own priests like people in other countries? Whoever comes to consecrate himself with a young bull and seven rams, can become a priest for what aren&amp;rsquo;t gods. 10The LORD is our God. We haven&amp;rsquo;t left him. The descendants of Aaron are serving him as priests and the Levites are doing their work. 11Every morning they burn burnt offerings and fragrant incense to him. They set the showbread on the clean table, and the golden lampstand with its lamps is ready to light every evening, because we&amp;rsquo;re keeping the charge of the LORD our God. But you&amp;rsquo;ve left him. 12God is at our head and his priests with the signal bugles to sound the alarm against you, Israel. Don&amp;rsquo;t fight with the LORD God of your ancestors; you won&amp;rsquo;t prevail.&amp;rdquo;&#x9; 2 Ch 13:4-12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-14&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 14&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When Abijah died, they buried him in The City of David, and his son Asa became king. The country had peace for 10 years.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Asa did what was good. 3He removed the foreign altars and high places, tore down the scared pillars, cut down the Asherah poles, 4and commanded Judah to look to the LORD God of their ancestors and to observe the Law and the commandments. 5He removed the high places and incense altars from the towns in Judah. 6He built fortified towns in Judah since the LORD had given the country rest. 7He said to Judah, &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s build these towns and surround them with walls and towers, gates and bars. The country is still ours because we&amp;rsquo;ve sought the LORD, and he&amp;rsquo;s given us rest all around.&amp;rdquo; They built and prospered. 8Asa had a standing army of 300,000 from Judah that carried spears and large shields and 280,000 from Benjamin that carried shields and handled bows—fearless soldiers.&#x9;2 Ch 14:1-8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 15</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-15&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 15&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Spirit of God came on Azariah son of Oded, 2and he went out to meet Asa, &amp;ldquo;Listen, Asa, Judah, and Benjamin, the LORD is with you when you&amp;rsquo;re with him. If you look for him, he&amp;rsquo;ll let you find him. If you leave him, he&amp;rsquo;ll leave you. 3For a long time Israel was without the true God, without a teaching priest, without law. 4But in their distress they turned to the LORD and looked for him, and he let them find him. 5In those times, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any peace to the ones who traveled; disturbances troubled the people in many countries. 6Nation crushed nation, city crushed city, because God distressed them with all kinds of problems. 7But you, be strong. Don&amp;rsquo;t lose courage; there&amp;rsquo;s reward for your work.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-16&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 16&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the thirty-sixth year of Asa&amp;rsquo;s reign, Baasha, king of Israel, came up against Judah and fortified Ramah to prevent anyone from going out or coming in to Asa. 2Asa brought out silver and gold from the treasuries of the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple and the king&amp;rsquo;s palace, and sent them to Benhadad, king of Aram, who lived in Damascus, and said, 3&amp;quot;Let&amp;rsquo;s make a treaty between us, like the one between our fathers. I&amp;rsquo;ve sent you silver and gold; go break your treaty with Baasha so he&amp;rsquo;ll withdraw from me.&amp;quot; 4Benhadad listened and sent his armies against the towns in Israel. They conquered Ijon, Dan, Abel-maim, and the store towns in Naphtali. 5When Baasha heard about it, he stopped fortifying Ramah. 6Then King Asa brought Judah, and they carried away the stones and timber from Ramah that Baasha had been using, and with them Asa fortified Geba and Mizpah. &#x9;2 Ch 16:1-6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 17</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-17&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 17&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; His son Jehoshaphat became king and secured his position against Israel. 2He placed troops in Judah&amp;rsquo;s fortified towns and set garrisons in Judah and the towns in Ephraim his father had captured. 3The LORD was with him because he followed his ancestor David&amp;rsquo;s earlier days and didn&amp;rsquo;t look to the images of Baal. 4He sought his father&amp;rsquo;s God, followed his commandments, and didn&amp;rsquo;t do like Israel. 5The LORD secured the kingdom under him, Judah brought tributes to him, and he had great wealth and honor. 6He took pride in the ways of the LORD and removed again the high places and Asherah poles from Judah.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 18</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-18&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 18&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jehoshaphat had great wealth and honor, and allied himself by marriage with Ahab. 2Some years later he went down to visit Ahab in Samaria. Ahab slaughtered lots of sheep and oxen for him and the people with him, and induced him to go up against Ramoth-gilead. 3He asked Jehoshaphat, &amp;ldquo;Will you go with me against Ramoth-gilead?&amp;rdquo; He told him, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m like you, my people like yours. We&amp;rsquo;ll go with you into the battle.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-19&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 19&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jehoshaphat went back safely to his palace in Jerusalem. 2Jehu son of Hanani the seer went out to meet him and said, &amp;ldquo;Should you help the sinful, love the ones that hate the LORD, and bring his wrath on you? 3But there&amp;rsquo;s some good in you: you&amp;rsquo;ve removed the Asherah poles from the country and set your heart to look to God.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Jehoshaphat lived in Jerusalem, circulated again among the people from Beersheba to the hill country of Ephraim, and brought them back to the LORD God of their ancestors. 5He appointed judges in each fortified city in Judah, 6&amp;quot;Consider what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. You&amp;rsquo;re not just judging for people but for the LORD that&amp;rsquo;s with you. 7Respect him; he won&amp;rsquo;t take part in sin, partiality, or bribery.&amp;rdquo;           &#x9;2 Ch 19:1-7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 20</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-20&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 20&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After that, the Moabites, Ammonites, and some Meunites came to attack Jehoshaphat. 2Some people brought him a report, &amp;ldquo;A large army is coming out of Edom from the other side of the sea. They&amp;rsquo;re in Hazazon-tamar (En-gedi).&amp;rdquo; 3He was afraid, set himself to look to the LORD, and declared a fast throughout Judah. 4Judah gathered from all the towns to look to the LORD for help.&#x9;2 Ch 20:1-4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-21&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 21&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jehoshaphat died, and they buried him in The City of David. His son Jehoram became king. 2His brothers were Azariah, Jehiel, Zechariah, Azariyahu, Michael, and Shephatiah. 3Their father had given them many gifts of silver, gold, and other precious things along with fortified towns in Judah. But he gave the kingdom to Jehoram, his firstborn.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; When Jehoram had taken over the kingdom and made himself secure, he killed his brothers with the sword and some of the rulers too. 5He was 32 when he became king and ruled for 8 years in Jerusalem. 6He followed the ways of Israel&amp;rsquo;s kings like Ahab did. (His wife was Ahab&amp;rsquo;s daughter.) He did evil, 7but because of his covenant with David, the LORD wouldn&amp;rsquo;t destroy David&amp;rsquo;s house. He&amp;rsquo;d promised to give him and his descendants a lamp permanently.     2 Ch 21:1-7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 22</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-22&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 22&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then the people in Jerusalem made Ahaziah/Jehoahaz, his youngest son, king. The band of men that came with the Arabs to the camp had killed the older sons. 2Ahaziah was 22 and ruled for 1 year in Jerusalem. His mother was Athaliah, granddaughter of Omri. 3To his destruction, he also followed Ahab&amp;rsquo;s practices because his mother gave him bad advice. 4He sinned in 5going with Jehoram son of Ahab to fight Hazael, king of Aram, at Ramoth-gilead. But the Arameans wounded Joram/Jehoram. 6He came back to heal in Jezreel from his wounds at Ramah. Ahaziah son of Joram/Jehoram king of Judah went down to see Joram/Jehoram in Jezreel because he was wounded.&#x9; 2 Ch 22:1-6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 23</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-23&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 23&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the seventh year, Jehoiada summoned the courage to make a pact with the commanders of hundreds: Azariah son of Joram/Jeroham, Ishmael son of Johanan, Azariah son of Obed, Maaseiah son of Adaiah, and Elishaphat son of Zichri. 2They gathered to Jerusalem the Levites from the towns in Judah and the heads of families. 3When the assembly made a pact with the king in God&amp;rsquo;s Temple, Jehoiada told them, &amp;ldquo;The king&amp;rsquo;s son will reign like the LORD has said regarding David&amp;rsquo;s descendants. 4A third of you, priests and Levites that come in on the Sabbath, will be gatekeepers. 5A third will be at the king&amp;rsquo;s palace, and a third at the Foundation Gate. The people will be in the courts of the Temple. 6Don&amp;rsquo;t let anybody go into the Temple except the priests and servicing Levites. They can go in because they&amp;rsquo;re holy. Have the people keep the charge of the LORD. 7The Levites will surround the king with weapons in hand. Kill whoever comes into the Temple. Be with the king when he comes in and goes out.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-24&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 24&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Joash was 7 when he became king and ruled for 40 years in Jerusalem. His mother was Zibiah from Beersheba. 2He did what was good all the time Jehoiada was alive. 3Jehoiada took two wives for him, and he became the father of sons and daughters.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; After that, Joash decided to restore the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple. 5He gathered the priests and Levites, and said, &amp;ldquo;Go out to the towns in Judah and collect money to repair your God&amp;rsquo;s Temple annually; do it right away.&amp;rdquo; But the Levites didn&amp;rsquo;t act right away. 6He summoned Jehoiada the chief priest, &amp;ldquo;Why haven&amp;rsquo;t you required the Levites to bring in from Judah and Jerusalem the tax Moses laid on Israel for the Tent of Testimony?&amp;rdquo; 7The sons of Athaliah had broken into God&amp;rsquo;s Temple and used the holy things for the images of Baal.&#x9;2 Ch 24:1-7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 25</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-25&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 25&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Amaziah was 25 and ruled for 29 years in Jerusalem. His mother was Jehoaddan of Jerusalem. 2He did what was good, but not with all his heart. 3As soon as his kingdom was firmly in hand, he executed the officials that had assassinated his father. 4He didn&amp;rsquo;t put their children to death, like the LORD commanded in the Law of Moses: &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t execute parents for offspring or offspring for parents. Execute each person for that person&amp;rsquo;s sin.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 26</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-26&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 26&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The people in Judah took Uzziah/Azariah at 16 and made him king after his father Amaziah. 2He built Eloth and restored it to Judah, 3and ruled for 52 years in Jerusalem. His mother was Jechiliah of Jerusalem. 4He did what was good like everything good his father Amaziah had done. 5He continued to look to God in the time of Zechariah, who had understanding through the vision of God. As long as he sought the LORD, God caused him to flourish.&#x9; 2 Ch 26:1-5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 27</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-27&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 27&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jotham was 25 and ruled for 16 years in Jerusalem. His mother was Jerushah daughter of Zadok. 2He did what was good like his father, but he didn&amp;rsquo;t go into the Temple. The people kept acting corruptly. 3He built the upper gate of the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple and built extensively the wall of Ophel. 4He built towns in the hill country of Judah, and fortresses and towers on the wooded hills. 5He fought the Ammonites and prevailed; for three years they paid him 7550 lbs 100 talents of silver, 110,000 bushels 10,000 kors of wheat, and 110,000 bushels 10,000 kors of barley a year. 6He became powerful because he ordered his ways in the LORD his God. 7The rest of the acts of Jotham, including his wars, are recorded in The Book of the Kings of Israel and Judah. [8] 9He died, and they buried him in The City of David. His son Ahaz became king. &#x9;2 Ch 27:1-9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 28</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-28&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 28&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Ahaz was 20 and ruled for 16 years in Jerusalem. He didn&amp;rsquo;t do what was good like David did. 2He followed the kings of Israel, made molten images for the worshipping Baal, 3burned incense in the Valley of (Ben)Hinnom, and burned his sons like the nations the LORD had driven out. 4He sacrificed and burned incense on the high places on the hills under every green tree.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 29</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-29&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 29&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Hezekiah became king when he was 25 and ruled for 29 years in Jerusalem. 2He did what was right like David did.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Ch 29:31-36&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; In the first month of his first year, he reopened the doors of the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple and repaired them. 4He brought in the priests and Levites and gathered them in the courtyard on the east. 5He said, &amp;ldquo;Listen, Levites. Consecrate yourselves and the Temple of the LORD God of our ancestors. Remove ceremonial uncleanness from the Holy Place. 6Our ancestors have been unfaithful and done what he forbids. They&amp;rsquo;ve turned their backs on where he lives. 7They&amp;rsquo;ve shut the doors of the vestibule and put out the lamps. They haven&amp;rsquo;t burned incense or offered burnt offerings in the Holy Place. 8So God&amp;rsquo;s wrath has been against Judah and Jerusalem. He&amp;rsquo;s made them something to abhor, be amazed at, hissed at, as you can see. 9Our ancestors fell by the sword. Our sons, daughters, and wives are in captivity because of it. 10I intend to renew the covenant with the LORD God of Israel so his furious anger will turn away from us. 11Sons, don&amp;rsquo;t neglect your responsibilities any longer. The LORD has chosen you to stand in his presence, perform service to him and his people, and burn incense.&amp;rdquo; &#x9;2 Ch 29:1-11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 30</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-30&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 30&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Hezekiah wrote letters to everywhere in Israel and Judah, to Ephraim and Manasseh to come to the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple in Jerusalem, to keep Passover to the God of Israel. 2The king, his officials, and the whole assembly in Jerusalem had decided to keep Passover in the second month. 3They couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep it at its regular time because the priests hadn&amp;rsquo;t sanctified themselves in sufficient numbers, and the people hadn&amp;rsquo;t gathered in Jerusalem. 4The plan seemed right to the king and the whole assembly. 5They circulated a proclamation from Dan to Beersheba to come and keep Passover at Jerusalem; they hadn&amp;rsquo;t kept it in great numbers as written. 6So runners went everywhere in Israel and Judah with letters from the king and his officials: &amp;ldquo;People of Israel, come back to the LORD God of Abraham, Isaac, and Israel so he&amp;rsquo;ll come back to the remnant of you that have escaped from the kings of Assyria. 7Don&amp;rsquo;t be like your ancestors and fellow Jews that weren&amp;rsquo;t faithful to him. He made them desolate, as you can see. 8Don&amp;rsquo;t stiffen your neck like they did. Yield to him and go into the sanctuary he&amp;rsquo;s consecrated permanently. Serve him so his furious anger will turn away from you. 9If you come back to him, your fellow Jews and descendants will receive mercy from their captors and come back to this land. The LORD is gracious and merciful. He won&amp;rsquo;t turn away from you if you come back to him.&amp;rdquo; &#x9;2 Ch 30:1-9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 31</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-31&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 31&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; When that finished, Israel went out and broke down the pillars in pieces, cut down the Asherah poles, pulled down the high places and altars, and destroyed them everywhere in Judah and Benjamin, Ephraim and Manasseh. Then they returned to their towns and properties.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Hezekiah appointed the divisions of priests and Levites, according to each one&amp;rsquo;s service: for burnt offerings and peace offerings, to minister, give thanks and praise in the camp of the LORD. 3He also appointed the kings&amp;rsquo; portion of goods for the burnt offerings—for the morning and evening burnt offerings, the Sabbaths, new moons, and fixed festivals like the Law says. 4He commanded the people in Jerusalem to give the portion due to the priests and Levites so they could devote themselves to the Law of the LORD. 5As soon as the order spread, the Israelites provided in abundance a tenth of the first part of the harvest of grain, new wine, oil, honey, and produce.  6The ones that lived in the towns in Judah also brought in a tenth of the oxen and sheep, and a tenth of the sacred gifts consecrated to the LORD and placed them in piles. 7In the third month, they began to make the piles and finished them by the seventh. 8When Hezekiah and the rulers came and saw the piles, they blessed the LORD and his people. 9Hezekiah asked the chief priests and Levites about the piles. 10Azariah, the chief priest from the House of Zadok, said, &amp;ldquo;Since the contributions started coming to the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple, we&amp;rsquo;ve had enough to eat with this amount left over. He has blessed his people.&amp;rdquo;&#x9; 2 Ch 31:1-10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 32</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-32/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-32&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 32&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; After those faithful acts, Sennacherib, king of Assyria, invaded Judah, laid siege to fortified towns, and intended to break into them. 2When Hezekiah saw he&amp;rsquo;d come and meant to attack Jerusalem, 3he, his officers, and soldiers decided to cut off the water supply from the springs outside the city. 4Many people came together and stopped up the springs feeding the stream that flowed through the region, &amp;ldquo;Why should Assyria&amp;rsquo;s kings come and find abundant water?&amp;rdquo; 5He took courage and rebuilt the wall that had been torn down, erected towers on it, built an outside wall, strengthened the Millo in The City of David, and made a great number of weapons and shields. 6He appointed military officers over the people, and gathered them in the square at the city gate to encourage them, 7&amp;quot;Be strong and courageous; don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid or intimidated by Assyria&amp;rsquo;s king or his army. The One that&amp;rsquo;s with us is greater than the one that&amp;rsquo;s with him. 8All he&amp;rsquo;s got is a physical army, but we have the LORD our God to help us and fight our battles.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 33</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-33/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-33&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 33&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Manasseh was 12 and ruled for 55 years in Jerusalem. 2He did evil like the nations the LORD drove out. 3He rebuilt the high places Hezekiah had torn down, erected altars for the images of Baal, set up Asherah poles, and worshiped and served the stars in the sky. 4He built altars in the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple where the LORD had said, &amp;ldquo;I will identify with Jerusalem permanently.&amp;rdquo; 5He built altars for the host of heaven in the two courts of the LORD&amp;rsquo;s Temple. 6He burned his sons as an offering in the Valley of (Ben)Hinnom. He angered the LORD with lots of sins he did: witchcraft, fortunetelling, sorcery, consulting mediums and spiritists. 7Then he put in God&amp;rsquo;s Temple the carved image of the idol he&amp;rsquo;d made about which God had told David and Solomon his son, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to identify myself permanently with this Temple and with Jerusalem out of all the tribes in Israel. 8I won&amp;rsquo;t again remove Israel from the land I&amp;rsquo;ve appointed for their ancestors, if only they&amp;rsquo;ll observe everything I&amp;rsquo;ve commanded them in the Law, statutes, and ordinances I gave through Moses.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 34</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-34/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-34&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 34&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Josiah was 8 and ruled for 31 years in Jerusalem. 2He did what was good and didn&amp;rsquo;t stray from the ways of David. 3In his eighth year, while he was still young, he began to look to David&amp;rsquo;s God. In his twelfth year he began to purge Judah and Jerusalem of the high places, Asherah poles, and carved and molten images. 4The people tore down the Baal altars and chopped down the incense altars above them. The Asherah poles, carved images, and molten images he broke in pieces, ground into powder, and scattered on the graves of those who had sacrificed to them. 5He burned the bones of the priests on their altars. 6In the towns and surrounding ruins in Manasseh, Ephraim, and Simeon as far as Naphtali, 7he destroyed the altars and Asherah poles, beat the carved images into powder, and chopped down the incense altars everywhere in Israel.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 35</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-35/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-35&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 35&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then Josiah celebrated Passover to the LORD in Jerusalem. They killed the Passover animals on the fourteenth of the first month. 2He appointed the priests to their offices and encouraged them in the service for the Temple. 3He told the Levites that taught Israel and were holy to the LORD, &amp;ldquo;Put the holy Ark in the Temple Solomon built. It won&amp;rsquo;t be a burden on your shoulder anymore. Serve the LORD your God and his people Israel. 4Prepare yourselves by divisions within families like David and Solomon wrote. 5Stand in the Holy Place by those divisions of your relatives the lay people. With the Levites make divisions within families. 6Slaughter the Passover animals, sanctify yourselves, and be ready to do for your relatives what the LORD said by Moses.&amp;rdquo;&#x9; 2 Ch 35:1-6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chronicles 36</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-ot/2-chronicles/chapter-36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-chronicles-chapter-36&#34;&gt;2 Chronicles Chapter 36&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The people took Joahaz son of Josiah and made him king. 2He was 23 and ruled for 3 months in Jerusalem. 3The king of Egypt deposed him and imposed on the land a fine of 7550 lbs 100 talents of silver and 75.5 lbs a talent of gold. 4The king of Egypt made Eliakim his brother king over Judah and Jerusalem, and changed his name to Jehoiakim. But Neco took Joahaz to Egypt. 5Jehoiakim was 25. He eHeHeruled for 11 years in Jerusalem and did evil. 6Nebuchadnezzar came up against him, bound him with bronze chains, and took him to Babylon. 7He took some articles from the Temple to Babylon and put them in his temple. 8The rest of the acts of Jehoiakim, his disgusting deeds, and the charges against him are recorded in The Book of the Kings of Israel and Judah. His son Jehoiachin became king.&#x9;2 Ch 36:1-8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
