<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 Timothy on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 Timothy on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2 Timothy 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-timothy-chapter-1&#34;&gt;2 Timothy Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul, apostle of-Christ Jesus by (the) will of-God according-to (the) promise of-life [the] in Christ Jesus, 2to-Timothy, beloved son.  Grace, mercy, peace from God (the) Father and Christ Jesus the Lord of-us.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; I-have grace to-[the] God, whom I-serve from (my) forefathers with (a) clear conscience, as I┘constantly└have the remembrance concerning you in the prayers of-me night and day, 4longing to-see you, remembering the tears of-you in-order-that I-might-be-filled with-joy, 5taking remembrance of-the sincere faith in you, which first resided in the grandmother of-you, Lois, and the mother of-you, Eunice, and I-have-been-persuaded that also (is) in you.  6On-account-of which reason I-remind you to-stir-up-into-a-flame/to-stir-up the spiritual-gift of-[the] God that is in you through the laying-on of-the hands of-me.  7For [the] God did┘not└give us (a) spirit of cowardice/timidity, but of-power and love and self-control.  8So do┘not└be-ashamed-of the mystery of-the Lord of-us nor me, the prisoner of-him, but suffer-with (me), for-the gospel according-to (the) power of-God, 9the-One having-saved us and having-called (us) with-(a)-holy calling, not according-to the works of-us, but according-to his-own purpose and grace, the-one having-been-given to-us in Christ Jesus before times eternal, 10and/but now having-been-revealed by the appearing of-the Savior of-us Christ Jesus, (the-One) having-destroyed death [on-the-one-hand] and having-brought-to-light life and immortality through the gospel, 11to which I was-appointed (a) preacher and apostle and teacher, 12on-account-of which reason also I-suffer these-things.  But I-am┘not└ashamed, for I-know whom I-have-believed and have-been-persuaded that he-is able to-keep the entrusted-matter of-me to that [the] day.  13Have (the) pattern of-sound words that you-heard from me in (the) faith and love [the] in Christ Jesus.  14By the Holy Spirit [the] residing in us, keep the good matter-entrusted to-you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Timothy 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-timothy-chapter-2&#34;&gt;2 Timothy Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; You then, my son, be-strong in the grace [the] in Christ Jesus, 2and what-things you-heard from me through many witnesses—these-things entrust to-faithful men who will-be able to-teach others.  3Suffer-hardship-with (me) as (a) good soldier of-Christ Jesus.  4Nobody, serving-as-a-soldier, gets-mixed-up-in the affairs of-[the] everyday-life, in-order-that he-may-please the-one having-recruited-(him)-as-a-soldier.  5And also if anybody competes-as-an-athlete, he-does┘not└win-the-crown unless2 he competes according-to-the-rules/legally.  6It-is-necessary-for the laboring farmer to-share-in the crops first.  7Think-over what I-am-saying, for the Lord will-give you understanding in all-things.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Timothy 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-timothy-chapter-3&#34;&gt;2 Timothy Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now know this:  that in (the) last days hard times will-be-present.  2For [the] men will-be self-lovers, lovers-of-silver, boasters, arrogant, slanderers, disobedient to-parents, ungrateful, not-lovers-of-good, 3lacking-natural-affection, heartless, malicious-gossiping-ones, without-self-control, vicious, not-loving-good, 4treacherous, reckless, having-been-puffed-up-with-pride, lovers-of-pleasure rather than lovers-of-God, 5having the/a form of-godliness but having-denyed the power of-it, and avoid these-(men).  6For out-of these are the-ones sneaking-into [the] houses and seducing morally-weak-women having-been-weighed-down with sins, led-on by-various desires, 7always learningfem, and never able to-come to (a) knowledge of-(the)-truth.  8And in-the-same-way2 Jannes and Jambres opposed Moses, so also these oppose the truth, men having-been-corrupted with-regard-to-the mind, rejected concerning the faith.  9But they-will┘not└progress on further, for the foolishness of-them will-be clear to-all, as also the (foolishness) of-those-(men) became (clear).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Timothy 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/2-timothy/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-timothy-chapter-4&#34;&gt;2 Timothy Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; I-solemnly-charge (you) before [the] God and Christ Jesus, the-One going to-judge (the) living and (the) dead, and with-respect-to-the appearing of-him and the kingdom of-him:  2preach the word, be-ready in season (and) out-of-season; refute, rebuke, encourage with all longsuffering and teaching.  3For (the) time will-be when they-will┘not└put-up-with/endure [the] sound teaching; but according-to [the] their-own desires, they-will-accumulate for-themselves teachers itchingnom with-respect-to-the what-they-hear, 4and will-wander-off-from/turn-away-from the truth with-respect-to-the message, and will turn-aside to [the] myths.  5But you be-self-controlled in all-things, suffer-hardship, do (the) work of-(an)-evangelist, fulfill the ministry of-you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
