<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Funerals on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/categories/funerals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Funerals on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/categories/funerals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>For All the Saints Who from Their Labors Rest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/for-all-the-saints-who-from-their-labors-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/for-all-the-saints-who-from-their-labors-rest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For All the Saints Who from Their Labors Rest&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;William Walsham How&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For all the saints who from their labors rest,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who Thee by faith before the world confessed,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thy name, O Jesus, be forever blest.  Alleluia!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou wast their rock, their fortress, and their might;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou, Lord, their captain in the well-fought fight;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thou, in the darkness dread, their one true light.  Alleluia!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O may Thy soldiers, faithful, true, and bold,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jennifer Chantell Wenzl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/jennifer-chantell-wenzl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/jennifer-chantell-wenzl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Chantell Wenzl&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the Wenzls, I want to thank you for this wonderful demonstration of support for the family and for such an overwhelming expression of love for Jenny in this time of intense sorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grief is our response to loss, and the deepest loss is the loss of a person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not so much what a person does for/with us, but who she is as expressed through her actions toward us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raymond F. Schober</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/raymond-f-schober/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/raymond-f-schober/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raymond F. Schober&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Raymond F. Schober, 71, of Vermillion, Kansas, died Saturday evening, February 20, 1999, at the hospital in Onaga, Kansas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mr. Schober owned and operated Schober’s Service in Vermillion since 1955 and Dutch’s Place since 1965.  From 1980 to 1994 he was a field engineer for Associated Engineers.  He served on a U. S. Navy minesweeper in the Pacific Theater during World War II.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Born on March 14, 1927 in Rossville, Kansas, to Fred and Mary Schober, Raymond later attended school in Centralia.  He was a member of the Vermillion Christian Church, American Legion Post #257, VFW Post #1359, and was active in the city council of Vermillion.  He married Daisy Willard on December 24, 1950, in Westmoreland.  She survives of the home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE LEGACY OF DORCAS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-legacy-of-dorcas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-legacy-of-dorcas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE LEGACY OF DORCAS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 9:35-42&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What We Learn from Experience&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Peter came to Joppa that day, they began showing him the garments and coats Dorcas had made. I venture to say, they did not do that because the garments were nicely made, although no doubt they were. I venture to say, they did not do that because she was a good seamstress, although she probably was. I venture to say, they did not do that because the garments were expensive, although she may have used the best material she could find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PASSING OF JAIRUS’ DAUGHTER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-passing-of-jairus-daughter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/the-passing-of-jairus-daughter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PASSING OF JAIRUS’ DAUGHTER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 8:49-55)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Her name is not given, but she was twelve. The father, a ruler of the synagogue, did what desperate fathers do: he went to find the only help he knew, because she was ill and very weak. At the earnest urging of Jairus, our Lord turned that day from present labors and walked beside a worried man toward the object of his care.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
