<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SABBATH-SUNDAY on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/sabbath-sunday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SABBATH-SUNDAY on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/sabbath-sunday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ADDED NOTATIONS ON SABBATH OBSERVANCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/added-notations-on-sabbath-observance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/added-notations-on-sabbath-observance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ADDED NOTATIONS ON SABBATH OBSERVANCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discussions with seventh-day Christians include five questions. (1) The first question asks for the scripture basis for “changing” Saturday to Sunday as the day of observance. That question miswords the issue. It “begs the question” by assuming that the issue involves a change from one day to the other. Our approach notes that Sabbath was a memorial of the exodus, a Jewish national holiday; so there is no basis for Sabbath observance outside the context of Jewish national life. There will be no “scripture basis” for “changing” from Sabbath to Sunday, because there was no “change.” The two items are not in series but in parallel. The two days have different meanings relative to different “nations” and different founding events. It is not a matter of one continuing entity changing one of its national holidays from one day to another. Since this matter relates to the change of covenants, consult the essay entitled “Old Testament Covenants and the Messianic Covenant.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SUNDAY WORSHIP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sunday-worship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/sunday-worship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SUNDAY WORSHIP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Worship on Saturday after sundown&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the New Testament we encounter the Jewish custom of reckoning days from sundown to sundown as distinguished from the Roman reckoning from midnight to midnight. The question sometimes comes up whether Christians today could have church on Saturday evening instead of Sunday morning and/or Sunday evening.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do not conceive of Sunday as beginning at dark the night before. It is doubtful that we would be associating Saturday evening with the Lord’s resurrection day. It would still be, as we say, Saturday evening. Of course, not all Christian gatherings have to associate the time of gathering with the time of his resurrection; but it is most appropriate to incorporate that association into the “stated” gathering time. All clear passages about the time of gathering in the New Testament place it on Sunday rather than some other day. Meeting on the day of his resurrection was consistent enough that “the Lord’s Day” (κυριακὴ ἡμέρα) became a designation for the first day of the week (Revelation. 1:10).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE SABBATH AS A MEMORIAL OF THE EXODUS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-sabbath-as-a-memorial-of-the-exodus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-sabbath-as-a-memorial-of-the-exodus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE SABBATH AS A MEMORIAL OF THE EXODUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Sabbath observance was not a memorial of the creation. If it were, it would have been observed as long as this creation stands: from the beginning, by all nations, till the end of time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. The Sabbath is a memorial only of the exodus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;A memorial will not be a memorial of two unrelated events. The emphasis here is on realities. The creation and the Sabbath are both associated with the week, but they are not related by their nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
