<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>THEOLOGY on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/theology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in THEOLOGY on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/theology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE NATURE OF THEOLOGY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NATURE OF THEOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The Nature of Theology vs. Exegesis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the most part, the epistles of the New Testament are problem-solution writings; they were written to deal with difficulties in particular times and places. In the process of answering the problems, the apostles drew upon information on many topics that relate to the need. Not everything about any one topic is in any one place; so readers have to assemble the partial treatments and combine them to form the whole picture. In exegesis, readers follow along the present line of presentation. Theology requires an added step beyond following the line of thought: the readers topically arrange the data into a harmonious whole so they can understand the message itself instead of just one presentation that contains parts of that whole. Exegesis deals with the text; theology deals with the topic. Exegesis operates verse by verse; theology operates with the truth itself as information gathered from the several contexts that address it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THEOLOGY AND LIBERAL ARTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/theology-and-liberal-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/theology-and-liberal-arts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THEOLOGY AND LIBERAL ARTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Theology establishes the context for liberal arts. It is the discipline of the whole, the discipline of the ultimate. It addresses what is original, eternal, central, basic, ultimate, and all-inclusive. As such, theology affirms first that reality is cohesive rather than chaotic—that the parts have a whole to be part of. Theology calls for “centeredness” and centers reality in the Creator rather than the creation and in the Teacher rather than the student. By implication, theology contextualizes all other disciplines as sub-disciplines, integrates them into one whole, relates them to each another, limits their province, and critiques their methods and findings in at least a restrictive sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
