<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ephesians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/ephesians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ephesians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/ephesians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ACCEPTING THE PAULINE CORPUS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/accepting-the-pauline-corpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/accepting-the-pauline-corpus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ACCEPTING THE PAULINE CORPUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hebrews&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Titus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Timothy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Timothy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;modern order of&#x9;&#x9;2 Thessalonians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;being questioned&#x9;3&#x9;1 Thessalonians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philemon&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Colossians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philippians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Galatians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 Corinthians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romans&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a distinction between progressivism and evolution, the one being forward movement while the latter is simply modification. Progressivism in the 1800s expressed itself in post-millennialism and in biblical criticism in the Tübingen school, which denied to Paul all his letters except four: Romans, 1 Corinthians, 2 Corinthians, and Galatians. German rationalism postulated a long upward development pattern that brought about the Christian literary canon as late as A.D. 180. In the 1900s, this extreme gave way to a more reasonable approach that did not see a need for 150 years to develop the New Testament documents. Some, like John A. T. Robinson went to the opposite extreme by saying that all the New Testament books could have existed by A.D. 70. World War I smashed the onward-and-upward hopefulness about humankind, and led to pre-millennialism eschatologically and a turn toward less extreme critical viewpoints in New Testament studies. The evolutionary framework is still presupposed, but Paul is usually allowed to have at least nine of the letters that ancient Christian writers assigned to him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF EPHESIANS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-ephesians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/characteristics-and-peculiarities-of-ephesians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHARACTERISTICS AND PECULIARITIES OF EPHESIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;distinctive expressions include&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“in the heavenlies [ἐν τοῖς οὐρανοῖς]”: 1:3, 20; 2:6; 3:10; 6:12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“to the praise of the/his glory (of his grace)”: 1:6, 12, 14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“the new man [ὁ καινὸς ἄνθρωπος]”: 2:15; 4:25 (cp. ὁ νεὸς ἄνθρωπος in Colossians 3:10)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Along with Colossians (1:26-27; 2:2; 4:3) and Romans (16:25), Ephesians uses mystery (μυστήριον, mystērion) to refer to the previously unrevealed fact that Gentiles as Gentiles have access to fellowship with God through faith: 1:9; 3:3-9; 6:19. (See notations on Colossians.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOODSPEED’S ARGUMENTS AGAINST THE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/goodspeeds-arguments-against-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/goodspeeds-arguments-against-the/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GOODSPEED’S ARGUMENTS AGAINST THE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PAULINE AUTHORSHIP OF EPHESIANS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians reflects no definite, localized, historical situation which it is intended to meet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesians does represent a historical situation. Tychicus is the bearer, who will tell a definite readership about the affairs of Paul. The lack of detailed historical and geographical data is offset by its probable encyclical destination and its hortatory-doctrinal purpose. Furthermore, since Ephesians was published contemporary with Colossians and borne by the same messengers, historical details were not of such importance, being available from the bearers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MATTERS THAT AFFECT STYLE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/matters-that-affect-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/matters-that-affect-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MATTERS THAT AFFECT STYLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Higher critics do not allow a wide enough range of style variance in New Testament authors. The items below have implication for greater variety in style.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Subject matter&#x9;&#x9;Complex problems tend to cause complex presentations. Certain (topic)&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;subjects call for special vocabulary. What we are trying to combat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;determines terminology: “faith and works” (Judaism), “fullness” (Gnosticism), priesthood (new subject). For the sake of meeting the minds of the ones we want to address, we use the vocabulary of the other in reference to our own subject so there can be a correlation of parts of thought systems, or functional equivalents. Becoming/being a Christian we might call a natural “high” because of the modern drug scene. Vocabulary generated by such circumstances will be peculiar to the circumstance (cp. “circumcision of the heart,” “fullness of the godhead,” “armor of salvation”).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NEW TESTAMENT STUDIES AND THE USE OF AMANUENSES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/new-testament-studies-and-the-use-of-amanuenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/new-testament-studies-and-the-use-of-amanuenses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NEW TESTAMENT STUDIES AND THE USE OF AMANUENSES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The majority of New Testament writings are letters, so we expect them to reflect practices in first-century letter writing. One custom was using an amanuensis, a stenographer who wrote down the contents. Biblical studies do not give this factor much attention even though New Testament writers used amanuenses. The oversight seems unusual to us today since most of us in the Western world write our own correspondence. If we do employ a secretary, it is primarily for computer skills. We are accustomed to reproducing by typeset, copiers, or computer printers. But ancient writers had to use different methods. If the work of an amanuensis can impact New Testament studies, we should allow that to affect our thinking where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USE OF AMANUENSES IN THE NEW TESTAMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/use-of-amanuenses-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/use-of-amanuenses-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;USE OF AMANUENSES IN THE NEW TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Overview)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Basic Data Regarding Amanuenses&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul used amanuenses                                    Paragraphs explained as Pauline&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;postscripts&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Romans 16:22&#x9;16:25-27 after 15:33; 16:20 (21-23)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;1 Corinthians 16:21&#x9;16:21-23* after 16:19-20&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C.&#x9;2 Corinthians&#x9;13:(13-)14 after 13:12 (-13)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;D.&#x9;Galatians (6:11-18?)&#x9;6:11-18?*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;E.&#x9;Ephesians&#x9;6:23-24?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;F.&#x9;Philippians&#x9;4:21-23&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;G.&#x9;Colossians 4:18&#x9;4:18*&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;H.&#x9;1 Thessalonians&#x9;5:28&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. &#x9;2 Thessalonians 3:17&#x9;3:17-18* after 3:16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;J.&#x9;1 Timothy&#x9;6:21b&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
