<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Galatians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Galatians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Galatians 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;galatians-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Galatians Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul, (an) apostle not from men nor through men, but through Jesus Christ and God (the) Father, the-one having-raised him from (the) dead, 2and all the brothers with me to-the churches of-[the] Galatia. 3Grace to-you and peace from God (the) Father of-us and (the) Lord Jesus Christ, 4the-One having-given himself on-behalf-of the sins of-us, in-order-that he-might-deliver us from the present [the] evil world according-to the will of-the God and Father of-us, 5to-whom (be) [the] for the ages of the ages. Amen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galatians 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;galatians-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Galatians Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Then after fourteen years again I-went-up to Jerusalem with Barnabas, also taking┘Titus└along. 2But I-went-up by revelation and I-put-before them the gospel that I-was-preaching among the Gentiles, but privately to-the reputed-ones lest somehow I-would-be-running or had-run in vain. 3But not-even Titus the-one with me, being (a) Greek, was-compelled to-be-circumcised. 4But because-of secretly-come-in false-brothers, who-slipped-in to-spy-out the liberty of-us that we-have in Christ Jesus, in-order-that they-would-bring┘us└into-bondage, 5to-whom not-even for (an) hour did-we-yield to-[the] subjection, in-order-that the truth of-the gospel might-remain with you. 6But from the-ones reputed to-be something—whatever at-the-time they-were matters nothing to-me; [the] God does┘not└receive (the) face of-(a)-man—for the reputed-ones added nothing to-me. 7But to-the-contrary, seeing that I-had-been-entrusted-with the gospel of-the uncircumcision as Peter (with the gospel) of-the circumcision—8for the-one having-worked for-Peter in (the) apostleship of-the circumcision also worked for-me in the Gentiles—9and, knowing the grace [the] given to-me, James and Cephas and John, the reputed to-be pillars, gave to-me and to-Barnabas (the) right (hands) that we (might go) to the Gentiles, and they to the circumcision; 10only in-order-that we-might-remember the poor, which also I┘myself└was-eager to-do this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galatians 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;galatians-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Galatians Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; O foolish Galatians, who put┘you└under-a-spell, to-whom according-to eyes Jesus Christ was-displayed crucified? 2This only do-I-want to-learn from you: did-you-receive the Spirit by works of-law or (the) hearing of-faith? 3Are-you so foolish, having-begun with-spirit, are-you┘now└trying-to-finish with flesh? 4Did-you-suffer so-many-things for-nothing—if indeed2 (it was) for-nothing? 5So then, the-one providing the Spirit to-you and working miracles among you—(does he do it) by works of-law or by (the) hearing of-faith? 6Even-as Abraham &amp;ldquo;believed [the] God, and it-was-regarded to-him for righteousness.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galatians 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;galatians-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Galatians Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Now I-say, for as-long┘(a) time└as the/an heir is (a) minor, he-differs with-respect-to-nothing from-(a)-slave, though-being lord of-all, 2but is under guardians and trustees until the pre-set-time of-the father. 3So also we, when we-were minors, were enslaved by the basic-rules of-the world; 4but when the fullness of-[the] time came, [the] God sent-out the Son of-him, becoming from woman, become under law, 5in-order-that he-might-redeem the-ones under law in-order-that we-might-receive [the] sonship-by-adoption. 6And because you-are sons, [the] God sent-out the Spirit of-the Son of-him into the hearts of-us, crying-out, &amp;ldquo;Abba, [the] Father.&amp;rdquo; 7So-that yousg are no-longer (a) slave, but (a) son; and if (a) son, also (an) heir through God. 8But at-that-time, not knowing God, you-served the-ones by-nature not being gods. 9But now, having-come-to-know God—but rather having-been-known by God, how do-you-turn-back again to the weak and beggarly elements which you-desire to-serve back again? 10You-observe days and months and seasons and years. 11I-am-afraid-for you lest somehow I-have-labored for you for-nothing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galatians 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;galatians-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Galatians Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Christ certainly set┘us└free3; so stand-firm and do┘not again└be-subject to-(a)-yoke of-bondage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Behold, I, Paul, tell you that if you are circumcised, Christ will┘not└benefit you anything. 3And I-testify again to every man (that is) circumcised that he is (a) debtor to-do the whole Law. 4You-have-been-cut-off from Christ, (you) who are-justified by law; you-fell from [the] grace. 5For we by-(the)-spirit out-of trust are-waiting-for (the) hope of-righteousness. 6For in Christ Jesus neither circumcision accomplishes anything nor uncircumcision, but trust working through love.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galatians 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/wooden-nt/galatians/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;galatians-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Galatians Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Brothers, even if (a) man is-caught-up in any sin, you the-ones spiritual restore [the] such-(a person) in (the) spirit of-humility/gentleness, watching yourselves lest you also get-tempted. 2Bear the burdens of-one-another, and in-this way fulfill the &amp;rsquo;law&amp;rsquo; of-[the] Christ. 3For if anybody thinks (himself) to-be something, being nothing, he-deceives himself. 4But let┘each└examine the work of-himself, and then he-will-have [the] boasting to himself only and not to the other-(person). 5For each will-bear [the] his-own burden. 6But let┘the-one taught the word└share-with the-one teaching in all good-things. 7Do┘not└be-deceived; God is┘not└mocked. For what (a) man sows—this he-will┘also└reap; 8because the-one sowing to-the flesh of-himself will-reap from the flesh corruption, but the-one sowing to the spirit will-reap from the spirit eternal life. 9But doing [the] good, let-us┘not└become-discouraged, for in-our-own-time we-will-reap, not giving-up. 10So then, as we-have opportunity, let-us-work-(hard at) the good-thing toward all, but especially toward the-ones of-(the)-household of-[the] faith/trust.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
