<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ephesians on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ephesians on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul, apostle of ChristMessiah Jesus by God&amp;rsquo;s will, to the saints [in Ephesus]ms and faithful in Christ Jesus. 2Grace and peace from God our Father and the Lord Jesus Christ.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ. He&amp;rsquo;s blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in high places. 4Before he founded the world, he chose us in Christ to be holy and blameless in his presence in love. 5It pleased him to destine us ahead of time to be his children through Jesus Christ. 6So we praise the glorious grace he freely extended to us in the Beloved. 7He redeemed us by his blood, and that forgiveness demonstrates the rich grace 8he lavished on us by providing us wisdom and insight. 9He let us know his previously unrevealed will that, in his good pleasure, he intended for Christ 10to oversee when the time came. He chose to sum up everything in Christ in heaven and on earth. 11In him we&amp;rsquo;ve become an inheritance for the One who accomplishes everything according to his own counsel and purpose. 12As a result of what he&amp;rsquo;s done, we praise his glory—we who have already placed our hope in Christ. 13You&amp;rsquo;ve heard the truth as well—the good news about salvation—and put your trust in him; and he has sealed you with the Holy Spirit he promised. 14The Spirit is God&amp;rsquo;s pledge to give us our full inheritance when he redeems his people—to the praise of his glory.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; You were &amp;lsquo;dead&amp;rsquo; because of the sins 2you once lived in like the rest of the world. It was a way of living that corresponded to the ruler of the power in the air, the spirit that operates in disobedient people. 3Among those people at one time we all lived by fleshly drives. We were doing what the flesh and imagination desired. Our character made us objects of God&amp;rsquo;s anger like everybody else. 4But God was so merciful because he loved us so much. 5We &amp;lsquo;died&amp;rsquo; by sinning, but he &amp;lsquo;made us alive&amp;rsquo; with Christ (by grace he saved us). 6He raised us up with him and seated us with him in high places. 7In the coming ages, what he did will show the tremendous wealth of his grace and kindness toward us in Christ Jesus. 8By grace we&amp;rsquo;re saved people through faith, and that salvation doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from us; it&amp;rsquo;s God&amp;rsquo;s gift; 9so we can&amp;rsquo;t be proud. 10We&amp;rsquo;re his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for living the way God designed us ahead of time to live. 11-12So, you Gentiles in the flesh—called Uncircumcision by the handmade Circumcision in the flesh, remember that you were separated from Christ at that time. You were excluded from the Commonwealth of Israel, without hope, and without God in the world. 13But you that were once afar off have come near through Christ&amp;rsquo;s blood. 14-15Christ is the basis for peace between us. He made both of us into one group and tore down the wall that separated us. In his flesh he abrogated the Law that&amp;rsquo;s made up of regulations. That way, from the two groups he could create in himself one new united mankind and could make peace between us. 16He could reconcile both of us to God in one body through the cross. In himself he killed the hostility. 17He came and offered peace to you that were far away and to us that were close by. 18Through him we both have access to the Father by one Spirit. 19So you&amp;rsquo;re not strangers and aliens anymore, but fellow citizens and members of God&amp;rsquo;s family. 20You&amp;rsquo;re built on the foundation of the apostles and prophets with Christ Jesus as the cornerstone. 21In Christ the whole building fits together and grows upward to become a holy sanctuary. 22In him you&amp;rsquo;re growing along with us into a spiritual house for God in the person of the Spirit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m Christ&amp;rsquo;s prisoner for you Gentiles. 2You&amp;rsquo;ve heard about the stewardship of grace God gave me for you. 3He revealed to me his previously unrevealed message, like I noted briefly before. 4When you read it, you can understand my insight into that message about Christ. 5In other generations God hadn&amp;rsquo;t made it known to anybody, but now the Spirit has revealed it to his holy apostles and prophets. 6This is the message: Gentiles are fellow heirs, fellow members of the body, fellow partakers of the promise available in Christ Jesus through the good news. 7I became a minister of that message by the grace God gave me in keeping with his powerful working. 8To me, the least of the saints, he gave this grace to present to Gentiles Christ&amp;rsquo;s amazing riches 9and to bring to light the message that in ages past God kept to himself, who created everything. 10The church can make known to rulers and authorities in high places the many forms of God&amp;rsquo;s wisdom. 11That comes from the eternal purpose he brought about in Christ our Lord. 12In him we have confident bold access because we trust him. 13So don&amp;rsquo;t get discouraged over my difficulties on your behalf. They honor you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So I, a prisoner in the Lord, urge you to live appropriate to your calling—2with humility and gentleness, with patience toward each other in love. 3Make every effort to maintain spiritual unity* by being bound together with peace.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s one body, one Spirit, one hope you&amp;rsquo;re called to,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; Christ has measured out grace to each of you, 8like it says,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v9&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; What does &amp;ldquo;he ascended&amp;rdquo; involve but that he had also descended to earth? 10And the One that had descended also ascended above the skies to complete everything. 11He &amp;ldquo;gave&amp;rdquo; apostles, prophets, evangelists, and pastor-teachers 12to equip the saints for service and to build up Christ&amp;rsquo;s body. 13That work goes on till we become one in trusting and knowing God&amp;rsquo;s Son and are full-grown as measured by the stature of Christ. 14That&amp;rsquo;s so we won&amp;rsquo;t stay like little kids, tossed back and forth and blown around by every idea that sly people devise to trick us. 15Let&amp;rsquo;s speak the truth in love and grow up in Christ in every respect. 16He&amp;rsquo;s the head that unites the whole body. Every ligament holds it together so each part can contribute properly to the growth of the body as it builds itself up in love.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So imitate God like children he loves. 2Live in love like Christ loved you and gave himself for you as an offering, a sacrifice to God for a sweet fragrance. 3Don&amp;rsquo;t let immorality, impurity, or greed even be mentioned among you, as is appropriate for saints. 4Don&amp;rsquo;t allow any indecency or foolish, vulgar talk among you; express gratitude instead. 5Know for certain that no immoral, impure, or covetous person—covetousness amounts to idolatry—will inherit anything in the kingdom of Christ and God.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephesians 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/ephesians/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ephesians-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Ephesians Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Children, obey your parents in the Lord; it&amp;rsquo;s the right thing to do. 2-3&amp;quot;Honor your father and mother so you&amp;rsquo;ll live long and well&amp;quot; [Ex 20:12; Deut. 5:16] (the first commandment with a promise attached). 4Dads, don&amp;rsquo;t make your kids resent you. Raise them up in the Lord&amp;rsquo;s instruction and discipline.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Servants, obey your masters with fear and trembling, sincerely as if obeying Christ. 6Don&amp;rsquo;t just try to create impressions to please them; but as Christ&amp;rsquo;s servants, do God&amp;rsquo;s will honestly 7with good intentions. Be serving the Lord, as it were, not people. 8Understand that whatever each of you does, you&amp;rsquo;ll receive it back from the Lord whether you&amp;rsquo;re a servant or free. 9Masters, treat your servants the same way. Give up making threats; you know that their Lord and yours is in heaven, and he doesn&amp;rsquo;t show preferences.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
