<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PREPARATION for Ministry on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/preparation-for-ministry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PREPARATION for Ministry on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/preparation-for-ministry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIAN LIBERAL ARTS EDUCATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christian-liberal-arts-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christian-liberal-arts-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIAN LIBERAL ARTS EDUCATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People have different reasons for getting an education. (a) Education for knowledge is a German emphasis. The goal is accuracy and completeness in any field of study. If anything develops out of that knowledge, well and good; but the stress falls on knowledge for its own sake and the love for learning as such.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What has been a British emphasis is (b) education for culture. The goal consists of fulfilling expectancies associated with a person’s position in the social structure. Cultured people should know their way around in the world, be able to converse intelligently about what goes on there, and be able to place themselves and their society in the proper historical niche. The upper classes serve as tradition bearers who give stability to the present social structure. As a primary function, education reinforces social position.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EDUCATION FOR USE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/education-for-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/education-for-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EDUCATION FOR USE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Teaching Task&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bible colleges adapt higher education in partial preparation for ministry. On the one hand, they obviously differ from “secular” institutions by presenting courses from a Christian perspective. Unlike seminaries, Bible colleges begin ministry preparation at the undergraduate level. They differ also from Christian liberal arts institutions by including mostly those courses that have the greatest transfer to ministry, by teaching them with a view to ministering, by reducing the emphasis on liberal arts as such, and by including practical courses. On the other hand, Bible colleges do not try to become simply vocational-technical schools. In both practical and conceptual aspects of the curriculum, a governing principle for Bible colleges is “education for use.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FORMAL PREPARATION FOR MINISTRY: THE 18-30 YEARS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/formal-preparation-for-ministry-the-18-30-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/formal-preparation-for-ministry-the-18-30-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FORMAL PREPARATION FOR MINISTRY: THE 18-30 YEARS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graduating someone with a ministry degree does not necessarily increase the number of personnel in permanent ministry. Several factors contribute to significant attrition, especially during the early years of ministry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes opportunities come for pursuing other interests that are more financially rewarding. More often, however, leaving the ministry stems from disillusionment, lack of fulfillment, inability to get people to respond to one’s leadership, frustration, little sense of progress. Adjusting the manner of preparation will not eliminate the problem, but adjustments in the way we conceive of ministry preparation will preserve for service a greater number of ministerial graduates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LANGUAGE, EXEGESIS, AND THEOLOGY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/language-exegesis-and-theology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/language-exegesis-and-theology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LANGUAGE, EXEGESIS, AND THEOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biblical languages, texts, and topics naturally combine for study that undergirds personal growth and Christian ministry. Acquaintance with the original languages of scripture raises options not suggested by the English, eliminates possibilities English wording might allow, and gives access to additional study tools. Furthermore, a knowledge of Greek and Hebrew facilitates the evaluation of points made by other commentators on the biblical text, a great advantage to ministers, because we are constantly called upon to deal with doctrinal issues purportedly based on “the original.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE GOAL OF A “THEOLOGICAL” EDUCATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-goal-of-a-theological-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-goal-of-a-theological-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE GOAL OF A “THEOLOGICAL” EDUCATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People have different reasons for pursuing an education. (a) Education for knowledge has been considered a German emphasis. The goal consists of accuracy and completeness in any field of study. If anything develops out of that knowledge, well and good; but the stress falls on knowledge for its own sake and the love for learning as such.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What has been regarded as a British emphasis is (b) education for culture. The goal here consists of fulfilling expectancies associated with one’s position in the social structure. Cultured people should know their way around in the world, be able to converse intelligently about what goes on there, and be able to place themselves and their society in the proper historical niche. The upper classes serve as tradition bearers who contribute to the stability of the present social structure. As a primary function, education reinforces social position.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRUTH AND EDUCATION IN A CHRISTIAN WORLDVIEW</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/truth-and-education-in-a-christian-worldview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/truth-and-education-in-a-christian-worldview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRUTH AND EDUCATION IN A CHRISTIAN WORLDVIEW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the trial of Jesus, Pilate remarked, “What is truth?” Jesus had just explained that he came into the world to “bear witness to the truth.” Interestingly, the truth issue does occupy the central reason for the personal incarnation of God into the world of human persons. It establishes the agenda for the followers of Christ, for “education that is Christian,” and for ministry preparation through an education process. As goes the view of truth, so goes the nature of education and the process of preparing for that education of the world that is called evangelism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
