<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bible Resources on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/bible-resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bible Resources on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/bible-resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 KINGS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/1-kings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/1-kings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 KINGS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David in His Old Age&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1When King David got old, they covered him with blankets, but he still had the chills. 2His advisers told him, “Have us look for a young virgin so she can attend you, become your nurse, and lie in your arms to keep you warm.” 3They searched throughout Israel for a beautiful girl and found Abishag the Shunammite, and brought her to the king. 4She became his nurse, but he didn’t have relations with her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 KINGS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/2-kings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/2-kings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 KINGS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yahveh’s Judgment on Ahaziah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1After Ahab died, Moab revolted against Israel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Ahaziah fell through the lattice in his upper room in Samaria and seriously injured himself. He told messengers to go ask Baal-zebub, Ekron’s god, if he’d recover. 3But the angel of Yahveh told Elijah the Tishbite,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Go meet the king’s messengers and say, ‘Are you asking Baal-zebub because there’s no God in Israel?’ 4So Yahveh says you won’t get out of bed. You’ll die.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 SAMUEL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/2-samuel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/2-samuel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 SAMUEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;David Learns of Saul’s Death&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1After Saul died, David came back from massacring the Amalekites and stayed two days in Ziklag. 2The third day, a man came from Saul’s camp with torn clothes and dust on his head, and prostrated himself to David.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3David said, “Where have you come from?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I’ve escaped from Israel’s camp.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4“How did things go?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“They’ve fled from the battle; many have fallen. Saul and his sons Jonathan are dead.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AMOS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/amos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/amos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AMOS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1The Message of Amos, Shepherd from Tekoa, That He Saw About Israel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at the Time of Uzziah, King of Judah, and Jeroboam Ben-Joash, King of Israel,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two Years Before the Earthquake&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2He said,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Yahveh will roar from Zion;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;he’ll thunder from Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The shepherds’ pastures will dry up;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the grass on Carmel’s summit will wither away.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God’s Judgment on Israel’s Neighbors&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3Yahveh says,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“For three sins of Damascus and for four,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMPOSITE ACCOUNT OF CORNELIUS’ CONVERSION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/composite-account-of-cornelius-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/composite-account-of-cornelius-conversion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMPOSITE ACCOUNT OF CORNELIUS’ CONVERSION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts 10:1-24 (Caesarea/Joppa); 10:25-48 (Caesarea); 11:1-18 (Jerusalem)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(wording found in more than one segment)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[generalization] [italics viewpoint adjustment]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(presented as from Peter’s defense in Jerusalem)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11:1The apostles and brothers in Judaea heard that Gentiles had received God’s message. 2When Peter went up to Jerusalem, members of the Circumcision took issue with him, 3“You went in and ate with uncircumcised men.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Peter explained step by step. 10:1“A centurion in Caesarea named Cornelius, from the Italian cohort, 2is a devout God-fearer along with his whole house. 30He gave considerable charitable gifts to the people and prayed to God constantly. He was keeping three p.m. prayer in his house. 3In a vision he saw clearly an angel of God coming and standing in front of him, ‘Cornelius.’&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMPOSITE ACCOUNT OF PAUL’S CONVERSION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/composite-account-of-pauls-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/composite-account-of-pauls-conversion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMPOSITE ACCOUNT OF PAUL’S CONVERSION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(as if told to Agrippa)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Acts 9:1b-22; 22:4-16; 26:10-20;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;common material; 3rd to 1st person)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I persecuted The Way to death, binding and imprisoning men and women as the high priest and presbytery can confirm. That’s what I did in Jerusalem. Not only did I lock up many saints in prison with the authority of the chief priests; but when they were being put to death, I voted against them. When I punished them often in every synagogue, I tried to make them blaspheme. I was insanely furious and started persecuting them even to foreign cities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversational Yahveh Covenant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/conversational-yahveh-covenant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/conversational-yahveh-covenant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JOB&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Job lived in the land of Uz, a blameless, godly man that respected God and shunned evil. 2He had seven sons and three daughters; 3and owned 7,000 sheep, 3,000 camels, 500 yoke of oxen, 500 female donkeys; and many servants. 4His sons would hold feasts in each other’s houses and invite their three sisters. 5When the feasting days had completed their cycle, Job would consecrate them, getting up early and offering burnt offerings for each one, “Maybe my children have sinned and cursed God in their hearts.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DANIEL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/daniel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/daniel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DANIEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Daniel Taken to Babylon&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1In the third year of Jehoiakim’s reign in Judah, Nebuchadnezzar, king of Babylon, laid siege to Jerusalem. 2Yahveh delivered Jehoiakim to him, along with articles from God’s Temple. He took them to the temple of his god in the land of Shinar/Babylonia and put them in the treasury. 3He ordered Ashpenaz, his chief eunuch, to bring in some of the Israelites, including members of the royal family and the nobles, 4young men with no defects, good looking, intelligent, educated men that could serve in the king’s court. He had him teach them the language and literature of the Babylonians, 5and allotted them a daily ration of the royal food and the wine he drank. He assigned them three years of education; then they were to enter his personal service. 6Among them were Daniel, Hananiah, Mishael, and Azariah from the tribe of Judah. 7The chief eunuch renamed them: Daniel was Belteshazzar, Hananiah was Shadrach, Mishael was Meshach, and Azariah was Abed-nego.&#x9;Dan 1:1-7&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESTHER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/esther/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/esther/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ESTHER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;King Xerxes’ Banquet&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Ahasuerus/Xerxes ruled from India to Nubia over 127 provinces [486-65 B.C.]. 2In his third year on his throne in Susa the capital, 3he held a banquet for his nobles and officials, the army chiefs of Persia and Media, and the nobles and governors of the provinces. 4For 180 days he showed the wealth of his royal glory and the splendor and pomp of his majesty. 5After that, he gave everybody there—least and greatest—a banquet that lasted a week in the court of his palace garden. 6There were white cotton curtains and blue hangings held up by cords of fine purple linen on silver rings and marble pillars. There were gold and silver couches on a mosaic pavement made out of porphyry, marble, mother-of-pearl, and precious stones. 7Drinks were served in gold cups of different kinds, and the royal wine was plentiful according to the king’s bounty. 8The drinking was done by law: attendees were not compelled, because the king had ordered each official of his household to follow each person’s wishes. 9Queen Vashti also gave a banquet for the women in the king’s palace.&#x9;&#x9;Esther 1:1-9&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EXODUS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/exodus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/exodus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EXODUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Israel’s descendants and their households that went to Egypt with Jacob: 2Reuben, Simeon, Levi, Judah, 3Issachar, Zebulun, Benjamin, 4Dan, Naphtali, Gad, and Asher: 570 people (though Joseph was already there)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6That whole generation died, 7but Israel’s descendants multiplied and became so numerous they filled the country.&#x9;Ex 1:1-7&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Israelites Oppressed&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;8In time, a new king came to power in Egypt who didn’t know Joseph. 9He told his people, “There are too many Israelites, and they’re too strong. 10Let’s deal with them wisely so, if there’s war, they won’t join our enemies and leave.” 11They appointed taskmasters and subjected the Israelites to hard labor. They built storage cities for Pharaoh: Pithom and Raamses. 12But the more they mistreated them, the more they multiplied and spread. The Egyptians were afraid of them [13] 14and made their lives miserable, making bricks and mortar and laboring in the fields. &#x9;Ex 1:8-14&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EZEKIEL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/ezekiel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/ezekiel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EZEKIEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Vision of Living Beings and&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the Glory of Yahveh&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1The fifth day, fourth month, thirtieth year, I was by the Chebar River with the exiles. The sky opened up, and I saw a vision of God. (2The fifth month, fifth year of Jehoiachin’s exile, 3God’s message came to Ezekiel, and God’s hand came on him.) 4A strong north wind was blowing, and a large cloud with a bright glow around it flashed constantly with lightning. In the cloud was something like glowing metal 5and four figures like living beings with human forms. 6Each one had four faces and four wings. 7They had straight legs, and their feet resembled calf hooves that shined like polished bronze. 8There were hands under their wings, 9and the wings of all four touched each other. Their faces didn’t turn as they moved straight forward. 10Each one had the faces of a man, an eagle, a lion on the right, and a bull on the left. 11Their wings spread out above them, two wings touching the wings of the next living beings and two covering their bodies. 12They went straight forward wherever the spirit went, without turning as they went. 13Among the beings were what looked like burning coals, like torches moving back and forth. The fire burned bright, and lightning kept flashing out of it. 14The living beings darted back forth like bolts of lightning.&#x9;Ezek 1:1-14&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EZRA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/ezra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/ezra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EZRA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cyrus Lets the Exiles Return&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1In the first year of Cyrus, king of Persia, to fulfill his message through Jeremiah, Yahveh stirred up Cyrus. He sent a written proclamation everywhere in his kingdom:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2“Cyrus, king of Persia, says, ‘Yahveh God of heaven has given me the kingdoms of the world and appointed me to build him a temple in Jerusalem, in Judah. 3Whoever is from his people, your God be with you! Go up and rebuild the Temple of Yahveh God of Israel, the God in Jerusalem. 4Wherever there’s a survivor, support him with silver and gold, supplies and livestock, plus freewill offerings.’”           &#x9;Ezra 1:1-4&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOREIGN TERMS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/foreign-terms-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/foreign-terms-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOREIGN TERMS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abaddon (Ἀβαδδών): “Destroyer” (Revelation 9:11**)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abba (Αββα): “father” (Mark 14:36; Romans 8:15; Galatians 4:6**)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Akeldama (Ἀκελδαμάχ): “Field of Blood” (Acts 1:19**)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;anathema (ἀνάθεμα): Galatians 1:9; 1 Corinthians 16:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Armageddon (Ἁρμαγεδών): “The Hill of Megiddo” (Revelation 16:16**)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bar-Jesus (Βαριησούς): Acts 13:6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Simon) Bar-Jonah/Bar-Jonah (Βαιωνά/Βαριωνᾶς): “(Simon), son-of John” (Matthew&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:17)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Barnabas (Βαρναβᾶς): “Son of Consolation” (Acts 4:36 “which is interpreted [ὅ&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ἐστιν μεθερμηνευόμενον]”)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Barsabbas (Βαρσαββᾶς): Joseph Barsabbas (Acts 1:23); Judas Barsabbas (Acts 15:22)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GENESIS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/genesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/genesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GENESIS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Version&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Whole Creation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1In the beginning God created earth and sky.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Earth was unformed and empty, and open water lay in the darkness. God’s Spirit was moving over the ocean. 3God said, “Let there be light,” and there was light. 4He saw the light was good and separated it from darkness. 5He called light “day” and darkness “night.” Morning and evening made day one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6God said, “Let an expanse separate the water 7below it from the water above it.” It happened. 8He called the expanse “sky.” Morning and evening made day two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HABAKKUK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/habakkuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/habakkuk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HABAKKUK&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1The Oracle That Habakkuk the Prophet Saw&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Habakkuk’s Complaint&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2How long, Yahveh, will I call out for help,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and you won’t listen?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I cry out, “Violence!”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;but you don’t protect me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3Why do you make me watch wickedness?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Destruction and violence go on right in front of me;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;fighting and arguing keep getting worse and worse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4The courts ignore the Law,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;so they don’t render justice;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HAGGAI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/haggai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/haggai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HAGGAI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1The First Day, Sixth Month, Second Year of King Darius&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Message from Yahveh to the Prophet Haggai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;for Zerubbabel Ben-Shealtiel, Governor of Judah,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and for Joshua Ben-Jehozadak, the High Priest,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God’s Call to Rebuild the Temple&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2“Yahveh says, ‘These people are saying this is no time to be rebuilding Yahveh’s Temple.’”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3A message came by Haggai, 4“Is this a time for you to be living in your paneled houses while my Temple lies in ruins?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOSEA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/hosea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/hosea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HOSEA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Messages from Yahveh to Hosea Ben-Beeri&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at the Time of Uzziah, Jotham, Ahaz, and Hezekiah, Kings of Judah,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and Jeroboam Ben-Joash/Jehoash, King of Israel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hosea’s Wife and Children&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2When Yahveh spoke the first time through Hosea, he said, “Marry a prostitute and have children, because the land is committing flagrant prostitution by abandoning me.” 3So he married Gomer Bat Diblaim, and she had a son. 4Yahveh said,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I SAMUEL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/i-samuel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/i-samuel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I SAMUEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Birth of Samuel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Elkanah was from Ramathaim-zophim in the hill country of Ephraim. He was the son of Jeroham Ben-Elihu (Ben-Tohu Ben-Zuph), an Ephraimite. 2He had two wives: Hannah and Peninnah. Peninnah had children but Hannah didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3He went up to Shiloh every year to worship and sacrifice to Yahveh of hosts. Eli’s two sons, Hophni and Phinehas, were priests there. 4When Elkanah sacrificed, he’d give portions to Peninnah and her sons and daughters; 5but he’d give Hannah a double portion because he loved her. But Yahveh had closed her womb, 6and her rival would bully her mercilessly about it 7year after year. As often as she went up to Yahveh’s Tabernacle, Peninnah would torment her. She’d cry and wouldn’t eat. 8Elkanah asked her, “Hannah, why are you crying and not eating? Why are you sad? Am I not better to you than ten sons?”&#x9;1 Sam 1:1-8&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/introduction-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/introduction-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction to&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE YAHVEH COVENANT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Yahveh Covenant presents a modified form of the Old Testament portion of The Conversational Version. Besides the features of that translation, the following points come up in this variant of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Yahveh Covenant uses the personal name of the God of Moses in places where it appears in the Hebrew text. The intent is to highlight the personal character of Old Testament revelation by using God’s personal name instead of substituting a descriptor—Lord, Master, God, Almighty, and the like. There is a difference in feel between listening to a brother talk and listening to John.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ISAIAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/isaiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/isaiah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ISAIAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Visions Isaiah Ben-Amoz Saw&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About Judah and Jerusalem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the Reigns of Uzziah, Jotham, Ahaz,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and Hezekiah, Kings of Judah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rebellious Judah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Listen, earth and sky, Yahveh says,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“I brought up sons,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;but they’ve rebelled.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3An ox knows its owner,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and a donkey recognizes its owner’s manger,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;but Israel doesn’t know me;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;my people don’t recognize&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;that I’m the One who provided for them.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4Sinful nation,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JEREMIAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/jeremiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/jeremiah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JEREMIAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1The Words of Jeremiah Ben-Hilkiah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;from the Priests at Anathoth in Benjamin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Messages from Yahveh came to him in the thirteenth year of Josiah Ben-Amon, king of Judah. 3They came as well during the reign of Jehoiakim Ben-Josiah, king of Judah, till the end of the eleventh year of Zedekiah Ben-Josiah, king of Judah, till Jerusalem’s exile in the fifth month. &#x9;&#x9;  Jer 1:1-3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Call of Jeremiah&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JOEL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/joel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/joel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JOEL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1A Message from Yahveh to Joel Ben-Pethuel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mourning over a Locust Invasion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Listen to this, elders;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pay attention, everybody in the land.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Has anything like this ever happened in your lifetime&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;or your ancestors’ lifetime?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3Tell your descendants about it;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;they need to tell their descendants, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Joel 1:1-3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4What the cutting locusts left&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the swarming locusts have eaten.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What the swarming locusts left&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JONAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/jonah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/jonah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JONAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jonah’s Flight from Yahveh&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Yahveh told Jonah Ben-Amittai, 2“Go to Nineveh, that big city, and shout against it; I’ve seen how sinful they are.” 3But Jonah ran away. 3He went down to Joppa, found a ship to Tarshish, paid the fare, and boarded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4Yahveh hurled a gale on the sea, and it was about to break up the ship. 5The sailors were scared, and every man cried out to his god. They threw the cargo overboard to lighten the ship. Jonah had gone below and fallen sound asleep. 6The captain came and said, “How come you’re sleeping? Get up, call on your god. Maybe he’ll be concerned about us enough to keep us from dying.” 7They said to one another, “Let’s cast lots to find out who caused this catastrophe to hit us.” They cast lots, and it fell on Jonah. 8“Tell us, now! Why has this catastrophe fallen on us? What’s your job? What’s your country? Who are your people?” &#x9;Jon 1:1-8&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JOSHUA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/joshua/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/joshua/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JOSHUA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yahveh’s Charge to Joshua&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1After Moses died, God said to Joshua Ben-Nun, Moses’ assistant,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2“Moses has died. You and the people, cross the Jordan to the land I’m giving you. 3Like I promised Moses, everywhere you go I’ll deliver it to you. 4Your territory will be from the desert and Lebanon to the big Euphrates River, the land of the Hittites to the Mediterranean Sea in the west. 5Nobody will be able to stand up to you all your life. I’ll be with you like I was with Moses; I won’t fail you or abandon you. 6Be strong and courageous. You’ll enable my people to inherit the land I swore to their ancestors I’d give them. 7Make sure you do everything in the Law that Moses commanded you. 8Think about it day and night. You’ll prosper and succeed. 9Haven’t I commanded you? Don’t be afraid or intimidated. Yahveh your God is with you.”&#x9;Josh 1:1-9&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JUDGES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/judges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/judges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;JUDGES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Partial Conquest of Remaining Territory&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1After Joshua died, the people asked Yahveh, “Who will go up first to fight the Canaanites?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2He said, “Judah. I’ll deliver the land to him.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3Judah said to his brother Simeon, “Go with me to my territory to fight the Canaanites, and I’ll go with you to yours.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So he went with him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4Judah went up and Yahveh delivered 10,000 Canaanites and Perizzites to him at Bezek. 5-6They attacked Adoni-bezek 6and he fled, but they caught him and cut off his thumbs and big toes. 7He said, “Seventy kings with their thumbs and big toes cut off used to pick up scraps under my table. God has done to me what I’ve done.” They took him to Jerusalem, where he died.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LEVITICUS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/leviticus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/leviticus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LEVITICUS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Yahveh called to Moses from the Tent of Meeting and told him,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2“When you take an offering to Yahveh, take it from the herd or flock. 3For a burnt offering from the herd, offer a male without defect. Offer it at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting 4and put your hand on its head to make it acceptable to atone for you. 5Slaughter the young bull, and the sons of Aaron, the priests, will offer up its blood and sprinkle it around on the altar at the entrance to the Tent of Meeting.  6Skin the burnt offering and butcher it. 7The sons of Aaron will put fire on the altar, arrange wood on the fire, 8and arrange the pieces, head, and fat on the wood. 9But you’ll wash its entrails and legs, and the priest will offer it up in smoke for a burnt offering,&#x9;Lev 1:1-9&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MALACHI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/malachi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/malachi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MALACHI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1An Oracle from Yahveh to Israel Through Malachi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jacob Loved More Than Esau&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Yahveh says, “I’ve loved you.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But you ask, “What do you mean ‘loved us’?”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Wasn’t Esau Jacob’s brother? Yet I’ve loved Jacob 3and set Esau aside, made his hill country desolate, and left his inheritance for desert jackals.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4Esau’s descendants claim, “We’ve been beaten down, but we’ll come back and rebuild the ruins.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MICAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/micah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/micah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MICAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Version&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1A Message from Yahveh to Micah from Moresheth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at the Time of Jotham, Ahaz, and Hezekiah, Kings of Judah.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What He Saw About Samaria and Jerusalem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Judgment Against Samaria and Jerusalem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Listen, every nation;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;listen, world and everybody in it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let the Lord Yahveh testify against you from his holy Temple.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3He’s coming down from his place&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;to walk on the mountaintops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4The mountains will mash down under his feet&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NAHUM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/nahum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/nahum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NAHUM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1The Oracle of Nahum&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Book of the Vision of Nahum&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yahveh’s Anger Against Nineveh&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Yahveh is an exclusive God&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;that avenges with anger.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He carries out vengeance on his adversaries;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;he stores up anger for his enemies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3He doesn’t get mad quick,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;but he does exert his power;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;he doesn’t let the guilty go free.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He displays his power in storms and tornadoes;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;clouds are dust beneath his feet.&#x9;Nah 1:1-3&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NEHEMIAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/nehemiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/nehemiah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NEHEMIAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1;1The Memoirs of Nehemiah Ben-Hacaliah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Report from Jerusalem&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the month Chislev, the twentieth year, I was in Susa, the capital. 2Hanani, one of my brothers, and some men came from Judah. I asked them about the Jews that had survived the captivity and about Jerusalem. 3They told me, “The remnant in the province is in dire straits and dishonor. The wall around Jerusalem has been torn down and its gates burned.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Testament Quotations from the Old Testament</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/new-testament-quotations-from-the-old-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/new-testament-quotations-from-the-old-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Testament Quotations from the Old Testament&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LXX: wording following the Septuagint Greek translation of the Hebrew Old Testament&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 1:23 &#x9;&amp;lt; Isaiah 7:14&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2:6&#x9;&amp;lt; Micah 5:2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2:15&#x9;&amp;lt; Hosea 11:1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2:18&#x9;&amp;lt; Jeremiah 31:15&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3:3&#x9;&amp;lt; Isaiah 40:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:4&#x9;&amp;lt; Deuteronomy 8:3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:6&#x9;&amp;lt; Psalm 91:11-12&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:7&#x9;&amp;lt; Deuteronomy 6:16&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:10&#x9;&amp;lt; Deuteronomy 6:13&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4:15-16&#x9;&amp;lt; Isaiah 9:1-2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5:21&#x9;&amp;lt; Exodus 20:13; Deuteronomy 5:17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5:27&#x9;&amp;lt; Exodus 20:14; Deuteronomy 5:18&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NUMBERS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/numbers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NUMBERS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Census of Israel’s Troops&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1On the first day, second month, second year after they left Egypt, Yahveh told Moses at Sinai in the Tent of Meeting,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2“Take a census by families. Count the men 320 years old and up that can go to war. You and Aaron count them by armies. 4To help you, appoint one man from each tribe as head of his ancestor’s house. 5They’ll stand with you:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OBADIAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/obadiah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/obadiah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OBADIAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1The Vision of Obadiah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edom’s Judgment Foretold&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Lord Yahveh says this about Edom;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;we’ve heard the report;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;an ambassador has gone out to the nations to say,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“To arms, attack Edom.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2“I’ll make you a minor player among the nations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and utterly despised.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3Your arrogance has deceived you,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;you that live high in caves&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and tell yourselves that nobody can bring you down.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4Though you’ve built high like an eagle&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OLD TESTAMENT QUOTATIONS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/old-testament-quotations-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/old-testament-quotations-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OLD TESTAMENT QUOTATIONS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:3 &amp;lt; 2 Corinthians 4:6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Light will shine out of darkness.” [Gen 1:3; Is. 9:2]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 1:27 &amp;lt; Matthew 19:4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Made them male and female. [Gen 1:27; 5:2]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 2:2 &amp;lt; Hebrews 4:4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“On the seventh day God rested from his work.” [Gen 2:2]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 2:7 &amp;lt; 1 Corinthians 15:45&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The first man Adam became a living soul.” [Gen 2:7]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Genesis 2:24 &amp;lt; Matthew 19:5&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PROVERBS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/proverbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/proverbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROVERBS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Proverbs of Solomon Ben-David, King of Israel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2for knowing wisdom and instruction,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;for understanding words that give insight,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3for receiving instruction in smart living,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;goodness, justice, and equity;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4for giving prudence to the simple,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and knowledge and discretion to the young;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;5for increasing learning in the wise&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and gaining skill at understanding;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6for understanding proverbs and wise sayings,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;riddles and profound speech.&#x9;&#x9;Prov 1:1-6&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;7Respect for Yahveh is the first thing about being wise;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>QUESTIONED TEXTS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/questioned-texts-in-the-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/questioned-texts-in-the-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;QUESTIONED TEXTS IN THE NEW TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below is a list of forty-one noticeable places in the New Testament where the text is uncertain. About 80% of the variants occur in historical segments, which is a little less than 60% of the New Testament. Brackets mark the questioned portions. Double parentheses mark the more important and more doubtful of these readings. Quotations are from The Conversational Version.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 6:13b&#x9;[because the kingdom, power, and glory&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RUTH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/ruth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/ruth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RUTH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elimelech’s Family Moves to Moab&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Judges were ruling when a famine came over the country. A man from Bethlehem in Judah went with his wife and sons to stay in Moab. 2His name was Elimelech, his wife was Naomi, and his sons were Mahlon and Chilion, Ephrathites. 3But Elimelech died and Naomi was left with her two sons. 4They married Moabite wives Orpah and Ruth. They lived there about ten years, 5and Mahlon and Chilion died too. So Naomi lost her husband and both sons.&#x9;Ruth 1:1-5&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE COMBINED GOSPELS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-combined-gospels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-combined-gospels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE COMBINED GOSPELS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mt Mk Lk Jn&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luke’s Prologue (Lk 1:1-4)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1Quite a number of people have undertaken to put together an account of what’s been fulfilled among us. 2Eyewitnesses from the beginning and ministers of the message have handed down those events to us. 3It seemed fitting to me as well, to trace them from the start and write you an orderly account, most excellent Theophilus. 4That way you can know for sure that your oral instruction was accurate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE CONVERSATIONAL NEW TESTAMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-conversational-new-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-conversational-new-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE CONVERSATIONAL NEW TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MATTHEW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Genealogy of Jesus (cp. Lk 3:23-38)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1The genealogy of Jesus the Messiah, son of David, son of Abraham&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Abraham, father of&#x9;&#x9;Isaac, father of&#x9;  &#x9;Jacob, father of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Judah and his brothers;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3Judah was father of&#x9;Peres and Zerah by Tamar;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Peres was father of &#x9;Hezron, father of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ram, 4father of&#x9;&#x9;Amminadab, father of&#x9;Nahshon, father of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Salmon, 5father of&#x9;&#x9;Boaz by Rahab;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boaz was father of&#x9;Obed by Ruth;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE CONVERSATIONAL OLD TESTAMENT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-conversational-old-testament/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-conversational-old-testament/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE CONVERSATIONAL OLD TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GENESIS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Whole Creation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1In the beginning God created earth and sky.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Earth was unformed and empty, and open water lay in the darkness. God’s Spirit was moving over the ocean. 3God said, “Let there be light,” and there was light. 4He saw the light was good and separated it from darkness. 5He called light “day” and darkness “night.” Morning and evening made day one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6God said, “Let an expanse separate the water 7below it from the water above it.” It happened. 8He called the expanse “sky.” Morning and evening made day two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE CONVERSATIONAL VERSION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-conversational-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-conversational-version/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE CONVERSATIONAL VERSION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TRANSLATION NOTES FOR THE NEW TESTAMENT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Conversational Version falls between wooden translation and loose paraphrase. It is not a word-for-word translation or one told “in our own words.” Its main contribution is at the second level of translation, the custom-of-usage level, that is, semantic equivalence. The aim has been to use a casual, everyday manner of speaking. The translation tries to follow specific patterns of form and grammar that do not affect subject matter. That includes several standard principles of written composition:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PSALMS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-psalms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-psalms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PSALMS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BOOK 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psalm 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1People are blessed that don’t&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;take advice from the wicked&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;or stand among sinners&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;or sit with scoffers,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2but delight in the Law of Yahveh&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and meditate on it day and night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3They’re like trees planted beside a river&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;that bear fruit in season,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;whose leaves don’t wither.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They’re successful at what they do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4Sinners aren’t like that:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;they’re like chaff that wind blows away;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE YAHVEH COVENANT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-yahveh-covenant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/the-yahveh-covenant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE YAHVEH COVENANT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Version&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GENESIS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Whole Creation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1In the beginning God created earth and sky.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2Earth was unformed and empty, and open water lay in the darkness. God’s Spirit was moving over the ocean. 3God said, “Let there be light,” and there was light. 4He saw the light was good and separated it from darkness. 5He called light “day” and darkness “night.” Morning and evening made day one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZECHARIAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/zechariah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/zechariah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ZECHARIAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1The Eighth Month, Second Year of Darius&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Message from Yahveh to the Prophet Zechariah Ben-Berechiah Ben-Iddo&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Call to Return to Yahveh&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2“IYwas angry with your ancestors. 3So tell the people, ‘Yahveh of hosts says, “Come back to me so I can come back to you. 4Don’t be like your ancestors that former prophets told to come back from their sinful ways and deeds, but they didn’t pay any attention. 5Where are those ancestors? Prophets don’t live forever, 6but my message commanded through them did come to bear on your ancestors. As a result, they repented and said, ‘Yahveh of hosts has dealt with us the way he intended, according to our ways and deeds.’”’” &#x9;Zech 1:1-6&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZEPHANIAH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/zephaniah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/translations/resources/zephaniah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ZEPHANIAH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conversational Yahveh Covenant&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1:1A Message from Yahveh to Zephaniah Ben-Cushi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Ben-Gedaliah Ben-Amariah) Ben-Hezekiah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at the Time of Josiah Ben-Amon, King of Judah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Coming Judgment on Judah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2“I’ll remove everything&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;from the earth,” Yahveh says,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3“people and animals,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;birds in the sky,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;fish in the sea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll destroy sinful people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;4“I’ll reach out against Judah&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and those who live in Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll remove the remnant of Baal from this place&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
