<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 Peter on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1 Peter on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Peter 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-peter-chapter-1&#34;&gt;1 Peter Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Peter, apostle of Jesus ChristMessiah, to the Chosen who live as foreigners in the Dispersion throughout Pontus, Galatia, Cappadocia, Asia, and Bithynia, 2known by God the Father a long time ago, sanctified by his Spirit, sprinkled with Christ&amp;rsquo;s blood, and obedient to him. Grace and peace many times over.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ. In his great mercy, he gave us a living hope by resurrecting Jesus. 4He has reserved for us in heaven an inheritance that doesn&amp;rsquo;t deteriorate, that can&amp;rsquo;t be defiled, and won&amp;rsquo;t fade away. 5Trusting his power protects us so we can receive the salvation that&amp;rsquo;s ready for him to reveal in the end.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Peter 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-peter-chapter-2&#34;&gt;1 Peter Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So, get rid of hate, deceit, hypocrisy, jealousy, insults. 2Like newborn babies, be hungry for pure spiritual milk so you can grow up to salvation—3if you&amp;rsquo;ve tasted how good the Lord is. 4Come to him as to a living stone, rejected by people, but chosen and precious to God. 5Like living stones you&amp;rsquo;re building yourselves up into a spiritual house for a holy priesthood that offers spiritual sacrifices to God through Christ. 6So it stands in scripture,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Peter 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-peter-chapter-3&#34;&gt;1 Peter Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Wives, defer to your husbands so even if they don&amp;rsquo;t believe the message, your conduct will win them over aside from it 2as they watch your innocent, respectful behavior. 3For beauty, don&amp;rsquo;t rely on external things like elaborately braided hair or the gold or clothes you wear. 4Root your beauty in the inner self as in a gentle, quiet spirit; that&amp;rsquo;s especially precious to God. 5That&amp;rsquo;s the way holy women who hoped in God used to adorn themselves in respect for their husbands. 6Sarah respected Abraham and called him Sir [lord]. You&amp;rsquo;re her daughters. if you do good and feel secure in your situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Peter 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-peter-chapter-4&#34;&gt;1 Peter Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Christ suffered; so arm yourselves with the attitude he took, because suffering purifies from sin. 2You won&amp;rsquo;t be living the rest of your life by human desires, but by God&amp;rsquo;s will. 3You spent enough time following the pattern of life the Gentiles carry on: a lifestyle of sensuality, lust, drunkenness, revelry, drunken parties, disgusting idolatry. 4They&amp;rsquo;re surprised that you don&amp;rsquo;t run with them in that excessive, reckless living; and they slander you for it. 5They&amp;rsquo;ll give account to the One who&amp;rsquo;s set to judge the living and the dead. 6In that connection, the good news was presented even to the dead so they&amp;rsquo;d be judged like the living who live according to God in the spirit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Peter 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/translations/cnt-nt/1-peter/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-peter-chapter-5&#34;&gt;1 Peter Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Elders, I&amp;rsquo;m a fellow elder, a witness of Christ&amp;rsquo;s sufferings. I share in the glory that&amp;rsquo;s going to be revealed. 2Shepherd God&amp;rsquo;s flock that&amp;rsquo;s among you. Provide oversight, not because you have to, but because you want to; not to make money (which is shameful), but out of internal initiative. 3Don&amp;rsquo;t lord it over your charges; set an example for the flock. 4When the Chief Shepherd appears, you&amp;rsquo;ll receive a glorious crown that won&amp;rsquo;t fade away.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
