<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GOD  (Theology Proper) on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/god--theology-proper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GOD  (Theology Proper) on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/god--theology-proper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ATTRIBUTES OF GOD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/attributes-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/attributes-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ATTRIBUTES OF GOD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suggested breakdowns&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Communicable and incommunicable: attributes that can or cannot be&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;communicated to his creatures&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Absolute and relative: those which belong to God independently and those that he&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;shares with his creatures in varying degrees&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Immanent and transcendent: those which belong to God’s inner being and those&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;which pass over to his creatures&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Individual and relational&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two ways by which we speak of God’s nature even though by experience we do not know what spirit is like: (a) by negating the characteristics of the material/physical world; (b) by taking shared characteristics via imago dei and pushing them to absolutes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FATHER, SON, AND HOLY SPIRIT: THREE-IN-ONE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/father-son-and-holy-spirit-three-in-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/father-son-and-holy-spirit-three-in-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FATHER, SON, AND HOLY SPIRIT: THREE-IN-ONE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sense in which Father, Son, and Spirit are three&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and the senses in which they are one&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at the same time to the exclusion of all optons&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Distinctness within the One Deity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trinity question calls for analyzing activities between Father, Son, and Holy Spirit. Approaches based on words are less satisfactory because words can vary in their meanings. Many attempts to arrive at a scriptural understanding, however, rely on (unclear) words rather than on (clearer) relational behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOREKNOWLEDGE AND SIN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/foreknowledge-and-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/foreknowledge-and-sin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOREKNOWLEDGE AND SIN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God’s reasons for creating us are summarized under divine self-fulfillment (delight), goodness (grace), glory and betterment. Of these four reasons the first and last are personal while the other two are interpersonal. The first two are the reasons for people; the third is the purpose of people beyond themselves. If we speak strictly about the purpose of people, we focus attention on God’s goodness and on what grow out of it, particularly dominion and commission. Self-fulfillment highlights the unnecessitated satisfaction that moves persons to express themselves. Goodness roughly corresponds with God-to-man action; glory corresponds with man-to-God re-action. We say “roughly” because we cannot draw a sharp line between these aspects, which is exactly what we expect in the highly complex, reciprocating, transacting activity that interpersonal process involves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOD KNOWN AS “HE”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/god-known-as-he/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/god-known-as-he/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GOD KNOWN AS “HE”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture consistently characterizes God in masculine terms. At the grammatical level, that pattern expresses itself in Hebrew masculine pronouns, adjectives, and verbs. “She” never designates the God Yahveh in any book of either testament.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the noun אלהים, “God/god,” does rarely refer to a goddess (1 Kings 11:33, Ashtoreth), but that never happens with the God of Israel. Not only do masculine pronouns refer to אלהים—and all his other designations—but Hebrew verbs with it carry masculine gender terminations. (Hebrew verbs have gender in the second and third persons.) Masculine adjectives likewise modify אלהים. This characterization holds true for Greek texts as well, which show θεός in the New Testament and the Greek translation of the Old Testament (LXX).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAYOUT OF THOUGHTS ON DEUTERONOMY 6:4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/layout-of-thoughts-on-deuteronomy-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/layout-of-thoughts-on-deuteronomy-64/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LAYOUT OF THOUGHTS ON DEUTERONOMY 6:4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;יהוה אלהינו יהוה אהד&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Yahveh our God is one Yahveh.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Yahveh is our God, Yahveh alone.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Yahveh is our God, Yahveh is one.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Yahveh is our God; Yahveh is unique.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Jewish                                &#x9;   &#x9;  A  Jewish&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Viewpoint      &#x9;Response      &#x9; Response                   &#x9;Counter-response&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deuteronomy 6:4  “us”              &#x9;(a) majestic plural        &#x9;Genesis   3:22*   “one   of   us”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;does not mean majestic plural;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;it is the clearest Old Testament&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;text   on   plurality   associated&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DIVINE TRINITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-divine-trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-divine-trinity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DIVINE TRINITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Methodology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.  &#x9;Investigate the activities of the Father, Son, and Holy Spirit (as well as statements about them) in passages where they are mentioned together, thus observing interaction in real circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Examples of relational activities are clearer than abstract statements about relationship. That procedure minimizes problems created by figurative language, the various meanings that words like “one” can have, and the possibility of accommodation to our mode of thinking and being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE PROBLEM OF EVIL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-problem-of-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-problem-of-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE PROBLEM OF EVIL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ANTILOGISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Supposedly only two of these points of the antilogism may be affirmed at any one time. The solution to an antilogism comes by adding new factors, which implies that one of the factors is not an absolute bereft of circumstantial qualifications. Evil is not an absolute, and neither are the other two characteristics. As omnipotence is qualified by holiness, all three of these points are qualified by love. Love, for example, may allow free will to be used to do evil rather than stifle every attempt to misuse free will. The most important consideration in the presentation below is that a larger category surrounds the antilogism—the interpersonal one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TRINITY THOUGHTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/trinity-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/trinity-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TRINITY THOUGHTS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Letter to a friend&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I took the opportunity presented by your question Sunday to assemble some thoughts that can also be part of the internet ministry effort I am working on. There is probably enough here to founder a good-sized horse, but that is the risk you take when you raise a good question that is at the same time complex and controversial. The first attachment I wrote up new as a second-level treatment of the trinity issue as I have come to see it. The other two attachments are more elaborate because they are lifted from my notes on Christian Doctrine, a course I taught at Manhattan Christian College for many years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VIEWS OF DEITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/views-of-deity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/views-of-deity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VIEWS OF DEITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God/god refers to ultimate reality. Christianity views God as eternal, ethical interpersonality with certain other knowable attributes. In contrast, the ancient nations around Israel as well as peoples living in modern times have concepts of deity that are incompatible with the biblical understanding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.&#x9;Theism. A general term for belief in God, usually considered transcendent and personal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B.&#x9;Atheism. The disbelief in the existence of any deity. All reality has one level, non-theistic. God is not a direction-setting aspect within the universe (panentheism, theistic naturalism), nor is he transcendent to the universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
