<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ETHICS on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/ethics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ETHICS on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A LETTER ABOUT SEXUAL IDENTITY DISORDER</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/a-letter-about-sexual-identity-disorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/a-letter-about-sexual-identity-disorder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A LETTER ABOUT SEXUAL IDENTITY DISORDER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;xxxxx,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several days ago your letter came, revealing your struggles with sexual identity disorder and what you have proposed to do about the matter. You will not be surprised, I am sure, to find a concerned ear for you in the situation you are handling, but you will not find a sympathetic ear for what you are contemplating doing with it. There is a distinction between the disorder itself and what a person proposes to do with it. The disorder may be understandable; what people decide to do with it is another matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAPITAL CRIMES IN MOSAISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/capital-crimes-in-mosaism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/capital-crimes-in-mosaism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CAPITAL CRIMES IN MOSAISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adultery/Incest&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10‘If a man commits adultery with another man’s wife, execute them both.’ Lev 20:10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;22“If a man is caught lying with a married woman, both of them will die. That’s how you’re to remove evil from Israel.” Lev 20:10; Deut 22:22&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;23“If a virgin is engaged, and another man lies with her, 24take them both to the city gate and stone them to death—the girl, because she didn’t scream in the city, and the man because he violated his neighbor’s wife. That’s how you’re to remove evil from Israel.” Deut 22:23-24 (engaged woman)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIANS AND TEMPORAL AUTHORITIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christians-and-temporal-authorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/christians-and-temporal-authorities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIANS AND TEMPORAL AUTHORITIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In non-Christian societies, people wonder whether they can continue in their jobs if they become Christians. The minister of a new congregation in Moscow asked about that issue. A policeman had asked whether he would have to quit his job if he accepted Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A policeman would not have to give up his source of income in accepting Christ. Paul states the principle in 1 Corinthians 7:20: “Let people stay in the calling where they were when they were called.” Paul is addressing marriage issues, but he is drawing on a broader principle because he also connects it with slavery (7:21-24) and circumcision (7:18-19). Christianity is transcultural and trans-vocational; it has no racial, social, marital, economic, societal, or vocational association.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMMENTS ON DIVORCE: MATTHEW 5:32</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-divorce-matthew-532/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/comments-on-divorce-matthew-532/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMMENTS ON DIVORCE: MATTHEW 5:32&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Everyone that puts away his wife—except for sexual immorality—treats* her like an adulteress, and whoever marries a divorced woman commits adultery.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For purposes here, we pass over some technicalities associated with the aorist passive infinitive (μοιχευθῆναι, moicheuthēnai, “makes her to be adulterated[?]”) and deal with more straightforward considerations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus teaches that divorce is contrary to God’s original intention for marriage. Marriage is no longer the way it was under the Mosaic Law, where a husband could legally divorce his wife even if she had not been unfaithful. No longer could he, for example, use divorce to avoid adultery—divorce his wife to marry “the other woman.” Such a thing amounts to adultery in motive and attitude.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETHICS AND THE GOLDEN RULE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ethics-and-the-golden-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ethics-and-the-golden-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETHICS AND THE GOLDEN RULE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Treating other people the way we want to be treated implies the fundamental continuity of humankind. Variations between people do exist, but they do not normally deal with matters that impinge on ethical considerations. Supposing the continuity of human nature as the background for the Golden Rule is preferable to supposing that the Golden Rule describes a non-content procedure, the approach of R. M. McIver, “The Deep Beauty of the Golden Rule” in Philosophy and Contemporary Issues, pp. 233-39.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ETHICS STANDARDS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ethics-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/ethics-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ETHICS STANDARDS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the standard and the basis for it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In That Hideous Strength (p. 285) C. S. Lewis has Dr. Cecil Dimble telling his wife that polygamy was not wrong for Abraham. That comment seems misleading, but it does raise the question about standards. There seems to be more than one way of speaking of an “ethical standard.” There is (a) the ideal standard, the one that God has always had in mind for everyone everywhere. The ideal standard is based on the originating purpose of God before creation. PURPOSE&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIXED MARRIAGE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/mixed-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/mixed-marriage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MIXED MARRIAGE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripture says so much about marriage because it is a universal experience. Besides, it is an intense experience. Married life calls for more skill and understanding than other relationships. It is harder than living alone because it is more complicated, especially when children enter the picture. It is harder than being a good neighbor, getting along with people at work, or even living together in the community of faith. Marriage affects the full range of life rather than just some aspects of it (total). The actions of one partner likely affect the other, and marriage involves a degree of intimacy. We find it possible—and even fulfilling—to relate to many people in varying degrees of “distance” or “closeness,” but in marriage there is no “distance,” and nothing is hidden. Besides, marriage is all the time whereas work is only part of the waking hours and not every day. Marriage is exclusive of all other relationships; its distinctives are not experienced with anyone else. Finally, marriage is permanent while other relationships are not necessarily for life. In a universal, total, permanent, exclusive relationship, it is imperative that the partners share at least the basic values by which marriage operates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIMARY FACTORS IN ETHICAL THEORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/primary-factors-in-ethical-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/primary-factors-in-ethical-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRIMARY FACTORS IN ETHICAL THEORY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preliminary Factors&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conclusions about specific moral matters depend on what framework we use when we think about them. Several fundamental constructs set limits on how Christians should act. The factors involved help us interpret scripture correctly when it does address moral issues we face. Those factors are particularly vital when we have to generalize biblical standards to questions that special revelation does not address.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first primary framework focuses on start-up factors that impact human behavior:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESPONDING TO ETHICAL RELATIVITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/responding-to-ethical-relativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/responding-to-ethical-relativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RESPONDING TO ETHICAL RELATIVITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relativity in ethics seems sensible because (a) incompatible moral beliefs and practices exist, and (b) no one seems able to establish a universal basis for ethical theory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In response to the second point, (1) the presence of a universal God (creator, sustainer, intervener) provides that universal basis. It does so because he had purpose in creating and if he has created us in his image. Furthermore, (2) human nature is universal for humans. We should not do what is contrary to human nature physically, psychologically, and socially; we should practice what enhances well-being, peace, and unity under God’s values. Presumably there is a hierarchy of what yields greater or lesser satisfaction, gratification, peace, and happiness, according to how well actions correlate with the givens of human nature—matters like the desire to be loved, the drive for worth, the urge for security, the impulse for innocence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOME VALUES OF LOVE AS AN ETHICAL PRINCIPLE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/some-values-of-love-as-an-ethical-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/some-values-of-love-as-an-ethical-principle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOME VALUES OF LOVE AS AN ETHICAL PRINCIPLE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Love gets us past legal minimums of do’s and don’t’s. It provides a basis for going beyond the call of duty, takes into consideration other people’s differing preferences, watches out for negative effects on weaker brothers’ behavior, and concerns itself with good and better, not just with good and bad. Love fosters a concern for enhancing the quality of other people’s lives, not just with the rightness or wrongness of specific behaviors relative to some standard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>STRAY NOTATIONS ON THE COMPLEXITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/stray-notations-on-the-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/stray-notations-on-the-complexity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;STRAY NOTATIONS ON THE COMPLEXITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF ETHICAL BEHAVIOR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ethics and morality relate to the interpersonal realm, with humankind. Since persons in relationship constitutes the most complex reality there is, ethics is a complex discipline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. The complexity of ethical theory comes from the fact that several principles determine right and wrong, and these principles are not of equal value. There is a plurality of unequal principles. Purpose, relationship, and nature are three primary factors that form the morality matrix; but subsidiary ones come into the picture as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THREE THOUGHTS ON ABORTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/three-thoughts-on-abortion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/three-thoughts-on-abortion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THREE THOUGHTS ON ABORTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I.  Not My Body, Not My Choice&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is the other within the mother. It has its own DNA, its own blood type, its own sex, its own body type, skin tone, eye color, and eventually all the features that make it a distinct individual. Choice does come into the picture; it comes in the mother’s behaviors prior to the pregnancy. We have no right to take out on the baby our own sexual irresponsibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
