<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CANON  NT BOOKS on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/canon--nt-books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CANON  NT BOOKS on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58357/cir-library/categories/canon--nt-books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CANON CRITICISM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/canon-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/canon-criticism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CANON CRITICISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. Definition of Canonicity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Canonicity constitutes normative literature. It sets the doctrinal “norms” by which we consider issues and measure viewpoints. In Christianity, canonicity correlates with inspiration. The canon consists of writings that came from “inspired” men, men whose writings were as correct and authoritative as they would have been if God himself had “exhaled them” (2 Timothy 3:16).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II. Principles for Canonicity (See separate document “The Determining Principles for&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DATES AND ORIGIN OF NEW TESTAMENT WRITINGS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/dates-and-origin-of-new-testament-writings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/dates-and-origin-of-new-testament-writings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DATES AND ORIGIN OF NEW TESTAMENT WRITINGS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;by Four Scholars Compared&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Book&#x9;Guthrie&#x9;Harrison&#x9;Thiessen&#x9;Hiebert&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew&#x9;80-100&#x9;70-80&#x9;45-50&#x9;66&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jerusalem&#x9;Palestine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark&#x9;60-70&#x9;65-70&#x9;67-68&#x9;64-65&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jerusalem&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Rome&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luke&#x9;75-85&#x9;70&#x9;58&#x9;66-67&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Achaia&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John&#x9;90-110&#x9;80-100&#x9;85-90&#x9;80-98&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acts&#x9;64&#x9;55-60&#x9;61&#x9;67-68&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Romans&#x9;57-59&#x9;56-57&#x9;56&#x9;58&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Macedonia&#x9;Corinth&#x9;Corinth&#x9;Corinth&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Corinthians&#x9;spring 57&#x9;55-56&#x9;spring 54, 55&#x9;spring 57&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&#x9;Ephesus&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GENERAL SCHEMATIC FOR CHRISTIAN APOLOGETICS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/general-schematic-for-christian-apologetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/general-schematic-for-christian-apologetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GENERAL SCHEMATIC FOR CHRISTIAN APOLOGETICS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following abstract of the flow of apologetics shows how critical introduction to the New Testament fits in the full picture of Christian evidence. Instead of beginning with objective Christian evidence, as traditionally done, this format includes a prior step with evangelism and apologetics becoming parts of the larger schematic. Coming to conviction begins in the present with (1) evidence people depend on. (2) The answer in Christianity comes from a cluster of historical events surrounding the person of Jesus the Messiah, especially his resurrection and the meaning of his life, death, and resurrection for human need in any age. (3) When people begin to carry out the principles of living Christ taught and to receive in experience the love of Christ, the purposefulness of life, the freedom from guilt, and the confidence of living under One that is trustworthy, they confirm subjectively that the truth in reality is also the truth for them. Living in the new condition helps them identify more clearly their real needs in addition to perceived needs. This stage helps them understand the message itself more clearly, and so on. The process forms an ongoing dynamic of reciprocal causation between the “poles” in the picture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEG DATES FOR NEW TESTAMENT STUDIES</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/peg-dates-for-new-testament-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/peg-dates-for-new-testament-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PEG DATES FOR NEW TESTAMENT STUDIES&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.D.&#x9;34 (perhaps 37)&#x9;Accession of Aretas&#x9;Paul’s   conversion   had   to   follow   this &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;date (Gal. 1:17-18; 2 Cor. 11:32).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;36&#x9;Pontius Pilate deposed&#x9;Does   the   absence   of   a   procurator   in &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;Palestine  account  for  the  possibility  of&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;executing      Stephen     and     of     Paul’s &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;putting   others   to  death?   (Acts  7:1-8:3; &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;9:1-2; 26:9-11)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;40&#x9;Death of Aretas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;44&#x9;Death of Herod Agrippa I&#x9;Paul’s  first   missionary   journey   had   to &#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;follow  this  date. (Acts 12:20-23 recounts&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;his death + 13:1-14:28 records the tour.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIMARY QUESTIONS IN THE COLLECTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/primary-questions-in-the-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/primary-questions-in-the-collection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRIMARY QUESTIONS IN THE COLLECTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OF THE NEW TESTAMENT CANON&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some scholars suppose the apostles did not consider their work as something for the subsequent ages of the church. They were writing for the then and there. They had supposed that Christ would return within the lifetime of some first-generation Christians. Writing for posterity did not enter their minds. If their literary activity took place under these conditions, collecting their writings to establish a permanent canon would not have been a concerted effort either. Only when it became evident that Christ would not immediately return did the early Christians begin to locate and assemble apostolic writings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE DETERMINING PRINCIPLES FOR CANONICITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-determining-principles-for-canonicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/the-determining-principles-for-canonicity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE DETERMINING PRINCIPLES FOR CANONICITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In keeping with the structure of apologetics, the following sketch deals with the principles for determining whether a writing belongs in the Judaeo-Christian canon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The historical principle comes logically first because canonicity has first to do with (5) where the book came from, which means who wrote it and where he got his information. Behind this step lies the concern about (4) how people recognized divine spokesmen and distinguished them from false claimants. The question rests on the observation that God’s breaking into the world through special revelation always, by definition and the nature of the case, involves (3) miracle. Even the prophets themselves must be able to distinguish divine revelation from their own thoughts. The next step is (2) the distinction between divine miracle that confirms revelation and other phenomena like demonic miracle, deception, parapsychological phenomena, misidentified natural occurrences. This distinction is most decisively made by (1) the triumph of the divine in confrontation with alternatives: the “resurrection” of Israel from Egypt (and attendant events) for the Old Testament and the resurrection of Messiah from the grave in the New Testament serve as prime examples. These are historical considerations because biblical revelation is a historical (vs. metaphysical) construct. The historical principle determines canonicity by giving us the right books in the first place; it is positive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TYPICAL ISSUES IN CRITICAL INTRODUCTION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/typical-issues-in-critical-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58357/cir-library/essays/typical-issues-in-critical-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TYPICAL ISSUES IN CRITICAL INTRODUCTION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Critical introduction addresses several issues related to the study of documents. In this setting, “introduction” does not mean getting acquainted with a book’s contents for the first time. “Critical” introduction does not “criticize” the book as if to degrade it. Critical introduction evaluates the nature of a book and matters surrounding its origin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two classifications of information critics draw on in this endeavor are internal evidence and external evidence. Internal evidence refers to data in the writing; external evidence refers to information from elsewhere. In critical introduction to the New Testament, (a) extant early Christian literature provides most of the external evidence. (b) Other resources related to the origins of Christianity help evaluate the records of early Christianity. They have been assembled in writings like F. F. Bruce’s Jesus and Christian Origins Outside the New Testament (Grand Rapids, MI: Wm. B. Eerdmans Publishing Co., 1974) or Gary R. Habermas’ Ancient Evidence for the Life of Jesus: Historical Records of His Death and Resurrection (Nashville, TN: Thomas Nelson Publishers, 1984). A final, more distant source of introductory information comes from extra-biblical records that preserve (c) the historical background in the contemporary biblical world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
