<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UNITY Christian and IP on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/categories/unity-christian-and-ip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UNITY Christian and IP on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61882/cir-library/categories/unity-christian-and-ip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Central to Less Central: An Interpersonal Format</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/central-to-less-central-an-interpersonal-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/central-to-less-central-an-interpersonal-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Central to Less Central: An Interpersonal Format&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;for Prioritizing Issues in Christian Unity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation proposes a way to help fulfill two responsibilities that we tend to put in tension with one another: our responsibility for representing Christian truth and our responsibility for facilitating Christian unity. The proposal stems from believing that interpersonalism prioritizes what naturally occupies central place in Christianity. We can draw on that observation to help us in the quest for unity in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIAN ATTITUDE AND CHRISTIAN UNITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/christian-attitude-and-christian-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/christian-attitude-and-christian-unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIAN ATTITUDE AND CHRISTIAN UNITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article encourages using interpersonal principles in the quest for Christian unity.1 We are reflecting on the role of attitude in creating an atmosphere for conflict resolution in the body of Christ today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first observation is simply that (a) proper attitude increases other people’s willingness to listen to our viewpoint. The Golden Rule works because we tend to respond in kind. The pattern operates negatively and positively: disrespect usually evokes disrespect, and respect evokes respect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHRISTIAN UNITY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/christian-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/christian-unity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHRISTIAN UNITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I. The Importance of Christian Unity&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interpersonalism highlights the importance of Christian unity because (a) unifying mankind is the very purpose of the church. In Christ, God is creating “a new united mankind” (Ephesians 2:14-16). What has come together in him must exemplify the purpose of him. The importance of unity also lies in its (b) apologetic value. Division in Christ belies the call to unity in Christ. The credibility of the Christian calling and claim is weakened or destroyed otherwise (John 17: 21, 23; Luke 11:18). The richness of the (c) Christian experience lies specifically in the “peace” that comes from Christians living together in harmony (1 Corinthians 7:15; cp. Romans 14:19).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOME INTERPERSONAL IMPLICATIONS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/some-interpersonal-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61882/cir-library/essays/some-interpersonal-implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOME INTERPERSONAL IMPLICATIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOR ONENESS IN CHRIST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Efforts at Christian unity have variously stressed one or more bases: organizational union, common experience, or essential doctrine. Roman Catholicism exemplifies the concern for unity through the church as an institution, which is particularly fitting because Catholic theology conceives of grace as flowing through the church by way of duly ordained clergy: “where the bishop is, there is the church.” Because of the emphasis on tongue speaking, pentecostalism can illustrate the common-experience approach. Erasmus among others advocated a minimum set of essential doctrines as foundational for Christian unity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
