<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SALVATION (Soteriology) on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/salvation-soteriology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SALVATION (Soteriology) on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/cir-library/categories/salvation-soteriology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>“FRIENDS” OR “SONS”? IMPLICATIONS FOR PERSEVERANCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/friends-or-sons-implications-for-perseverance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/friends-or-sons-implications-for-perseverance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“FRIENDS” OR “SONS”? IMPLICATIONS FOR PERSEVERANCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“He’s God’s friend.” That is about the nicest thing a person can say about someone. In the mouth of God himself, Isaiah says, “Abraham, my friend” (Isaiah 41:8; cp. James 2:23; 2 Chronicles 20:7). Friendship implies several things about our relationship to God. Jesus tells us what he is doing—revelation (John 15:15); so “friend” better describes us than “slave” or “servant” does. Besides, he cares about us—a lot, enough even to die an excruciating death for us (John 15:13-15; Romans 5:6-8, etc.). That implies doing for us whatever else we need and cannot do for ourselves; that is what a friend does (Romans 8:32; 1 John 3:17). Friendship with God separates us from people that are at cross purposes with him: “Friendship with the world is enmity with God” (James 4:4); so we have the same values and purposes that he does. Experience shows us a number of points that help us understand what ideal friendship is like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASPECTS OF HUMAN RIGHTEOUSNESS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/aspects-of-human-righteousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/aspects-of-human-righteousness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ASPECTS OF HUMAN RIGHTEOUSNESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Goodness has several aspects. In relation to a standard, goodness is humanly measurable behavior relative to the divine ideal—as to its “letter” and its “spirit.” As to the behavior, goodness is the overt behavior (which tends to correlate with what is humanly measurable) but the motive, attitude, and character—generalized pattern vs. specific act. As to the setting, goodness has a subjective and objective aspect. As to the kind of interpersonal behavior, there is morality, wisdom, and ministry. These dimensions of goodness are detailed under the headings below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PREDESTINATION IN SHORT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/predestination-in-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/predestination-in-short/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PREDESTINATION IN SHORT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Choice, act, consequence (free vs. fixed)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The choice itself is free, but the act is not necessarily free.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The act may be free, but the consequences are fixed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Permeable, semi-permeable, impermeable&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We choose our thought (permeable limit), but God may intervene between our choice and its fulfillment (semi-permeable; Abraham’s choice to sacrifice Isaac).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We may fulfill our chosen act, but God determines the consequences (impermeable).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The principle is true for individual acts, the sum total of life, and the whole of history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRESENTING THE GOSPEL TO “THE GOOD MORAL MAN”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/presenting-the-gospel-to-the-good-moral-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/presenting-the-gospel-to-the-good-moral-man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PRESENTING THE GOSPEL TO “THE GOOD MORAL MAN”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What do you do with a man like “Bob”? He really is a “good guy.” A happy, outgoing person that is glad to see you and always willing to stop and talk. Several years ago he quit a good-paying job so he could spend more time working with his only son, who became a successful race-car driver in our part of the country. One day he told me, “When I was a kid, my dad never had any time to do things with me. I’m not going to be that way with ‘Earl.’” I don’t know that I ever heard him use a “cuss” word. He gets along well with his wife . . . As far as Christ is concerned, what do you do with a man like “Bob”?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SHORTENING UP THE STUDY OF SALVATION FROM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/shortening-up-the-study-of-salvation-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/shortening-up-the-study-of-salvation-from/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SHORTENING UP THE STUDY OF SALVATION FROM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What the Bible Says About Salvation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since What the Bible Says About Salvation is rather long, using it in a church setting requires reducing it somewhat. There are two ways to reduce the amount of material and get at it more efficiently. First, use only the positive presentations (instead of looking at the alternative beliefs together with the reasons for and against them). Second, use the booklet Questions and Answers on “What the Bible Says About Salvation” on just the chapters (or parts of chapters chosen from the text itself).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE NATURE OF SALVATION</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-salvation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-nature-of-salvation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE NATURE OF SALVATION&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Salvation as reconciliation is the most distinctive feature of Christianity. Herein lies the primary difference between the gospel, on the one hand, and the Law, wisdom literature, and the prophets, on the other. In this respect, Christianity differs from the purposes of previous divine economies and from the goals of other religions and human agendas. In Christ, God is concerned with more than letting people know that he exists, what he is like, what his moral standards are, and what his expectancies are within his purposes. Salvation is not simply from ignorance, as by revelation; it is not deliverance from physical existence as in Gnosticism and Eastern dualism; it is not a deliverance from individuality as in Hinduism. Salvation is reconciliation from alienation and from all the negatives that come from separation from God and other people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE UNEVANGELIZED ELECT?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-unevangelized-elect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/the-unevangelized-elect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE UNEVANGELIZED ELECT?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Notion in a Nutshell: An Opinion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The diagram above takes its cue from Paul’s comments in Romans 2. God can judge unevangelized people on the basis of where their conscience has properly led them, the shaded area in the diagram. For practical purposes in that non-standard situation, God can disregard honest ignorance—where the conscience has misled and where it has omitted the rest of what Christianity stands for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TWO RESPONSES TO SIN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/two-responses-to-sin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/two-responses-to-sin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TWO RESPONSES TO SIN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sin involves two issues that correspond to the two sides of a sin situation. There is the doing of a moral wrong and the reacting to a moral wrong. Because sin takes place between people, there is the person who does evil and the one who suffers evil. In resolving that circumstance, repentance happens on one side and forgiveness happens on the other.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What happens, though, when there is no repentance? The basic principle seems to be that “where there is no repentance there is no forgiveness.” What people have done in the past they would do again unless they have changed, or “repented.” Without a change of mind, a change of heart, a change of resolve to behave differently, they are the same as they were when they sinned. Since “sin separates,” the separation continues because nothing has changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TWO SYSTEMS FOR RIGHTEOUSNESS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/two-systems-for-righteousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/two-systems-for-righteousness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TWO SYSTEMS FOR RIGHTEOUSNESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LAW [Moses]&#x9;GRACE [Messiah] (IP)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Purpose of both: human righteousness (Gal. 3:21)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Righteousness is for fellowship&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;with God and other people (IP).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Law and grace are parallel1 as to identity and kind&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Jer. 31:31-34 &amp;lt;Heb. 8:7-10:18; John 1:17; Rom 4:13-14; Gal. 3:21).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Principle of personal perfection (1 person)&#x9;Principle of trust in another to consider us&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deut 27:26; Lev. 18:5 (works&#x9;as perfect (Gen. 15:6; Hab 2:4)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>x x x,</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/x-x-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/cir-library/essays/x-x-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;x x x x,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your presentation follows the pattern used by Roman Catholic missionaries and many others, where general revelation (through nature) and theistic proofs bring someone to belief in God, his eternality, omnipotence, and other natural attributes. Special revelation adds a saving knowledge of God through Christ as holy, good, and loving (through history regarding God’s moral attributes). The first format has its precursor in Paul’s Areopagus speech; the second step follows Gamaliel’s argument in Acts 5, a resurrectiono-centric format in which the existence of the church and the fact of Jesus’ resurrection stand or fall together: the church exists; therefore, the resurrection occurred, Christ’s claim are true because resurrection is supernatural, and miracle confirms the claims of the miracle worker, etc. In the modern day, that two-step process has been enhanced by increased awareness of the complexity of nature with its accompanying tendency away from the likelihood that gradual change could explain chemistry-to-man by “endogenous complexification,” upward increase in complexity only by factors inside the natural order. Natural evolution replaces the need—not the fact/disproof—of supernatural deity; so it has become the apparent option for replacing the creationist model. A relevant observation, I might add, is that it is not possible to put in sequence the origin of reciprocating parts (especially for the level of observable complexity culminating in human social relationships).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
