<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 Timothy on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1 Timothy on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 Timothy 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-timothy-chapter-1&#34;&gt;1 Timothy Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Paul, apostle of ChristMessiah Jesus by the authority of God our Savior and Christ Jesus our hope, 2to Timothy my loyal son in the faith. Grace, mercy, and peace from God the Father and Christ Jesus our Lord.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; When I left for Macedonia, I urged you to stay in Ephesus to instruct certain people not to teach false doctrine 4or pay attention to myths and endless genealogies. Those things lead to speculation rather than God&amp;rsquo;s plan, which operates by faith. 5The goal of instruction is love from a pure heart, a clear conscience, and sincere faith. 6Some have turned away from these to empty talk and got lost. 7They want to teach the Law, but they don&amp;rsquo;t know what they&amp;rsquo;re talking about so confidently.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Timothy 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-timothy-chapter-2&#34;&gt;1 Timothy Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; So I encourage prayers and thanksgiving for everybody—2kings and other people in authority—that we can lead a peaceful, quiet, godly life. 3That&amp;rsquo;s good and acceptable to God our Savior. 4He wants everyone to learn the truth and be saved. 5There&amp;rsquo;s one God and one Mediator between him and us, the man Christ Jesus, 6who gave himself as a ransom for many, as a testimony given at the right time. 7That&amp;rsquo;s why he appointed me to be a herald and apostle, to teach Gentiles about faith and truth. That&amp;rsquo;s the truth.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Timothy 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-timothy-chapter-3&#34;&gt;1 Timothy Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s a reliable statement: &amp;ldquo;If anyone aspires to being an overseer, he&amp;rsquo;s aspiring to do a good thing.&amp;rdquo; 2He needs to be above criticism, faithful to his wife, moderate, sensible, respectable, hospitable, able to teach. 3He must not be pushy or addicted to wine. He should be gentle, not combative or greedy for money. 4An overseer needs to manage his family well; his children need to be obedient and well-behaved. (5If someone doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to manage his own family, how can he take care of God&amp;rsquo;s church?) 6He shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a new convert; he can get proud and fall into the devil&amp;rsquo;s condemnation. 7He needs to have a good reputation among people that aren&amp;rsquo;t Christians so he won&amp;rsquo;t fall into disgrace and the devil&amp;rsquo;s trap.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Timothy 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-timothy-chapter-4&#34;&gt;1 Timothy Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The Spirit says that later on people will abandon the faith. They&amp;rsquo;ll pay attention to deceiving spirits and demons&amp;rsquo; doctrines, and indulge 2in the hypocrisy of liars that have a seared conscience. 3They&amp;rsquo;ll forbid marriage and require abstinence from food that God created for faithful people to receive with gratitude. 4Everything he created is good, and nothing should be rejected if people that know the truth receive it gratefully. 5God&amp;rsquo;s word and our prayers sanctify everything he created.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Timothy 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-timothy-chapter-5&#34;&gt;1 Timothy Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t reprimand an elder; urge him like a father. Encourage younger men like brothers; 2older women like mothers, and younger women like sisters, in purity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Honor widows that don&amp;rsquo;t have anybody to depend on. 4If a widow has children or grandchildren, they should first learn to practice godliness toward their own family and repay parents; that&amp;rsquo;s acceptable with God.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; A widow that&amp;rsquo;s by herself has put her hope in God and continues in prayers and thanksgiving day and night. 6But one that lives in self-interest is dead while she&amp;rsquo;s alive. 7Tell widows to be above criticism.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Timothy 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/translations/cnt-nt/1-timothy/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-timothy-chapter-6&#34;&gt;1 Timothy Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Servants should fully respect their masters so God and his doctrine aren&amp;rsquo;t slandered. 2Servants with believing masters must not disregard them because they&amp;rsquo;re equals; they need to serve them even more because the ones that are benefiting from their good service are faithful and loved.&#x9; 1 Tim 6:1-2a Teachsg and encourage everyone to do these things. 3If anybody teaches something that doesn&amp;rsquo;t agree with sound words from our Lord Jesus Christ and with godly teaching, 4he&amp;rsquo;s conceited and lacks understanding. He has an unhealthy desire to debate and arguments about words. Things like that produce jealousy, division, slander, suspicion, 5constant arguing by people depraved in mind and deprived of truth. They think godliness is a way to gain wealth, 6but godliness with contentment is a great gain. 7We didn&amp;rsquo;t bring anything into the world, and we can&amp;rsquo;t take anything out. 8Let&amp;rsquo;s be content with food and clothes. 9People that want to get rich encounter temptation, which traps them in foolish, harmful desires and drags them down to ruin. 10The love for money is the root of all kinds of evil. Some that strain after wealth have wandered away from the faith and pierced themselves with many sorrows.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
