<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KNOW, How We,   (Epistemology) on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/categories/know-how-we---epistemology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in KNOW, How We,   (Epistemology) on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61779/cir-library/categories/know-how-we---epistemology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FAITH AND SIGHT/SCIENCE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/faith-and-sightscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/faith-and-sightscience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FAITH AND SIGHT/SCIENCE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Science deals with the experience of recurrent natural processes in the present. The technology science uses enhances the degree and kinds of sense perception in the natural realm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Limitations of Science&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A. Science cannot deal with universals or absolutes. It is subject to “the plague of particularity.” Science must take an inductive approach although it can form hypotheses, which are proposed universals suggested by observed particulars. The scientific method cannot deal with the absolutes of universal space or eternal time; hence, strictly speaking, it cannot see the big picture and cannot produce a worldview, because it is based on human experience, which is limited.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KNOWING BY FAITH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/knowing-by-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61779/cir-library/essays/knowing-by-faith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;KNOWING BY FAITH&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Limitations of Science&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Science has three major limitations. First, (1) science cannot deal with universals, or absolutes. It is subject to “the plague of particularity” because it is limited to the inductive approach. Science can, of course, form and test hypotheses, which are perhaps mental deductions from previous particulars; but these hypotheses are approximate since they are based on limited previous experience. Since science cannot deal with the absolutes of universal space or eternal time, science cannot lead to an adequate understanding of “the big picture.” Another way to say this is that science cannot produce a worldview. It deals more with particulars than with systematic investigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
