<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel on Christian Internet Resources</title>
    <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Daniel on Christian Internet Resources</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 1</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-1&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the third year of Jehoiakim&amp;rsquo;s reign in Judah, Nebuchadnezzar, king of Babylon, laid siege to Jerusalem. 2The LORD delivered Jehoiakim to him, along with articles from God&amp;rsquo;s Temple. He took them to the temple of his god in the land of Shinar/Babylonia and put them in the treasury. 3He ordered Ashpenaz, his chief eunuch, to bring in some of the Israelites, including members of the royal family and the nobles, 4young men with no defects, good looking, intelligent, educated men that could serve in the king&amp;rsquo;s court. He had him teach them the language and literature of the Babylonians, 5and allotted them a daily ration of the royal food and the wine he drank. He assigned them three years of education; then they were to enter his personal service. 6Among them were Daniel, Hananiah, Mishael, and Azariah from the tribe of Judah. 7The chief eunuch renamed them: Daniel was Belteshazzar, Hananiah was Shadrach, Mishael was Meshach, and Azariah was Abed-nego.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 2</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-2&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the second year of Nebuchadnezzar&amp;rsquo;s reign, haunting dreams kept him awake. 2He gave orders to call in the magicians, conjurers, sorcerers, and astrologers to tell him what he&amp;rsquo;d dreamed. When they came in, 3he told them, &amp;ldquo;I had a dream, and I&amp;rsquo;m disturbed about what it means.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; The astrologers said in Aramaic, &amp;ldquo;Long live the King! Tell us the dream, and we&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what it means.&amp;rdquo; 5&amp;quot;I&amp;rsquo;m giving an unalterable command. If you don&amp;rsquo;t tell me what I dreamed and its meaning, I&amp;rsquo;ll have you torn limb from limb, and make your houses trash piles. 6But if you tell me, I&amp;rsquo;ll reward you with gifts and high honor. So tell me the dream and its interpretation.&amp;rdquo; 8&amp;quot;You&amp;rsquo;re stalling because you can see I&amp;rsquo;ve given an unalterable command. 9If you don&amp;rsquo;t tell me the dream, there&amp;rsquo;s only one decree for you. You&amp;rsquo;ve conspired to lie and say bogus things till I change my mind. Tell me what I dreamed so I know you can tell me what it means.&amp;quot; 10&amp;quot;Nobody can do that. No great king or ruler has ever asked such a thing from any magician, conjurer, or astrologer. 11What you&amp;rsquo;re demanding is not possible. Nobody but the gods can tell you that, and they don&amp;rsquo;t live in mortal flesh.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 3</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-3&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Nebucharnezzar made a gold image 90ft tall and 18ft wide, and set it up on the Plain of Dura in the province of Babylon. 2Then he sent word to gather the satraps, prefects, governors, advisors, treasurers, judges, magistrates, and rulers of the provinces to come to the dedication of the image. 3They came and stood in front of it. 4The herald declared loudly, &amp;ldquo;Every people, nation, and language group, 5when you hear the horn, flute, lyre, trigon, harp, pipes, and other instruments, fall down and worship the gold image the king has set up. 6Whoever doesn&amp;rsquo;t will immediately be thrown into the blazing furnace.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 4</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-4&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; King Nebuchadnezzar to the peoples, nations, and language groups that live all over the empire:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; It has seemed good to me to tell about the signs and wonders the Most High God has done for me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; How great his signs,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; I, Nebuchadnezzar, was at ease in my house,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; A dream terrified me;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; So I ordered the wise men in Babylon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; The magicians, conjurers, astrologers, and fortunetellers came.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 5</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-5&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 5&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; King Belshazzar held a huge feast for 1,000 of his nobles and drank wine with them. 2While he was tasting the wine, he sent for the gold and silver items his predecessor Nebuchadnezzar had taken out of the Temple in Jerusalem. 3The king, his nobles, wives, and concubines drank out of them, 4and praised their idols made out of gold, silver, bronze, iron, wood, and stone.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 6</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-6&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 6&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; King Darius thought it good to appoint 120 satraps to oversee the empire. 2He put three commissioners over them. (Daniel was one of them.) The satraps would report to them, and they would protect the king&amp;rsquo;s interests. 3Daniel soon distinguished himself among the satraps and other commissioners because he had exceptional ability. The king planned to appoint him over the whole empire. 4Then the commissioners and satraps tried to find some grounds for accusing him of mismanaging government affairs, but they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any evidence of corruption. He was dependable, and they couldn&amp;rsquo;t find him negligent. 5They said, &amp;ldquo;We won&amp;rsquo;t find any grounds for accusing him unless it&amp;rsquo;s in connection with the Law of his god.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 7</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-7&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 7&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Previously, in the first year of Belshazzar, king of Babylon, Daniel had a dream while he was in bed. He wrote down this summary of it: 2&amp;quot;During the night I had a vision. Four winds were churning up the Mediterranean Sea, 3and four different beasts emerged from it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; The first was like a lion with wings like an eagle. As I watched, its wings were pulled off, and it was made to stand on its two hind legs like a human being and receive a human mind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 8</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-8&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 8&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the third year of Belshazzar&amp;rsquo;s regency, I, Daniel, had another vision. 2I was in Susa the capital, in the province Elam beside the Ulai Canal. 3I looked up and saw a ram with two horns standing by the canal. The horns were long, one longer than the other even though the longer one had grown up last. 4The ram was butting west, north, and south. No other animals could stand up to it, and nobody could rescue anyone from it. It did what it pleased and became great.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 9</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-9&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 9&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The First Year of Darius Son of Ahasuerus,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; I, Daniel, read in the scroll that the LORD had set 70 years for Jerusalem to lie in ruins, as revealed to Jeremiah the prophet. 3So I turned my attention to the Lord God and looked to him in prayer with fasting, burlap, and ashes. 4I confessed,         &#x9; Dan 9:1-4a &amp;ldquo;LORD, great awesome God that keeps covenant and enduring love for those who love you and keep your commandments, 5we&amp;rsquo;ve sinned, we&amp;rsquo;ve committed iniquity, we&amp;rsquo;ve acted sinfully and rebelled, we&amp;rsquo;ve turned away from your commandments and ordinances. 6We&amp;rsquo;ve ignored your prophets who spoke in your name to our kings, our officials, our ancestors, and the common people. 7You&amp;rsquo;re good, but we&amp;rsquo;re openly shameful—people of Judah, Jerusalem, and all Israel, near and far in all the countries where you&amp;rsquo;ve driven us for our unfaithfulness. [8] 9You have mercy and forgiveness although we&amp;rsquo;ve rebelled, 10haven&amp;rsquo;t obeyed, haven&amp;rsquo;t followed the laws your prophets set before us. 11Because Israel has sinned against your Law and turned aside from obeying you, you&amp;rsquo;ve poured out on us and our rulers the curse you swore in the Law of Moses. 12You&amp;rsquo;ve confirmed what you said by bringing this catastrophe on us. Nothing under heaven has ever been done like what you&amp;rsquo;ve done to Jerusalem. 13This catastrophe has come on us, but we still haven&amp;rsquo;t sought your blessing by paying attention to your truth. 14So you&amp;rsquo;ve brought on us the catastrophe you held in store. You&amp;rsquo;re good in everything you do, but we still haven&amp;rsquo;t obeyed you. 15Lord our God who brought a people out of Egypt with a powerful hand and made a permanent name for yourself, we&amp;rsquo;ve sinned; we&amp;rsquo;ve been wicked. 16In keeping with all your righteous acts, turn your anger away from your city Jerusalem, your holy mountain. Our ancestors&amp;rsquo; iniquities and our own sins have made Jerusalem and your people a byword to everybody around us. 17So listen to my prayer and supplication. For your honor, smile on your desolate sanctuary. 18Turn your ear and listen; open your eyes and look at the city and our desolation. We&amp;rsquo;re not presenting our supplication because we have any merits, but because you have great mercy. 19Lord, listen! forgive! do something! don&amp;rsquo;t delay! It&amp;rsquo;s your name the city and your people are wearing!     &#x9;Dan 9:4b-19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 10</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-10&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 10&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; The third year of Cyrus, king of Persia, a message came to Daniel (Belteshazzar) about great warfare. He understood that the vision was about future events.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; At that time, I, Daniel, had been in mourning for three weeks. 3I didn&amp;rsquo;t eat any tasty food or meat, drink any wine, or use any lotions that whole time. 4The twenty-fourth of the first month, I was on the bank of the Tigris River. 5I looked up and saw a man dressed in linen with a belt of pure gold from Uphaz around his waist. 6His body was like beryl, his face flashed like lightning, his eyes flamed like torches, his arms and feet shined like polished bronze, and his voice sounded like an enormous crowd. 7I was the only one that saw the vision, but such an overwhelming sense of dread came over the men that were with me that they ran and hid. 8So I was alone. My strength was gone, and my healthy appearance grew deathly pale. 9When I heard him start to speak, I passed out facedown on the ground.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 11</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-11&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 11&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; In the first year of Darius the Mede, I arose to encourage and protect him. &#x9;Dan 10:19-11:1 2&amp;quot;Three more kings will come to power in Persia. A fourth will gain far more wealth than the others. As soon as he gains power by his wealth, he&amp;rsquo;ll stir up the empire against Greece. 3A strong king will come to power there and rule as he pleases. 4But not long after he ascends to power, his kingdom will break up into the four points of the compass. It won&amp;rsquo;t pass on to heirs or continue with the authority he exercised. His sovereignty will cease and pass on to others than descendants. 5&amp;quot;Then the king of the South will grow strong along with one of his commanders. But his commander will gain more power than he has and obtain a large kingdom of his own.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daniel 12</title>
      <link>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://all-messi.github.io/cir-library/translations/cnt-ot/daniel/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-chapter-12&#34;&gt;Daniel Chapter 12&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;verse&#34; id=&#34;v1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;verse-num&#34;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; At that time, Michael, the great prince that guards your people, will rise up. There&amp;rsquo;ll be a distressful time like nothing since nations began. Everyone among your people who are written in the scroll will be rescued. 2Many asleep in their graves will wake up, some to eternal life, some to disgrace and eternal contempt. 3The wise will shine as bright as the sky, including those who lead many to goodness—like the stars forever. 4Close up this message, Daniel, and seal the scroll till the time of the end. People will travel everywhere and spread knowledge.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
